<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Otto Guevara"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Otto Guevara" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Otto Guevara Guth&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (born October 13, 1960) is a politician in [[Costa Rica]] and founder of the Partido [[Movimiento Libertario]] (Libertarian Movement Party). He served in the Costa Rican legislature from 1998-2006. Guevara is currently the president of the Libertarian Movement Party and has been its candidate for president of Costa Rica in 2002, 2006, and 2010.

==Personal history==
Otto Guevara is the son of civil servants.  His father, Claudio, was a physician for Costa Rica’s social security system.  His mother, Mariechen, worked for the Social Security system before resigning to run the family&amp;apos;s tourism business.

Guevara studied at the [[University of Costa Rica]] where he earned Bachelor’s degree in law followed by a Masters in International Business from [[National University of Costa Rica]] and a second Masters degree in Law with an emphasis on Conflict Resolution from [[Harvard University]].  He was also a long-serving professor of law at the University of Costa Rica where he imparted his understanding of education and conflict resolution to his students.

In addition to his work as a lawyer and a professor, he has also made a name in tourism, commercial trade, and public policy.  He also produced and hosted a number of television and radio shows focused on his moderate pro-freedom message.

==Political history==
Failing to see any representation for his values in Costa Rica’s traditional parties, Guevara founded the Movimiento Libertario in 1994 to challenge the conventional orthodoxy of Costa Rican politics which he saw as lurching towards greater corruption and less respect for the individual rights of his people. He believes that the principles of moderate intervention of the State and more economical freedom as the best way to improve the lives of the Costa Rican people.

First elected to congress as the sole representative for the Movimiento Libertario in 1998, Guevara earned recognition as Costa Rica’s best legislator by the press every year of his first term. In 2002, Libertarian Movement, with Guevara as the presidential candidate, elected 6 members to Congress out of 57 seats, but few weeks later they lost a Congressman, declared independent. After a split within the party that saw a group of libertarian members leave, Guevara said his party was moving to be liberal and not libertarian.

The year 2006 saw the Libertarian Movement Party again elect 6 members to congress, but they lost again other Congressman. As a [[Costa Rican presidential election, 2006|presidential candidate in 2006]], Guevara earned almost 10% of the vote. In 2009, Guevara is elected presidential candidate for third time. In February 2010, Guevara lost the [[Costa Rican general election, 2010|Presidential election]] with 20% of the vote for a third place finish.

On election day, Guevara was involved in a religious controversy, as his girlfriend Deborah Formal was seen on national television pocketing part of the host after receiving [[Eucharist]] at [[Catholic]] [[Mass (Catholic Church)|Mass]].[http://www.catholicnewsagency.com/news/spouse_of_costa_rican_presidential_candidate_pockets_eucharist/]

==External links==
*[http://www.movimientolibertario.com/ Movimiento Libertario] Official Site
*[http://www.relial.org/ RELIAL] Network of Latin America Libertarian/Classical Liberal Organizations
*[http://www.reason.com/news/show/33309.html Reason Magazine] interview with Otto Guevara

{{Persondata &amp;lt;!-- Metadata: see [[Wikipedia:Persondata]]. --&amp;gt;
| NAME              = Guevara, Otto
| ALTERNATIVE NAMES =
| SHORT DESCRIPTION = Costa Rican politician
| DATE OF BIRTH     = October 13, 1960
| PLACE OF BIRTH    =
| DATE OF DEATH     =
| PLACE OF DEATH    =
}}
{{DEFAULTSORT:Guevara, Otto}}
[[Category:1960 births]]
[[Category:Living people]]
[[Category:Harvard University alumni]]
[[Category:University of Costa Rica alumni]]
[[Category:Members of the Legislative Assembly of Costa Rica]]
[[Category:Movimiento Libertario politicians]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
