<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Indian Agricultural Research Institute"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Indian Agricultural Research Institute" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;[[Image:IARI Pusa Bihar.jpg|thumb|Pusa in Bihar, circa 1927]]
[[File:IARILogo.jpg|thumb|left|Logo of the Imperial Agricultural Research Institute]]
The &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Indian Agricultural Research Institute (IARI)&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is India&amp;apos;s premier national Institute for agricultural research, education and extension. It has served the cause of science and society with distinction through first rate research, generation of [[appropriate technologies]] and development of human resources. In fact, the &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Green Revolution was born in the fields of IARI&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; and its graduates constitute the core of the quality human resource in India&amp;apos;s agricultural research and education. The Institute has all along been adjusting and improving its policies, plans and programmes to effectively respond to the needs and opportunities of the nation. During the fifties, the advancement of scientific disciplines constituted the core programme and provided the base for its fast expansion in the 1960s and 1970s in all its three interactive areas, namely, research, education and extension. Besides basic research, applied and commodity research gained great importance resulting in the development of several popular high yielding varieties of almost all major crops and their associated management technologies, which brought about an unprecedented increase in the national food and agricultural production.

The &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Indian Agricultural Research Institute&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (IARI) is the institute for advanced education in [[agriculture]] in [[India]]. It was originally established in 1905 as the &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Imperial Agricultural Research Institute&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; with the financial assistance of an American Philanthropist, Mr. Henry Phipps in Pusa, [[Samastipur district|Samastipur]], [[Bihar]] and was relocated after the Bihar earthquake of 1934 to New Delhi to a place that is now called Pusa in [[New Delhi]]. The new campus at New Delhi was inaugurated in 1936. The institute was recognized as a &amp;apos;deemed university&amp;apos; in 1958 under the UGC act of 1956 of Parliament and since then it has awarded M.Sc. and Ph.D. degrees. It is financed and administered by the [[Indian Council of Agricultural Research| Indian Council of Agricultural Research (ICAR)]]. The IARI was responsible for the research leading to the &amp;quot;Green revolution&amp;quot; of the 1970s.

==External links==
* [http://www.iari.res.in/ IARI website]

[[Category:Research institutes in India]]
[[Category:Agricultural universities and colleges in India]]
[[Category:Agricultural research in India]]

{{science-org-stub}}&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
