<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Seminyak"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Seminyak" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{No footnotes|article|date=April 2009}}
&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Seminyak&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is a mixed [[tourism|tourist]] / residential area on the west coast of [[Bali]] just north of [[Kuta]] and [[Legian]]. Originally a separate township, this is now just another suburb of Kuta. This area is very popular with resident expatriates and land and accommodation prices are amongst the highest in Bali. Plenty of luxury spas and hotels abound. Owing to its high density of high-end shopping, combined with the clustering of many fine eating establishments, it has rapidly become one of the most well known tourist areas on the island.

Other well-known areas popular with tourists include [[Ubud]], [[Sanur]], [[Nusa Dua]], [[Jimbaran]] and the [[Bukit Peninsula]].

In addition to a few commercial strips with popular and lively restaurants, bars, villas and good crafts/furniture shops, there are a few notable establishments: Ku Dé Ta, which is a bar/restaurant with a cult following based on its beach side/semi-resort atmosphere that has earned it the title of number one party spot in various magazines, and Oberoi, which is an expensive hotel with a worldwide reputation. La Lucciola is a restaurant located in the north of Seminyak on the beach and has been in existence for over a decade.

Jalan Raya Seminyak (more often referred to as Jalan Legian), runs parallel with the beach, bisecting the district and acts as its main road artery.

{{see also|List of beaches in Indonesia}}

== External links ==

* [http://query.nytimes.com/gst/fullpage.html?res=9901E6D7173DF931A15751C0A9629C8B63&amp;amp;sec=&amp;amp;spon=&amp;amp;pagewanted=1 A Bali Beach Worth a Stay - NY Times Article on Seminyak - Feb 22, 2004]
* {{Wikivoyage-inline}}
{{coord|8|41|S|115|10|E|display=title|region:ID_type:city_source:GNS-enwiki}}
{{Tourist attractions in Indonesia}}

[[Category:Beaches of Indonesia]]
[[Category:Populated places in Bali]]

{{Kuta District}}
{{Bali-geo-stub}}&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
