<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Hillel, son of Gamaliel III"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Hillel, son of Gamaliel III" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Eras of the Halakha}}
{{unreferenced|date=February 2012}}
&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Hillel, son of Gamaliel III&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, was a [[Jew]]ish scholar in the 3rd century CE. He was son of [[Gamaliel III]], brother of [[Judah II]], and probably a pupil of his grandfather [[Judah I]].

Of his early history nothing is known. As illustrating his modesty the following incidents may be quoted: He and his brother were once at [[Biri]], where people remonstrated against their walking on the Sabbath in shoes with golden buckles, which was not customary at that place: they resignedly removed their shoes and handed them over to their accompanying slaves. On another occasion at [[Kabul]] they were about to bathe together when the people informed them that they did not consider it moral for brothers to bathe together: Hillel and his brother thereupon desisted. In either case they could have shown the people that their acts were perfectly legal, but they preferred to comply with the local customs ([[Tosef.]], [[M. Ḳ]]. ii. 15, 16; Pes. 51a).

While Hillel is not often quoted in connection with [[halakha|Jewish law]], he was an able interpreter of the [[Hebrew Bible]]; this accounts for Origen seeking his society and consulting him frequently on difficult Biblical passages.

It was probably this [[Hillel (disambiguation)|Hillel]] that declared, &amp;quot;The Jews have no Messiah to expect, for they have already consumed him in the days of Hezekiah&amp;quot; (Talmud, tracate Sanhedrin 99a).

Some credit Hillel, and not his better-known namesake, with the authorship of the following maxims: &amp;quot;Separate not thyself from the community&amp;quot;; &amp;quot;Be not confident in thyself until the day of thy death&amp;quot;; &amp;quot;Condemn not thy neighbor until thou hast been placed in his condition&amp;quot;; &amp;quot;Use no unintelligible expressions assuming that ultimately they will be understood&amp;quot;; &amp;quot;Say not &amp;apos;When I have leisure I shall study&amp;apos;: thou mayest never be at leisure&amp;quot; ([[Pirkei Avot|Ab.]] ii. 4; see [[Tosef.]], Yom-Tov, ad loc.).

[[Category:Talmud rabbis of the Land of Israel]]
[[Category:3rd-century rabbis]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
