<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Niccolò Piccinino"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Niccolò Piccinino" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;[[Image:Niccolò Piccinino.png|frame|right|Portrait.]]
&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Niccolò Piccinino&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (1386 – 15 October 1444) was an [[Italy|Italian]] [[condottiero]].

==Biography==
He was born at [[Perugia]], was the son of a butcher.

He began his military career in the service of [[Braccio da Montone]], who at that time was waging war against Perugia on his own account, and at the death of his chief, shortly followed by that of the latter&amp;apos;s son Oddo, Piccinino became leader of Braccio&amp;apos;s &amp;apos;&amp;apos;condotta&amp;apos;&amp;apos;. After serving for a short period under the Florentine Republic, he went over to [[Filippo Maria Visconti]], duke of Milan (1425), in whose service together with [[Niccolò Fortebraccio]] he fought in the [[Wars in Lombardy]] against the league of [[Pope Eugene IV]], [[Venice]] and [[Florence]]. {{sfn|Chisholm|1911}}

After an outstanding victory over the Venetians at the [[battle of Delebio]] (19 November 1432), he defeated the papal forces at Castel Bolognese (1434). When another papal army under [[Francesco Sforza]] defeated and killed Fortebraccio at Fiordimonte, Piccinino was left in sole command of the Visconti army, and in a series of campaigns against Sforza he seized a number of cities in [[Romagna]] by treachery.
[[Image:Peter Paul Ruben&amp;apos;s copy of the lost Battle of Anghiari.jpg|thumb|250px|left|[[Peter Paul Rubens]]&amp;apos;s copy of &amp;apos;&amp;apos;The Battle of Anghiari&amp;apos;&amp;apos; by [[Leonardo Da Vinci]]. Allegedly Niccolò Piccinino is the horseman 2nd from left.]]
In 1438, during the war between [[Republic of Venice|Venice]] and [[Duchy of Milan|Milan]], Piccinino, fighting for the duchy of Milan [[Filippo Maria Visconti]], tried to take the city of [[Brescia]], in [[Lombardy]], but [[Scaramuccia da Forlì]], fighting for [[Venice]], intervened successfully to raise the siege. In 1439 Piccinino again fought in [[Lombardy]] with varying success against Sforza, who had now entered the Venetian service.{{sfn|Chisholm|1911}}

Piccinino then induced the duke of Milan to send him to [[Umbria]], where he hoped, like so many other &amp;apos;&amp;apos;condottieri&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, to carve out a dominion for himself. He was defeated by Sforza at the [[Battle of Anghiari (1440)]], but although a number of his men were taken prisoners they were at once liberated, as was usually done in wars waged by soldiers of fortune. Again the war shifted to Lombardy, and Piccinino, having defeated and surrounded Sforza at Martinengo, demanded of the visconti the lordship of Piacenza as the price of Sforza&amp;apos;s capture.{{sfn|Chisholm|1911}}

The duke by way of reply concluded a truce with Sforza; but the latter, who, while professing to defend the [[Papal States]], had established his own power in the [[Marche]], aroused the fears of the pope and the king of [[Naples]], as well as of the Visconti, who gave the command of their joint forces to Piccinino. Sforza was driven from the Marche, but defeated Piccinino at Montelauro, and while the latter was preparing for a desperate effort against Sforza he was suddenly recalled to Milan, his army was beaten in his absence, and he died of grief and of his wounds in 1444.{{sfn|Chisholm|1911}}

Short of stature, lame and in weak health, he was brave to the point of foolhardiness, wonderfully resourceful, and never overwhelmed by defeat. He was cruel and treacherous, and had no aim beyond his own aggrandizement. Piccinino left two sons, [[Jacopo Piccinino|Jacopo]] and [[Francesco Piccinino|Francesco]], both condottieri.

==References==
{{reflist}}
;Attribution
*{{Cite EB1911|wstitle=Piccinino, Niccolò}}
==External links==
{{Commons category|Niccolò Piccinino}}
{{1911}}

{{Persondata &amp;lt;!-- Metadata: see [[Wikipedia:Persondata]]. --&amp;gt;
| NAME              = Piccinino, Niccolo
| ALTERNATIVE NAMES =
| SHORT DESCRIPTION =
| DATE OF BIRTH     = 1386
| PLACE OF BIRTH    =
| DATE OF DEATH     = 15 October 1444
| PLACE OF DEATH    =
}}
{{DEFAULTSORT:Piccinino, Niccolo}}
[[Category:1386 births]]
[[Category:1444 deaths]]
[[Category:People from Perugia]]
[[Category:Condottieri]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
