<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="The Makioka Sisters (film)"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="The Makioka Sisters (film)" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{nihongo|&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;The Makioka Sisters&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;|細雪|Sasame-yuki|extra=lit.&amp;apos;&amp;apos;small snow flakes&amp;apos;&amp;apos;}} is a 1983 drama film directed by [[Kon Ichikawa]] based on the [[The Makioka Sisters (novel)|serial novel]] of the same name by [[Jun&amp;apos;ichirō Tanizaki]].

==Cast==
*[[Keiko Kishi]]
*[[Yoshiko Sakuma]]
*[[Juzo Itami]]
*[[Kayoko Shiraishi]]

==Characters==

===The Sisters===
*Tsuruko Makioka:  The eldest Makioka sister is described as being [[phlegmatic]], and most of her voice throughout the novel is heard through letters she sends to her sisters.  Tsuruko lives in the &amp;quot;main&amp;quot; Makioka house in [[Osaka]], and is not only removed physically from her sisters, who live in a branch house in [[Ashiya, Hyōgo|Ashiya]], but also seems to be removed emotionally.
*Sachiko Makioka:  The second eldest Makioka sister who is the mistress of the branch house in Ashiya.  Sachiko is good-tempered and indulgent of her younger sisters, who live with her instead of, as tradition would have it, with Tsuruko.
*Yukiko Makioka:  Melancholy Yukiko is still unmarried at thirty, because, when the Makioka family was in its heyday, all of her marriage proposals were turned down as not being good enough.  Now, with the family in decline, marriage opportunities are much more scarce, and Yukiko&amp;apos;s stoicity and shyness do nothing to incite her suitors&amp;apos; attentions.  So shy that she cannot even speak on the telephone, Yukiko is sometimes frustrating, but ultimately loved by her sisters.
*Taeko Makioka:  The youngest Makioka sister embraces both Western clothing style and Western attitudes toward the world more than any of her sisters.  Taeko smokes, has affairs and willfully defies the orders of the main Osaka house.  This is mostly because she is impatient waiting for Yukiko to marry, which she must do before Taeko is allowed.  Taeko is called &amp;quot;Koi san&amp;quot; endearingly, by her two older sisters in Ashiya.  Calling the youngest sister &amp;quot;Koi san&amp;quot; is something commonly practiced in Osaka.

===Other important characters===
*Tatsuo Makioka:  Tsuruko&amp;apos;s husband, who took the Makioka name when he married her, and is now the master of the Makiokas.  The three Ashiya sisters find Tatsuo abrasive, and somewhat dull.  Tatsuo is employed at a bank.
*Teinosuke Makioka:  Sachiko&amp;apos;s husband who also took on the Makioka name.  Teinosuke is kind, respectful of the sisters and brilliantly smart, especially when it comes to literary arts, such as poetry and letter-writing.  Teinosuke is an [[accountant]].
*Etsuko:  Sachiko&amp;apos;s school-aged daughter, who is especially fond of Yukiko.
*O-Haru:  A maid at the Ashiya house.  Sachiko took O-Haru under her wing and tries to teach the gossipy maid manners and decorum.
*Mrs. Itani:  The owner of a beauty salon that the three younger sisters frequent.  Mrs. Itani&amp;apos;s gossip and love of matchmaking often help the sisters find prospects for a husband for Yukiko.
*Okubata:  Also called &amp;quot;Kei-boy&amp;quot; by the Ashiya sisters, is one of Taeko&amp;apos;s suitors with whom she tried, and failed, to elope ten years before the story&amp;apos;s beginning.
*Itakura:  A photographer friend of Taeko&amp;apos;s, a stranger to the Makioka family, to whom Taeko is attracted.

==Setting==

The story takes place in Japan primarily during the late 1930s (Shōwa era). The sisters live in the [[Kansai]] area ([[Kobe]]/[[Osaka]]) and travel to Tokyo and other prefectures throughout the novel.
==References==
{{reflist}}

==External links==
*{{imdb title|id=0086242|title=The Makioka Sisters}}
*{{jmdb title|1983|dg001540|title=The Makioka Sisters}}

{{Kon Ichikawa}}

[[Category:1983 films]]
[[Category:Japanese films]]
[[Category:Japanese-language films]]
[[Category:Films based on novels]]
[[Category:Films directed by Kon Ichikawa]]
[[Category:1983 Japanese films]]
[[Category:Toho films]]
{{DEFAULTSORT:Makioka Sisters, The}}&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
