<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Trinity College of Arts and Sciences"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Trinity College of Arts and Sciences" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{For|other institutions named Trinity College|Trinity College (disambiguation)}}
[[Image:SocSci.jpg|right|thumb|275px|Social Sciences building]]

&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Trinity College of Arts and Sciences&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is the undergraduate liberal arts college at [[Duke University]] in [[Durham, North Carolina]]. The college is currently one of two [[undergraduate]] divisions at Duke, the other being the [[Edmund T. Pratt School of Engineering]].

&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Arts &amp;amp; Sciences and Trinity College&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is the collective name of all educational and research programs in the [[humanities]], [[social sciences]], and the [[natural sciences]] at Duke, inclusive of undergraduate programs and many degree programs in Duke&amp;apos;s [[Graduate School of Duke University|Graduate School]]. Arts and Sciences consists of approximiately 580 faculty members in 44 academic departments, as well as assorted interdisciplinary units. As of 2003, there were 5,400 undergraduates enrolled in Trinity College of Arts and Sciences, the undergraduate degree granting unit. An additional 1000 undergraduates in the [[Pratt School of Engineering]] take roughly half their courses in Trinity College, while the Graduate School trains some 1200 doctoral and masters students in the arts and sciences as well as in [[Duke Divinity School|divinity]], [[Pratt School of Engineering|engineering]], [[Fuqua School of Business|business]], and [[Nicholas School of the Environment and Earth Sciences|environmental and earth sciences]]. The division&amp;apos;s unusual dual name may reflect the fact that it is responsible for undergraduate education (through Trinity College) and graduate education and research (Arts and Sciences).

Trinity College was the name of the predecessor of Duke University. Tobacco magnate and philanthropist [[James Buchanan Duke]] left a $24 million bequest to transform the college into a research university called &amp;quot;Duke University&amp;quot; in honor of his father [[Washington Duke]]. In 1930, the institution&amp;apos;s original Durham campus became known as the Women&amp;apos;s College of Duke University, while Trinity continued as the name of the undergraduate men&amp;apos;s college. The West or [[Gothic architecture|Gothic]] campus about a mile from East Campus became home to Trinity College, along with [[Duke University Medical Center|Duke University Hospital]] and the graduate and professional schools. The two colleges continued as coordinate residential and degree-granting entities for forty years. However, there was always a single faculty of Arts and Sciences responsible for undergraduate and graduate instruction. Trinity College and the Women&amp;apos;s College merged in 1972 to form Trinity College of Arts and Sciences and the East and West campus became co-educational.

==External links==
*[http://www.trinity.duke.edu/ Trinity College of Arts &amp;amp; Sciences]
*[http://www.duke.edu/ Duke University]

{{Dukeschools}}

{{coord missing|North Carolina}}

[[Category:Liberal arts colleges at universities in the United States]]
[[Category:Duke University]]
[[Category:Educational institutions established in 1930]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
