<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="The Boys from Brazil (novel)"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="The Boys from Brazil (novel)" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Infobox book
| name          = The Boys from Brazil
| image         = [[File:TheBoysFromBrazil.jpg|200px]]
| caption = 1st edition
| author        = [[Ira Levin]]
| illustrator   =
| cover_artist  =
| country       = [[United States]]
| language      = [[English language|English]]
| series        =
| subject       =
| genre         =
| publisher     = [[Random House]]
| pub_date      = 21 Oct 1976
| english_pub_date =
| media_type    = print
| pages         = 312
| isbn          = 0-394-40267-7
| dewey= 813/.5/4
| congress= PZ4.L664 Bo PS3523.E7993
| oclc= 1818465
| preceded_by   =
| followed_by   =
}}
&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;The Boys from Brazil&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is a 1976 [[Thriller (genre)|thriller]] [[novel]] by [[Ira Levin]]. It was subsequently made into a [[The Boys from Brazil (film)|movie of the same title]] that was released in 1978.

== Plot ==
Yakov Liebermann is a [[Nazi hunter]]: he runs a center in [[Vienna]] that documents crimes against humanity perpetrated during [[the Holocaust]]. The waning interest of the Western nations in tracking down Nazi criminals has forced him to move the center to his lodgings.

Then, in September 1974, Liebermann receives a phone call from a young man in Paraguay who claims he has just finished eavesdropping on the so-called &amp;quot;Angel of Death,&amp;quot; Dr. [[Josef Mengele]], the [[concentration camp]] medical doctor who performed horrible experiments on camp victims during [[World War II]]. According to the young man, Mengele is activating the [[Kameradenwerk]] for a strange assignment: he is sending out six Nazis (former SS Officers) to kill 94 men, who share a few common traits. All men are [[civil service|civil servants]], and all of them have to be killed on or about particular dates, spread over several years. All will be 65 years old at the time of their killing.  Before the young man can finish the conversation, he is killed.

Liebermann hesitates about what to do, and wonders if the call was a [[prank phone call|prank]]. But he investigates and discovers that the killings the young man spoke of are taking place.  As he tries to determine why the seemingly unimportant men are being killed, he discovers by coincidence that the children of two of the men are identical. It eventually transpires each of the 94 targets has a son aged 13, a genetic [[Cloning|clone]] of [[Adolf Hitler]] planted by Mengele.  Mengele wishes to create a new [[Führer]] for the Nazi movement, and is trying to ensure that the lives of the clones follow a similar path to Hitler&amp;apos;s.  Each civil servant father is married to a woman about 23 years younger, and their killing is an attempt to mimic the death of Hitler&amp;apos;s own father.

Liebermann manages to work out who one of the intended targets is, and travels to warn him that his life may be in danger.  However, Mengele reaches the man first, kills him, and then encounters Liebermann.  Liebermann is shot but Mengele is killed by the targeted man&amp;apos;s collection of dangerous dogs.  The plan is halted, but 18 Hitler clones have already lost their fathers.  The book ends with one of the Hitler clones developing [[delusions of grandeur]].

==References==
{{Reflist}}

{{Ira Levin}}

{{DEFAULTSORT:Boys From Brazil, The}}
[[Category:1976 novels]]
[[Category:Thriller novels]]
[[Category:Novels about Nazi Germany]]
[[Category:Novels by Ira Levin]]
[[Category:Adolf Hitler in fiction]]
[[Category:Cloning in fiction]]
[[Category:American novels adapted into films]]
[[Category:Novels set in Vienna]]
[[Category:Random House books]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
