<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="North Auckland Peninsula"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="North Auckland Peninsula" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{refimprove|date=February 2011}}
[[Image:North Auckland Peninsula.png|thumb|The North Auckland Peninsula stretches from the [[Auckland]] isthmus to the northern tip of New Zealand&amp;apos;s [[North Island]]]]

The &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;North Auckland Peninsula&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, frequently referred to as the &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Northland Peninsula&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, is located in the far north of the [[North Island]] of [[New Zealand]]. It is joined to the rest of the island by the [[Auckland isthmus]], a relatively narrow piece of land lying between the [[Waitemata Harbour]] and the [[Manukau Harbour]] in the middle of the [[Auckland]] metropolitan area. The peninsula is not conterminous with the local government region of &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Northland Region|Northland]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, which occupies the northern 80% of the peninsula only. The southern section of the peninsula is administratively part of the [[Auckland Region]].

The peninsula stretches northwest for about 330 kilometres from the Auckland isthmus, reaching a maximum width of 85 kilometres.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;{{cite encyclopedia |last=Orange |first=Claudia |encyclopedia=Te Ara - the Encyclopedia of New Zealand |title=Northland region - Geography |url=http://www.TeAra.govt.nz/en/northland-region/2 |accessdate=24 December 2012 |date=2 March 2009 |quote=Northland is a narrow peninsula, about 330 kilometres long from Auckland to Cape Rēinga. [....] The region is 85 kilometres across at its widest point.}}&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;{{cite encyclopedia |last=Franklin |first=Samuel Harvey |editor=A.H. McLintock |encyclopedia=An Encyclopaedia of New Zealand |title=North Auckland region |url=http://www.TeAra.govt.nz/en/1966/north-auckland-region/1 |accessdate=24 December 2012 |year=1966 |quote=The northernmost region of New Zealand projects out as a long peninsula some 200 miles in length (from the Waitemata Harbour) and not much more than 50 miles at its widest point.}}&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt; It has a convoluted coastline, with many smaller peninsulas branching off it. The last 100 kilometres of its length is the [[Aupouri Peninsula]] – a peninsula on a peninsula – with the island narrowing to only some 10 kilometres in width for this final northern part of the island.

At its northern end, the Aupouri Peninsula reaches a number of capes each of which is claimed by some people to be the North Island&amp;apos;s northernmost point: [[Cape Maria van Diemen]], [[Cape Reinga]], [[North Cape, New Zealand|North Cape]], and the [[Surville Cliffs]]. The honour actually goes to the latter of these, the cliffs being at a latitude of 34° 23&amp;apos; 47&amp;quot; South.

The North Auckland Peninsula features the massive gash of the [[Kaipara Harbour]] part way up its western ([[Tasman Sea]]) shore. This harbour is one of the largest natural harbours in the world, stretching some 65 kilometres in a north-south direction. Further north is a smaller natural harbour, the [[Hokianga]], which is of historic and cultural significance within New Zealand, especially to the native [[Māori people]]. Another historically significant site on the North Auckland Peninsula is [[Waitangi]] and the surrounding [[Bay of Islands]]. This was a major settlement in early colonial New Zealand, and was the site of the [[Treaty of Waitangi]], which is seen as the founding document of New Zealand&amp;apos;s nationhood.

The largest settlement on the peninsula (other than parts of the Auckland conurbation) is [[Whangarei]], on a natural harbour opening on the [[Pacific Ocean]] close to the peninsula&amp;apos;s widest point.

==See also==
*[[Auckland Region]]
*[[Northland Region]]

==References==
&amp;lt;references /&amp;gt;

{{coord|35.387|S|173.810|E|display=title|source:dewiki_scale:1250000}}

[[Category:Geography of the Northland Region]]
[[Category:Geography of the Auckland Region]]
[[Category:Peninsulas of New Zealand]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
