<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Yamaha Phazer"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Yamaha Phazer" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Phazer&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is the name of a model of [[snowmobile]] produced by the [[Yamaha Motor Corporation]].  Introduced in 1984, it became an immensely popular model for Yamaha and spawned several follow-up models (such as the Phazer II, Phazer Deluxe, Phazer Mountain Lite, Phazer FX, and Phazer GT); its design features were also incorporated into other models (such as later-model [[Exciter (snowmobile)|Exciter]]s as well as the Venture Lite).

Of particular note on the Phazer is way in which the [[headlight]] is directly connected to the [[handlebar]]s so that the headlight follows the direction of a turn.  This feature was certainly new among Yamaha models when it was introduced in 1984, and Yamaha claims that it and other features &amp;apos;began a new era in snowmobiling&amp;apos;. The Phazer was always known for its sharp handling, free-revving 485cc fan-cooled engine, solid reliability (most notably on Phazer II), light weight, and most importantly, value. It was not so well known for its ride quality, however, as with many Yamaha&amp;apos;s of the day.

Snowmobiles under the original Phazer name appear until 1989; new models such as the Phazer II, [[Phazer Deluxe]], etc., were sold until 2001. For the 2002 model year the Phazer nameplate was axed, where it would take a five year absence. Yamaha released a bold new snowmobile under the Phazer name-plate for the 2007 model year. [http://www.yamaha-motor.com/sport/products/modelhome/507/0/home.aspx] The snowmobile featured a radical new design which is inspired from the YZ250F motocross bike.  The new Phazer is powered by a new 80hp 499cc [[fuel-injected]] liquid-cooled [[four-stroke]] twin which makes its peak power at 11,000RPM. The engine is based on Yamaha&amp;apos;s highly successful and dependable YZ250F dirt bike engine. With a 487 pound estimated dry weight, it is one of the lightest production four-strokes.

The 4th generation Phazer is hoping to continue the legacy that was started 23 years ago, using the same principle as the original; provide a light-weight, high-revving, ground-breaking machine that anyone could afford and have fun on, this philosophy was highly successful and sent Yamaha to #1 in the snowmobile market-share world, where it would stay until the early 90&amp;apos;s when [[Polaris Industries|Polaris]] toppled them with their &amp;quot;wedge&amp;quot; chassis and powerful three-cylinder engines in such applications as the XLT, XCR and fuel-injected RXL.

== External links ==
* [http://www.yamaha-motor.com/sport/products/modelhome/506/0/home.aspx Model Homepage]

[[Category:Yamaha vehicles|Phazer]]
[[Category:Snowmobiles]]
[[Category:1984 introductions]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
