<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Philippine General Hospital"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Philippine General Hospital" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Unreferenced|date=June 2011}} {{Historical information needed|date=February 2013}}
{{Infobox hospital
| Name        = Philippine General Hospital
| Org/Group   =
| Image       = Philgenhospital.jpg
| image alt   =
| Caption     = PGH Main Building
| map_type    =
| Logo        = Up-PhlGenHospital.png
| Logo Size   = 150px
| Location    = [[Ermita, Manila]]
| Region      =
| State       =
| Country     = [[Philippines]]
| latd = 14 | latm = 34 | lats = 40 | latNS = N
| longd = 120 | longm = 59 | longs = 9 | longEW = E
| iso_region = PH
| coordinates_display = inline,title
| HealthCare  = Public
| Funding     =
| Type        = General, Public, Teaching
| Specialty   = General
| Standards   =
| Emergency   =
| Affiliation = [[University of the Philippines]]
| Patron      =
| Network     =
| Beds        = 1000 indigent, 500 private
| Founded     = 1907
| Closed      =
| Website     = [http://www.pgh.gov.ph www.pgh.gov.ph]
| Wiki-Links  =
}}
The &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Philippine General Hospital (PGH)&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is a tertiary state-owned hospital administered and operated by the [[University of the Philippines Manila]], the [[University of the Philippines System]]&amp;apos;s Health Sciences Center. It is the largest government hospital administered by the university, and is designated as the National University Hospital. It is located at [[Ermita, Manila]] in the [[Philippines]]. It is the biggest hospital in the country with a 1,500-bed capacity. It is a mixed-use hospital, with 1,000 beds for indigent patients and 500 beds for private patients, and offers some of the lowest rates for patients and is generally known as the hospital for indigent patients.

The PGH, being the largest training hospital in the country, is the laboratory hospital of health science students enrolled in the [[University of the Philippines]]. This includes students of medicine, nursing, physical therapy, pharmacy, occupational therapy, dentistry and speech pathology.

There are 14 clinical departments—Anesthesiology, Internal Medicine, Surgery, Neurosciences, Pediatrics, Otorhinolaryngology-Head &amp;amp; Neck Surgery, [http://www.sojr.org Ophthalmology], Orthopedics, Rehabilitation Medicine, Psychiatry, Radiology, Pathology, Emergency Medicine and Obstetrics &amp;amp; Gynecology—all of which offer residency and fellowship training. It also offers various training for paramedical specialties such as nursing, physical therapy, occupational therapy, speech pathology, radiation technology, nutrition, hospital dentistry, medical technology and EMT training.

On an average year, about 600,000 patients pass through the hospital&amp;apos;s halls. Because of this, many organizations help the hospital. Some help the hospital directly, such as the PGH Medical Foundation and the Fr. Barbero Foundation. Others help patients by financing the cost of medications, operations and therapies. Some of these organizations are based within the University, notably the Mu Sigma Phi Fraternity and Sorority of the College of Medicine, recognized by UP Manila and the City of Manila as its outstanding organizations, LIKAS and Pagsama, both multi-college organizations and the Phi Lambda delta Sorority and [[Phi Kappa Mu]] Fraternity, also of the [[University of the Philippines College of Medicine]].

PGH celebrated its centennial in 2007, one hundred years since the US government passed a law establishing it. The hospital has seen the worst of tropical epidemics during its early existence and the worst of the war in the 1940s. It is one of the very few Philippine hospitals that remained open all throughout the war.

==References==
{{Reflist}}

==External links==
*[http://www.pgh.gov.ph Official website]
*[http://iampgh.org/ Philippine General Hospital Foundation]
*[http://www.sojr.org Sentro Oftalmologico Jose Rizal (PGH Department of Ophthalmology and Visual Sciences)]

{{Manila landmarks}}
{{University of the Philippines Manila}}
{{UP}}

[[Category:Hospitals in the Philippines]]
[[Category:Hospitals established in 1907]]
[[Category:Buildings and structures in Manila]]
[[Category:1907 establishments in the Philippines]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
