<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Year of the Eucharist"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Year of the Eucharist" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Use mdy dates|date=February 2012}}
&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;The Year of the Eucharist&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is the name of the [[liturgical year]] from October 2004 to October 2005, as celebrated by [[Roman Catholics|Catholics]] worldwide. On June 10, 2004, [[Pope John Paul II]] announced the dedication of an entire year to the [[Blessed Sacrament]] and invited the entire Church to reflect upon the [[Eucharist]].

==Opening the Year==
Pope John Paul II stated that the idea came from scheduled events to take place in the following liturgical year. The [[International Eucharistic Congress]] was scheduled for October 10, 2004 to October 17, 2004, and would mark the opening of &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Year of the Eucharist&amp;apos;&amp;apos;. The year would close with the &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Ordinary Assembly of the Synod of Bishops]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, held from October 2, 2005 to October 29, 2005.

He stated that the [[World Youth Day 2005]] was another consideration in his decision of the dedication. He said, &amp;quot;I would like the young people to gather around the Eucharist as the vital source which nourishes their faith and enthusiasm.&amp;quot;

Specifically how the year was to be celebrated was left to the particular Churches. However, Pope John Paul II offered some basic guidelines. Suggestions were also presented by the [[Congregation for Divine Worship and the Discipline of the Sacraments]]. In the United States, many dioceses encouraged local parishes to conduct celebrations, to examine the place of the Eucharist in parish life, to encourage [[Eucharistic adoration]] separate from the Mass, and to evaluate how Eucharistic adoration is conducted locally. Many Bishops took the time to encourage their local parishes to institute 40-hour devotions.

==Goals of the Year of the Eucharist==
[[Pope John Paul II]] made several suggestions to the Church in order to help the faithful benefit from the &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Year of the Eucharist&amp;apos;&amp;apos;. He called on Catholics to understand the Eucharist as &amp;quot;an urgent summons to testimony and evangelization,&amp;quot; providing the necessary strength to carry out the &amp;quot;charge&amp;quot; given at the end of each Mass to spread the Gospel. John Paul II also asked for a commitment to a &amp;quot;culture of the Eucharist,&amp;quot; i.e. a commitment to providing witness to God&amp;apos;s &amp;apos;&amp;apos;real&amp;apos;&amp;apos; presence in the world.

Another reflection offered by Pope John Paul II is that of the meaning of the word &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Eucharist]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos;: [[Thanksgiving]]. John Paul II said, &amp;quot;In Jesus, in his sacrifice, in his unconditional &amp;apos;yes&amp;apos; to the will of the Father, is contained the &amp;apos;yes&amp;apos;, the &amp;apos;thank you&amp;apos; and the &amp;apos;amen&amp;apos; of all humanity.&amp;quot; He asked for a commitment to giving thanks to God, which he called a &amp;quot;&amp;apos;Eucharistic&amp;apos; attitude.&amp;quot;

==Notable events==
Among the many reflections published in honor of the year, Archbishop Alfred C. Hughes&amp;apos; of the [[Roman Catholic Archdiocese of New Orleans|Archdiocese of New Orleans]] wrote, &amp;quot;On this side of heaven, one cannot experience a more substantial or intense communion with Christ&amp;apos;s presence than in the Eucharist.&amp;quot;&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;[http://www.archdiocese-no.org/eucharist/letter/index.html Archbishop Alfred C. Hughes&amp;apos; Letter on the Year of the Eucharist]&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;
This year also saw the death of [[Pope John Paul II]] on April 2, 2005 (the one who established the year itself), and the subsequent election of [[Pope Benedict XVI]] on April 19, 2005.

There was an [[Eucharistic Congress]] in the [[Basilica of the National Shrine of the Immaculate Conception]] in Washington, D.C., on September 25, 2004, the [[homily]] was given by Cardinal [[Francis Arinze]], [[prefect]] of the [[Congregation for Divine Worship]].&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;[http://www.adoremus.org/Arinze-EuchUnites.html THE HOLY EUCHARIST UNITES HEAVEN AND EARTH] Francis Cardinal Arinze&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt; The closing Mass was attended by 3,000 Catholics.

==External links==
*[http://www.yearoftheeucharist.com/ USCCB Year of the Eucharist webpage]
*[http://www.vatican.va/roman_curia/congregations/ccdds/documents/rc_con_ccdds_doc_20041014_anno-eucaristia_en.html Year of the Eucharist Vatican Website]
*[http://www.adoremus.org/JPIICatechesisEucharist.html Catechesis of His Holiness John Paul II on the Eucharist] presented by Adoremus

==References==
*{{cite web|title=Apostolic Letter Mane nobisum Domine|work=Apostolic Letter, MANE NOBISCUM DOMINE, of the Holy Father John Paul II to the Bishops, Clergy and Faithful for the Year of the Eucharist|url=http://www.vatican.va/holy_father/john_paul_ii/apost_letters/documents/hf_jp-ii_apl_20041008_mane-nobiscum-domine_en.html|accessdate=December 13, 2005}}
*{{cite web|title=Solemnity of Corpus Christi – Homily of John Paul II|work=Mass and Eucharistic Procession for the Solemnity of the Body and Blood of Christ, Homily of John Paul II, Basilica of St John Lateran, Thursday, June 10, 2004|url=http://www.vatican.va/holy_father/john_paul_ii/homilies/2004/documents/hf_jp-ii_hom_20040610_corpus-domini_en.html|accessdate=December 13, 2005}}
{{reflist}}
{{CatholicMass|collapsed}}

{{DEFAULTSORT:Year Of The Eucharist}}
[[Category:Catholic spirituality]]
[[Category:Eucharist in the Catholic Church]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
