<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Sung Wong Toi"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Sung Wong Toi" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Chinese|c=宋王臺|j=Sung3 Wong4 Toi4|p=Sòng Wáng Tái|pic=Sung_Wong_Toi.jpg}}
&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Sung Wong Toi&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is an important historic relic in [[Kowloon]], [[Hong Kong]]. While its remaining portion is now located in the Sung Wong Toi Garden in [[Ma Tau Wai]], it was originally a 45 m tall [[boulder]] standing on the top of Sacred Hill (聖山) in [[Ma Tau Chung]] above [[Kowloon Bay]].

==Literal meaning==
The name &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Sung Wong Toi&amp;apos;&amp;apos; literally means &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Terrace of the [[Song Dynasty|Sung]] kings&amp;apos;&amp;apos;. The stone is believed to have been a memorial to the last two boy emperors of the [[Southern Song Dynasty]], [[Zhao Shi]] and [[Zhao Bing]], who temporarily lived in Hong Kong from 1277 to 1279.

==History==
[[File:SWT1920.jpg|thumb|640px|c. 1920s. The boulder bearing the three carved characters is situated on top of the hill (right); both were protected as sacred relics by a special ordinance in 1899. The gate, the steps to the inscription and the balustrade around the boulder were erected in 1915. The hill was levelled and the boulder was broken up in blasting operations to extend Kai Tak airport.]]

===Sung Dynasty===
According to historical records, the two young Sung emperors were pursued by the Mongolian army and fled south, eventually taking refuge at the Sacred Hill along the seashore. Zhao Shi died of illness in Hong Kong, while Zhao Bing died when a retainer put him on his shoulders and jumped off a cliff following the naval defeat of the Sung Dynasty by the [[Mongols]] at the [[Battle of Yamen]].

===Yuan Dynasty===
After the Sung Dynasty was overthrown by the Mongol army in 1279 AD, local residents inscribed the words &amp;quot;Sung Wong Toi&amp;quot; on this large rock that was on the Sacred Hill at that time.

Note that the Chinese character [[wiktionary:王|王]] ([[pinyin]] wáng, which means &amp;apos;&amp;apos;king&amp;apos;&amp;apos;) is carved in the stone instead of the conventional character [[wiktionary:皇|皇]] ([[pinyin]] huáng, which means &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[emperor of China|emperor]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos;). Both 王 and 皇 pronounced as &amp;quot;Wong&amp;quot; in Cantonese. The most likely reason is that the locals wished to avoid angering the new [[Yuan dynasty|Yuan]] rulers.  It not known whether 皇 was used initially, with the upper part of the character later cut off, or if 王 was used from the start.

===Qing Dynasty===
[[File:Sung Wong Toi before 1943.jpg|thumb|Sung Wong Toi before Japanese Occupation]]
In 1807, seven smaller characters were added on the right side of the stone to record the renovation work in the tingmau year of the [[Qing]] Emperor [[Jiaqing]].

===Japanese Occupation of Hong Kong===
During the [[Japanese Occupation of Hong Kong]] in 1941-1945, the boulder was dislodged from its place when the Sacred Hill was leveled for an extension of the [[Kai Tak Airport]]. A portion of the rock inscribed with Chinese characters survived the blasting operation. That part of the boulder, about one-third of its original size, displays the Chinese name of the stone, &amp;quot;Sung Wong Toi&amp;quot;.

===Post war===
[[File:SWT1950.jpg|thumb|300px|Stone carving before its separation from the original rockface (c.1950)]]After [[World War II]] this portion of the stone was shaped into a rectangular block and moved to the Sung Wong Toi Garden, a small park especially constructed for it. This park is located in the present-day [[Kowloon City|Kowloon City District]], at the junction of Sung Wong Toi Road and Ma Tau Chung Road, which is close to the stone&amp;apos;s original site. The construction work of the park was completed in the winter of 1945.

==See also==
* [[List of urban public parks and gardens of Hong Kong]]
* [[List of buildings and structures in Hong Kong]]
* [[History of Hong Kong]]

==References==
*&amp;apos;&amp;apos;In search of the past: a guide to the antiquities of Hong Kong&amp;apos;&amp;apos; 香港文物志, The [[Urban Council of Hong Kong]], 1988.

==External links==
*[http://www.discoverhongkong.com/eng/mustknow/hkstory/winning/hk_stor_winn08.jhtml An account about the boulder]
*[http://www.fso-tela.gov.hk/accessibility/eng/locations_details.cfm?Photo_Num=00393 Film Services Office]
*[http://www.centamap.com/scripts/centamap2.asp?lg=B5&amp;amp;cx=837554&amp;amp;cy=820656&amp;amp;zm=4&amp;amp;mx=837554&amp;amp;my=820656&amp;amp;ms=2&amp;amp;sx=&amp;amp;sy=&amp;amp;ss=0&amp;amp;sl=&amp;amp;vm=&amp;amp;lb=&amp;amp;ly= Maps by Centamap]
*[http://www5.lcsd.gov.hk/gishinter/html/viewer_en.htm The Geographical Information System on Hong Kong Heritage]
*[http://www.gohk.gov.hk/eng/welcome/kc_spots.html?spots=7 Hong Kong Fun in 18 Districts - Welcome to 18 Districts]
*[http://www.greatarchaeology.com/Archa_monument_review.php?archaeological_monument=Sung_Wong_Toi Description and History]

{{coord|22|19|29.35|N|114|11|21.54|E|display=title}}

{{Commons category|Sung Wong Toi}}

[[Category:History of Hong Kong]]
[[Category:Song Dynasty]]
[[Category:Urban public parks and gardens in Hong Kong]]
[[Category:Monuments and memorials in Hong Kong]]
[[Category:Kowloon City]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
