<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Street prostitution"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Street prostitution" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Refimprove|date=January 2008}}

[[File:10.3010 Torino-nightlife.v2.jpg|thumb|right|280px|A street prostitute talking to a potential customer in [[Turin]], [[Italy]], 2005]]
&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Street prostitution&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is a form of [[prostitution]] in which a [[sex worker]] [[solicitation|solicits]] customers from a public place, most commonly a street, while waiting at street corners or walking alongside a street, but also other public places such as parks, beaches, etc. The street prostitute is often dressed in a provocative manner. The sex act may be performed in the customer&amp;apos;s car or in a nearby secluded street location, or at the prostitute&amp;apos;s apartment or in a rented [[motel]] room.
In the UK a study showed that up to 95% of women in prostitution are problematic drug users, including around 78% heroin users and rising numbers of crack cocaine addicts.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;(Home Office 2004a)&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;  Abuse is often suffered by prostitutes, more than half of UK women in prostitution have been raped and/or seriously sexually assaulted and at least three quarters have been physically assaulted.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;(Home Office 2004b)&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

A global study of prostitution found that 9 out of 10 women in prostitution would like to exit if they could.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;(Farley, 2003)&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

==Legality==
{{Unreferenced section|date=August 2009}}

Street prostitution is often illegal, even in jurisdictions that allow other forms of prostitution.

Many countries which outlaw street prostitution have &amp;quot;unofficial&amp;quot; tolerance zones, where the practice is tolerated by the authorities, in spite of its illegality.

In some jurisdictions where prostitution itself is legal, such as in [[Prostitution in Canada|Canada]] and [[Prostitution in the United Kingdom|the United Kingdom]], street prostitution is still illegal.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;S. 1(1) of the [[Street Offences Act 1959]] as amended by [http://www.legislation.gov.uk/ukpga/2009/26/section/16 section 16] of the [[Policing and Crime Act 2009]]&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt; The prohibition applies to both prostitutes and customers, and these two countries also outlaw brothels.

Some jurisdictions also outlaw [[kerb crawler|kerb crawling]], slowly driving around with the intent to procure the services of a prostitute.

In [[Prostitution in Australia|Australia]], in [[New South Wales]] it is legal to solicit on the streets, except in some areas (such as near schools). The other [[Australian]] states and territories prohibit street solicitation, although some of these jurisdictions allow licensed brothels.

Street prostitution is legal in [[Prostitution in New Zealand|New Zealand]]. In [[Prostitution in Germany|Germany]] it is allowed too, but cities can restrict it to certain areas or hours (regulations vary widely from place to place).

In the [[Prostitution in the United States|United States]], street prostitution is illegal in all 50 states; 49 of the states outlaw all forms of prostitution; Nevada allows licensed brothels, but only in some rural areas, not in the major metropolitan areas (only 8 counties have active brothels and prostitution outside these brothels is illegal throughout the state).

In six towns in the [[Prostitution in the Netherlands|Netherlands]], a special zone (&amp;apos;&amp;apos;tippelzone&amp;apos;&amp;apos;) is designated for legal street prostitution. The zone is often in a [[business park]], to avoid inconvenience for residents. In some of the zones the prostitutes need a [[licence]], no new licences are granted  as there is an &amp;quot;[[extinction]] policy&amp;quot;.

==Risks and research==
{{Globalize|date=December 2010}}

Street prostitutes are extremely vulnerable to physical and sexual assaults, as well as to muggings, by clients and [[pimp]]s. [[Melissa Farley]]&amp;apos;s study of 854 prostitutes in nine countries, including The United States of America, found that 95% of women had been physically assaulted, and 75% had been raped. 89% of the women interviewed stating that they wanted to leave prostitution.

In a 2008 study of [[Chicago|Chicago, USA]] street prostitutes, economists [[Steven D. Levitt]] and [[Sudhir Alladi Venkatesh]] found that women working without pimps work for an average hourly rate of about $25, and those working with pimps make 50% more. This is roughly four times the wage of other jobs available to them. Prostitutes are arrested once for every 450 encounters and every 10th arrest results in jail time.
&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;www.chicagobooth.edu/capideas/apr09/4.aspx&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

==See also==
* [[Solicitation]]

==References==
{{Reflist}}

== External links ==
{{Commonscat|Street prostitution}}
* [http://www.cops.usdoj.gov/mime/open.pdf?Item=285 &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Street prostitution&amp;apos;&amp;apos;] by Michael S. Scott, US DOJ Problem-Oriented Guides for Police Series, No. 2 ([[PDF]] file)
* [http://www.streetwomen.org &amp;apos;&amp;apos;StreetWomen.org&amp;apos;&amp;apos;] Website documenting lives of women involved in street prostitution.

{{DEFAULTSORT:Street Prostitution}}
[[Category:Street culture|Prostitution]]
[[Category:Prostitution]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
