<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Whipped-cream charger"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Whipped-cream charger" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Unreferenced|date=July 2010}}
[[File:Whippits.jpg|thumb|250px|right|Whipped-cream chargers]]
A &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;whipped cream charger&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (also called &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;whippits&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;whippets&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;nossies&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, or &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;nangs&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;) is a steel cylinder or cartridge filled with [[nitrous oxide]] (N&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;2&amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt;O) that is used as a whipping agent in a [[whipped cream]] dispenser. The nitrous oxide in whipped cream chargers is also used by recreational drug users as an [[inhalant]] for its psychoactive effects. Chargers are also used as a cheap source of nitrous oxide for small, powerful [[model rocket]]s.

==Description==

The cylinders are about 6.3&amp;amp;nbsp;cm (2.5&amp;amp;nbsp;inches) long and 1.8&amp;amp;nbsp;cm (0.7&amp;amp;nbsp;inches) wide, and they are rounded at one end with a narrow tip at the other end. The chargers&amp;apos; walls are about 2&amp;amp;nbsp;mm (about 1/16&amp;amp;nbsp;inch) thick to withstand the great pressure of the gas contained within. Their interior volume is 10 cm&amp;lt;sup&amp;gt;3&amp;lt;/sup&amp;gt; and most brands contain 8 [[gram|g]] of N&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;2&amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt;O under pressure. Used chargers are non-refillable, but 100% recyclable where steel recycling programs exist.

==Culinary use==

Nitrous oxide is used because it migrates easily into the cream, and does not cause the cream to oxidize while it is in the can.
Cream must have a minimum fat content of 28% to produce whipped cream with a dispenser. To use a whipped cream dispenser, one starts by following a recipe — typically 1 cup of heavy cream, 2–3 tablespoons of [[sugar]], and any [[flavoring]]s/[[colorings]] as desired. The device is capped and one or two chargers are discharged into the unit, depending on its size. These pressurize the device with nitrous oxide and cause the fat-soluble gas to dissolve into the cream, just like carbon dioxide dissolves into water to create soda water. Shaking the dispenser a few times helps the gas dissolve. The dispenser is then ready for use.

When the cream dispenser&amp;apos;s valve is opened, the cream is forced out of the nozzle by the high pressure. However, when the pressure is released, the dissolved gas turns to bubbles and comes out of the solution — just as opening a soda bottle results in the formation of a head of bubbles. These expanding bubbles instantly transform the cream into a frothy, whipped state. Nitrous oxide is bacteriostatic (prevents bacteria from growing) and a charged cream dispenser can be kept in the refrigerator for up to 2&amp;amp;nbsp;weeks.

==Production==
In Europe, where production and use of whip cream chargers originated, there are presently 3 factories involved in its production. Standard size for whip cream chargers is 8&amp;amp;nbsp;grams of nitrous oxide per cartridge. Whipped cream chargers are intended for low-volume or occasional use, such as home kitchens, restaurants, and coffee shop applications. For very high volume commercial use, there do exist regulated tank systems for filling much larger containers and dispensing more whipped cream. These are more desirable if volume is in excess of a production level of 10&amp;amp;nbsp;liters per hour. Whipped cream chargers are designed to be opened with a device that punctures the thin metal seal at the narrow end of the tube; whipped cream dispensers have this integrated into the device&amp;apos;s cap.

==Use in model rocketry==

Whipped cream chargers are also used by model rocket enthusiasts for so-called [[hybrid rocket | micro hybrid engines]], where it acts as an [[oxidizer]] for solid fuels such as [[polyethylene]] or [[HTPB]].

==External links==
* [http://mattson.creighton.edu/N2O/ Microscale Gas Chemistry: Experiments with Nitrous Oxide]


{{DEFAULTSORT:Whipped-Cream Charger}}
[[Category:Drug paraphernalia]]
[[Category:Dissociative drugs]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
