<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Bearer bond"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Bearer bond" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{refimprove|date=November 2011}}
[[File:BabyBondLA.jpg|thumb|right|A 19th century bearer bond]]
A &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;bearer bond&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is a debt security issued by a business entity, such as a corporation, or by a government. It differs from the more common types of investment securities in that it is unregistered &amp;amp;ndash; no records are kept of the owner, or the transactions involving ownership. Whoever physically holds the paper on which the bond is issued owns the [[Financial instrument|instrument]]. This is useful for [[investor]]s who wish to retain anonymity. Recovery of the value of a bearer bond in the event of its loss, theft, or destruction is usually impossible.  Some relief is possible in the case of [[United States public debt]].&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;{{cite web|title=Loss, Theft, Or Destruction Of United States Bearer Or Registered Securities Assigned As Payable To Bearer|url=http://www.treasurydirect.gov/forms/sec3987.pdf|publisher=US Treasury|date=February 2007}}&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

== History ==
Bearer bonds have historically been the financial instrument of choice for money laundering, tax evasion, and concealed business transactions in general. In response, new issuances of bearer bonds have been severely curtailed in the United States since 1982.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;{{cite web|url=http://www.investopedia.com/articles/bonds/08/bearer-bond.asp|title=Bearer Bonds: From Popular to Prohibited|publisher=Investopedia}}&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

In the United States all the bearer bonds issued by the [[United States Department of the Treasury|US Treasury]] have matured. They no longer pay interest to the holders.  As of May 2009, the approximate amount outstanding is $100 million.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;{{cite web|url=http://www.treasurydirect.gov/govt/reports/pd/pd_bearregsec.pdf|title=Bearer and Registered Securities Balances as of May 31, 2009|publisher=US Treasury}}&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

In June 2009, Italian financial police and custom guards seized documents purporting to be US bearer bonds, totalling $134.5 billion. The bonds were in $500 million and $1 billion denominations, although the highest denomination ever issued by the US Treasury was $1,000,000.  It was unclear what the purpose of the fake bonds was; the two men carrying them were not detained after the bonds were seized.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;{{cite news|work=New York Times|author=Elisabetta Povoledo|date=June 26, 2009|title=Italy Intercepts Billions in Fake Treasuries}}&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;{{cite news|url=http://www.nytimes.com/2009/06/26/business/global/26fake.html|title=Mystery of Fake US Bonds Fuels Web Theories|publisher=NYTimes.com|first=Elisabetta|last=Povoledo|date=June 26, 2009}}&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

== National policy and practice ==
In the United States, since the passage of the [[Tax Equity and Fiscal Responsibility Act of 1982]], the issuance of debt in bearer form has been substantially curtailed. The interest paid on any such bonds issued after 1982 would be non-tax-deductible by the issuer in the case of corporate bonds, and taxable income to the holder in the case of municipal bonds. In contrast, registered bonds retain favorable tax treatment.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;{{cite web|url=http://www.fdic.gov/regulations/examinations/trustmanual/section_11/rta_manualroleoftransferagent.html|title=Role Of The Transfer Agent|publisher=[[Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation]]}}&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

==References==
&amp;lt;references /&amp;gt;

{{Commonscat|Bearer bonds}}

{{DEFAULTSORT:Bearer Bond}}
[[Category:Commercial bonds]]
[[Category:Bonds]]

{{bond market}}&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
