<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Young Shik Rhee"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Young Shik Rhee" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;[[Image:YoungShikRhee.jpg]]
{{Infobox Korean name
|hangul=이영식
|hanja={{linktext|李|永|植|}}
|rr=I Yeong-sik
|mr=Yi Yŏngsik
}}
Reverend &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Young Shik Rhee&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (1894–1981) is the founder of [[Daegu University]] in [[Daegu]], [[South Korea]], a pioneer of special education in Korea and a [[Korean independence movement]] leader in Daegu, Korea.

In September 1919, Young Shik Rhee was imprisoned for 18 months in Daegu Prison by the Japanese colonial authorities for his leadership role in the [[March 1st Movement|March 1st (&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Samil&amp;apos;&amp;apos;) Movement]] and other Korean Independence activities in Daegu. Torture by the Japanese police resulted in permanent hearing loss in one ear.

In 1926, Young Shik Rhee attended Kobe Theological Seminary (고베신학교 神戶神學校)in Kobe, Japan. As an ordained Christian minister, Reverend Young Shik Rhee presided as pastor of Daegu Seomoon Presbyterian Church from 1927 to 1936. Although popular as pastor and well known for his stirring sermons, Reverend Rhee later resigned from the church in order to minister to the less fortunate. He embarked on his lifelong journey of social work and ministry by serving as pastor at a leper treatment center in Daegu.

After the Korean independence from Japan in 1945, Young Shik Rhee expanded his social work by looking after orphans and handicapped children. In 1946, Young Shik Rhee founded the Daegu School for the Blind, the first special education school founded by a Korean. (The very first special education school in Korea, Pyongyang School for the Deaf and Blind, was founded by [[Rosetta Sherwood Hall]], a medical missionary and educator from U.S., in 1894. In 1913, the Japanese occupation government established the Seoul School for the Blind). When the devastating [[Korean War]] (1950–1953) resulted in increased number of war-orphans and the handicapped, Reverend Rhee was among the few who were devoted to helping them. The orphanage housed many handicapped children—who were clothed, fed and taught skills that would help them eventually leave the orphanage and live independently. Reverend Rhee ministered to the children&amp;apos;s spiritual and emotional needs, as well as raising funds, eliciting donations and recruiting volunteer teachers and doctors.

Young Shik Rhee saw the need to train special education teachers and social workers in addition to furthering the education of handicapped students who had special talents. In 1956, he founded the Korea Social Work School in Daegu. The school became a formal college in 1961. In recognition for the decades of invaluable contributions made by Reverend Young Shik Rhee, Korean President [[Park Chung-hee]] personally awarded him the 5.16 Minjok National Medal (5.16 민족상 교육부문 본상) in May 1969.

Korea Social Work College, founded in 1961, became Daegu University in 1981. Reverend Young Shik Rhee was president from 1961 to 1982. Daegu University installed the first Braille library in Korea in 1981, and the university continues its tradition of being in the forefront of social welfare and special education in Korea.

During the 1970s and 1980s, Reverend Young Shik Rhee traveled extensively to the [[Mariana Islands]] in the Pacific where many Korean laborers were forced to work under the Japanese military during the Japanese expansion before and during World War II. Reverend Rhee discovered decades-old burial sites of Korean laborers deep in the jungles of [[Tinian]] and repatriated the remains to a national cemetery in Korea. He also founded a group that erected a Korean Peace Memorial in the island of [[Saipan]] (Korean Peace Memorial at Malpi Point, Saipan) and in Tinian, in remembrance of thousands of Korean laborers who died in those islands.

In 1977, Reverend Young Shik Rhee was awarded the National Foundation Medal 건국포장 (建國褒章) by the Korean government in recognition for his role in Korean Independence.

Reverend Young Shik Rhee died of natural causes in [[Tumon]], [[Guam]], in 1981 at age 87.

== See also ==
* [http://micronesia.hawaii.com/marianas/attractions/index.php Korean Peace Memorial in Saipan]
* [http://www.theallineed.com/news/0506/287063.htm Japanese Emperor and Empress visits Saipan Korean Memorial]

{{Authority control|VIAF=50611377}}
{{Persondata &amp;lt;!-- Metadata: see [[Wikipedia:Persondata]]. --&amp;gt;
| NAME              = Rhee, Young Shik
| ALTERNATIVE NAMES =
| SHORT DESCRIPTION =
| DATE OF BIRTH     = 1894
| PLACE OF BIRTH    =
| DATE OF DEATH     = 1981
| PLACE OF DEATH    =
}}
{{DEFAULTSORT:Rhee, Young Shik}}
[[Category:1894 births]]
[[Category:1981 deaths]]
[[Category:South Korean religious leaders]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
