<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Rosół"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Rosół" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{unsourced|date=June 2012}}
{{Infobox prepared food
| name             = Rosół
| image            = [[File:09516 rosol z makaronem, sanok.jpg|222px|]]
| caption          = Traditional &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Rosół&amp;apos;&amp;apos;.
| alternate_name   = Rosół z kury, Rosół królewski, Rosół myśliwski
| country          = [[Poland]]
| region           =
| creator          =
| course           = [[Soup]], [[entree]]
| served           = Hot
| main_ingredient  = [[Chicken]], [[noodle]], [[broth]]
| variations       =
| calories         =
| other            =
}}
&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Rosół&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;  {{Audio|Pl-rosół-2.ogg|listen}} is a traditional [[Poland|Polish]] [[meat]] [[broth]]. The most popular variety is &amp;apos;&amp;apos;rosół z kury&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, or clear [[chicken soup]]. It is commonly served with fine noodles. A vegetarian version can be made, using vegetable stock cubes.

It is  one of the most popular Polish soups and is served on family dinners and also is a traditional soup for weddings. It is also said to be a great remedy if one catches a cold.
The name &amp;quot;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;rosół&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;quot; derives from a dish made of salted meat (old conservation method) cooked in water to make it more edible. Later fresh meat was used instead of salted. Much later that dish of cooked meat became a soup that we know today.

There are lots of types of &amp;apos;&amp;apos;rosół&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, as:
&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Rosół Królewski&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (The royal rosół)- that made of three meats: beef or veal, white poultry (hen, turkey or chicken) and dark poultry as duck, goose (crob only!), just a couple of dried king boletes, one single cabbage leaf and variety of vegetables as parsley, celery, carrot,  leek. The cooking must take at least six hours of sensitive boiling on small fire. At the end there must be added softly burnt onion.

&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Rosół myśliwski&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (The hunter&amp;apos;s rosół)- made of variety of wild birds as well as pheasant, capercaillie, wood grouse, black grouse or grey partridge, with small addition of roe deer meat, couple of wild mushrooms, 2-3 juniper fruits. Instead of wild poultry helmeted guineafowl can be used.

The most important thing about making &amp;apos;&amp;apos;rosół&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is that there can be no addition of pork, since that could make &amp;apos;&amp;apos;rosół&amp;apos;&amp;apos; not clear. It also cannot be boiling too fast because of the same reason.

So, on to the recipe from year 1682{{Cn|date=September 2012}}:

This is the way to cook Polish rosół: take beef meat or veal,
hazel grouse or partridge, pigeon and whatever meat that in rosół can be cooked.
Soak it, lay in pot, then strain and pour over meat,
add parsley, butter, salt, and skim well.
One have to know what to put in rosół to not stink of water or wind,
that is parsley, dill, onion or garlic, nutmeg or rosmarin or pepper to taste.
Lime will not spoil any rosół as well.
{{cookbook}}

{{DEFAULTSORT:Rosol}}
[[Category:Polish soups]]

[[pl:Rosół]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
