<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Thermoception"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Thermoception" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Thermoception&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; or &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;thermoreception&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is the [[sense]] by which an [[organism]] perceives temperatures. The details of how temperature receptors work are still being investigated.  [[Ciliopathy]] is associated with decreased ability to sense heat, thus [[cilia]] may aid in the process.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;{{cite web |url=http://www.hopkinsmedicine.org/news/media/releases/can_you_feel_the_heat_your_cilia_can |accessdate=2011-09-03 |date=2007-10-22 |title=Can You Feel The Heat? Your Cilia Can}}&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;  [[Transient receptor potential channel]]s (TRP channels) are believed to play a role in many species in sensation of hot, cold, and pain.  [[Mammal]]s have at least two types of sensor: those that detect heat (i.e., temperatures above body temperature) and those that detect cold (i.e. temperatures below body temperature).{{citation needed|date=September 2011}}

A particularly specialized form of [[Infrared sensing in snakes|thermoception]] is used by [[Crotalinae]] (pit viper) and [[Boidae]] (boa) snakes, which can effectively see the infrared radiation emitted by hot objects.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;E. A. Newman, P. H. Hartline (1982). The Infrared ‘vision’ of snakes. Scientific American 20:116-127.&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt; The snakes&amp;apos; face has a pair of holes, or pits, lined with temperature sensors.  The sensors indirectly detect infrared radiation by its heating effect on the skin inside the pit. They can work out which part of the pit is hottest, and therefore the direction of the heat source, which could be a warm-blooded prey animal. By combining information from both pits, the snake can also estimate the distance of the object.

The [[vampire bat|common vampire bat]] Desmodus rotundus has specialized infrared sensors in its nose-leaf.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;L. Kürten, U. Schmidt, K. Schäfer (1984): [http://link.springer.com/article/10.1007%2FBF00396621 Warm and Cold Receptors in the Nose of the Vampire Bat, Desmodus rotundus]. Naturwissenschaften 71:327-28.&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;E. O. Gracheva, J. F. Codero-Morales, J. A. González-Carcaía, N. T. Ingolia, C. Manno, C. I. Aranguren, J. S. Weissman, D. Julius (2011). [http://www.nature.com/nature/journal/v476/n7358/full/nature10245.html Ganglion-specific splicing of TRPV1 underlies infrared sensation in vampire bats.] Nature 476:88-91.&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt; Vampire bats are the only mammals that feed exclusively on blood. The infrared sense enables Desmodus to localize homeothermic (warm-blooded) animals (cattle, horses, wild mammals) within an range of about 10 to 15&amp;amp;nbsp;cm. This [[Infrared sensing in vampire bats|infrared perception]] is possibly used in detecting regions of maximal blood flow on targeted prey.

Other animals with specialized heat detectors are forest fire seeking beetles (Melanophila acuminata), which lay their eggs in conifers freshly killed by forest fires. Darkly pigmented butterflies [[Pachliopta aristolochiae]] and Troides rhadamathus use specialized heat detectors to avoid damage while basking. The blood sucking [[Hemiptera|bugs]] [[Triatoma infestans]] may also have a specialised thermoception organ.

In humans, temperature sensation from [[thermoreceptor]]s enters the spinal cord along the axons of [[Lissauer&amp;apos;s tract]] that synapse on second order neurons in [[grey matter]] of the [[Posterior horn of spinal cord|dorsal horn]]. The axons of these second order neurons then [[decussation|decussate]], joining the [[spinothalamic tract]] as they ascend to neurons in the [[ventral posterolateral nucleus]] of the [[thalamus]].

== See also ==
* [[Infrared sensing in snakes]]
* [[Infrared sensing in vampire bats]]
* A. Campbell, R. R. Naik, L. Sowards, M. O. Stone (2002). Biological infrared imaging and sensing. Micron 33:211-225. [http://web.neurobio.arizona.edu/gronenberg/nrsc581/thermo/biologicalinfraredsenses.pdf pdf.]

== References ==
{{Reflist}}

{{Sensory_system}}

[[Category:Perception]]
[[Category:Sensory system]]
[[Category:Temperature]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
