<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Wikipedia:Articles for deletion/Procrasturbate"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Wikipedia:Articles for deletion/Procrasturbate" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;Article [[Procrasturbate]] listed on [[WP:VFD]] Apr 28 to May 4 2004, consensus was to delete.  Discussion:

Apparently a neologism; gets 33 google hits. In any event Wikipedia is not a (slang) dictionary. [[User:Maximus Rex|Maximus Rex]] 13:43, 28 Apr 2004 (UTC)
*Delete, until such a time as the term has significant implication in an event.  [[User:Falcon Kirtaran|Falcon]] 14:07, Apr 28, 2004 (UTC)
**If y&amp;apos;all decide to delete my page, that&amp;apos;s cool, but I have to question the reasoning here; what does it even mean &amp;quot;until such a time as the term has significant implication in an event&amp;quot;?  Why delete the article now and then potentially put it back later?; that&amp;apos;s a waste of effort (both mine now and someone else&amp;apos;s down the road).  If you think this topic will ever potentially merit an article in the future, then I don&amp;apos;t see the point of killing it now.  --[[User:Chinasaur|Chinasaur]] 21:53, May 5, 2004 (UTC)
*Delete, I considered VFDing this myself earlier but became .. distracted.  [[User:Topbanana|TB]] 14:11, 28 Apr 2004 (UTC)
*The main reason I made this page was to take the information off of [[List of portmanteaus]], where it was creating clutter.  If this page gets deleted, probably the best thing to do will be to take the word off the portmanteau list as well (as has been suggested a couple times anyway since I added it there).  One reason I think this page is worth having despite wikipedia not being a slang dictionary is that the different meanings that have been suggested are pretty diverse.  Seems to me, of all neologisms, this is one people are likely to try to look up.  [[User:Chinasaur|Chinasaur]] 16:49, Apr 28, 2004 (UTC)
*Delete. Maybe we need a Wikibook dictionary of slang and neologisms? [[User:Andrewa|Andrewa]] 19:16, 28 Apr 2004 (UTC)
**&amp;quot;Slang and neologisms&amp;quot; could be implemented as a separate language in Wiktionary. [[User:Fredrik|Fredrik]] 23:24, 28 Apr 2004 (UTC)
*I came in expecting this to be a dictionary definition stub. Instead it has an actual article all about the word. And a word I&amp;apos;ve actually seen before. Good work on writing an article on a verb! [[User:Wiwaxia|Wiwaxia]] 18:04, 30 Apr 2004 (UTC)

&amp;apos;&amp;apos;End discussion&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
