<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Queanbeyan East, New South Wales"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Queanbeyan East, New South Wales" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Refimprove|date=September 2007}}
{{Infobox Australian place| type = town
| name     = Queanbeyan East
| state    = nsw
| image    =
| caption  =
| latd  =35  |latm =20 |lats  =43
| longd =149 |longm =14 |longs =46
| pushpin_label_position = left
| pushpin_map_caption = Location in New South Wales
| postcode = 2620
| lga      = [[Queanbeyan City Council]]
| stategov = [[Electoral district of Monaro|Monaro]]
| fedgov   = [[Division of Eden-Monaro|Eden-Monaro]]
| est      =
| pop      =
}}

[[Image:East Queanbeyan facing westerly.jpg|thumb|right|Overlooking Queanbeyan East from the city&amp;apos;s edge]]
[[Image:Looking north east in Queanbeyan East from Gracelands Estate.jpg|thumb|right|Looking towards Wright Park in Queanbeyan East from Gracelands Estate]]

East Queanbeyan is one of [[Queanbeyan]]&amp;apos;s newly proclaimed suburbs, lying on the north eastern side of the [[Queanbeyan River]], with the river forming its western boundary.  The suburb is a mixed residential and industrial zone, incorporating Queanbeyan&amp;apos;s (and one of the region&amp;apos;s largest) manufacturing and general industrial hubs along the eastern length of Yass Road.

East Queanbeyan is predominantly residential however, featuring a mix of high density units and free standing homes.  In recent years a number of new mini housing estates have been completed (or are under construction), adding significantly to the population, and providing new housing stock.  Additionally a new high density residential complex has been completed adjacent to the Queanbeyan river.

The suburb contains a small general shopping strip, consisting of several major brand outlets.  Queanbeyan East Public School and Queanbeyan TAFE both reside in East Queanbeyan, as do a number of significant and popular playing grounds, including the city&amp;apos;s largest sports ground, [[Seiffert Oval]].  The suburb is notable for the number of playing grounds and general parkland within it.

Additionally, East Queanbeyan is home to a lawn bowls club, a number of restaurants, several motels, and borders the Queanbeyan Golf Club.

The Airport Motor Inn lies just inside the city, close by the railway line which forms the border with the [[Australian Capital Territory]].

==External references==
* [http://www.qcc.nsw.gov.au/page.aspx?page=4128 A map of Queanbeyan Suburbs courtesy of Queanbeyan City Council]

{{LGAs Southern Tablelands}}

[[Category:Queanbeyan]]
[[Category:New South Wales geography stubs]]


{{NewSouthWales-geo-stub}}&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
