<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Zebah and Zalmunna"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Zebah and Zalmunna" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{no footnotes|date=January 2013}}
&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Zebah&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (man-killer or sacrifice) and &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Zalmunna&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; were the two kings who led the vast host of the [[Midian]]ites who invaded the [[land of Israel]], and over
whom [[Gideon]] gained a great and decisive victory ([[Book of Judges|Judges]] 8). Zebah and Zalmunna had succeeded in escaping across the [[Jordan River]] with a remnant of the Midianite host, but were overtaken at Karkor, probably in the [[Hauran]], and routed by [[Gideon]]. The kings were taken alive and brought back across the Jordan; and confessing that they had personally taken part in the killing of Gideon&amp;apos;s brothers, they were put to death (compare [[Books of Samuel|1 Samuel]] 12:11; [[Book of Isaiah|Isaiah]] 10:26; [[Psalms]] 83:11).


Judges 8:18-26

18Then said he unto Zebah and Zalmunna, What manner of men were they whom ye slew at Tabor? And they answered, As thou art, so were they; each one resembled the children of a king.

19And he said, They were my brethren, even the sons of my mother: as the LORD liveth, if ye had saved them alive, I would not slay you.

20And he said unto Jether his firstborn, Up, and slay them. But the youth drew not his sword: for he feared, because he was yet a youth.

21Then Zebah and Zalmunna said, Rise thou, and fall upon us: for as the man is, so is his strength. And Gideon arose, and slew Zebah and Zalmunna, and took away the ornaments that were on their camels&amp;apos; necks.

22Then the men of Israel said unto Gideon, Rule thou over us, both thou, and thy son, and thy son&amp;apos;s son also: for thou hast delivered us from the hand of Midian.

23And Gideon said unto them, I will not rule over you, neither shall my son rule over you: the LORD shall rule over you.

24And Gideon said unto them, I would desire a request of you, that ye would give me every man the earrings of his prey. (For they had golden earrings, because they were Ishmaelites.)

25And they answered, We will willingly give them. And they spread a garment, and did cast therein every man the earrings of his prey.

26And the weight of the golden earrings that he requested was a thousand and seven hundred shekels of gold; beside ornaments, and collars, and purple raiment that was on the kings of Midian, and beside the chains that were about their camels&amp;apos; necks. (King James Version)


{{eastons}}
[[Category:Midian]]
[[Category:Monarchs of the Hebrew Bible]]
[[Category:Articles about multiple people]]

{{Tanakh-stub}}&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
