<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Villedieu-les-Poêles"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Villedieu-les-Poêles" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Infobox French commune
|name               = Villedieu-les-Poêles
|image              = Villedieu01.jpg
|region             = [[Basse-Normandie]]
|department         = [[Manche]]
|arrondissement     = Saint-Lô
|canton             = Villedieu-les-Poêles
|INSEE              = 50639
|postal code        = 50800
|mayor              =
|term               =
|intercommunality   =
|longitude          = -1.2211
|latitude           = 48.8392
|elevation m        =
|elevation min m    =
|elevation max m    = 105
|area km2           = 8.05
|population         = 3920
|population date    = 2006
}}

&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Villedieu-les-Poêles&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is a [[Communes of France|commune]] in the [[Manche]] [[Departments of France|department]] in [[Normandy]] in north-western [[France]].

Its inhabitants are called &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Sourdins&amp;apos;&amp;apos; from the French &amp;apos;&amp;apos;sourd&amp;apos;&amp;apos; meaning [[deaf]]. Most of the people involved in the manufacturing of copper pans, which involved repeated hammering, became deaf.

==Geography==
[[Pont-Farcy]] lies to the east, [[Saint-Lô]] to the north, [[Vire]] to the South-East and [[Granville, Manche|Granville]] to the west.

==Economy==
It is traditionally a centre of metal-work, especially the [[brass]] and [[copper]] pans and basins from which the &amp;apos;&amp;apos;poêles&amp;apos;&amp;apos; in its name derives. It is also famous for its artisanal manufacture of large church bells, which was started by immigrants from [[Lorraine (province)|Lorraine]] around 1780.

In addition to metal-work, current industries are a [[slaughterhouse]] and a cheese factory.  Tourism now plays a large part in the local economy. Villedieu also provides services for the surrounding countryside, such as a hospital and a retirement home.

==History==
Villedieu owes its name to the religious order [[Knights Hospitaller]], that later became the Knights of Malta. [[Henry I of England|Henry I]], King of England and Duke of Normandy, granted Villedieu to this order in the 12th century. Low taxes and good administration attracted people to Villedieu. Advanced coppersmithing technology was presumably imported from the Middle East by the Knights. By the early 14th century, the Corporation of the Coppersmiths of Villedieu was officially recognized by the Kings of France.

In the years following the [[French Revolution]], in the late 18th century, the people of Villedieu were strong supporters of the Revolution, unlike most of people in the surrounding area. A major reason of their support is that the Revolution abolished customs duties between French regions; before the Revolution, copper pans exported from Villedieu to [[Brittany]], {{convert|50|km|mi|abbr=on}} away, faced higher import duties than copper pans from [[Portugal]]  After a losing battle with [[Chouan]] troops, the men from Villedieu escaped thanks to their women who threw stones, flowerpots and chamber pots from second-story windows at the pursuing Chouans. The general heading the Chouan troops was getting ready to bombard Villedieu and set it on fire. A delegation of women negotiated with him: the inhabitants were given a short time to hide their valuables and the Chouan soldiers then plundered the town for food and clothing.

In 1944, when the Germans withdrew from Villedieu, they left a sniper who shot some of the first US soldiers to enter Villedieu, before being neutralized.  The US commander was about to request airplane bombing runs when the mayor approached him, told him that there were no Germans left in Villedieu and offered to ride through Villedieu in the front seat of a US jeep.  Villedieu was thus one of the few towns in the region to escape major destruction.

===Heraldry===
{{Blazon-arms
|img1=Blason_Villedieu-les-Poêles_50.svg
|legend1=Arms of Villedieu-les-Poêles
|text=The arms of Villedieu-les-Poêles are [[blazon]]ed :&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Per pale 1: Argent, a cross couped gules; and 2: Or, 18 billets sable 4,5,4,3,2, and on a chief azure, a cross couped argent.&amp;apos;&amp;apos;

}}

==See also==
*[[Communes of the Manche department]]

{{Commons category|Villedieu-les-Poêles}}
{{Manche communes}}

{{DEFAULTSORT:Villedieu-Les-Poeles}}
[[Category:Communes of Manche|Villedieulespoeles]]

{{Manche-geo-stub}}&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
