<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Glymur"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Glymur" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Infobox waterfall
| name = Glymur
| photo = glymur.jpg
| photo_caption = Waterfall Glymur
| location = Iceland
| type = Horsetail
| height = {{Convert|198|m|ft|0|abbr=on}}
| number_drops = 1
| flow =
| coords = {{coord|64|23|45|N|21|14|28|W}}
}}
The [[waterfall]] &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Glymur&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, with a cascade of 196 m, is the highest waterfall of [[Iceland]].

It is situated at the rear end of the [[Hvalfjörður]]. Since the opening of [[Hvalfjörður Tunnel|the tunnel]] under this [[fjord]], most people bypass the area. However, it is a very beautiful part of the country with [[volcano]]es and tree plantations.

The river Botnsá leaves the lake [[Hvalvatn]] and after a short distance the water falls down alongside the volcano &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Hvalfell&amp;apos;&amp;apos; into a canyon with green moss. The waterfall can be accessed from Botnsá, a small village of summerhouses named after the river.  From the Botnsá parking area, one can hike up part of the mountain (350 m) on marked hiking paths. To get a better view of the waterfall it is necessary to see it from the south side of the river Botnsá, however the south side trail is strenuous and potentially hazardous, passing along the edges of steep dropoffs.

From the parking area, both trails begin by passing through a gate and walking up a dirt road.  The easier north side trail continues up the dirt road and is marked by rocks blazed with yellow paint.  A few hundred meters up the road, the south side trail (also marked by yellow rocks) branches off to the right.  This drops over a small cliff face and descends through a cave down to the river.  In the summer there is a small pole over the river with an adjacent cable for a handhold, where travelers can cross to the southern side.

After crossing the river, the south trail climbs steeply with various muddy, rocky and loose areas.  At times it skirts steep dropoffs.  About 3/4 way up this trail passes a small side waterfall with a sheltered pool.  Hikers often stop here to refresh themselves; this point is a milestone only a short distance below the viewing area.  Anyone attempting this trail should have proper boots, water, and preferably hiking poles though many people hike without poles.  The south trail is a strenuous but non-technical climb rather than a mere walk.

It is also possible to reach the base of the falls, but only by wading through the Botnsá.  There are strong winds and serious risks of rockfall in the narrow canyon bottom.

==See also==
* [[List of waterfalls]]
* [[Waterfalls of Iceland]]

==External links==
*[http://www.nat.is/travelguideeng/plofin_glymur_waterfall.htm  Informations]
*[http://eik.klaki.net/haf/02sept14/20020914_141120.jpg  Photo]
*[http://site.voila.fr/gonguferdir/glymur.html  Photos]

{{Iceland-geo-stub}}

{{Waterfalls of Iceland}}&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
