<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Herbs in Polish mythology"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Herbs in Polish mythology" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Unreferenced|date=August 2009}}
&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Herbs&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; are used in Polish folk customs. Do not use these herbs in any of the methods shown here without the approval of a qualified physician.

==Belladonna==
{{Main|Atropa belladonna}}
This plant is found chiefly in the [[Carpathian Mountains|Carpathian]] region of [[Poland]], and was listed as an ingredient in old flying ointment recipes. This led to the belief that it has always been associated with witches and evil. This plant is a hallucinogenic and very deadly.

==Bellflower==
{{Main|Campanula trachelium}}
Children suffering from [[Tuberculosis|consumption]] were bathed in this herb; and the results of skin darkening was used to divine whether they lived or would die. If the skin darkened, they would survive. If the skin stayed pale and sickly, the child would die.

==Birch==
{{Main|Birch}}
A harbinger of spring, and it is said to bring good fortune and protect against witches and the evil eye.

==Burnette Saxifrage==
{{Main|Burnette Saxifrage}}
A herb that in folklore is said to protect one from death by eating or drinking it.

==Juniper==
{{Main|Juniper}}
On the Holy Day of [[Dyngusy]], branches were used to playfully whip blessings onto each other.

==Lady&amp;apos;s Mantle==
{{Main|Lady&amp;apos;s Mantle}}
This herb would disperse storm clouds when thrown into a fire or hung in a window.

==Linden Tree==
{{Main|Tilia}}
Offering protection against evil spirits and lightning, the linden tree was commonly planted in front of houses to keep evil from entering. It was also a place to leave offerings and to hold folk rituals. The Blessed Mother is said to hiding in the tree, and since lightning didn&amp;apos;t strike it - it also became a symbol of luck. It is also a symbol of family, faith, and the good life.

==Meliot==
{{Main|Meliot}}
Meliot was used as incense for protection to those who had been given the evil eye. May wine was flavored with this herb.

==Mint==
{{Main|Mentha}}
Thought of as a Universal healing herb, the most common use was for aid of digestion.

==White Bryony==
{{Main|White Bryony}}
This herb was fenced in when it was found on property to protect it; the leaves resemble a child, and digging it up would destroy their own happiness. It is said that the stems and leaves from this plant were used in spells and incantations.

See also [[Polish mythology]]

{{DEFAULTSORT:Herbs In Polish Mythology}}
[[Category:Slavic mythology]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
