<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Zarf"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Zarf" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Other uses}}

A &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Zarf&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (plural: zarfs or zuruuf) is a holder, usually of ornamental metal, for a coffee cup without a handle ([[demitasse]] or [[fincan]]).&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;{{cite news|publisher=[[The Atlanta Journal-Constitution]]|date=February 7, 2009|title=Obituaries: Deborah Sapot, 69, whiz at Scrabble|author=Mark Davis|quote=His mother, said Ian Sapot, didn&amp;apos;t like losing. And she never did --- not in her family. Not with words such as: Zarf: A metal thing used to hold hot cups of coffee. It&amp;apos;s worth 16 points.}}&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

==History==
Although [[coffee]] was probably discovered in [[Ethiopia]], it was in [[Turkey]] at around the thirteenth century that it became popular as a beverage.  As with the [[Tea#Tea culture|serving of tea]] in [[China]] and [[Japan]], the serving of coffee in Turkey was a complex, [[ritual]]ized process.  It was served in small cups without handles (known as &amp;apos;&amp;apos;fincan&amp;apos;&amp;apos;), which were placed in holders known as &amp;apos;&amp;apos;zarf&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (from the [[Arabic language|Arabic]] word ظرف &amp;apos;&amp;apos;ẓarf&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, meaning container, envelope) to protect the cup and also the fingers of the drinker from the hot liquid. Cups were typically made of [[porcelain]], but also of glass and wood. However, because it was the holder that was more visible, it was typically more heavily ornamented.

==Styles==
The zarf was often made from metal, with [[silver]], [[gold]], [[copper]], and [[brass]] being the most common materials used.  Others were also made of woods such as [[coconut]], [[ebony]] or other hardwoods, or of [[ivory]], [[bone]], [[horn (anatomy)|horn]], or [[tortoise]]shell.

Metal zarfs were sometimes filigree work, sometimes decorated with [[chasing (metalworking)|chasing]], [[niello]], [[engraving]], or set with gems or other precious stones.

Wooden zarfs, very few of which remain, were favored because of the natural aroma of the wood from which they were fashioned.  They were very fragile.

Tortoiseshell, horn and ivory zarfs required special skill to make.  In the first two cases, sheets of the material in question were softened in hot water and then clamped in a [[Molding (process)|mold]] to create the required shape.  Ivory was carved in the same way as wood; however, its greater value meant that more care was needed to avoid mistakes.

The [[United States Navy]] also has an item, usually made in the on-base metal shops, that is bolted to bulkheads and consoles to hold coffee cups. The Navy zarf is not ornamented.

Coffee in disposable cups is often served by fast-food restaurants in holders of stiff paper. These too are zarfs.

==See also==
*[[Podstakannik]]
*[[Coffee cup sleeve]]
*[[Cup holder]]

==References==
{{wiktionary}}
{{Reflist}}

[[Category:Drinkware]]
[[Category:Coffee preparation]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
