<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Somatic cell"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Somatic cell" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;A &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;somatic cell&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (Greek: σὠμα/soma = body) is any [[cell (biology)|biological cell]] forming the body of an organism; that is, in a [[multicellular organism]], any cell other than a [[gamete]], [[germ cell]], [[gametocyte]] or undifferentiated [[stem cell]].&amp;lt;ref name=&amp;quot;campbell229&amp;quot;&amp;gt;{{Cite book|
title=Biology|
last1=Campbell|
last2=Reece|
last3=Urry|
last4=Cain|
last5=Wasserman|
last6=Minorsky|
last7=Jackson|
first1=Neil A.|
first2=Jane B.|
first3=Lisa A.|
first4=Michael L.|
first5=Steven A.|
first6=Peter V.|
first7=Robert B.|
edition=9th|
isbn=978-0-8053-6844-4|
page=229|
year=2009}}&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;  By contrast, gametes are cells that fuse during [[sexual reproduction]], for organisms that reproduce sexually; [[Germ cells]] are cells that give rise to gametes; [[Stem cells]] are cells that can divide through mitosis and differentiate into diverse specialized cell types. For example, in [[mammal]]s, &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;somatic&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; cells make up all the internal organs, skin, bones, blood and connective tissue. By contrast, mammalian germ cells give rise to [[spermatozoa]] and [[ovum|ova]] which fuse during [[fertilization]] to produce a cell called a [[zygote]], which develops into an [[embryo]]. Somatic cells are [[diploid]].&amp;lt;ref name=&amp;quot;campbell229&amp;quot; /&amp;gt;

The word &amp;quot;somatic&amp;quot; is derived from the [[Greek language|Greek]] word &amp;apos;&amp;apos;sōma&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, meaning &amp;quot;body&amp;quot;.

==Genetics and chromosome content==
Like all cells, somatic cells contain [[DNA]] arranged in [[chromosome]]s.  If a somatic cell contains chromosomes arranged in pairs, it is called [[diploid]] and the organism is called a diploid organism. (The gametes of diploid organisms contain only single unpaired chromosomes and are called [[haploid]].)  Each pair of chromosomes comprises one chromosome inherited from the father and one inherited from the mother. For example, in humans, somatic cells contain 46 [[chromosomes]] organized into 23 pairs.  By contrast, gametes of diploid organisms contain only half as many chromosomes. In humans, this is 23 unpaired chromosomes. When two gametes (i.e. a spermatozoon and an ovum) meet during conception, they fuse together, creating a [[zygote]]. Due to the fusion of the two gametes, a human zygote contains 46 chromosomes (i.e. 23 pairs).

However, a large number of [[species]] have the chromosomes in their somatic cells arranged in fours (&amp;quot;[[tetraploid]]&amp;quot;) or even sixes (&amp;quot;[[hexaploid]]&amp;quot;). Thus, they can have diploid or even triploid germline cells. An example of this is the modern cultivated species of [[wheat]], &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Triticum aestivum L.&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, a hexaploid species whose somatic cells contain six copies of every [[chromatid]].

==Cloning==
In recent years, the technique of [[cloning]] whole organisms has been developed in mammals, allowing almost identical genetic clones of an animal to be produced. One method of doing this is called &amp;quot;[[somatic cell nuclear transfer]]&amp;quot; and involves removing the [[cell nucleus|nucleus]] from a somatic cell, usually a skin cell. This nucleus contains all of the genetic information needed to produce the organism it was removed from. This nucleus is then injected into an [[ovum]] of the same species which has had its own genetic material removed. The ovum now no longer needs to be fertilized, because it contains the correct amount of genetic material (a [[diploid]] number of [[chromosomes]]). In theory, the ovum can be implanted into the [[uterus]] of a same-species animal and allowed to develop. The resulting animal will be a nearly genetically identical clone to the animal from which the nucleus was taken. The only difference is caused by any [[mitochondria]]l DNA that is retained in the ovum, which is different than the cell that donated the nucleus.  In practice, this technique has so far been problematic, although there have been a few high profile successes, such as [[Dolly the Sheep]] and, more recently, [[Snuppy]], the first cloned [[dog]].

==References==
{{Reflist}}

==See also==
* [[Somatic cell count]]

{{DEFAULTSORT:Somatic Cell}}
[[Category:Cloning]]
[[Category:Cells]]
[[Category:Developmental biology]]
[[Category:Genetics]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
