<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Rawhide (material)"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Rawhide (material)" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Unreferenced|date=May 2007}}

&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Rawhide&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is a [[Hides|hide]] or animal skin that has not been exposed to [[tanning]]. It is similar to [[parchment]], much lighter in color than [[leather]] made by traditional vegetable tanning.

The skin from [[American Bison|buffalo]], [[deer]], [[elk]] or [[cattle]] from which most rawhide originates is prepared by removing all [[fur]], [[meat]] and [[fat]]. The hide is then usually stretched over a frame before being dried. The resulting material is hard and translucent. It can be shaped by rewetting and forming before being allowed to thoroughly re-dry. It can be rendered more pliable by &amp;apos;working&amp;apos;, i.e. bending repeatedly in multiple directions, often by rubbing it over a post, sometimes traditionally by chewing. It may also be oiled or greased for a degree of waterproofing.

==Uses==
It is often used for objects such as [[whip]]s, [[drumhead]]s or [[lampshade]]s, and more recently [[chew toy]]s for dogs. It is thought to be more durable than leather, especially in items suffering abrasion during use, and its hardness and shapability render it more suitable than leather for some items. For example, rawhide is often used to cover saddle trees, which make up the foundation of a western [[saddle]], while wet: it strengthens the wooden tree by drawing up very tight as it dries, and resists the abrasion regularly encountered during stock work or rodeo sports.  It can also be used as a backing on a wooden bow.  Such a backing prevents the bow from breaking by taking a share of the tension stress.  Bows made from weaker woods such as birch or cherry benefit more from a rawhide backing.  Rawhide is, however, more susceptible to water than leather, and will quickly soften and stretch if left wet unless well waterproofed. It is quite effective when used for training dogs and also satisfies their natural desire for meat.{{Citation needed|date=March 2009}} Some veterinarians discourage the giving of rawhide to dogs due to the animals&amp;apos; theoretical inability to digest the rawhide properly and its tendency to swell in the stomach; this is much less of a problem in dogs that bite off smaller pieces and do not try to swallow the rawhide whole.

Wet rawhide has been used by some earlier cultures as a means of [[torture]] or [[execution]], gradually biting into or squeezing the flesh of body parts it encloses as it dries. An example is [[Boot (torture)#Spanish boot|buskin]].  On the other hand, it has also been used in the context of [[medicine]] by [[First Nations]] peoples, such as the [[Sioux Nation]]: wet rawhide would be wrapped around a long bone [[fracture]] and it would dry, slowly setting the bone{{citation needed|date=December 2012}} — the rawhide worked exactly as a plaster cast does today.

&amp;quot;Rawhide&amp;quot; laces often sold for boots or baseball gloves are made of normal tanned leather rather than actual rawhide. Rawhide is not pliable when dry and would be unsuitable for this use.

{{leather}}

[[Category:Hides]]


{{textile-stub}}

[[de:Rohleder]]
[[ru:Сыромятная кожа]]
[[sv:Skinn]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
