<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="United New Zealand"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="United New Zealand" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{about|the party founded in 1995|the party founded in 1927|United Party (New Zealand)}}

{{Unreferenced|date=November 2009}}
&amp;lt;div style=&amp;quot;float:right; width:185px; text-align:center&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
[[image:UnitedNewZealandLogo.png]]
&amp;lt;small&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;United New Zealand logo&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;
&amp;lt;/small&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;

&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;United New Zealand&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; was a [[centrism|centrist]] [[political party]] in [[New Zealand]] founded in 1995. It merged with the Christian-based [[Future New Zealand]] party to form the [[United Future|United Future New Zealand]] party in 2000.

==History==
United was founded in the middle of 1995, one of a number of new parties hoping to capitalize on the upcoming switch to the [[Mixed member proportional representation|MMP]] electoral system. It was intended to be a liberal centrist party, encompassing moderate voters from both the centre-left and the centre-right. The party was established by four MPs from the [[New Zealand National Party|National Party]], two MPs from the [[New Zealand Labour Party|Labour Party]], and former Labour MP [[Peter Dunne]], who had already established his own party, [[Future New Zealand (Dunne)|Future New Zealand]] (not to be confused with the Christian-based [[Future New Zealand|party of the same name]] which United later merged with). The party was led by [[Clive Matthewson]], a former Labour MP.

[[File:ChristianPoliticsNZ.png|right|400px]]
The MPs who established United were:
*[[Margaret Austin]] (Labour)
*[[Bruce Cliffe]] (National)
*[[Peter Dunne]] (Future New Zealand, originally Labour)
*[[Clive Matthewson]] (Labour)
*[[Pauline Gardiner]] (National)
*[[Peter Hilt]] (National)
*[[John Robertson (New Zealand politician)|John Robertson]] (National)

The party, while initially attracting interest, performed poorly in the 1996 election. The party&amp;apos;s policies were centrist and liberal in nature but to many appeared too bland to attract media profile. In addition, Matthewson, while charismatic, was seen by many as an intellectual light-weight. Bruce Cliffe had indicated he would resign from Parliament in 1996. Peter Dunne was the only United MP to retain his seat, with all others  being ejected from Parliament. Clive Matthewson, whose seat had been abolished in the change to MMP, placed fourth in his new electorate.

As the party&amp;apos;s only surviving MP, Peter Dunne became leader of United. When United entered into a coalition with the governing National Party in 1996, securing a [[New Zealand Cabinet|Cabinet]] post for Peter Dunne, many commentators claimed that the party had abandoned its centrist stance. United claimed that a deal with National would allow United to moderate National&amp;apos;s more extreme right-wing tendencies and that such arrangements would become common practice under the new MMP system.

In the [[New Zealand general election, 1999|1999 election]], United&amp;apos;s share of the vote declined even further, with swinging voters shifting to Labour to oust the [[Jenny Shipley|Shipley]] government. However, Peter Dunne managed to retain his electorate seat thereby preserving United&amp;apos;s parliamentary representation.

United merged with a social conservative, evangelical Christian-based party [[Future New Zealand]] (not to be confused with Peter Dunne&amp;apos;s party before United was formed) in 2000. Future New Zealand, formerly the [[Christian Democrat Party (New Zealand)|Christian Democrats]], was not represented in parliament. The merged party adopted the name [[United Future New Zealand]], and established a caucus that has extended from seven (47th New Zealand Parliament, 2002–2005) to three (48th New Zealand Parliament, 2005–2007) down to two members (48th New Zealand Parliament, May 2007 – 2008) with the departure of [[Gordon Copeland]]. Of these caucuses, Dunne remained the only constituency MP, while his caucus was formed from United Future&amp;apos;s MMP party list, and consisted of MPs who are progressive on social justice issues but conservative on some moral issues.

{{Historic New Zealand political parties}}
{{United Future NZ}}

[[Category:United New Zealand| ]]
[[Category:Political parties in New Zealand|United Party]]
[[Category:Political parties established in 1995]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
