<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Breed"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Breed" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Other uses}}

A &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;breed&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is a specific group of domestic animals or plants having [[wikt:homogeneous|homogeneous]] appearance, [[wikt:homogeneous|homogeneous]] [[behavior]], and other characteristics that distinguish it from other animals or plants of the same [[species]] and that were arrived at through [[selective breeding]]. Despite the centrality of the idea of &amp;quot;breeds&amp;quot; to animal husbandry, no scientifically accepted definition of the term exists.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;The state of the world&amp;apos;s animal genetic resources for food and agriculture. Barbara Rischkowsky and Dafydd Pilling. Commission on Genetic Resources for Food and Agriculture. 2007&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;  A breed is therefore not an objective or biologically verifiable classification but is instead a term of art amongst groups of breeders who share a consensus around what qualities make some members of a given species members of a nameable subset.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;The Genetics of Populations. Jay L Lush. Iowa State University Press. 1994&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt; The term is distinguished from &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[landrace]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, which refers to a naturally occurring regional variety of domestic (and sometimes [[feral]]) animal through uncontrolled breeding.

When bred together, animals of the same breed pass on these predictable traits to their offspring, and this ability&amp;amp;mdash;known as &amp;quot;[[breeding true]]&amp;quot;&amp;amp;mdash;is a  requirement for a breed. [[Plant]] breeds are more commonly known as [[cultivar]]s. The offspring produced as a result of breeding animals of one breed with other animals of another breed are known as [[crossbreed]]s or mixed breeds. Crosses between animal or plant variants above the level of breed/cultivar (species, [[subspecies]], [[Variety (botany)|botanical &amp;apos;&amp;apos;variety&amp;apos;&amp;apos;]], even different [[Genus|genera]]) are referred to as &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Hybrid (biology)|hybrids]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos;.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;Banga, Surinder S. (November 25, 1998).  &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Hybrid Cultivar Development&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, p. 119.  Springer-Verlag. ISBN 3-540-63523-8 &amp;lt;!--This is cited only for the fact that plant crosses above the cultivar level are called hybrids; doesn&amp;apos;t address animals.--&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

==Animal breeds==
{{main article|Animal breeding}}

===Breeders===
The [[breeder]] or breeders who initially establish a breed, do so by [[Selective breeding|selecting]] individual animals from within the groups [[gene pool]] that they see as having the necessary qualities needed to enhance the breed model they are aiming for. These animals are referred to as “breed foundation”, or “breed origination”. Further, the breeder mates the most desirable from his point of view representatives, aiming  to pass such characteristics to their [[Offspring|progeny]]. This process is known as [[selective breeding]]. A written description of desirable and undesirable breed representatives is referred to as a [[breed standard]].

===Breed characteristics===
Breed specific characteristics also known as breed traits are inherited, and [[purebred]] animals pass such traits from [[generation]] to generation. Thus, all specimens of the same breed carry several genetic characteristics of the original foundation animal(s). In order to maintain the breed, a breeder would select those animals with the most desirable traits, to achieve further maintenance and developing of such traits. At the same time, avoiding animals carrying characteristics, not typical and/or undesirable for the breed, known as faults or [[genetics|genetic]] defects. The [[population]] within the same breed consists of a sufficient number of animals to maintain the breed within the specified parameters without the necessity of forced [[inbreeding]]. The breed includes several bloodlines that can be interbred to sustain the breed in whole without weakening the gene pool.

Domestic animal breeds commonly differ from country to country, and from nation to nation. Breeds originating in a certain country are known as &amp;quot;native breeds&amp;quot; of that country.

===Domestic animal breeds===

{|
|align=&amp;quot;left&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;275px&amp;quot; valign=&amp;quot;top&amp;quot;|
; Mammals
*[[List of dog breeds]]
*[[List of cat breeds]]
*[[List of horse breeds]]
*[[List of rabbit breeds]]
*[[List of sheep breeds]]
*[[List of goat breeds]]
*[[List of cattle breeds]]
*[[List of domestic pig breeds]]
*[[List of guinea pig breeds]]
*[[List of domestic Asian water buffalo breeds]]
|align=&amp;quot;left&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;275px&amp;quot; valign=&amp;quot;top&amp;quot;|
;Birds
*[[List of chicken breeds]]
*[[List of pigeon breeds]]
*[[List of goose breeds]]
*[[List of duck breeds]]
*[[List of turkey breeds]]
|}

==See also==
* [[Cultivar]]
* [[Landrace]]
* [[Purebred]]
* [[Race (biology)]]
* [[Selective breeding]]
* [[Subspecies]]
* [[Plant variety (disambiguation)]]

==References==
{{Reflist}}

{{Breed}}

[[Category:Domesticated animals]]
[[Category:Breeding| ]]
[[Category:Zoological nomenclature]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
