<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Infanticide Act"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Infanticide Act" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;The &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Infanticide Act&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is the name of two Acts introduced into [[English Law]] that started treating  killing of an infant child by its mother during the early months of life as a lesser crime than murder. The [[Infanticide Act (Northern Ireland) 1939]] makes similar arrangements for Northern Ireland.

==England and Wales==
&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;The Infanticide Act 1922&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;: effectively abolished the death penalty for a woman who deliberately killed her new born child while the balance of her mind was disturbed as a result of giving birth, by providing a partial defence to [[murder in English law|murder]].  The sentence that applies (as in other partial defences to murder) is the same as that for [[manslaughter in English law|manslaughter]]. This Act was repealed by section 2(3) of the Infanticide Act 1938.

The [[Infanticide Act 1938]]: extended this defence to cases where &amp;quot;at the time of the act or omission the balance of her mind was disturbed by reason of her not having fully recovered from the effect of giving birth to the child or by reason of the effect of lactation consequent upon the birth of the child.&amp;quot;&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;[http://hansard.millbanksystems.com/lords/1938/mar/22/infanticide-bill-hl Infanticide Act, 1938, Second Reading], House of Lords Hansard.  22 March 1938&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

Before the partial murder defence of [[diminished responsibility in English law|diminished responsibility]] was introduced to [[English law]] in the [[Homicide Act 1957]], this provided an important means of selecting a more lenient  sentence for a mother found guilty of killing her infant than the [[Life sentence#Interpretation in Europe|mandatory life sentence]] or [[Capital punishment in the United Kingdom|death sentence]] applying to murder at the time.

In recent years, it has become very rare for a mother who kills her infant child to receive a custodial sentence, except in very exceptional circumstances.{{Citation needed|date=July 2010}}

In a report the terms of which were agreed on 1 November 2006, the Law Commission recognized the difficulties facing the court when the defendant was in denial and would not accept that she had killed her child and unwilling to submit to a psychiatric examination where she perceived that  the purpose of the examination was to prove that she did kill her child when she is in denial of committing the act in the first place.  In such cases the mother is unlikely to have any other defence and will probably be convicted of murder.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;The [[Law Commission (England and Wales)|Law Commission]]. Murder, Manslaughter and Infanticide. Law Com 304. HC 30. TSO. London. 28 November 2006. Paragraph 1.51 at page 13. See also Consultation Paper No 177. Paragraphs 9.97 et seq.&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

==See also==
[[List of short titles]]
==References==
&amp;lt;references/&amp;gt;


[[Category:Infanticide]]
[[Category:British laws]]
[[Category:English criminal law]]
[[Category:Acts of the Parliament of the United Kingdom]]
[[Category:United Kingdom Acts of Parliament 1922]]
[[Category:United Kingdom Acts of Parliament 1938]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
