<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Jeff Chandler (boxer)"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Jeff Chandler (boxer)" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{No footnotes|date=March 2011}}
&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;quot;Joltin&amp;apos;&amp;quot; Jeff Chandler&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (born September 3, 1956 in [[Philadelphia, Pennsylvania]]) is a former [[Boxing|boxer]].  Chandler reigned as the [[World Boxing Association|WBA]] Bantamweight Champion from November 1980 to April 1984.

The 5&amp;apos;7&amp;quot; (67&amp;amp;nbsp;inches - 1.70 metres) tall Philadelphian began his professional career with a four-round draw in 1976 after only two amateur bouts.  Chandler then began a four-year string of victories culminating in a challenge for the WBA 118-pound championship held by [[Julian Solís]].  On November 14, 1980 Chandler won the title by a fourteenth-round [[knockout]] in [[Miami, Florida|Miami]], becoming the first American fighter to hold the bantamweight crown in over 30 years.

Chandler&amp;apos;s first defence was against former champion [[Jorge Luján]], winning on points in fifteen rounds.  He then travelled to Japan to face [[Asia]]n champion [[Eljiro Murata]], and although he was almost floored in the early rounds, Chandler came back to hold his title with a draw. Many ringside observers felt Chandler deserved a clear points victory. With his status in the boxing world rising, Chandler followed this up with a repeat victory over Solis, this time in seven rounds. Chandler finished 1981 against Murata, earning a thirteenth-round knockout rematch win.

In March 1982, Chandler faced the only opponent who ever defeated him as an amateur, fellow Philadelphian [[Johnny Carter]]{{Disambiguation needed|date=June 2011}}. The tables were turned this time as he scored a sixth round knockout on national television. Soon after, Chandler was sidelined by an injury sustained in a street-fight. During a traffic altercation in Philadelphia, he was stabbed on the right shoulder with a broken bottle, leaving a distinctive circular scar, but doing no permanent damage.

In 1983, Chandler ventured into the [[Super bantamweight]] ranks, winning a ten-round decision over [[Hector Cortez]]. He then faced tough [[Los Angeles, California|Angelino]] [[Oscar Muniz]] in another non-title bout. Muniz took the fight to Chandler, winning narrowly on points over ten rounds, Chandler&amp;apos;s first defeat in the professional ranks. He defended once more against Murata (another knockout, in the tenth round), then faced Muniz again, this time with the title on the line. A severe cut over Muniz&amp;apos;s eye brought a stoppage in the seventh round, enabling Chandler to retain his belt.

On April 7, 1984, Chandler faced the undefeated contender [[Richie Sandoval]]. This time his skills were not enough to stop an eager young foe. Sandoval took the title with a fifteenth-round knockout.  This turned out to be Chandler&amp;apos;s last fight. He elected to have surgery on cataracts that had been diagnosed the year before. Rather than risk blindness, Chandler retired from boxing.

He finished his career with a record of 33 wins, 2 losses and 2 draws. Jeff Chandler provided boxing fans with many memorable performances. In 2000, he was elected to the [[International Boxing Hall of Fame]] at [[Canastota, New York]].

{{S-start}}
{{succession box|
 before= [[Julian Solís]]|
 title= [[WBA Bantamweight Champion]]|
 after= [[Richie Sandoval]]|
 years= November 14, 1980 &amp;amp;ndash; April 7, 1984
}}
{{S-end}}

==External links==
*[http://members.tripod.com/~bxhof/chandler.html Chandler biography and highlights]
* [http://www.ibhof.com/chandler.htm IBHOF Bio]
* {{boxrec|id=44766|name=Jeff Chandler}}
{{Use mdy dates|date=November 2011}}

{{Persondata &amp;lt;!-- Metadata: see [[Wikipedia:Persondata]]. --&amp;gt;
| NAME              = Chandler, Jeff
| ALTERNATIVE NAMES =
| SHORT DESCRIPTION = American boxer
| DATE OF BIRTH     = September 3, 1956
| PLACE OF BIRTH    =
| DATE OF DEATH     =
| PLACE OF DEATH    =
}}
{{DEFAULTSORT:Chandler, Jeff}}
[[Category:1956 births]]
[[Category:Living people]]
[[Category:Bantamweight boxers]]
[[Category:Sportspeople from Philadelphia, Pennsylvania]]
[[Category:World boxing champions]]
[[Category:World bantamweight boxing champions]]
[[Category:World Boxing Association champions]]
[[Category:Boxers from Pennsylvania]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
