<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Virginia Judge"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Virginia Judge" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Virginia Judge&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; b. [Cooma, New South Wales]), a former Australian politician, was a member of the [[New South Wales Legislative Assembly]] representing [[Electoral district of Strathfield|Strathfield]] for the [[Australian Labor Party]] from 2003 until [[New South Wales state election, 2011|2011]].

==Early life==
Judge was born in Cooma and educated in her early years in both Canberra, ACT and New Delhi, India. She later returned to Canberra for her secondary schooling. She received a [[Bachelor of Education]] from the [[Australian National University|Canberra School of Music]].&amp;lt;ref name=aw&amp;gt;{{cite web
  | title =Judge, Virginia
  | publisher =Australian Women
  | url =http://www.womenaustralia.info/biogs/AWE1863b.htm
  | accessdate = 2007-03-02 }}&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

Judge taught in primary and secondary schools in both [[Sydney]] and [[Canberra]]. She also worked as a volunteer abroad for the Overseas Service Bureau in [[Tonga]] and as a project officer for  small non-government organisation, &amp;apos;&amp;apos;The Australian Foundation for the Peoples of the South Pacific&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, delivering items such as humidicribs, toilets and ovens to Pacific islands such as [[Nauru]], the [[Solomon Islands]] and [[Fiji]].&amp;lt;ref name=aw/&amp;gt;

Judge returned to Sydney,and worked in real estate, qualifying for her real estate licence. She was also studying Law part-time at [[Macquarie University]] prior to her election to the Legislative Assembly.&amp;lt;ref name=aw/&amp;gt;

==Political career==
Judge was elected to [[Municipality of Strathfield|Strathfield Council]] in 1995 and served until 2004. She served as Mayor from 2000 to 2003 when she entered the NSW Parliament.

Judge was elected as member for Strathfield in 2003, representing Labor.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;{{cite web
  | title =Ms Virginia Judge, B.Ed. MP
  | work =Members of Parliament
  | publisher =[[Parliament of New South Wales]]
  | url =http://www.parliament.nsw.gov.au/Prod/Parlment/Members.nsf/d890a06557517cedca256e700008765e/1b9973c4fd6ddebaca256cfa0012c0c7
  | accessdate =  }}&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;  The seat was won with a 15% majority.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;{{cite web
  | title =Strathfield
  | work =2007 NSW Election Guide
  | publisher =[[Australian Broadcasting Corporation]]
  | url =http://www.abc.net.au/elections/nsw/2007/guide/stra.htm
  | accessdate = 2007-03-02 }}&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

In 2007, she was appointed as Parliamentary Secretary Assisting the Minister for Education and Training, Industrial Relations, and Minister Assisting the Minister for Finance. In 2008, she was then appointed Minister for Fair Trading, Minister for Citizenship and Minister Assisting the Premier on the Arts. Then in 2010 was appointed Minister for the Arts and held the portfolios until the 2011 election.

In July 2011, Judge became National Manager, Strategic Partnerships and Capital Works Program for the Children&amp;apos;s Medical Research Institute (CMRI) which is an independant medical research institute which commenced operations in 1958 as part of the Royal Alexandra Hospital for Children in Camperdown, Sydney. CMRI has a long history of medical discoveries and an equally long history in public fundraising, including Australia&amp;apos;s first ever telethon and establishment of the nationally recognised Jeans for Genes brand. Their vision is to deliver a world-class, paediatric institute benefitting Western Sydney, NSW and Australia.

In 2013, she also became a Board Member of the Riverside Theatres Parramatta and Board Member of Gallery 49 Marrickville.

==Notes==
{{reflist|2}}

== External links ==
*[http://www.parliament.nsw.gov.au/prod/parlment/hansart.nsf/V3Key/LA20030429040 Virginia Judge&amp;apos;s inaugural speech].


{{Persondata &amp;lt;!-- Metadata: see [[Wikipedia:Persondata]]. --&amp;gt;
| NAME              = Judge, Virginia
| ALTERNATIVE NAMES =
| SHORT DESCRIPTION = Australian politician
| DATE OF BIRTH     =
| PLACE OF BIRTH    =
| DATE OF DEATH     =
| PLACE OF DEATH    =
}}
{{DEFAULTSORT:Judge, Virginia}}
[[Category:Living people]]
[[Category:Members of the New South Wales Legislative Assembly]]
[[Category:Australian Labor Party politicians]]
[[Category:Women mayors of places in Australia]]
[[Category:University of Canberra alumni]]
[[Category:Keneally Cabinet]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
