<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Brazier"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Brazier" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{about|the container for fire}}
[[File:3238 - Athens - Casserole and brazier - Stoà of Attalus Museum - Photo by Giovanni Dall&amp;apos;Orto, Nov 9 2009.jpg|thumb|[[Ancient Greece|Ancient Greek]] brazier and [[casserole]], 6th/4th century BC, exhibited in the Ancient Agora Museum in [[Athens]], housed in the [[Stoa of Attalus]]]]
[[File:Brazier.JPG|right|thumb|Simple Brazier]]
[[File:NewFireBrazier.JPG|thumb|Brazier used for lighting the [[Paschal candle]] during [[Easter Vigil]].]]

A &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;brazier&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;{{pronunciation-needed}} is a container for [[fire]], generally taking the form of an upright standing or hanging metal bowl or box. Used for burning solid fuel, braziers principally provide heat and light, but may also be used for cooking and cultural rituals. Braziers have been recovered from many early [[archaeology|archaeological]] sites, for example the [[Nimrud brazier]] recently excavated by the [[Iraqi National Museum]], which dates back to at least 824 [[BCE]].&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;http://www.archaeological.org/pdfs/papers/J_Russell_recovery.pdf&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt; Charred [[cannabis]] seeds found in a brazier at a 3rd millennium BCE archaeological site in present day [[Romania]]{{Citation needed|date=April 2011}} indicate that braziers were used for cultural rituals, as well as for more mundane domestic purposes.

Braziers are mentioned in the [[Bible]]. The Hebrew word for brazier is of Egyptian origin, suggesting an invention imported from Egypt. The only reference to it in the Bible is in Jeremiah 36:22-23, where braziers heat the winter palace of King [[Jehoiakim]]. In some churches a brazier is used to create a small fire, called new fire, which is then used to light the [[Paschal candle]] during the [[Easter Vigil]].

The Roman Emperor Jovian was poisoned by the fumes from a brazier in his tent in [[Common Era|CE]] 364, ending the line of Constantine. But despite the risks associated with burning [[charcoal]] on open fires, braziers were widely adopted as a source of domestic heat, particularly in the Spanish-speaking world. [[Fernando de Alva Cortés Ixtlilxochitl]] notes that the [[Tepanec]] [[Tlatoani]] in New Spain slept between two braziers because he was so old he produced no natural heat. In many areas they used to be considered healthier than fireplaces and chimneys,&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;[[Parish, Sir Woodbine]]. 1839. Buenos Ayres and the Provinces of the Rio de La Plata; Their Present State, Trade and Debt. John Murray.,&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;&amp;lt;ref name=&amp;quot;FordRichard&amp;quot;&amp;gt;[[Ford, Richard]]. 1845. A Handbook for Travellers in Spain. John Murray.&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt; and continued to be one of the primary means of heating houses in Spain until the early 20th century. [[Gerald Brenan]]&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;[[Brenan, Gerald]]. 1957. South from Granada. Hamish Hamilton.&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt; described the widespread habit in Spain in the 1920s of placing a brazier beneath a cloth-covered table to keep the legs and feet of the family warm on winter evenings.

When burned moist, rose and grapevine trimmings produce a pungent, sweet-smelling smoke, and make very good charcoal. When the charcoal fumes became overbearing, however, aromatics (lavender seeds, orange peel) were sometimes added to the embers in the brazier.&amp;lt;ref name=&amp;quot;FordRichard&amp;quot; /&amp;gt; A brazier used exclusively for burning aromatics ([[incense]]) is known as a [[censer]] or [[thurible]].

Braziers used to be a commonplace sight on industrial picket lines, although as strikes in the UK have become increasingly [[white-collar worker|white collar]], they are seen less and less.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;http://www.guardian.co.uk/Columnists/Column/0,5673,849402,00.html&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

In Japanese, a brazier is called a &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[hibachi]],&amp;apos;&amp;apos;. They are used principally for cooking and in cultural rituals such as the [[Japanese tea ceremony]].

==See also==
*[[Angithi]], a traditional Indian brazier
* [[Hibachi]], a Japanese brazier
* [[Torch]]

==References==
{{Reflist}}

{{Wiktionary}}
{{Commons category|Braziers (containers)}}

[[Category:Fireplaces]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
