<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Hervanta"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Hervanta" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;[[Image:Hervanta1.jpg|thumb|256px|Residential tower blocks in Hervanta]]
[[Image:Hervanta4.jpg|thumb|right|240px|Community center complex by [[Reima Pietilä]] ]]

&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Hervanta&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is a large suburb, or satellite city, of [[Tampere]] in [[Finland]], located next to [[Hallila]] some 10 km south of the city centre.

Home to a population of over 26,000, Hervanta is best known for its [[prefabricated]] [[block of flats|blocks of flats]]. The total number of apartments is about 11,000. Nearly a fifth of the inhabitants (some 4,500 people) are students, many of them enrolled at the [[Tampere University of Technology]] (TUT) or the [[Police College of Finland|Police College]]. The largest student housing complex is [[Mikontalo]], in fact nearly 3% of people in Hervanta reside there. Almost 8% of Hervanta&amp;apos;s population is composed of foreigners from 75 different nationalities.

Hervanta currently covers an area of 13.8&amp;amp;nbsp;km² and is continuing to grow. It was selected as Finland&amp;apos;s top suburb in a survey conducted by the [[Helsingin Sanomat]] newspaper and published on 17 August 2003.

The complex of commercial buildings in the town center of Hervanta was designed by the Finnish architect [[Reima Pietilä]].

==Technology==

Hervanta is sometimes called the [[Silicon Valley]] of Finland, because of the high concentration of high tech companies in the area and the presence of the Tampere University of Technology. As well as the University, Hervanta is also home to the [[Hermia (Tampere)|Hermia]] science centre and the [[Valtion teknillinen tutkimuskeskus|VTT]] office complex. The world&amp;apos;s first-ever [[GSM]] phone call was made in Hervanta in 1991, when [[Radiolinja]] started building its GSM network. [[Nokia]], [[Intel]] and many other companies have offices in Hervanta.

==Recreation==

On the north edge of Hervanta at Lukonmäki there&amp;apos;s a [[downhill skiing]] centre with two skiing runs and one lift. Ski centre also includes a small [[ski jump]] tower that is clearly visible when entering Hervanta from the north along Hervannan valtaväylä road.

On the west side of Hervanta is located lake [[Suolijärvi]] that has a small beach for [[sunbathing]] and [[Human swimming|swimming]]. Around the lake goes two trails. The innernmost and smaller trail goes around the lake near the shore while the outermost one makes a longer route keeping a fair distance to the lake. The longer route is linked to the trail network stretching around Tampere. The trails are used for [[jogging]] and [[cross-country skiing]] (during winter).

Hervanta has numerous small sport fields that are generally used for [[soccer]] and [[finnish baseball]]. During winter some of the fields are frozen for [[ice-skating]] and [[ice hockey]].

Hervanta also has a kind of a central park called Ahvenispuisto around lake Ahvenisjärvi. In southern part of Hervanta there is another big park called Näyttelijänpuisto. Näyttelijänpuisto has a [[disc golf]] track and a noteworthy hill that is used for [[tobogganing]] in winter. In addition to the two mentioned parks there are numerous smaller parks.

==External links==
{{Commonscat|Hervanta}}

*[http://www.hervannansanomat.fi/ Hervannan Sanomat. The local newspaper of Hervanta] {{fi icon}}
*[http://www.tut.fi/ Tampere University of Technology]
*[http://maps.google.com/maps?ll=61.448450,23.850803&amp;amp;spn=0.037257,0.062459&amp;amp;t=k&amp;amp;hl=en Hervanta on Google Maps]
*[http://sketchup.google.com/3dwarehouse/cldetails?mid=87a4e9229c3f57efe7b3e4b5e14877e8 Hervanta collection in 3D Warehouse]

[[Category:Tampere]]
[[Category:Districts of Tampere]]
{{coord|61.4481|23.8521|type:city|display=title}}&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
