<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Lashing (ropework)"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Lashing (ropework)" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Howto|date=September 2009}}
[[File:Temple St. bamboo scaffolding 2.JPG|thumb|right|Bamboo scaffolding secured with lashings in [[Kowloon]].]]
A &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;lashing&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is an arrangement of [[rope]] wire or webbing with linking device used to secure and fasten two or more items together in a somewhat rigid manner. Lashings are most commonly applied to timber poles, and are commonly associated with the cargo, containerisation, the [[Scouting]] movement, and with [[sailor]]s.

This word usage derives from using [[whipcord]] to tie things together.

It has been imagined, the first lashing made by humans was wrapping a few strips of bark around a stone to hold it to a tree branch to make an ax to hunt and build with. In modern times, the same methods are used, but strips of bark and vines have been replaced with natural and synthetic fiber ropes. [[Scouting|Scout]]s and campers use lashings to build camp gadgets and improve their campsites for comfort and convenience. Lashings are also used in [[Pioneering (Scouting)|pioneering]],  the art of creating structures such as bridges and towers, using ropes and wooden spars.

There are still areas in the world where lashing spars (or bamboo poles) is the basic means of building.

==Types==
[[File:Square lashing with piece of wood.JPG|thumb|right|A square lashing binding a wooden spar to a tree trunk]]
===Square lashing===

&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Square lashing&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is a type of lashing used to bind spars (poles) together. There are different types, but all consist of a series of wraps around the spars, and fraps around the wraps between the spars.

===Diagonal lashing===

&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Diagonal lashing&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is a type of lashing used to bind [[spar (sailing)|spar]]s or poles together, to prevent racking. It is usually applied to cross-bracing where the poles do not initially touch, but may by used on any poles that cross each other at a 45° to 90° angle. Large, semipermanent  structures may be built with a combination of square lashing, which is stronger, and diagonal lashing.

===Shear lashing===

&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Shear lashing&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (two-spar shear lashing) also spelled &amp;quot;sheer lashing&amp;quot; is most often used when spar legs are to be spread apart to form an A-frame.

===Round lashing===

The &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;round lashing&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (also known as vertical lashing) is used to join two poles together to extend their length.

===Tripod lashing===

The &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;tripod lashing&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (also known as gyn lashing, figure of eight lashing, and three-spar shear lashing) is used to join three spars together to form a tripod.

==See also==
{{Portal|Scouting}}
*[[Binding knot]]
*[[List of knots]]

==External links==
*http://www.ropeworks.biz/archive/tripod.html
*http://scoutpioneering.com -  Scout Pioneering photos, diagrams, illustrations and procedures

{{Knots}}
{{DEFAULTSORT:Lashing (Ropework)}}
[[Category:Ropework]]
[[Category:Survival skills]]
[[Category:Lashing knots]]

[[nl:Sjorring]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
