<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Nilometer"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Nilometer" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Refimprove|date=May 2010}}
[[Image:Cairo Nilometer 2.jpg|Thumb|right|300px|Measuring shaft of the Nilometer on Rhoda Island, Cairo]]
A &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Nilometer&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; was a structure for measuring the Nile River&amp;apos;s clarity and water level during the annual flood season.

Between July and November, the reaches of the Nile running through [[Egypt]] would burst their banks and cover the adjacent [[flood plain]].
When the waters receded, around September or October, they left behind a rich [[Alluvium|alluvial deposit]] of exceptionally fertile black silt over the croplands.  The inundation &amp;amp;ndash; &amp;apos;&amp;apos;akhet&amp;apos;&amp;apos; in the [[Egyptian language]] &amp;amp;ndash; was one of the three seasons into which the [[Ancient Egypt]]ians divided their years. (See [[Season of the Inundation]].)

It would be difficult to overstate the importance of the annual flood to Egyptian civilization.  A moderate inundation was a vital part of the agricultural cycle; however, a lighter inundation than normal would cause [[famine]], and too much flood water would be equally disastrous, washing away much of the infrastructure built on the flood plain.  Records from Pharaonic times indicate that on average, one year out of every five saw an inundation that was either over-abundant or fell short of expectations.{{citation needed|date=November 2010}}

The ability to predict the volume of the coming inundation was part of the mystique of the Ancient Egyptian priesthood.  The same skill also played a political and administrative role, since the quality of the year&amp;apos;s flood was used to determine the levels of tax to be paid.  This is where the nilometer came into play, with priests monitoring the day-to-day level of the river and announcing the awaited arrival of the summer flood.

The simplest nilometer design is a vertical column submerged in the waters of the river, with marked intervals indicating the depth of the water.
One that follows this simple design, albeit housed in an elaborate and ornate stone structure, can still be seen on the island of [[Rhoda Island|Rhoda]] in central [[Cairo]].  While this nilometer dates only as far back as AD&amp;amp;nbsp;861, when the [[Abbasid]] caliph [[al-Mutawakkil]] ordered its construction, it was built on a site occupied by an earlier specimen which was seen by the Syrian Orthodox patriarch [[Dionysius of Tel Mahre]] in 830.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;Bar Hebraeus, &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Chronicon Ecclesiasticum&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, i. 373&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;
[[Image:Nilometer Rhoda Island Cairo June 1966.jpg|240px|thumb|left|Conical structure covers the Nilometer on southern tip of Rhoda Island in the Nile River at Cairo The structure is modern but the Nilometer dates from 861 AD.]]

[[Image:Egypt.Aswan.ElephantineIsland.Nilometer.01.jpg|thumb|right|240px|Nilometer on [[Elephantine|Elephantine Island]] ]]  The second nilometer design comprises a flight of stairs leading down into the water, with depth markings along the walls.
The best known example of this kind can be seen on the island of [[Elephantine]] in [[Aswan]].  This location was also particularly important, since for much of Egyptian history, Elephantine marked Egypt&amp;apos;s southern border and was therefore the first place where the onset of the annual flood was detected.

The most elaborate design involved a channel or culvert that led from the riverbank &amp;amp;ndash; often running for a considerable distance &amp;amp;ndash; and then fed a well, tank, or cistern.  These nilometer wells were most frequently located within the confines of [[temple]]s, where only the priests and rulers were allowed access.
A particularly fine example, with a deep, cylindrical well and a culvert opening in the surrounding wall, can be seen at the [[Temple of Kom Ombo]] to the north of Aswan.

While nilometers originated in Pharaonic times, they continued to be used by the later civilizations that held sway in Egypt.
In the 20th century, the Nile&amp;apos;s annual inundation was first greatly checked, and then eliminated entirely, with the construction of the [[Aswan dam]]s.

While the Aswan High Dam&amp;apos;s impact on Egypt and its agriculture has been controversial for other, more complex reasons, it has also had the additional effect of rendering the nilometer obsolete.

== Notes ==
{{reflist}}

== References ==
* {{cite book |editor1-last=Abbeloos |editor1-first=Jean Baptiste |editor2-last=Lamy |editor2-first=Thomas Joseph  |title=Bar Hebraeus, Chronicon Ecclesiasticum (3 vols) |year=1877 |location=Paris}}

[[Category:Measuring instruments]]
[[Category:Nile]]
[[Category:Water supply]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
