<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Anaxagoras (mythology)"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Anaxagoras (mythology)" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Unreferenced|date=December 2009}}
In [[Greek mythology]], &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Anaxagoras&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; ({{lang-el|Αναξαγόρας}}) was a king of [[Argos]] and son of either [[Megapenthes]] or his son [[Argeus (king of Argos)|Argeus]]. The prince, Anaxagoras&amp;apos; son, suffered from a strange malady and the king offered a reward for anybody that could heal him.  [[Melampus]], a local seer, killed an ox and talked to the [[vulture]]s that came to eat the corpse.  They said that the last time they had had such a feast was when the king made a sacrifice.  They told Melampus that the prince had been frightened of the big, bloody knife and the king tossed it aside to calm the child.  It had hit a tree and injured a [[hamadryad]], who cursed the prince with the sickness.  The hamadryad told Melampus that the boy would be healed if the knife was taken out of the trunk of the tree and boiled, then the rusty water that resulted drunk by the prince.  Melampus followed her directions and demanded two thirds of the kingdom for himself, and one third for his brother, [[Bias (mythology)|Bias]]. The king ultimately agreed. When the women of Argos were driven mad by Dionysus, in the reign of Anaxagoras, [[Melampus]] was brought in to cure them, but demanded a third of the kingdom as payment. The king refused, but the women became wilder than ever, and he was forced to seek out Melampus again, who this time demanded both a third for himself and another third for his brother [[Bias (mythology)|Bias]]. Sometimes, this story is told not of Anaxagoras, but of his grandfather, [[Proetus]]. Anaxagoras was succeeded by his son [[Alector]].  His house lasted longer than those of Bias and Melampus, and eventually the kingdom was reunited under its last member, [[Cyanippus]].

{{s-start}}
{{s-reg}}
{{succession box|
 title=[[King of Argos]]|
 before=[[Argeus (king of Argos)|Argeus]]|
 after=[[Alector]]|
 years=
}}
{{s-end}}

{{DEFAULTSORT:Anaxagoras}}
[[Category:Greek mythology]]
[[Category:Kings of Argos]]
[[Category:Mythological kings]]
[[Category:Abantiades]]

{{Greek-myth-stub}}&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
