<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="German Academic Exchange Service"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="German Academic Exchange Service" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Infobox organization
|name         = German Academic Exchange Service
|image        = DAAD Logo.svg
|formation    =
|leader_title =
|leader_name  =
|headquarters = [[Bonn]], [[Germany]]
|website      = {{URL|http://www.daad.de/en/index.html|daad.de}}
}}
The &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;German Academic Exchange Service&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; or &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;DAAD&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; ({{lang-de|&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Deutscher Akademischer Austauschdienst&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;}}) is the largest [[Germany|German]] support organisation in the field of international academic co-operation.

DAAD is a private, federally funded and state-funded, self-governing national agency of the institutions of higher education in Germany, representing 365 German higher education institutions (100 universities and technical universities, 162 general universities of applied sciences, and 52 colleges of music and art) [2003].

The DAAD itself does not offer programs of study or courses, but awards competitive, merit-based grants for use toward study and/or research in Germany at any of the [[accredited]] German institutions of higher education. It also awards grants to German students, doctoral students, and scholars for studies and research abroad. With an annual budget of nearly 300 million Euros and supporting approximately 50,000 grantees annually, approximately 11,000 of which are on long-term scholarships, the DAAD is in fact the largest such academic grant organisation worldwide. The organisation was founded on 1 January 1925 but closed down in 1945, only to be refounded again in 1950.

==Headquarters and regional offices ==
[[File:DAAD.JPG|thumb|350px|DAAD headquarters in [[Bonn]]]]

The DAAD headquarters are in [[Bonn]], but there are around 15 other regional offices which exist to provide information and counseling about study and research opportunities, as well as available grants, tailored to students and academics within their region.

The New York office serves residents of the United States and Canada who are enrolled or employed full-time at an American or Canadian institution of higher education, and who would like to study or pursue research in Germany. From the perspective of this side of the exchange, the DAAD&amp;apos;s mission is to facilitate American and Canadian students&amp;apos; access to the distinguished German institutions of higher education and research--from universities (Universitäten) to universities of applied sciences (the [[Fachhochschule]] system), to colleges of music and art, to libraries and research archives, even to research institutions such as the [[Max Planck Institutes]].

== DAAD scholarships and programmes ==
The DAAD grants administered by the DAAD abroad are available to students of all academic disciplines and at each academic degree level, including [[undergraduates]], graduating undergraduates and recent graduates with a [[Bachelor of Arts|BA]], [[Masters degree]] students, [[doctoral]] students, [[PhD]] candidates and [[postdoctoral]] scholars, and faculty.

The DAAD worldwide network also includes around 50 information centres and around 450 DAAD lecturer positions.

==Notable DAAD Alumni==

*Muhammad Aslam
* [[Söhnke M. Bartram]], economist
*[[Jeffrey Eugenides]]
*[[Willie Doherty]]
*[[Auma Obama]]
*[[Daniel Pollmann]]
*[[Susan Sontag]]
==See also==
* [[International Quality Network]] (IQN)

==External links==
*[http://www.daad.de/en/index.html DAAD Homepage]
*[http://www.daad.org DAAD New York (North America)]

[[Category:Academic transfer]]
[[Category:Non-profit organisations based in Germany]]
[[Category:Education in Germany]]
[[Category:Politics of Germany]]
[[Category:Educational foundations]]
[[Category:Foundations based in Germany]]
[[Category:Organisations based in Bonn]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
