<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Idiopathic craniofacial erythema"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Idiopathic craniofacial erythema" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Idiopathic craniofacial erythema&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is a medical condition characterised by severe, uncontrollable, and frequently unprovoked, facial [[blushing]].

Blushing can occur at any time and is frequently triggered by even mundane events, such as, talking to friends, paying for goods in a shop, asking for directions or even simply making eye contact with another person.

For many years, the cause of the condition was thought to be an anxiety problem, caused by a mental health disorder. However, in recent years experts in the field of the disorder believe it to be caused by an overactive sympathetic nervous system, an automatic response which sufferers have no mental control over. It is related to hyperhidrosis, more commonly known as excessive sweating, as it is caused by the same overactive nerves which cause excessive sweating. Sufferers of severe facial blushing commonly experience hyperhidrosis. Studies have also shown that patients with severe facial blushing or hyperhidrosis commonly have family members with one or both of the related disorders.
== Treatment ==
A number of treatments are available.  The most successful [[Non-invasive (medical)|non-invasive procedure]] is [[cognitive behavioural therapy]] (CBT), which attempts to alleviate the anxiety felt by sufferers.

In extreme cases a [[surgical procedure]] known as [[endoscopic transthoracic sympathicotomy]] (ETS) is available.  Pioneered by [[surgeons]] in [[Sweden]], this procedure has recently become increasingly controversial due to its many potential [[Adverse effect (medicine)|adverse effects]].  Patients who have undergone the procedure frequently complain of compensatory sweating and [[Fatigue (physical)|fatigue]], with around 5% reconsidering getting the treatment.  ETS is now normally only considered in extreme cases where other treatments have been ineffective.

== External links ==

*[http://www.angelfire.com/journal2/sadhelp/nym.htm The New Yorker] - &amp;apos;&amp;apos;CRIMSON TIDE - What is blushing?, No one knows for sure, but it can ruin your life&amp;apos;&amp;apos; by [[Atul Gawande]].

[[Category:Anxiety disorders]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
