<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Valleuse"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Valleuse" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Unreferenced|date=December 2009}}
[[Image:Le Havre dot.png|thumb|Location within [[France]]]]

In the [[Pays de Caux]], [[Normandy]], [[France]] a &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;valleuse&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is a depression in the land surface of the [[plateau]] which permits access to the [[sea]]. On the rest of this [[coast]], that access is prevented by the height of the [[chalk]] [[cliff]]s.

There are three sorts:
* living valleuses: natural depressions as at [[Fécamp]], [[Yport]] and [[Étretat]].
* dead valleuses: to obtain the final access to the [[beach]] it is necessary to set up a [[stairway]].
*perched valleuses: simple depressions in the plateau surface which do not descend far enough to permit access to the beach. Elsewhere, it might be called a [[hanging valley]] though it is formed, not by a glacier but by maritime [[erosion]].

==Origins==
The word is peculiar to the Pays de Caux but the feature is not, though it shows itself particularly well here.  The [[valley]]s developed while the [[water table]] was much higher in the chalk than it now is so that a [[stream]] flowed in each of these truncated valleys.  It is likely that most of the formation of the valleys in the plateau occurred during cold periods. This region was never covered by an [[ice cap]] but it has been only about 230 kilometres from one. In those circumstances, the conditions will have been [[tundra]], sometimes verging on [[periglacial]]. When the frozen ground thawed in the [[Spring (season)|spring]], the surface soil was very wet because the melted snow and [[ground water]] could not sink into the [[permafrost]].  Any appreciable slope on the surface will have induced slumping and erosion but we have a plateau so the slopes were not originally great.

During the glacial periods, the sea level was low enough to have emptied the [[English Channel]] to the north of the Pays de Caux. The truncated valleys in the chalk, represent the headwaters of streams flowing down to what is now the bottom of the sea. During the [[interglacial]]s the sea eroded the coast and steepened the slope down which they flowed  but they will have required ever wetter conditions to keep the water table in the chalk sufficiently high to make the streams flow. In the end, the sea cut the cliff back quicker than the streams cut the valleys downward.

&amp;lt;gallery&amp;gt;
Image:Pierre-Auguste Renoir 081.jpg|[[Pierre-Auguste Renoir]], Mer et bateaux, 1883, [[Metropolitan Museum of Art]], [[New York]]. Note the one living and two perched Valleuses.
&amp;lt;/gallery&amp;gt;

[[Category:Geomorphology]]
[[Category:Geography of Upper Normandy]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
