<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Delocalized electron"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Delocalized electron" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;[[Image:Benz4.png|thumb|right|200px|[[Benzene]], with the delocalization of the [[electron]]s indicated by the circle.]]

In chemistry, &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;delocalized electrons&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; are [[electron]]s in a [[molecule]], [[ion]] or solid [[metal]] that are not associated with a single [[atom]] or &amp;apos;&amp;apos;one&amp;apos;&amp;apos; [[covalent bond]].
&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;IUPAC Gold Book [http://goldbook.iupac.org/D01583.html &amp;apos;&amp;apos;delocalization&amp;apos;&amp;apos;]&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;
Delocalized electrons are contained within an [[Molecular orbital|orbital]] that extends over several adjacent atoms.  Classically, delocalized electrons can be found in [[conjugated system]]s and [[mesoionic]] compounds. It is increasingly appreciated that electrons in [[Sigma bonds|sigma bonding]] levels are also delocalized.  For example, in [[methane]], the bonding electrons are shared by all five atoms equally.  Pervasive existence of delocalization is implicit in [[molecular orbital theory]].

== Examples ==

In the [[simple aromatic ring]] of [[benzene]] the &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;delocalization&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; of six [[Pi bond|π electrons]] over the C&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;6&amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt; ring is often graphically indicated by a circle.  The fact that the six C-C bonds are equidistant is one indication of this delocalization.  In [[valence bond theory]], delocalization in benzene is represented by [[resonance (chemistry)|resonance structures]].

Delocalized electrons also exist in the structure of solid metals, where the [[d orbital|d-subshell]] interferes with the above [[s orbital|s-subshell]]. Metallic structure consists of aligned positive [[ion]]s ([[cation]]s) in a &amp;quot;sea&amp;quot; of delocalized electrons. This means that the electrons are free to move throughout the structure, and gives rise to properties such as [[electrical conductivity|conductivity]].

In [[diamond]] all four outer electrons of each [[carbon]] atom are &amp;apos;localized&amp;apos; between the atoms in covalent bonding. The movement of electrons is restricted and diamond does not conduct an electric current. In [[graphite]], each carbon atom uses only 3 of its 4 outer energy level electrons in covalently bonding to three other carbon atoms in a plane. Each carbon atom contributes one electron to a delocalized system of electrons that is also a part of the chemical bonding. The delocalized electrons are free to move throughout the plane. For this reason, graphite conducts electricity along the planes of carbon atoms, but does not conduct in a direction at [[right angle]]s to the plane.

In the case of ions it is  common to speak about &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;delocalized charge&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (charge delocalization) when meaning delocalized electrons. An example of delocalized electrons (delocalized charge) in ions can be found in the [[carboxylate]] group, wherein the negative charge is centered equally on the two oxygen atoms. Charge delocalization in anions is an important factor determining their reactivity (generally: the higher the extent of delocalization the lower the reactivity) and, specifically, the acid strength of their conjugate acids. As a general rule, the better delocalized is the charge in an anion the stronger is its [[conjugate acid]]. For example, the negative charge in [[perchlorate]] anion (ClO&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;4&amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt;&amp;lt;sup&amp;gt;-&amp;lt;/sup&amp;gt;) is evenly distributed among the symmetrically oriented oxygen atoms (and a part of it is also kept by the central chlorine atom). This excellent charge delocalization combined with the high number of oxygen atoms (four) and high [[electronegativity]] of the central chlorine atom leads to [[perchloric acid]] being one of the strongest known acids (with p&amp;apos;&amp;apos;K&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;a&amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt; values cited in the range of -7 .. -10). The extent of charge delocalization in an anion can be quantitatively expressed via the WAPS parameter.&amp;lt;ref name=&amp;quot;Kaupmees&amp;quot;&amp;gt;{{cite journal | author = Kaupmees K., Kaljurand I., Leito I. | title = Influence of Water Content on the Acidities in Acetonitrile. Quantifying Charge Delocalization in Anions | journal = J. Phys. Chem. A | year = 2010 | volume = 114 | pages = 11788&amp;amp;ndash;11793 | doi = 10.1021/jp105670t }}&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

== Delocalization in reactions ==

Delocalized electrons are important for several reasons. One, an expected chemical reaction may not occur because the electrons delocalize to a more stable configuration, resulting in a reaction that happens at a different location. An example attempting the [[Friedel–Crafts reaction|Friedel–Crafts]] [[alkylation]] of benzene with 1-chloro-2-methylpropane; the [[carbocation]] rearranges to a tert-[[butyl]] group stabilized by [[hyperconjugation]], a particular form of delocalization. Delocalization leads to lengthening of wavelength of electron therefore decreases the energy.

==See also==

*[[Conjugated system]]
*[[Molecular orbital]]
*[[Aromatic ring current]]

==References==
{{reflist}}

[[Category:Chemical bonding]]
[[Category:Electron states]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
