<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Gothic Quarter, Barcelona"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Gothic Quarter, Barcelona" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;[[File:Basílica de la Mercè - Barcelona (Catalonia).jpg|thumb|300px|right|La Mercè basilica]]
[[File:Barcelona - Carrer del Bisbe.jpg|thumb|300px|right|Carrer del Bisbe Irurita]]
[[File:Ayuntamiento Barcelona.jpg|thumb|300px|right|City hall]]

The &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Gothic Quarter&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; ({{lang-ca|Barri Gòtic}}, {{IPA-ca|ˈbari ˈɣɔtik|IPA}}) is the centre of the old city of [[Barcelona]]. It stretches from [[La Rambla, Barcelona|La Rambla]] to [[Via Laietana]], and from the [[Mediterranean]] seafront to [[Ronda de Sant Pere]].

Despite several changes undergone in the 19th and early 20th century, many of the buildings date from [[Middle Ages|Medieval times]], some from as far back as the [[Ancient Rome|Roman]] settlement of Barcelona. Remains of the squared Roman Wall can be seen around Tapineria and Sots-Tinent Navarro to the north, Avinguda de la Catedral and Plaça Nova to the west and Carrer de la Palla to the south. [[El Call (Barcelona)|El Call]], the medieval [[Jewish Quarter (diaspora)|Jewish quarter]], is located within this area too.

The Barri Gòtic retains a labyrinthine street plan, with many small streets opening out into [[plaza|squares]]. Most of the quarter is closed to regular traffic although open to service vehicles and taxis.

==Landmarks==
*[[Cathedral of Santa Eulàlia]]
*[[Basilica of La Mercè]]
*[[Santa Maria del Pi, Barcelona|Church of Santa Maria del Pi]]
*[[Church of Sant Miquel]]
*[[Plaça Sant Jaume]], including [[Casa de la Ciutat]] (city hall) and [[Palau de la Generalitat de Catalunya]] (presidential palace).
*[[Plaça Reial]]
*[[Plaça del Rei]], including [[Museu d&amp;apos;Història de la Ciutat de Barcelona]]
*[[Plaça de Sant Felip Neri]]
*[[Portal de l&amp;apos;Àngel]]
*Remains of the temple of [[Augustus]]
*[[Els Quatre Gats]]

==Controversy over Authenticity of the Gothic Quarter==

In 2011, a controversy emerged over the authenticity of numerous Gothic Quarter buildings due to the publication of a [[dissertation]] entitled &amp;quot;[http://www.ub.edu/geocrit/sn/sn-371.htm The Gothic Quarter of Barcelona: Planning the Past and Brand Image]&amp;quot; by Agustín Cócola. According to the author, during the neoclassical period of the city&amp;apos;s history, the downtown quarter was completely transformed from a sombre neighborhood to a tourist attraction through a massive restoration project. The transformation of the neighborhood was mostly completed in time for the 1929 International Exhibition, which then took on great significance in displaying both the city and Catalunya in a positive light to the worlds media. Further restoration of existing buildings and the creation of brand new Neo-gothic works continued as late as the 1960&amp;apos;s. The seminal work of Agustín Cócola and other contributors from the Department of Architectural Composition, Universitat Politècnica de Catalunya in recognizing the invention of the “Barri Gòtic” has played an important role in our understanding of the complex process Barcelona underwent in an attempt to promote a sense of national identity of Catalan Art and Culture.

Among the principal buildings inappropriately listed as Gothic are included:

*[[Barcelona_cathedral|Barcelona Cathedral]]’s façade: constructed between 1882 and 1913 by Josep Oriol Mestres and August Font i Carreras with a profusion of Gothic style elements.
*Hiking Center of Catalonia’s building (Paradís Street): work by [[Lluís Domènech i Montaner]] carried out in 1922 on a building of uncertain origins to which he added Coronella windows, battlements, and merlons.
*The [[Flamboyant]]-style bridge that crosses Bisbe street: newly constructed 1928 by [[Joan Rubió]].
*Padellàs House: present-day Barcelona History Museum, moved from Mercaders street to Plaza del Rei– where the Salón del Tinell is located – in 1936.
*Aguilar Palace: present-day [[Museu Picasso]] (Montcada street), restored by Adolf Florensa in 1959, who added galleries with arches and Coronella windows.
*Pignatelli Palace: present-day Royal Artistic Circle of Barcelona, restored in 1970 including the addition of various Gothic windows retrieved from municipal warehouses.

==Barcelona Metro==
*[[Barcelona Metro line 4|L4]] station [[Jaume I (Barcelona Metro)|Jaume I]]
*[[Barcelona Metro line 3|L3]] stations [[Liceu (Barcelona Metro)|Liceu]] and [[Drassanes (Barcelona Metro)|Drassanes]]

==External links==
*[http://www.bcn.es/turisme/catala/turisme/llocs/13_0.htm Barri Gòtic at Bcn.es]
*[http://www.barcelonabusturistic.cat/web/guest/rutes?p_p_id=Rutes_WAR_tmbrutesportlet&amp;amp;_Rutes_WAR_tmbrutesportlet_ACTION=GO_TO_POI&amp;amp;_Rutes_WAR_tmbrutesportlet_poiId=PARADA_BARRI_GOTIC Barri Gòtic at Tmb.cat]

{{Barcelona}}

{{coord|41|22|58|N|2|10|37|E|type:city(50000)_region:ES-CT_source:dewiki|display=title}}

{{DEFAULTSORT:Gothic Quarter, Barcelona}}
[[Category:Neighbourhoods of Barcelona]]
[[Category:Visitor attractions in Barcelona]]
[[Category:Ciutat Vella]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
