<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Yarralumla brickworks"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Yarralumla brickworks" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;[[Image:Yarralumla brickworks 1924.jpg|right|thumb|270px|Workers at Yarralumla Brickworks in 1924]]
[[Image:Yarralumla brickworks today.jpg|right|thumb|270px|The tall chimney and newest kiln]]
The &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Yarralumla brickworks&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, also known as the Commonwealth Brickworks, was one of the earliest construction projects in [[Canberra]], [[Australia]]. It was built in the suburb of [[Yarralumla, Australian Capital Territory|Yarralumla]] to produce the bricks used to build many of Canberra&amp;apos;s early buildings. It opened in around 1913 and operated until its closure in 1976. &amp;lt;ref&amp;gt; * &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Exploring the ACT and Southeast New South Wales&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, J. Kay McDonald, Kangaroo Press, Sydney, 1985, p41
 ISBN 0-86417-049-1 &amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt; It is known for producing the bricks used to build itself.

[[Narrow gauge railway|Narrow gauge]] goods [[railway]] lines for the transportation of bricks linked Yarralumla to some of the major building sites in central Canberra such as [[Parliament House, Canberra|Old Parliament House]], and the [[Kingston, Australian Capital Territory|Kingston]] Power House. No sign of this early Canberra transport system remains today.

The original brick [[kiln]]s were built according to [[Walter Burley Griffin]]&amp;apos;s designs with fan forced short [[chimney]]s intended to stay below the height of the surrounding [[pine tree]]s. In 1950 after [[World War II]] increased building demands in Canberra meant that a large 46 metre natural-draft chimney was built for the new kilns. This greatly increased brick production capacity. The tall chimney is visible from many locations around central Canberra.

In recent years a report found that the tall chimney was not earthquake-safe. As the chimney was heritage listed and located within falling distance of nearby homes, an engineering firm was called in to make it safe. A frame was built inside the chimney to support it without affecting its external appearance.

The brickworks today is closed to the public but has  had various uses over the past 20 years. There have been several recent ideas that haven&amp;apos;t eventuated, including using the site for Canberra&amp;apos;s new [[gaol]], making the site the new permanent home for [[Floriade (Canberra)|Floriade]] (a yearly Canberra flower festival) or to turn the brickworks into a holiday resort. Future plans for the site are still undecided.

==References==
&amp;lt;references/&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;!-- Broken link *[http://www.cintec.com/en/casehist/chimney/chim06.htm CINTEC case report] --&amp;gt;

{{coord|35|18|30|S|149|5|26|E|display=title}}

[[Category:Manufacturing plants in Australia]]
[[Category:Buildings and structures in Canberra]]
[[Category:Brickworks]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
