<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Jan Brueghel the Elder"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Jan Brueghel the Elder" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;[[File:Peter Paul Rubens -Familie van Jan Bruegel de Oude - Courtauld Gallery Londen 2-12-2009 16-35-20.JPG|thumb|Family of Jan Breughel the Elder, by [[Pieter Paul Rubens]], presumably a posthumous portrait of his wife Catharina van Mariënburg, who died in 1627 and who is highlighted in the painting. The children are Anna Brueghel (pupil of Rubens who married David Teniers), and Jan the Younger.]]

&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Jan Brueghel the Elder&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; ({{IPA-nl|ˈjɑn ˈbɾøːɣəl}}; 1568 – 13 January 1625) was a [[Flemings|Flemish]] [[Painting|painter]], son of [[Pieter Bruegel the Elder]] and father of [[Jan Brueghel the Younger]]. Nicknamed &amp;quot;Velvet&amp;quot; Brueghel, &amp;quot;Flower&amp;quot; Brueghel, and &amp;quot;Paradise&amp;quot; Brueghel, of which the latter two were derived from his floral [[still life]]s which were his favored subjects, while the former may refer to the velveteen sheen of his colors or to his habit of wearing velvet.

== Biography ==
[[File:Bouquet (Jan Brueghel the Elder).jpeg|thumb|250px|&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Bouquet&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, painted 1603.]]
Jan was born in [[Brussels]]. His father died in 1569, and then, following the death of his mother in 1578, Jan, along with his brother [[Pieter Brueghel the Younger]] and sister Marie, went to live with their grandmother [[Mayken Verhulst]] (widow of [[Pieter Coecke van Aelst]]). She was an artist in her own right, and according to [[Carel van Mander]], possibly the first teacher of the two sons. The family moved to [[Antwerp]] sometime after 1578.

In about 1589 Jan traveled to Italy, probably via Cologne. There he resided first in Naples, where his patron was Francesco Carracciolo. Next he moved to Rome, working for several discerning cardinals including, most famously, Federico Borromeo. It was in the company of Borromeo that Brueghel left Rome and took up residence in Milan, where he was part of the Cardinal&amp;apos;s household. In the summer of 1596 he returned to Antwerp, where he remained for the rest of his life apart from short journeys to Prague and to the Dutch Republic.

While in Italy he applied himself principally to landscapes and history paintings, including Biblical narratives and scenes from mythology and ancient history. Back in Antwerp he continued these types of subject matter but also acquired considerable reputation by his flower paintings and allegories.  He formed a style more independent of his father&amp;apos;s than did his brother Pieter the Younger.

Many of his paintings are collaborations in which figures by other painters were placed in landscapes painted by Jan Brueghel; in other cases, Brueghel painted the figures into another artist&amp;apos;s landscape or architectural interior. The most famous of his collaborators was [[Peter Paul Rubens]] in several of his small pictures—such as his &amp;quot;Vertumnus and Pomona,&amp;quot; the &amp;quot;Satyr viewing the Sleeping Nymph,&amp;quot; and the &amp;quot;Terrestrial Paradise.&amp;quot;.

He had a studio in [[Antwerp]], where he died from [[cholera]] on 13 January 1625.

&amp;lt;gallery&amp;gt;
Image:Janbrueghelark.jpg|The Entry of the Animals Into [[Noah&amp;apos;s Ark]], painted 1613.
File:The Wedding Feast Jan Brueghel the Elder.jpeg|&amp;apos;&amp;apos;The Wedding Feast&amp;apos;&amp;apos;
File:Coastal Landscape with the Sacrifice of Jonas.jpeg|&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Coastal Landscape with the Sacrifice of [[Jonas]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos;
File:Jan Brueghel the Elder - The Archdukes Albert and Isabella Visiting a Collector&amp;apos;s Cabinet - Walters 372010.jpg| &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[The Archdukes Albert and Isabella Visiting a Collector&amp;apos;s Cabinet (painting)|The Archdukes Albert and Isabella Visiting a Collector&amp;apos;s Cabinet]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos;.  [[The Walters Art Museum]].
&amp;lt;/gallery&amp;gt;

==Family tree==
{{Brueghel}}

==See also==
*[[List of Belgian painters]]

==References==
*{{Cite EB1911|wstitle=Breughel, Pieter}}
*{{Cite Americana|wstitle=Bruegel|year=1920}}

==External links==
{{commons}}
*[http://www.kfki.hu/~arthp/html/b/bruegel/jan_e/ Web Gallery of Art: Jan Brueghel the Elder]
*[http://www.abcgallery.com/B/bruegel/jan.html Jan Brueghel the Elder at Olga&amp;apos;s Gallery]
*[http://www.pubhist.com/person/72/jan-brueghel-the-elder Works and literature on Jan Brueghel the Elder] at PubHist
*&amp;apos;&amp;apos;[http://libmma.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/compoundobject/collection/p15324coll10/id/97318 Pieter Bruegel the Elder: Drawings and Prints]&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, a full text exhibition catalog from The Metropolitan Museum of Art, which includes material on Jan Brueghel the Elder (see index)

{{Use dmy dates|date=April 2011}}

{{Authority control|VIAF=100909732}}
{{Persondata &amp;lt;!-- Metadata: see [[Wikipedia:Persondata]]. --&amp;gt;
| NAME              = Brueghel, Jan (The Elder)
| ALTERNATIVE NAMES =
| SHORT DESCRIPTION = Dutch painter
| DATE OF BIRTH     = 1568
| PLACE OF BIRTH    = Brussels
| DATE OF DEATH     = 13 January 1625
| PLACE OF DEATH    = Antwerp
}}
{{DEFAULTSORT:Brueghel The Elder, Jan}}
[[Category:Flemish Baroque painters]]
[[Category:People from Brussels]]
[[Category:History of Antwerp]]
[[Category:1568 births]]
[[Category:1625 deaths]]
[[Category:Bruegel family|Jan a]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
