<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Von Sternberg House"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Von Sternberg House" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Von Sternberg House&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; was a single bedroom (servants&amp;apos; bedrooms excluded) mini-[[mansion]] designed by the architect [[Richard Neutra]].  It was built in 1935 in [[Northridge, California]], in the then-rural [[San Fernando Valley]] for the movie director [[Josef von Sternberg]]. It was demolished in 1972 to make way for a housing development.

Neutra was known as a philosopher of [[Modernism]] in [[architecture]], and his work as a  practitioner was in constant interaction with his thoughts and writings.  Von Sternberg house was one of the most impressive of the incarnations of this philosophy, along with [[Lovell House]].

The design of the Von Sternberg House contrasts with the typical homes built at the beginning of the 21st century.  The Von Sternberg House had a very small number of rooms and a relatively small surface area which played up its unique design features.  While it did have a few features of ostentatious display, such as a separate, larger and higher garage bay for a [[Rolls-Royce car|Rolls-Royce]] in addition to the two other garage bays for lesser automobiles (in an era where even rich homes had only one or two garages) most of its characteristics were original and discrete, showing Neutra&amp;apos;s attention to the integration of custom details.

The exterior look of the house and of its landscaped surroundings was made of sinuous lines, yet the interiors were orthogonal, making furniture placement simple and easy. As in many others of his domestic designs, Neutra made heavy use of industrial windows and sidings, fulfilling both aesthetic and practical functions, such as making privacy screens and windbreaks.

Neutra was mindful of his customer&amp;apos;s desires even when he found them absurd.  He would later regale his friends with the story (among others) of Von Sternberg asking that none of the bathroom doors have locks, in order to prevent his party guests from locking themselves up in there and threatening to commit suicide.  As a movie director Sternberg was well acquainted with the theatrical behavior of many [[Hollywood]] actors, while Neutra had a social life which kept him in touch with artists in other domains.

In the 1940s novelist-philosopher [[Ayn Rand]] bought the house at 10000 Tampa Avenue in the San Fernando Valley (Chatsworth). Concerned by the 13 ac (5 ha) ranch&amp;apos;s 20&amp;amp;nbsp;mi (32&amp;amp;nbsp;km) distance from Hollywood, where she worked as a screen writer, Rand and her husband actor Frank O&amp;apos;Connor paid $24,000 for the house. In 1963, according to Rand biographer [[Barbara Branden]], Ayn and Frank sold the house for $175,000.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;Branden, [[The Passion of Ayn Rand]], p. 186&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

==Notes==
{{reflist}}

==References==
*Hines, Thomas. &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Richard Neutra]] and the Search for Modern Architecture.&amp;apos;&amp;apos;.  New York: Oxford University Press, 1982.
*Neutra, Richard Joseph. &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Life and Shape.&amp;apos;&amp;apos; New York: Appleton-Century-Crofts, 1962.
{{coord missing|Los Angeles County, California}}

{{Modernism}}
{{Modern architecture}}

[[Category:Richard Neutra buildings]]
[[Category:History of the San Fernando Valley]]
[[Category:Houses in California]]
[[Category:Houses completed in 1935]]
[[Category:Buildings and structures in the San Fernando Valley]]
[[Category:Houses in Los Angeles County, California]]
[[Category:Modernist architecture in California]]
[[Category:International style architecture in the United States]]
[[Category:Demolished buildings and structures in the United States]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
