<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Oswaldo Cruz Foundation"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Oswaldo Cruz Foundation" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Citations missing|date=January 2009}}
{{Coord|22|52|29.57|S|43|14|43.58|W|display=title}}
[[Image:FIOCRUZ-Palace-CCBYSA.jpg|thumb|right|220px|Façade of the [[Moorish Revival|Neo-Mouresque]] Palace of Manguinhos, seat of the Instituto Oswaldo Cruz in Rio de Janeiro.]]
The &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Oswaldo Cruz Foundation&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; ([[Portuguese language|Portuguese]] &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Fundação Oswaldo Cruz&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, also known as &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;FIOCRUZ&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;) is a scientific institution for research and development in biomedical sciences located in [[Rio de Janeiro]], [[Brazil]], it is considered one of the world&amp;apos;s main [[public health]] research institutions. It was founded by Dr. [[Oswaldo Cruz]], a noted physician and epidemiologist.

The Federal Serum Therapy Institute was established with the objective of developing serum and vaccines against the [[bubonic plague]]. The institute’s activities, however, changed from simple production into research and experimental medicine, especially after Oswaldo Cruz assumed its leadership in 1902. From there on, the institute became the base for memorable sanitation campaigns in an age of outbreaks and epidemics of the [[bubonic plague]], [[yellow fever]], and [[smallpox]].
The Institute, however, was not confined to [[Rio de Janeiro]] and, on the contrary, collaborated in the occupation of the country’s inlands through scientific expeditions, aiding in the development of the country.

When Oswaldo Cruz died, in 1917, the Institute, which by then already bore his name, was nationally consolidated through important scientific achievements, such as [[Carlos Chagas]]’ description of the complete cycle of the [[American trypanosomiasis]] including the clinical pattern of the disease.
On 16 January 2007, the Institute announced that it had developed a gel from [[algae]] which it is hoped will reduce [[HIV]] transmission to women.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;{{cite web |url=http://news.bbc.co.uk/2/hi/health/6266527.stm |title=Algae gel to combat HIV infection | work=BBC News | date=16 January 2007 | accessdate=5 January 2010}}&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

Today the institution has a broad range of responsibilities related to the health and wellbeing of the Brazilian population. This includes hospital and ambulatory care; health-related research; development of vaccines, drugs, reagents, and diagnostic kits; training of public health and health workers; and providing information and communications related to health, science, and technology. The Fiocruz workforce members are over 7,500. Fiocruz includes several fixed facilities in Rio de Janeiro and other locations; however, it contributes to improving health throughout the country, through its support to the Sistema Único de Saúde (Unified Health System, the Brazilian public health system), its proposals on public health policy-making, its research activities, its scientific expeditions, and the reach of its health services and products.

Fiocruz is one of the founding members of the [http://www.ianphi.org International Association of National Public Health Institutes], a membership organization of [[national public health institutes]].

==See also==
*[[Fiocruz Genome Comparison Project]]
*[[Oswaldo Cruz]]
*[[Museum of Life]]

==References==
{{reflist}}

==External links==
* [http://www.fiocruz.br/cgi/cgilua.exe/sys/start.htm?UserActiveTemplate=template_ingles Oswaldo Cruz Foundation]

{{Pasteur Institute}}

[[Category:Research institutes in Brazil]]
[[Category:Health in Brazil]]
[[Category:Medical research institutes]]

{{med-org-stub}}&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
