<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="XLN Telecom"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="XLN Telecom" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;฿{{multiple issues|orphan =August 2010|advert=March 2011}}

&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;XLN Telecom&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, founded in 2002, is the UK’s largest independent provider of [[telecommunications service|telecom services]] to small businesses in Britain having over 120,000 business customers across the country. In 2007, XLN was ranked as the highest placed telecoms provider in &amp;apos;&amp;apos;The [[The Sunday Times|Sunday Times]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos; [[Tech Track 100]] and was listed for a second consecutive year in 2008. In 2006 Christian Nellemann was a winner of the [[Ernst &amp;amp; Young]] Entrepreneur of the Year Award for Technology and Communication and again in 2010.

== History ==
XLN Telecom was founded by Christian Nellemann and Anthony Karibian in 2001. It is located in Vauxhall, London, United Kingdom.

XLN began operations in 2002. Deregulation of the UK Telecom’s industry has enabled XLN to offer an alternative phone service to BT at a considerably lower cost.

XLN is one of Britain’s fastest growing alternative Telecom Service Providers focusing on the Small Business sector. The company is profitable and backed by a leading multi-billion pound institutional investor.

In 2006, Nellemann, XLN’s founder and CEO was recognised as Ernst &amp;amp; Young’s Entrepreneur of the Year 2006 for Technology and Communication. He has been listed on four occasions as a finalist in what is recognised as one of the premier business awards.

Also in 2006, it was announced that XLN would face a full OFCOM investigation after the regulator reported receiving allegations from customers that they were misled during the initial sales approaches made by XLN Telecom representatives or had their service transferred to XLN Telecom without their consent.

The Telecom Provider has also been a National Business Awards Finalist in 4 years: 2004, 2005, 2006 and 2009.

In 2007 and 2008, XLN Telecom was ranked on the Sunday Times Tech Track 100 survey of the 100 fastest growing technology companies in the UK.

2009 XLN telecom became a finalist for the Customer Focus Award at the 2009 National Business Awards. Complaints about unpaid staff hit the media and affected their image.

2010 XLN won a Global Business Excellence award and a Best Company award in addition to being listed as finalists in the Fast Growth Awards and the Lambeth Business Awards for Best Customer Service.

XLN Telecom Ltd is a CarbonNeutral company, underlining the company&amp;apos;s commitment to social responsibility.

In the financial year ending March 2010, XLN Telecom broke £50m sales, achieving £54m and £12m ebitda.

== References ==
{{refbegin}}
*{{cite web|url=http://www.broadbandgenie.co.uk/broadband/review/xln-telecom-broadband/comment|title=
XLN Telecom Ltd Reviews|publisher=broadbandgenie|accessdate=2013-05-04}}
*{{cite web|url=http://www.fasttrack.co.uk/fasttrack2002/migration/dbIndex.asp?siteID=3&amp;amp;searchName=&amp;amp;yr=2007&amp;amp;sort=num&amp;amp;area1=99|title=2007 Tech Track 100 league table|publisher=Fast Track in association with The Sunday Times|accessdate=2009-09-11}}
*{{cite web|url=http://www.fasttrack.co.uk/fasttrack2002/migration/dbIndex.asp?siteID=3&amp;amp;searchName=&amp;amp;yr=2007&amp;amp;sort=num&amp;amp;area1=99|title=2007 Tech Track 100 league table|publisher=Fast Track in association with The Sunday Times|accessdate=2009-09-11}} {{Dead link|date=October 2010|bot=H3llBot}}
*{{cite web|url=http://www.fasttrack.co.uk/fasttrack2002/migration/dbIndex.asp?siteID=3&amp;amp;searchName=&amp;amp;yr=2008&amp;amp;sort=num&amp;amp;area1=99|title=2008 Tech Track 100 league table|publisher=Fast Track in association with The Sunday Times|accessdate=2009-09-11}} {{Dead link|date=October 2010|bot=H3llBot}}
{{refend}}

== External links ==
*[http://www.xlntelecom.co.uk/ XLN Telecom website]

{{DEFAULTSORT:Xln Telecom.}}
[[Category:Telecommunications companies of the United Kingdom]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
