<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Law enforcement"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Law enforcement" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;[[File:HH_Polizeihauptmeister_MZ.jpg|thumb|right|A senior [[police officer]] of [[Hamburg, Germany]]]]
[[Image:Ford_Crown_Victoria_1.JPG|thumb|right|A [[Ford Crown Victoria]] police car of the [[New York City Police Department]]]]

&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Law enforcement&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; broadly refers to any system by which some members of [[society]] act in an organized manner to promote adherence to the [[law]] by discovering and punishing persons who violate the rules and [[norm (social)|norm]]s governing that society. Although the term may encompass entities such as [[court]]s and [[prison]]s, it is most frequently applied to those who directly engage in patrols or surveillance to dissuade and discover [[crime|criminal]] activity, and those who investigate crimes and apprehend offenders.&amp;lt;ref name=&amp;quot;ILE&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Kären M. Hess, Christine Hess Orthmann, &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Introduction to Law Enforcement and Criminal Justice&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (2008), p. 1.&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt; Furthermore, although law enforcement may be most concerned with the prevention and punishment of [[crime]]s, organizations exist to discourage a wide variety of non-criminal violations of rules and norms, effected through the imposition of less severe consequences.

==Organizations==
{{Main|List of law enforcement agencies}}
Most law enforcement is conducted by some type of [[law enforcement agency]], with the most typical agency fulfilling this role being the [[police]]. Societal investment in enforcement through such organizations can be massive, both in terms of the resources invested in the activity, and in the number of people professionally engaged to perform those functions.&amp;lt;ref name=&amp;quot;ILE&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;

Law enforcement agencies tend to be limited to operating within a specified [[jurisdiction]]. In some cases, jurisdiction may overlap between organizations; for example, in the [[United States]], each state has its own statewide law enforcement arms, but the [[Federal Bureau of Investigation]] is able to act against certain types of crimes occurring in any state. Various specialized segments of society may have their own internal law enforcement arrangements. For example, [[military]] organizations may have [[military police]].

Social control capabilities have increased significantly over the past several decades, particularly because of an increased utilization of technologically advanced surveillance methods. Following the tragic events of September 11, 2001, U.S. Congress and the present Administration have granted law enforcement considerable new powers in the enforcement and prevention of terrorism-related crime. Collectively labeled under the heading of the so-called &amp;quot;war on terror&amp;quot;, the scope of such laws, policies and directives are challenged by civil rights organizations and numerous legislators for lack of definitional precision, arbitrary application of sanctions, and violation of privacy laws. One of federal law enforcement’s surveillance tools is ‘‘Project Carnivore,’’ a Justice Department Internet surveillance program that is administered by the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) to access information flowing to and from a central processing unit on a network connection. While, theoretically relying on Michel Foucault’s theory of discipline and governmentality, as well as related insights in the social control literature, this paper examines Project Carnivore relative to the larger context of state rationality and related privacy issues.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;{{cite journal|last=Ventura|first=Holly|coauthors=Mathieu Deflem|title=Governmentality and the War on Terror: FBI Project Carnivore and the Diffusion of Disciplinary Power.|year=2005|month=April|volume=13|issue=1|pages=16|doi=10.1007/s10612-004-6167-6|url=http://0-web.ebscohost.com.uncclc.coast.uncwil.edu/ehost/detail?vid=12&amp;amp;hid=7&amp;amp;sid=388643a5-dcc1-4cab-910e-d74d735cbe19%40sessionmgr13&amp;amp;bdata=JnNpdGU9ZWhvc3QtbGl2ZQ%3d%3d#db=i3h&amp;amp;AN=16409560}}&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

==See also==
*[[Outline of law enforcement]] - structured list of topics related to law enforcement, organized by subject area
*[[Coming into force]]
*[[Criminal law]]
*[[Law]]
*[[Law enforcement organization]]
*[[Law enforcement agency powers]]
*[[Specialist law enforcement agency]]
*[[Law and order (politics)]]
*[[Law enforcement and society]]
*[[Police]]
*[[Secret police]]

==References==
{{reflist}}

==External links==
{{wiktionary|law enforcement}}
*[http://biosecuritycommons.org/index.php?title=Law_Enforcement Biosecurity Commons]

[[Category:Law enforcement| ]]
{{Africa topic|Law enforcement in}}
{{Asia topic|Law enforcement in}}
{{North America topic|Law enforcement in}}
{{Europe topic|Law enforcement in}}
{{South America topic|Law enforcement in}}&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
