<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="University of Manitoba Students&#x27; Union"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="University of Manitoba Students&#x27; Union" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Infobox Students Union
| name               = University of Manitoba Students&amp;apos; Union
| image              = [[Image:University of Manitoba Students&amp;apos; Union logo new.jpg]]
| motto              =
| established        = 1919
| institution        = [[University of Manitoba]]
| president          = Al Turnbull
| vice presidents    = Amanda McMullin, Susie Ally, Christian Pierce, Thao Lam
| treasurer          =
| other officers     =
| location           = Winnipeg, Manitoba
| members            = 23,000+
| affiliated         = [[Canadian Federation of Students|CFS]], CFS-Manitoba
| colours            =
| free_label         = Campus businesses
| free               = The Hub (pub), IQ&amp;apos;s (pool hall/coffee shop), Degrees (restaurant), Archives (used textbook store), GPAs (convenience store), Digital Copy Centre (print shop)
| homepage           = http://www.umsu.ca/
}}
The &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;University of Manitoba Students&amp;apos; Union&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (UMSU) is the university-wide representative body for undergraduate students at the [[University of Manitoba]], located in [[Winnipeg]], [[Manitoba]], [[Canada]]. It was established in 1919, replacing the former University of Manitoba Students&amp;apos; Association established in 1914. Its head office is located at 101 University Centre, at the Fort Garry Campus of the University of Manitoba. UMSU is Local 103 of the [[Canadian Federation of Students]].

== Businesses &amp;amp; Services ==
The UMSU operates six student businesses on campus, including Degree&amp;apos;s (a restaurant), G.P.A.&amp;apos;s (a convenience store), IQ&amp;apos;s (a pool hall and coffee shop), Archives (a used bookstore for textbooks), Answers (an information booth also responsible for selling things like bus passes and concert tickets), and the Copy Centre. The organization has also recently acquired and renovated a space on the Fort Garry campus for The Hub (an on-campus pub), which opened in May 2012.

The union also operates a number of non-business operations, such as UMSU Living (for assistance with off-campus housing), the Bison Patrol (named after the campus athletic team name, the [[Manitoba Bisons]], it serves as a short-distance transportation service around campus), the Gallery of Student Art (which displays art installations created by students), the Grocery Run (which supplies students living in [[dormitory|residence]] with an opportunity to purchase groceries from the local grocery store), a tutor registry, a carpool registry and a Food Bank for students. It also administers a number of [[scholarships]] and [[bursaries]], travel [[Grant (money)|grants]], as well as providing funding for the student radio station, [[CJUM]], more popularly known as UMFM.

==Political structure==
The UMSU is run by a five-person elected executive, which includes a [[President]] and four [[Vice-President]]s. The four Vice-Presidents are each responsible for a different portfolio: Internal; External; Student Services; and Advocacy. Other than the membership itself, UMSU Council is the highest authority in the organization, and is made up of student representatives from each of the faculties, schools, student residences, the Inner-City Campus, and five positions for community representatives. Each faculty, school or residence has at least one representative, with some having up to four, depending on student population. The five community representatives represent marginalized communities of the student body: womyn students, international students, students living with disabilities, LGBTTQQ* students, and aboriginal students. The Council also has a number of committees that deal with specific areas, such as Policy and Bylaws, Finance, Campaigns and Governments Relations and Health and Dental Insurance Plan.

==References==
&amp;lt;references /&amp;gt;

==External links==
* [http://www.umsu.ca/ University of Manitoba Students&amp;apos; Union]
* [http://www.umanitoba.ca/ University of Manitoba]
{{Commons}}
{{Csa}}
{{Education by subject}}
{{Reflist}}
[[Category:Students&amp;apos; associations in Canada]]
[[Category:University of Manitoba]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
