<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Coat of arms of Colombia"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Coat of arms of Colombia" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Unreferenced|date=May 2009}}
{{Infobox coat of arms
|name             = Coat of arms of Colombia
|image            = Coat of arms of Colombia.svg
|image_width      = 250
|middle           =
|middle_width     =
|middle_caption   =
|lesser           =
|lesser_width     =
|lesser_caption   =
|armiger          = [[Republic of Colombia]]
|year_adopted     = 9 May 1834
|crest            = [[Andean condor]] proper with wings inverted displayed, facing dexter with an olive branch on bill, a Or ribbon in base
|torse            =
|shield           = Tierced per fess Azure, Platinum and Azure, in centre chief a  [[Pomegranate]] Or between in sinister chief a Cornucopia overflowing with coins Or and in dexter chief a cornucopia Or overflowing with fruits and vegetables proper, in center point a [[Phrygian cap]] Gules held on a [[Lance]] proper, in base the Isthmus of Panama Vert fesswise between two Ships Sable, sailed Argent.
|supporters       = [[Flag of Colombia|Flags of Colombia]]
|compartment      =
|motto            = &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Libertad y Orden&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; &amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;quot;Liberty and Order&amp;quot;
|orders           =
|other_elements   =
|earlier_versions =
|use              =
}}

The &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;coat of arms of [[Colombia]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; contains a shield with numerous symbols.  Perched on top of the shield is an [[Andean Condor]] holding an olive crown and the condor symbolizing freedom. The [[national motto]], &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Libertad y Orden&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (Spanish for &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Liberty and Order&amp;apos;&amp;apos;), is on a scroll in between the bird and the shield in black font over golden background. The condor is depicted facing front with his wings extended and looking to the right.

==Description==
The [[Flag of Colombia|national flag]] is draped on each side of the shield. The shield is broken into three portions. In the lowermost portion is a depiction of ships, pointing to the maritime history of Colombia, namely to the [[Isthmus of Panama]], which was part of Colombia until 1903. Nowadays represents the two oceans that border the country (Atlantic and Pacific). The sails mean the Colombian commerce with the rest of the world and the rising economy. In the middle section, over a [[field (heraldry)|field]] of [[platinum]], the [[Phrygian cap]] is presented; this being a traditional symbol of liberty and freedom. The topmost section contains a [[pomegranate]] over a field of [[azure (heraldry)|azure]], as a symbol of the [[Viceroyalty of New Granada]] (early colonial name of Colombia back in 18th century), in the middle flanked by two &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[cornucopia]]s&amp;apos;&amp;apos; or horns of plenty: the one at the right with golden and silver coins and the one at the left with tropical fruits. This portion represents the agricultural and mineral wealth of Colombian soil.

The Coat of Arms of the Republic was designed by [[Francisco de Paula Santander]], and was adopted via Act 3 of May 9, 1834, with later non-essential modifications according to Ordinance 861 of 1924.

==Criticism==
Some critics have argued that the coat of arms is outdated and [[anachronistic]], being the Andean Condor a very threatened species in the country, with barely 100 creatures soaring the landscape. It has also been discussed that the condor is still a vulture and feeds of [[carrion]], making it an animal with a low profile that never hunts its own food. In addition, the andean condor is also the national bird of [[Ecuador]], [[Bolivia]] and [[Chile]]. The pomegranate, being a [[Mediterranean]] fruit, is not currently cultivated in Colombia and the phrygian cap is of [[Greek people|Greek]] origin. The [[Isthmus of Panama]], no longer belonging to Colombia, has also been suggested to be changed.

==See also==
* [[Flag of Colombia]]
* [[National Anthem of Colombia|¡Oh, Gloria Inmarcesible!]]

==References==
{{reflist|}}

==External links==
{{Commons category|Coats of arms of Colombia}}

{{Symbols of Colombia}}
{{Coats of arms of South America}}

{{DEFAULTSORT:Coat Of Arms Of Colombia}}
[[Category:National coats of arms|Colombia]]
[[Category:Colombian coats of arms| ]]
[[Category:National symbols of Colombia]]

{{Link GA|es}}&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
