<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Isogamy"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Isogamy" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Refimprove|date=December 2009}}
[[Image:Isogamy.svg|thumb|Different forms of isogamy: A) isogamy of motile cells, B) isogamy of non-motile cells, C) conjugation]]

&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Isogamy&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is a form of [[sexual reproduction]] that involves [[gamete]]s of similar [[Morphology (biology)|morphology]] (similar shape and size), differing only in [[allele]] [[Gene expression|expression]] in one or more [[mating-type region]]s. Because both gametes look alike, they cannot be classified as &amp;quot;[[male]]&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;[[female]].&amp;quot; Instead, organisms undergoing isogamy are said to have different [[mating type]]s, most commonly noted as &amp;quot;+&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;-&amp;quot; strains, although in some species there are more than two mating types (designated by numbers or letters). [[Fertilization]] occurs when gametes of two different mating types fuse to form a [[zygote]].

==Evolution==
It appears that isogamy was the first stage of [[sexual reproduction]]. In several lineages (plants, animals), this form of reproduction independently evolved to [[anisogamy|anisogamous]] species with [[gamete]]s of male and [[female]] types to [[oogamy|oogamous]] species in which the female gamete is very much larger than the male and has no ability to move. There is a good argument that this pattern was driven by the physical constraints on the mechanisms by which two gametes get together as required for [[sexual reproduction]].&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;Dusenbery, David B. (2009). &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Living at Micro Scale&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, Chapter 20. Harvard University Press, Cambridge, Mass. ISBN 978-0-674-03116-6.&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

==Biological types==
There are several types of isogamy. Both gametes may be [[Flagellum|flagellated]] and thus [[Motility|motile]]. This type occurs for example in [[algae]] such as &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Chlamydomonas]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos; and other plants.

In another type, neither of the gametes is flagellated. This is the case for example in the [[mating of yeast]]. Yeast mating types are commonly noted as &amp;quot;a&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;α&amp;quot; (alpha) instead of &amp;quot;+&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;-&amp;quot;.

Another, more complex form, is conjugation. This occurs in some green algae, for example in &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Spirogyra]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos;. These algae grow as filaments of cells. When two filaments of opposing mating types come close together, the cells form conjugation tubes between the filaments. Once the tubes are formed, one cell balls up and crawls through the tube into the other cell to fuse with it, forming a zygote.

[[Fungus|Fungi]] and [[ciliates]] also use conjugation. In [[zygomycete]]s, two [[hyphae]] of opposing mating types form special structures called [[gametangia]] where the hyphae touch. The gametangia then fuse into a [[zygospore|zygosporangium]]. In other fungi, cells from two hyphae with opposing mating types fuse, but only cytoplasmic ([[plasmogamy]]). The two nuclei do not fuse, leading to the formation of a [[dikaryon]] cell that gives rise to a [[mycelium]] consisting of dikaryons. [[Karyogamy]] (fusion of nuclei) occurs in [[sporangia]] and leads to the formation of diploid cells (zygotes) that immediately undergo [[meiosis]] to form [[spore]]s.
[[File:SpirogyraConjugation100x5.jpg|thumb|Spirogyra conjugation]]
In many cases, isogamous fertilization is used by organisms that can also reproduce asexually through [[binary fission]], [[budding]], or asexual [[spore formation]]. The switch to [[sexual reproduction]] mode is often triggered by a change from favorable to unfavorable growing conditions.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;Bernstein H, Bernstein C and Michod RE (2011). Meiosis as an Evolutionary Adaptation for DNA Repair. Chapter in &amp;apos;&amp;apos;DNA Repair&amp;apos;&amp;apos; Inna Kruman (Ed.), ISBN: 978-953-307-697-3, InTech (Publisher). Available online from: http://www.intechopen.com/books/dna-repair/meiosis-as-an-evolutionary-adaptation-for-dna-repair&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt; Fertilization often leads to the formation of a thick-walled zygotic [[resting spore]] that can withstand harsh environments and will germinate once growing conditions turn favorable again.

==Isogamy in social anthropology==
The term isogamy is also used in anthropology to refer to [[marriage]] between people of equal [[social status]] or [[caste]].{{Citation needed|date=December 2009}}

==See also==
===Biology===
* [[Anisogamy]]
* [[Evolution of sexual reproduction]]
* [[Gamete]]
* [[Mating in fungi]]
* [[Meiosis]]
* [[Oogamy]]
* [[Sex]]

===Social anthropology===
* [[Hypergamy]]
* [[Hypogamy]]

==Notes and references==
&amp;lt;references/&amp;gt;

[[Category:Reproduction]]
[[Category:Germ cells]]
[[Category:Charophyta]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
