<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Stejneger&#x27;s beaked whale"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Stejneger&#x27;s beaked whale" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Automatic taxobox
| status = DD
| status_system = iucn3.1
| status_ref = &amp;lt;ref name=iucn&amp;gt;{{IUCN2008|assessors=Taylor, B.L., Baird, R., Barlow, J., Dawson, S.M., Ford, J., Mead, J.G., Notarbartolo di Sciara, G., Wade, P. &amp;amp; Pitman, R.L.|year=2008|id=13252|title=Mesoplodon stejnegeri|downloaded=24 March 2009}} Database entry includes a brief justification of why this species is of data deficient.&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;
| image = Stejneger&amp;apos;s_beaked_whale_size.svg
| image_caption = Size comparison against an average human
| taxon = Mesoplodon stejnegeri
| binomial = &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Mesoplodon stejnegeri&amp;apos;&amp;apos;
| binomial_authority = True, 1885
| range_map = Cetacea range map Stejneger sBeaked Whale.png
| range_map_caption = Stejneger&amp;apos;s Beaked Whale range
}}

&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Stejneger&amp;apos;s beaked whale&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Mesoplodon stejnegeri&amp;apos;&amp;apos;), sometimes known as the &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Bering Sea beaked whale&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; or the &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Saber-toothed whale&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, is a poorly-known member of the genus &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Mesoplodon]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos; inhabiting the northern North Pacific Ocean. [[Leonhard Hess Stejneger]] collected the type specimen (a beach-worn skull) on [[Bering Island]] in 1883, which provided the description by [[Frederick W. True]] in 1885. In 1904, the first complete skull (from an adult male that had stranded near [[Newport, Oregon]]) was collected, which confirmed the species&amp;apos; validity.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;True, F.W. 1910. &amp;apos;&amp;apos;An account of the beaked whales of the family Ziphiidae in the collection of the United States National Museum, with remarks on some specimens in other American museums&amp;apos;&amp;apos;. Washington: Government Printing Office.&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt; The most noteworthy characteristic of the males is the very large, saber-like teeth, hence the name.

==Description==
The body for this species is rather typical for a mesoplodont, long and tapering at both ends. The beak of the whale is of medium length, and the mouthline forms an arch, though much smoother than other species. The teeth of the males are much larger than those of most other mesoplodonts and point forwards and inwards right in front of the apex. Only [[Strap-toothed whale]] and the [[Spade-toothed whale]] have longer teeth. The coloration is overall dark gray to black on the body with light coloration below, and around the head giving it a &amp;quot;helmeted&amp;quot; appearance. The coloration darkens with age, but females have a light pattern on the bottom of the flukes which become more apparent with age. Like most species, scars occur on the males (from other males) and [[cookie cutter shark]] bites are present on both sexes. The length is at least 5.25 meters (17 feet 6&amp;amp;nbsp;inches) for males and 5.5 meters (18&amp;amp;nbsp;feet) for females. They are likely around 2.1 to 2.3 meters long (7 to 8 feet) when born.

==Population and distribution==
This is the northernmost species of beaked whale in the Pacific Ocean, ranging up into the Bering Sea. They are distributed along both sides of the Pacific to [[Miyagi Prefecture]], [[Japan]] and southern [[California]]. They may migrate south in winter. As with most species of beaked whales, no population estimates have been made.

==Behavior==
The whales are typically found in groups of 3 to 4 and sometimes up to 15 animals in a very close group. The groups may have age and sex segregation. Adult males fight each other extensively, and some specimens have been found with healed jaw fractures.

==Conservation==
This species has been occasionally hunted in Japan in the past, and occasionally been caught in driftnets. It is uncertain how much this affects the population.

==References==&amp;lt;!-- JZooWildlMed38:108. --&amp;gt;
{{Reflist}}

==Sources==
{{Portal|Cetaceans}}
*&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Encyclopedia of Marine Mammals&amp;apos;&amp;apos;. Edited by William F. Perrin, Bernd Wursig, and J.G.M Thewissen. Academic Press, 2002. ISBN 0-12-551340-2
*&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Sea Mammals of the World&amp;apos;&amp;apos;. Written by Randall R. Reeves, Brent S. Steward, Phillip J. Clapham, and James A. Owell. A &amp;amp; C Black, London, 2002. ISBN 0-7136-6334-0

==External links==
*[http://www.sci.tamucc.edu/tmmsn/29Species/MoreSpec/stejnegersbeakedwhale.html Cetaceans of the World]
*[http://www.cms.int/reports/small_cetaceans/data/m_stejnegeri/m_stejnegeri.htm CMS]
*[http://www.wdcs.org Whale &amp;amp; Dolphin Conservation Society (WDCS)]

{{Cetacea|O.1}}

{{DEFAULTSORT:Stejneger&amp;apos;s Beaked Whale}}
[[Category:Mesoplodont whales]]
[[Category:Animals described in 1885]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
