<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Tyrfing"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Tyrfing" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Other uses}}
{{Unreferenced|date=December 2009}}

[[File:King Svafrlame Secures the Sword Tyrfing.jpg|thumb|right|300px|Svafrlami secures the sword Tyrfing.]]
&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Tyrfing&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Tirfing&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; or &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Tyrving&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (The name is of uncertain origin, possibly connected to the [[Thervingi|Terwingi]]) was a [[magic sword]] in [[Norse mythology]], which figures in the &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Tyrfing Cycle]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, which includes a poem from the &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Poetic Edda]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos; called &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Hervararkviða]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, and the [[Hervarar saga]]. The name is also used in the saga to denote the [[Goths]]. The form &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Tervingi&amp;apos;&amp;apos; was actually recorded by Roman sources in the 4th century.

[[Svafrlami]] was the king of [[Gardariki]], and [[Odin]]&amp;apos;s grandson. He managed to trap the [[norse dwarves|Dwarves]] [[Dvalinn]] and [[Durin (Norse mythology)|Durin]] when they had left the rock where they dwelt. Then he forced them to forge a sword with a golden hilt that would never miss a stroke, would never rust and would cut through stone and iron as easily as through clothes.

The Dwarves made the sword, and it shone and gleamed like fire. However, in revenge they cursed it so that it would kill a man every time it was drawn and that it would be the cause of three great evils. They finally cursed it so that it would also kill Svafrlami himself.

When Svafrlami heard the curses he tried to slay Dvalin, but the Dwarf disappeared into the rock and the sword was driven deep into it, though missing its victim.

Svafrlami was killed by the [[berserker]] [[Arngrim]] who took the sword in his turn. After Arngrim, it was worn by [[Angantyr]] and his eleven brothers. They were all slain at [[Samsø]], by the Swedish champion [[Hjalmar]], and his Norwegian sworn brother [[Orvar-Odd]]; but [[Hjalmar]], being wounded by Tyrfing (its first evil deed), has only time to sing his death-song before he dies, and asks Orvar-Odd to bring his body to [[Yngvi and Alf#Hervarar Saga and the Saga of Orvar-Odd|Ingeborg, daughter of Yngvi]] at [[Gamla Uppsala|Uppsala]].

Angantyr&amp;apos;s daughter, [[Hervor]] (by his wife [[Tofa (Poetic Edda)|Tófa]]) is brought up as a bond-maid, in ignorance of her parentage. When at last she learns it, she arms herself as a [[shieldmaiden]], and goes to Munarvoe in [[Samsø]], in quest of the dwarf-cursed weapon. She finds it and marries King Gudmund&amp;apos;s son Höfund. They have two sons, Heidrek and Angantyr. Hervor secretly gave her son the sword Tyrfing. While Angantyr and Heidrek walked, Heidrek wanted to have a look at the sword. Since he had unsheathed it, the curse the Dwarves had put on the sword made Heidrek kill his brother Angantyr. This was the second of Tyrfing&amp;apos;s three evil deeds.

[[Heidrek]] became king of the Goths. During a voyage, Heidrek camped at the Carpathians (Harvaða fjöllum, cf. [[Grimm&amp;apos;s law]]). He was accompanied by eight mounted thralls, and when Heidrek slept at night, the thralls broke into his tent and took Tyrfing and slew Heidrek. This was the last one of Tyrfing&amp;apos;s three evil deeds. Heidrek&amp;apos;s son, also named [[Angantyr]], caught and killed the thralls, and reclaimed the magic sword, and the curse had ceased.

[[Angantyr]] was the next king of the Goths, but his illegitimate half-Hun brother [[Hlod]] (or Hlöd, Hlöðr) wanted half of the kingdom. Angantýr refused, and Gizur called Hlod a bastard and his mother a slave-girl. Hlod and 343,200 mounted Huns invade the Goths (See [[The Battle of the Goths and Huns]]). The Huns greatly outnumber the Goths.  The Goths won because Angantyr used Tyrfing. He killed his brother Hlod on the battleground. The bodies of the numerous warriors choke the rivers, causing a flood which filled the valleys with dead men and horses.

==See also==
*[[Tyrfing in popular culture]]
*[[Fornsigtuna]]

{{Notable swords}}
{{Tyrfing}}

[[Category:Artifacts in Norse mythology]]
[[Category:Mythological swords]]
[[Category:Tyrfing cycle]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
