<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Family court"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Family court" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Other uses}}
{{refimprove|date=July 2007}}

A &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;family court&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is a [[court]] convened to decide matters and make [[court order|orders]] in relation to [[family law]], such as [[child custody|custody of children]]. In common-law jurisdictions &amp;quot;family courts&amp;quot; are statutory creations primarily dealing with equitable matters devolved from a court of inherent jurisdiction, such as a superior court. The Family courts were first established in the United States in 1910, when they were called domestic relations courts although the idea itself is much older.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;{{cite web|title=Types of Cases Tried and Role of Court|url=family.laws.com/cases-tried-and-role-of-court/types-of-cases-tried-and-role-of-court|accessdate=2 December 2011}}&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

Family courts hear all cases that relate to familial and domestic relationships although each state has a different system utilized to address family law cases, each state strives to provide families with the best possible outcome in family law cases. Family courts can also issue decisions regarding divorce cases.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;{{cite web|title=Types of cases Tried and Role of Court|url=http://family.laws.com/cases-tried-and-role-of-court/types-of-cases-tried-and-role-of-court|accessdate=1 December 2011}}&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

== In the United States ==

In the United States family court falls under the heading of Trial Courts of Limited Jurisdiction. These types of courts deal only with a specific type of case and they are usually presided over by a single judge without a jury.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;{{cite web|title=Understanding Federal and State Courts|url=http://www.uscourts.gov/EducationalResources/FederalCourtBasics/CourtStructure/UnderstandingFederalAndStateCourts.aspx|accessdate=29 November 2012}}&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt; In the United States a family often will use mediation instead of a family court. This allows families to find solutions that suit their specific needs, rather than being forced to adhere to the ruling of a judge.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;{{cite web|title=Mediation|url=http://www.familycourt.us/Library/Mediation.html|accessdate=29 November 2012}}&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;The [[American Bar Association]] sites nearly 10,000 members in The Section of Family Law.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;{{cite web|title=Section of Family Law|url=http://www.americanbar.org/groups/family_law.html|accessdate=29 November 2012}}&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

== In the United Kingdom ==
Cases involving children are primarily dealt with under The Children Act 1989, amongst other statutes. Two types of scenario are covered by [[The Children Act]] 1989: private law cases, where the applicant and respondent are usually the child&amp;apos;s [[parent]]s; and public law cases, where the applicant is the local authority and the parents are usually respondents. There is much debate at present over whether the manner in which the law is administered generally leads to outcomes that are beneficial to the families concerned. In this context, see [[fathers&amp;apos; rights]].

If an accredited DNA tester is required the Ministry of Justice maintains a list of accredited laboratories to which to refer to.  Alpha Biolaboratories based in Warrington, UK is at the top of that list

Cases involving domestic violence are primarily dealt with under Part IV of the Family Law Act 1996.

== In India ==
The Family Courts Act, 1984 in India was enacted on 14th September, 1984 to provide for the family courts with a view to promoting conciliation in and secure speedy settlement of disputes relating to marriage and family affairs.  According to Section 2 (d) of the act, &amp;quot;Family Court&amp;quot; means a family court established under section 3. Section 3 describes the establishment of Family Courts and says that the State Government after consultation with the High Court and by notification shall establish a Family Court for every area of the state consisting of a city or town whose population exceeds ten lakhs and for other areas in the state as it may deem necessary.

The matters which are dealt in the Family Court in India are matrimonial relief which includes nullity of marriage, judicial separation, divorce, restitution of conjugal rights, declaration as to the validity of marriage and matrimonial status of the person, property of the spouses or any of them and declaration as to the legitimacy of any person, guardianship of a person or custody of any minor, maintenance including the proceeding under the Cr. P.C.

== References ==
&amp;lt;references /&amp;gt;

==See also==
* [[Family law]]
* [[Family Procedure Rules]]
* [[Subject-matter jurisdiction]]

{{DEFAULTSORT:Family Court}}
[[Category:Courts by type]]
[[Category:Family law]]

{{Law-stub}}
[[ar:محكمة الأسرة]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
