<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="File:Bahai how tehran.jpg"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="File:Bahai how tehran.jpg" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;== Summary ==
Architects elevation of proposed Baha&amp;apos;i temple, Tehran, Iran.

==Source==
This image was scanned from The Baha&amp;apos;i World volume XIV page 495.  That book, and its contents are copyright The Universal House of Justice, 1974.  The original image was prepared by Charles Mason Remy for the then head of the world Baha&amp;apos;i comminity Shoghi Effendi in the early 1950&amp;apos;s.  The use of this image has not been restricted by the House of Justice.


This is a unique image of a proposed building. Used in order to get a complete depiction of Baha&amp;apos;i places of worship. Also important as an example of the architecture used by the Baha&amp;apos;i.

This falls under Wikipedia&amp;apos;s fair use doctrine under the heading of: Images with iconic status or historical importance: As subjects of commentary.

==Fair use rationale for [[Bahá&amp;apos;í House of Worship]]==
#The image is of [[Charles Mason Remey]]&amp;apos;s drawing produced more than fifty years ago of the design for the Baha&amp;apos;i House of Worship in Tehran Iran.  It is iconic to Baha&amp;apos;is, and important for a complete illustration of the subject of Baha&amp;apos;i Houses of Worship.

Under the current Islamic republic government no opportunity for construction exists in the foreseeable future, therefore this image is the only image available anywhere period. Further a text-only description that the design was done is not the same thing as the design itself. Image scanned from design published in &amp;quot;The Baha&amp;apos;i World Volume IV page 495&amp;quot; - copyright held by the Universal House of Justice. (Identical images were published in most earlier volumes of The Baha&amp;apos;i World.

#The design is held by the Universal House of Justice  with few restrictions on its use, is in wide distribution as an image on Baha&amp;apos;i web sites and has no revenue potential to the Baha&amp;apos;i International Community or anyone else.
#This is a very small version of a photo of an architect&amp;apos;s drawing, and is used only one time.
#Source is in common use on Baha&amp;apos;i websites all over the world.
#This is the only extent image of the design for the Baha&amp;apos;i House of Worship in Tehran Iran, the home nation of the Baha&amp;apos;i Faith.

== Licensing ==
{{Non-free fair use in|Bahá&amp;apos;í House of Worship|image has rationale=yes}}
{{Non-free reviewed|date=03:06, 12 May 2011 (UTC)|user=[[User:Moe Epsilon|Moe Epsilon]]|pages=[[Bahá&amp;apos;í House of Worship]]}}

[[Category:Pictures of Bahá&amp;apos;í Houses of Worship]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
