<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="North China Coal Medical University"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="North China Coal Medical University" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Cleanup|date=October 2007}}
{{unreferenced|date=September 2012}}

&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;North China Coal Medical University&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (华北煤炭医学院 Huáběi méitàn yīxuéyuàn) is a university in [[Hebei]], [[People&amp;apos;s Republic of China|China]]. At one time it was the only medical university in China.

==History==
It was founded by a [[United Kingdom|British]] [[surgeon]] and now under provincial governance. The Coal Ministry is located in this major industrial city, Tangshan, Hebei Province. The university was founded in 1926. In August 1998, it was transformed into a university co-administered by the government of Hebei province as well as the Coal Ministry, and primarily administered by the former. After decades of expansion and development, it has now become to a multi-level, and multi-form educational and research institute.

==Structure==
The university has 1912 faculty and stuff with 700 professors. The university recruits students from all over the country. There are 11,772 undergraduates, 1300 graduate students, and 10000 students receiving career-education. It is composed of the main campus, the Qinghuangdao extension campus, one adult education institute, and the autonomous college Ji-Tang Institute.

It comprises 14 schools with 68 teaching and research sections. It offers 28 programs and grants medical and science degrees to students. As China’s reform is deepening in the higher education system, and especially since the country joined WTO, the university has established inter-university cooperative relationships with medical universities and research institutions in many countries including the USA, Japan, Germany, Austria, and Hungary. It has been accepting foreign students from Germany and Japan since 1991 and from Pakistan since 2007.

It now has 12 affiliated hospitals, 41 teaching and practicing hospitals. It publishes a number of journals, including the &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Journal of Chinese Clinical Medicine&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, the &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Journal of North China Coal Medical University&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, the &amp;apos;&amp;apos;China Coal Industry Medicine&amp;apos;&amp;apos; and the &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Chinese Journal of Psychologic Health&amp;apos;&amp;apos;.

==External links==
* [http://www.NCMC.edu.cn North China Coal Medical College Official Website]
{{Universities and colleges in Hebei}}

{{coord missing|Hebei}}

[[Category:Universities and colleges in Hebei]]
[[Category:Schools of medicine in China]]
[[Category:Educational institutions established in 1926]]

{{China-university-stub}}&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
