<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Inverse multiplexer"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Inverse multiplexer" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{refimprove|date=September 2009}}

An &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;inverse multiplexer&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (often abbreviated to &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;inverse mux.&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; or &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;imux.&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;) allows a [[data stream]] to be broken into multiple lower data rate [[communication link]]s.  An inverse multiplexer differs from a [[demultiplexer]] because the multiple output streams from the former stay inter-related, whereas those from the latter are unrelated.  An inverse multiplexer is the opposite of a [[multiplexer]] which divides one high speed link into multiple low speed links.

                                      | low rate link #1 |
 Tx — high rate data — inverse mux. — | low rate link #2 | — inverse demux. — rx
                                      | low rate link #3 |

This example provides an end to end connection of 3 times the data rate available on each of the low rate data links.  Note that, as with multiplexers, links are almost always bi-directional and, at either end of the link, an inverse mux will be combined with its reverse (an inverse demux) and still be called an &amp;apos;&amp;apos;inverse mux&amp;apos;&amp;apos;.

Inverse multiplexers are used, for example, to combine a number of [[Integrated Services Digital Network|ISDN]] channels together into one high rate circuit, where a higher rate connection than is available from a single [[Integrated Services Digital Network|ISDN]] connection is needed.   This is typically useful in areas where higher rate circuits are not available.

An alternative to an inverse mux. is to use three separate links and load sharing of data between them.  In the case of IP, network packets could be sent in [[round-robin scheduling#Data packet scheduling|round-robin]] mode between each separate link.  Advantages of using inverse multiplexing over separate links include:

* Lower link [[lag|latency]] (one single packet can be spread across all links)
* Fairer [[load balancing (computing)|load balancing]]
* Network simplicity (no [[Router (computing)|router]] needed between boxes with high speed [[network interface|interface]]s)

A simple analogy to transport can help explain the distinction between multiplexing and inverse multiplexing.  When small cargoes such as [[pencil]]s are shipped overseas, they are generally not carried one at a time.  Rather, they are assembled into small boxes, which are grouped into larger cartons, which go into [[intermodal container]]s, which join multiple containers aboard a [[container ship]].  Each step is a multiplexing.  Conversely a large cargo, for example in [[structure relocation]], may be disassembled for carriage on multiple vehicles and then reassembled in the correct order at the destination.  This is inverse multiplexing.

==See also==
*[[Bonding protocol]]
*[[Inverse Multiplexing for ATM]]
*[[Link aggregation]]
*[[Multiplexer-demultiplexer]]
*[[Point-to-Point Protocol#Multilink PPP|Multilink PPP]]
*[[Virtual concatenation]]

[[Category:Multiplexing]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
