<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Telecommunications in Albania"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Telecommunications in Albania" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;Until 1990, [[Albania]] was one of the world&amp;apos;s most isolated and controlled countries, and installation and maintenance of a modern system of international and domestic telecommunications was precluded. Callers previously needed operator assistance even to make domestic long-distance calls.

Albania&amp;apos;s telephone density was the lowest in [[Europe]], at 1.4 units for every 100 inhabitants. [[Tirana]] accounted for about 13,000 of the country&amp;apos;s 42,000 direct lines; [[Durrës]], the main port city, ranked second with 2,000 lines; the rest were concentrated in [[Shkodër, Albania|Shkodër]], [[Elbasan]], [[Vlorë]], [[Gjirokastër]], and other towns. At one time, each village had a telephone but during the land redistribution of the early 1990s peasants knocked out service to about 1,000 villages by removing telephone wire for fencing. Most of Albania&amp;apos;s telephones were obsolete, low-quality East European models, some dating from the 1940s; workers at a Tirana factory assembled a small number of telephones from Italian parts.

In the early 1990s, Albania had 240 microwave circuits to [[Italy]] and 180 to [[Greece]] carrying international calls. The Albanian telephone company had also installed two U-20 Italtel digital exchanges. The exchange in Tirana handled international, national, and local calls; the Durrës exchange handled only local calls. Two [[United States]] firms handled direct-dial calls from the United States to Tirana. At present the land lines are overloaded and it is difficult to receive a telephone number. As a result, the number of [[mobile phone]]s has skyrocketed in the bigger cities.

==Telephone system==
* Main lines in use: 316,400 (2008)
* Mobile cellular: 3.1 million (2008)

Despite investment in fixed lines, the density of main lines remains the lowest in Europe with nearly ten lines per 100 people (2008); however, cellular telephone use is widespread and generally effective.
* domestic: offsetting the shortage of fixed line capacity, mobile phone service has been available since 1996; by 2003 two companies were providing mobile services at a greater density than some of Albania&amp;apos;s Balkan neighbors
* international: inadequate fixed main lines; adequate cellular connections; international traffic carried by fiber optic cable and, when necessary, by microwave radio relay from the Tirana exchange to Italy and Greece (2003)

==Radio and television==
* Radio broadcast stations: FM 56 (3 national, 53 local), shortwave 1 (2008)
** Radios: 1 million (2001)
* Television broadcast stations: 76 (3 national, 73 local); note - 3 cable networks (2008)
**Televisions: 1 million (2008)

The state broadcaster in Albania is &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Radio Televizioni Shqiptar]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (RTSH). The broadcaster with the most audience is &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[TV Klan]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (according to a survey conducted in 2002).

==Internet==
* Internet Service Providers (ISPs): 10 (2001)
** Internet users: 1,000,000 (2009)
&amp;apos;&amp;apos;country comparison to the world:&amp;apos;&amp;apos; 98
* [[Country codes|Country code]]: AL

==References==
*{{CIA World Factbook}}
*{{loc}}
*&amp;apos;&amp;apos;This article contains material from [[ITU]] publications in the public domain&amp;apos;&amp;apos;.
*[http://www.kkrt.gov.al/images/stories/kkrt/files/projekti%20i%20strategjise.pdf KKRT (NCRT)]
*[http://www.regulateonline.org/intelecon/2003/July_2003/A-Albania-030704.htm Albania enhances telecom sale with mobile license]

==External links==
* [http://www.akep.al Authority of Electronic and Postal Communications (AKEP)]

==See also==

* [[Telephone numbers in Albania]]


{{Albania topics}}
{{Telecommunications}}


{{DEFAULTSORT:Telecommunications In Albania}}
[[Category:Telecommunications in Albania| ]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
