<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Nelder Grove"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Nelder Grove" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Nelder Grove&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is a [[list of sequoia groves|sequoia grove]] located in the [[Sierra National Forest]], [[Madera County, California]].  It is a 1540 acre (6.2 km²) tract containing over 100 mature [[Giant Sequoia]]s.  It also contains a number of sequoia stumps, left over from when the area was logged prior to its acquisition by the [[United States Forest Service]] in 1928.  A National Forest campground is also present.

==Noteworthy trees==
[[Image:Bull Buck.JPG|thumb|right|upright|Bull Buck Tree]]
Some of the trees and trails found in the grove that are worthy of special note are:

*Bull Buck Tree: this tree reaches a height of 246 feet (75 m) and has a ground-level circumference of 100 feet (30 m) but only a volume of {{convert|27383|cuft|m3}}, thus not among the top 40 giant sequoias.
*Graveyard of the Giants: an area which contains a number of large sequoias killed by a [[wildfire]], a fate rarely encountered due to the sequoia&amp;apos;s protective bark;
*Shadow of the Giants [[National Recreation Trail]]: a trail constructed in 1965 which was established as a National Recreation Trail in 1978;
*Remnants of the area&amp;apos;s logging days: including two restored cabins and replicas of cross-log and two-pole [[Log flume|log chute]]s.
*Nelder Tree: The largest tree in the grove at {{convert|34993|cuft|m3}}; it is the 22nd largest giant sequoia in the world.
*Old Grandad Tree: A tremendously rugged tree atop a hill, there is reason to believe this is a very old tree.

== Muir&amp;apos;s description ==

The area was logged extensively from 1878 until the mid-1890s by the [[Madera Flume and Trading]] company.  They logged mostly [[sugar pine]]s, [[ponderosa pine]]s, [[white fir]]s, and [[incense-cedar]]s, but they did cut down some of the sequoias as well.

The grove is named after [[John A. Nelder]], who was called by [[John Muir]] the &amp;quot;Hermit of the Fresno Forest&amp;quot;; Muir wrote about him and the area in 1878; the description was later included in his book &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Our National Parks]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos; [http://www.sierraclub.org/john_muir_exhibit/frameindex.html?http://www.sierraclub.org/john_muir_exhibit/writings/our_national_parks/chapter_9.html]:

:One of the first special things that caught my attention was an extensive [[landslide|landslip]]. The ground on the side of a stream had given way to a depth of about fifty feet [15 m] and with all its trees had been launched into the bottom of the stream ravine. Most of the trees--pines, firs, [[incense-cedar]], and Sequoia--were still standing erect and uninjured, as if unconscious that anything out of the common had happened. Tracing the ravine alongside the avalanche, I saw many trees whose roots had been laid bare, and in one instance discovered a Sequoia about fifteen feet [5 m] in diameter growing above an old prostrate trunk that seemed to belong to a former generation. This slip had occurred seven or eight years ago, and I was glad to find that not only were most of the Big Trees uninjured, but that many companies of hopeful seedlings and saplings were growing confidently on the fresh soil along the broken front of the avalanche. These young trees were already eight or ten feet [2 or 3 m] high, and were shooting up vigorously, as if sure of eternal life, though young pines, firs, and libocedrus were running a race with them for the sunshine with an even start. Farther down the ravine I counted five hundred and thirty-six promising young Sequoias on a bed of rough bouldery soil not exceeding two acres [8,000&amp;amp;nbsp;m²] in extent.

==External links==
*[http://www.fs.fed.us/r5/sierra/publications/maps/white_chief_mountain.htm Map of the area] (the White Chief Mountain Quad), from the [[Sierra National Forest]] website

{{Coord|37|26|N|119|35|W|display=title}}

[[Category:Giant sequoia groves]]
[[Category:Sierra National Forest]]
[[Category:Forests of California|Sequoiadendron]]
[[Category:Sierra Nevada (U.S.)]]
[[Category:Protected areas of Madera County, California]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
