<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Aquatic adaptation"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Aquatic adaptation" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Refimprove|date=July 2007}}

Several [[animal]] groups have undergone &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;aquatic adaptation&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, going from being purely terrestrial animals to living at least part of the time in water. The [[adaptation (biology)|adaptation]]s in early speciation tend to develop as the animal ventures into water in order to find available food. As successive generations spend more time in the water, natural selection causes the acquisition of more adaptations. Animals of later generations may spend the majority of their life in the water, coming ashore for mating. Finally, fully adapted animals may take to mating and birthing in water.

==Anapsid==
{{main|Anapsid}}
&amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Archelon]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is a type of giant [[sea turtle]] dating from the [[Cretaceous]] Period, now long extinct.  Its smaller cousins survive as the [[sea turtles]] of today.

&amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Mesosaurus]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (and other mesosaurids) were another group of anapsid [[reptiles]] to secondarily return to the sea, eschewing shells, and are also long extinct.

==Diapsid==
{{main|Diapsid}}
Living at the same time as, but not closely related to, dinosaurs, the [[mosasaur]]s resembled crocodiles but were more strongly adapted to marine life. They became extinct 65 million years ago, at the same time as the dinosaurs.

Modern diapsids which have made their own adaptions to allow them to spend significant time in the water include marine [[iguana]]s and marine [[crocodile]]s.  [[Sea snakes]] are extensively adapted to the marine environment, giving birth to live offspring in the same way as the Euryapsida (see below) and are largely incapable of terrestrial activity.  The arc of their adaptation is evident by observing the primitive [[Laticauda]] genus, which must return to land to lay eggs.

==Euryapsida==
{{main|Euryapsida}}
These marine reptiles had ancestors who moved back into the oceans, In the case of [[ichthyosaur]]s adapting as fully as the [[dolphins]] they superficially resemble, even giving birth to live offspring instead of laying eggs, in other cases more to the extent of the seal, as with [[plesiosaur]]s and [[placodont]]s.

==Cetacea==
{{Main|Cetacea|Evolution of cetaceans}}
During the [[Paleocene]] Epoch (about 55-65 million years ago), a group of [[wolf]]-like [[artiodactyl]]s related to &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Pakicetus]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos; began pursuing an amphibious lifestyle in rivers or shallow seas. They were the ancestors of modern whales, dolphins, and porpoises.  The cetacea are extensively adapted to marine life and cannot survive on land at all.  Their adaptation can be seen in many unique physiognomic characteristics such as the dorsal [[blowhole (anatomy)|blowhole]], [[baleen]] teeth, and the cranial &amp;apos;melon&amp;apos; organ used for aquatic [[Animal echolocation|echolocation]].  The closest extant terrestrial relative to the whale is the [[hippopotamus]], which spends much of its time in the water and whose name literally means &amp;quot;horse of the river.&amp;quot;

==Sirenians==
{{main|Sirenian|Evolution of sirenians}}
The ancestors of the [[dugong]] and [[manatee]]s first appeared in the fossil record about 45 to 50 million years ago in the ocean.

==Pinniped==
{{main|Pinniped}}
The fossil records show that [[phocid]]s existed 12 to 15 million years ago, and [[odobenid]]s about 14 million years ago. Their common ancestor must have existed even earlier than that.

==Polar bears==
{{main|Polar bear}}
Although still primarily a terrestrial animal, the polar bear shows the beginnings of aquatic adaptation to swimming (high levels of body fat and nostrils that are able to close), diving, and thermoregulation. Distinctly polar bear fossils can be dated to about 100,000 years ago. The polar bear has thick fur and layers of fat on its body to protect it from the cold.

==Speculative theories==
===Humans===
{{main|Aquatic ape hypothesis}}
Proponents of the aquatic ape hypothesis believe that part of [[human evolution]] includes some aquatic adaptation, which has been said to explain human hairlessness, [[bipedalism]], increased [[subcutaneous fat]], [[Larynx#Descended larynx|descended larynx]], [[vernix caseosa]], a hooded [[human nose|nose]] and various other physiological and anatomical changes.  The idea is not accepted by most scholars who study human evolution.&amp;lt;ref name = Meier&amp;gt;{{cite book | last = Meier | first = R | title = The complete idiot&amp;apos;s guide to human prehistory | publisher = Alpha Books | year = 2003 | isbn = 0-02-864421-2 | pages = [http://books.google.com/books?id=r_Wit4KYSmMC&amp;amp;pg=PA57 57–59]}}&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

==References==
{{reflist}}

{{aquatic ecosystem topics}}

[[Category:Aquatic organisms]]
[[Category:Biological evolution]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
