<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Dent v. West Virginia"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Dent v. West Virginia" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{SCOTUSCase
  |Litigants=Dent v. West Virginia
  |ArgueDate=
  |ArgueYear=
  |DecideDate=January 14
  |DecideYear=1889
  |FullName=Dent v. State of West Virginia
  |USVol=129
  |USPage=114
  |Citation=
  |Prior=
  |Subsequent=
  |Holding=The state can set reasonable requirements to obtain a medical license.
  |SCOTUS=1888-1889
  |Majority=Field
  |JoinMajority=unanimous court
  |Concurrence=
  |JoinConcurrence=
  |Concurrence2=
  |JoinConcurrence2=
  |Concurrence/Dissent=
  |JoinConcurrence/Dissent=
  |Dissent=
  |JoinDissent=
  |Dissent2=
  |JoinDissent2=
  |LawsApplied=
}}
&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Dent v. West Virginia&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, {{ussc|129|114|1889}}, was an important [[Supreme Court of the United States|United States Supreme Court]] case involving the reputable practice of physicians and state laws in the late 19th century.

==The Case==
Frank Dent was a physician of the [[Eclectic medicine|Eclectic sect]], a group which accepted and taught the conventional medical science of the time. However, in the area of therapeutics, the Eclectics carried on a rigorous campaign against excesses of drugging and bleeding, which were still practices used by many physicians at the time. In addition, all but one of their medical schools were open to women.

Dent had been in practice for six years when he was convicted under an 1882 [[West Virginia]] law which required physicians to hold a degree from a reputable medical college, pass an examination, or prove practice in West Virginia for the previous ten years. In this case, the State Board of Health refused to accept Dent&amp;apos;s degree from the American Medical Eclectic College of Cincinnati.

==The Decision==
Justice [[Stephen J. Field]] delivered the Court&amp;apos;s unanimous opinion which upheld the West Virginia statute. Field noted that each citizen had a right to follow any lawful calling, subject to natural restraints such as age, sex, etc., as well as state restrictions, as long as those state restrictions were reasonable. In addition, the Court ruled that medicine, because of the careful nature of its training, the large knowledge of the human body required of doctors, and nature of life-and-death circumstances with which doctors dealt, reliance needed to be placed on the assurance of a license. Certain circumstances might prompt states to exclude people without licenses from practicing medicine.

==Aftermath==
Later, the Court would extend its decision in the case &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Hawker v. New York]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, 170 U.S. 189 (1898) when it ruled that character was also an important qualification for doctors wishing to obtain a license.

==See also==
* &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Hawker v. New York]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, 170 U.S. 189 (1898)
*[[List of United States Supreme Court cases, volume 129]]

==External links==
{{wikisource}}
*[http://www.justia.us/us/129/114/case.html Full text of the decision &amp;amp; case resources from Justia &amp;amp; Northwestern-Oyez]
*[http://laws.findlaw.com/us/129/114.html Full text of the decision courtesy of Findlaw.com]

[[Category:United States Supreme Court cases]]
[[Category:United States substantive due process case law]]
[[Category:Legal history of West Virginia]]
[[Category:Medical regulation]]
[[Category:1889 in United States case law]]
[[Category:1889 in West Virginia]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
