<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="University Neighborhood, Syracuse, New York"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="University Neighborhood, Syracuse, New York" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Multiple issues
 | citation style=September 2009
 | refimprove=May 2008
}}
[[Image:Syracuse UA Neighborhood Sketch.png|thumb|150px|The University Neighborhood in relation to other nearby neighborhoods, with approximate boundaries. (Not to scale)]]

&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;The University Neighborhood&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is one of [[Syracuse, New York]]&amp;apos;s 26 officially recognized neighborhoods. It borders the neighborhoods of [[Westcott, Syracuse|Westcott]] to the north, [[University Hill, Syracuse|University Hill]] to the west, [[Outer Comstock]] to the southwest, [[Skytop, Syracuse|Skytop]] (South Campus) to the south, and [[Meadowbrook, Syracuse|Meadowbrook]] to the east.

The University Neighborhood is mostly residential, with only a few [[convenience store]]s located throughout. The neighborhood is close to retail and dining, however, with [[Westcott Street]] being lined with small shops and restaurants immediately to the north, and the Nottingham Plaza across East Colvin Street at its southeastern corner. This plaza has a grocery store, [[Eckerd]] drug store, liquor store, barber shop, as well as a [[UPS Store]] behind it. Additionally, [[Marshall Street]], the main retail area of adjacent University Hill is within a short walk of the northwestern corner of the neighborhood. The neighborhood is also home to the city&amp;apos;s only cooperative grocery store, the Syracuse Real Food Co-op.

==History==
Like its surrounding neighborhoods, the University Neighborhood grew as a result of the growth of Syracuse University, which was founded in 1870. Electric [[streetcar]]s ran along Euclid Avenue, its northern border. As the university continued to grow, particularly after [[World War II]], students moved into many of the houses along Euclid Avenue and its side streets. When the university went through a short period of enrollment decline in the early 1990s, it enacted a [[wiktionary:sophomore|sophomore]] residency requirement, which required second-year students to live in university housing. Previously only [[First year|freshmen]] were required to do so. As a result, some University Neighborbood buildings were acquired by non-students {{Citation needed|date=May 2008}}. It also includes the Berkeley Park Historic District [http://syracusethenandnow.org/Nghbrhds/BerkeleyPk/BerkeleyPk.htm].

==Conflicts==
&amp;lt;!-- Deleted image removed: [[Image:Syracuse Livingstock Riots.jpg|thumb|300px|Students during a block party on Livingston Avenue on the night of May 1, 1999. The party was supposed to end at 10 p.m., but rowdy students challenged police until 3 a.m. The event became known as the [[Livingstock Riots]].]] --&amp;gt;

Today the neighborhood consists of a mixture of families and students. This unusual combination results in vibrant diversity, but is also sometimes a cause of conflict due to differing priorities of the two groups. Though conflict is usually limited to noise complaints from late-night student parties, an extreme example occurred on May 1, 1999 when students hosted a [[block party]] on Livingston Avenue. Violence broke out when police arrived to end the party, causing the event to named the [[Livingstock Riots]]. Police used [[riot gear]] to break up the block party, which had spun out of control, leaving piles of furniture and debris burning in the streets. Subsequent block parties (resuming in 2007) have not featured violence.

==References==
* {{cite news | title=Off-campus residents face tougher law enforcement | date=9/5/2003 | publisher=The Daily Orange | url=http://www.dailyorange.com/news/2003/09/05/News/OffCampus.Residents.Face.Tougher.Law.Enforcement-458481.shtml}}
* {{cite web | title=Neighborhoods of Syracuse | work=City of Syracuse | url=http://www.syracuse.ny.us/nhood2.asp | accessdate=April 4, 2005 |archiveurl = http://web.archive.org/web/20050212195439/http://www.syracuse.ny.us/nhood2.asp &amp;lt;!-- Bot retrieved archive --&amp;gt; |archivedate = February 12, 2005}}
* {{cite web | title=Livingstock Riots | work=A.T. Marts | url=http://web.syr.edu/~atmarks/livingstock.html | accessdate=April 4, 2005}}

==External links==
* [http://www.unpa.net/index.htm University Neighborhood Preservation Association (UNPA)]
* [http://seuna.org Southeast University Neighborhood Association (SEUNA)]
* [http://syracusethenandnow.org/Nghbrhds/BerkeleyPk/BerkeleyPk.htm Syracuse Then and Now]
{{Syracuse Neighborhoods}}

{{coord missing|New York}}

[[Category:Neighborhoods in Syracuse, New York]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
