<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Zafarnamah"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Zafarnamah" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Zafarnāmah&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; {{IPAc-en|z|ə|f|ə|r|n|ɑː|m|ɑː}} ({{lang-pa|ਜ਼ਫ਼ਰਨਾਮਾ}}, {{lang-fa|{{nastaliq|ظفرنامہ}}}}, {{lang-hi|ज़फ़रनामा}}) means the &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Epistle of Victory&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; and is the name given to the letter sent by the tenth [[Sikh]] [[Guru]], [[Guru Gobind Singh|Guru Gobind Singh Sahib]] in 1705 to the [[Mughal Empire|Mughal]] Emperor of India, [[Aurangzeb]]. The letter is written in [[Persian language|Persian]] verse.

Guru Gobind Singh sent Bhai Daya Singh to Ahmednagar to give it to Aurangzeb.
The Original letter written in the hand of Guru Ji in not available. However it is said that a copy of Zafarnama, written in the hand of Guru Ji, was found with the Mahant of Patna Sahib in 1890 and one Babu Jagan Nath made a copy; this copy was somehow misplaced by him. Since Babu Jagan Nath was himself a scholar in [[Persian language]], he could reproduce it from his memory and got it printed in Nagri Parcharni Patrika in Benaras. He is also believed to have sent a copy to Sardar Umrao Singh Shergill in Amritsar who is said to have given it to Khalsa college and which in turn reproduced in Makhz-E-Twarikh Sikhan. In Punjab newspapers, it first appeared in the Khalsa Samachar of 16 July 1942. Then in 1944, Sardar Kapur Singh ICS published it in Urdu Ajit of Lahore under the heading &amp;quot;Fatehnama&amp;quot;. It is quite possible that in the process of translations and publications of Zafarnama at different stages, some verses were not reproduced correctly and what we have today is not the original Zafarnama of Guru Ji in its entirety. The abrupt end of Zafarnama also indicates that it is not complete and that some verses have been left out. Objections raised by some scholars on the authenticity of a few verses may be viewed in this context.

In this letter, [[Guru Gobind Singh]] reminds [[Aurangzeb]] how he and his henchmen had broken their oaths sworn upon the [[Quran]]. He also states that in spite of his several sufferings, he had won a moral victory over the Emperor who had broken all his vows. Despite sending a huge army to capture or kill the Guru, the Mughal forces did not succeed in their mission.

In the 111 verses of this notice, Guru Gobind Singh rebukes Aurangzeb for his weaknesses as a human being and for excesses as a leader. Guru Ji also confirms his confidence and his unflinching faith in the Almighty even after suffering extreme personal loss of his father, mother, and all four of his sons to Aurangzeb.
Guru ji invited aurenzeb to meet him in Kangar village near bhatinda and said no need to worry as Brar tribe will not harm him(Aurugzeb) as they are under his command.On the way, there will be no danger to your life,
For, the whole tribe of Brars accepts my command. (59)


Of the 111 verses, the maximum numbers of 34 verses are to praise God; 32 deal with Aurangzeb’s invitation for the Guru to meet him and the Guru&amp;apos;s refusal to meet the Emperor - instead the Guru asks Aurangzeb to visit him; 24 verses detail the events in the [[Battle of Chamkaur]], which took place on 22 December 1704; 15 verses reprove Aurangzeb for breaking promise given by him and by his agents to the Guru; In verses 78 and 79, Guru Gobind had also warned Aurangzeb about the resolve of the [[Khalsa]] not to rest till his evil empire is destroyed; 6 verses praise Aurangzeb.

Guru Gobind Singh wrote this letter from village [[Dina]] in [[Malwa (Punjab)|malwa region]] of the [[Punjab region|Punjab]]. &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Guru Gobind Singh&amp;apos;&amp;apos; spent few days at [[Dina]] and then moved to Dod, [[Kotkapura]], [[Dhilwan Kalan]], [[Jaitu]], [[Muktsar]], [[Lakhi Jangal]], and [[Damdama Sahib]]. Guru Gobind Singh&amp;apos;s last fight with Mughal Army happened at &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Khidrane Di Dhaab&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; now called [[Sri Muktsar Sahib]].

One of the most quoted verses from Zafarnamah is a couplet quoted by Guru Gobind Singh from [[Saadi (poet)|Saadi]]&amp;apos;s [[Bostan (book)|Bostan]]:

:&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Chu kar az hama heelt e dar guzshat,&amp;apos;&amp;apos;
:&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Halal ast burdan ba shamsheer dast.&amp;apos;&amp;apos;
:&amp;quot;All modes of redressing the wrong having failed,
:raising of sword is pious and just.&amp;quot;

==External links==
*[http://www.panjabdigilib.org/webuser/searches/displayPage.jsp?ID=369&amp;amp;page=1&amp;amp;CategoryID=3&amp;amp;Searched= Manuscripts of Zafarnama]
*[http://www.sikhs.org/transl5.htm English Translation of Zafarnama]
*[http://www.zafarnama.com/Pages/Download.html Zafarnama in Gurmukhi, Perso-Arabic and Latin script with English translations]
*[http://www.5abi.com/itihasak/zafarnama-h1.htm: Epistle of Victory]
*[http://www.hindustantimes.com/news/181_612147,0011000100070003.htm Hindustan Times, The Zafarnama]

{{Dasven Padshah Da Granth}}

{{Sikhism}}

[[Category:Sikh literature]]
[[Category:History of Sikhism]]
[[Category:Persian literature]]
[[Category:Dasam Granth]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
