<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="XDC"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="XDC" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Advert|date=March 2011}}
{{Infobox Company |
company_name             = XDC|
company_logo             = [[Image:XDC logo+baseline.jpg|190px]]|
company_type           = Member Company of EVS group |
foundation               = 8 June2004 by Laurent Minguet|
location                  =  [[Belgium]] (headquarters), [[France]], [[Germany]], [[Spain]]|
industry                = [[Digital cinema]]|
num_employees       = 50 |
homepage               = [http://www.dcinex.com/ www.dcinex.com]
}}

&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;XDC&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, a member company of EVS, was created in 2004 by Laurent Minguet but changed its name to dcinex in 2012. It is a digital distribution company based in [[Liège (city)|Liège]] (in [[Belgium]]) but it also has offices in [[France]], [[Spain]] and [[Germany]]. The principal activities of dcinex are [[digital cinema]], distribution of alternative content (Ddcinema) and development of the Cinestore products.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;
{{cite news|url=http://www.variety.com/article/VR1117946179.html?categoryid=18&amp;amp;cs=1|title=XDC expands network - Entertainment News, Business News, Media -
|publisher=Variety|accessdate=2008-01-23|last=Barraclough|first=Leo | date=2006-06-29}}&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;{{cite web|url=http://www.iht.com/articles/2005/05/22/yourmoney/movies23.php
|title=Nurturing digital cinema|publisher=International Herald Tribune|accessdate=2008-01-23|last=|first=}}&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

==Digital cinema==
The digital content lab of XDC prepares digital content for distribution. It creates the different versions and sub-titles and performs quality controls.
The company is the first entity to have VPF digital cinema deployment agreements with all the 6 major US studios Warner, Fox, Universal, Paramount, Sony and Disney for a total of 8,000 digital screens in 22 European countries. Today, XDC has signed VPF deals with exhibitors for about 1,000 screens spread over 11 European countries (Austria, Portugal, Germany, Switzerland, Spain, Belgium, The Netherlands, Hungary, Czech Republic, Slovakia and Poland). XDC has also achieved a global financing of 100 millions Euros with Fortis Bank to allow the VPF roll out of 2,000 digital screens in the first phase of its European deployment program.
XDC is also responsible for installing and maintaining the equipment, and training operators. XDC is currently in charge of more than 500 screens in 10 European countries ([[Sweden]], [[Belgium]], [[The Netherlands]], [[Luxembourg]], [[France]], [[Spain]], [[Germany]], [[Austria]], [[Switzerland]] and [[Poland]]) and its aim is to reach 1500 screens, in order to create the first European digital cinema network.

==Distribution of alternative content==
In December 2007, XDC has signed an agreement with Qubo and Dynamic to create DDcinema, a company dedicated to the distribution of digital cinema alternative content (mainly lyrical operas).

==Development of the Cinestore products==
The CineStore Systems include a comprehensive suite of high end Digital Cinema solutions. The products and tools are designed and developed in compliance with the international standards. The most advanced technologies are integrated into our CineStore Systems in order to take into account the most severe constraints of flexibility, security and reliability.
The CineStore Systems include:
Solo G3
The CineStore Solo G3 is a hybrid digital cinema server offering both JPEG 2000 and MPEG-2 play-back capabilities. It is used as Screen Management System (SMS).

Audi
The CineStore Audi is an advanced device which provides digital to analogue conversion, external analogue audio source inputs and high quality signal isolation.

Plaza
The CineStore Plaza is a hardware and software suite that enables to fully manage a cinema multiplex from a single point. It is used as Theatre Management System (TMS). The CineStore Plaza is provided with a Library in order to build a fully central networked asset management system into the cinema multiplex.

==Awards==
XDC has received the Bravo Award 2007 at the [[Venice Film Festival]] for its involvement in the digital cinema and is the official partner of [[Cannes Film Festival]] and [[Locarno Film Festival]].

==See also==
*[[Digital cinema]]

==References==
{{reflist}}

==External links==
* [http://www.xdcinema.com XDC official website]
* [http://www.evs.tv EVS Broadcast Equipment website]

{{DEFAULTSORT:Xdc}}
[[Category:Companies established in 2004]]
[[Category:Information technology companies of Belgium]]
[[Category:Digital media]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
