<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Background music"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Background music" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{For|the 2001 album by Give Up the Ghost|Background Music (album)}}
{{Multiple issues|
{{unreferenced|date=November 2010}}
{{essay|date=July 2009}}
{{cleanup|date=September 2009}}
{{cleanup-rewrite|date=September 2009}}
}}

&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Background music&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; refers to various styles of [[music]] or [[soundscape]]s primarily intended to be passively listened to. It is not meant to be the main focus of an audience, but rather to supplement that which is meant to be focused upon. Music that is played at a low volume and is not the main focus of an audience is also referred to as background music. Traditional examples of background music include music played at various [[Party|social gatherings]] and music played in certain [[Retail|retail venues]]. It is also common to employ background music in various [[electronic media]] including film, television, and [[Internet]] [[video]]s such as [[video blogs]].

==Antecedents==
In the [[Baroque music|Baroque]] and [[Classical music era]] music could be performed as a background to other activities. For instance:
*French kings of the baroque era could have music performed during their stately dinners.
*Opera or other public music performances could have such a high &amp;quot;[[social function]]&amp;quot; character that few people would actually listen to the music being performed.

==Ambient music==
{{Main|Ambient music}}
The term &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Ambient music&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is generally used when more, but often less distinguishable, influences, like elements of [[Jazz]] or sounds from nature, are mingled in the &amp;quot;[[soundscape]]&amp;quot;. However, some producers and composers of &amp;quot;ambient music&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;soundscapes&amp;quot; (as well as similar types of music) might not intend to use the qualifier &amp;quot;background&amp;quot; for their music.

==Incidental music==
{{Main|Incidental music}}
Incidental music is music in a play, radio/TV program or some other form that is not primarily musical, adding atmosphere to the action. It can be dated back at least as far as Greek drama. A number of classical composers have written incidental music for various plays.

==Furniture music==
{{Main|Furniture music}}
Furniture music was an invention of [[Erik Satie]] around 1920. It fell into oblivion when the composer died a few years later, and was not again executed until it was rediscovered several decades later. Typical of &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Furniture music&amp;apos;&amp;apos; are short musical passages, with an indefinite number of repeats.

==Elevator music==
{{Main|Elevator music}}
Elevator music is a more general term indicating music that is played in rooms where many people come together (that is, with no intention whatsoever to listen to music). There is a specific &amp;apos;&amp;apos;sound&amp;apos;&amp;apos; associated with elevator music, usually involving themes from &amp;quot;soft&amp;quot; popular music or &amp;quot;light&amp;quot; classical music being worked over by slow strings. This type of music was produced, for instance, by the [[Mantovani|Mantovani Orchestra]], and conductors like [[Franck Pourcel]] and [[James Last]], peaking in popularity around the 1970s.

==Video game and blog music==
Background music (often abbreviated &amp;quot;BGM&amp;quot;) is the [[video game music|music in video games]] (sometimes written &amp;quot;VGM&amp;quot;) and music in websites.

==Internet delivered background music==
In recent years the proliferation of Internet delivered background music by such companies as [[Trusonic]] has gained traction.  This allows the retailer to instantly update music and messages which are deployed at the store level as opposed to using older [[compact disc]] and [[satellite]] technologies.

==See also==
*[[Applied Media Technologies Corporation]]
*[[DMX (music)|DMX]]
*[[PlayNetwork]]
*[[Trusonic]]
*[[Muzak Holdings LLC]]
*[[Jamendo]]

{{DEFAULTSORT:Background Music}}
[[Category:Easy listening music]]
[[Category:Industrial music services]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
