<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Flying Saucers (magazine)"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Flying Saucers (magazine)" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Refimprove|date=January 2009}}

&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Flying Saucers&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; was a [[magazine]] published and edited by [[Raymond A. Palmer]], devoted to articles on [[UFOs]] and the [[Shaver Mystery]].&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;Flying Saucers From Other Worlds June 1957 Issue No. 1, August 1957 &amp;amp; July-August 1958 issues&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt; The magazine was first published as &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Flying Saucers from Other Worlds&amp;apos;&amp;apos; in 1957, before evolving into &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Flying Saucers&amp;apos;&amp;apos; in 1958.  The initial title was designed to create confusion with a science fiction magazine &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Other Worlds (magazine)|Other Worlds]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, which Palmer also published and which overlapped for two issues. Such confusion may have been designed to overcome the difficulty that a new magazine in a new category would have in finding space on news stands, to help attract readership, or more likely both. The confusion continues to tax collectors of science fiction magazines to this day.

&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Flying Saucers From Other Worlds&amp;apos;&amp;apos; was first published in June, 1957 and cost 35 cents an issue. The editorial by Ray Palmer on page 4 begins with &amp;quot;This is the first Flying Saucers From Other Worlds. Ray A. Palmer was Editor, Gray Barker was Eastern Editor and August C. Roberts was Photo Editor. Col. Ron Ormond was Western Editor several issues later. The front cover of issue number one was a composite from the movies Forbidden Planet&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Captive Women&amp;quot;. The editorial address was in Amherst, Wisconsin. The magazine itself was published by Palmer Publications, Inc. in Evanston, Illinois.

The second issue was published August, 1957 and the contents page stated that it was Issue No. 25 and subsequent issues were numbered accordingly based on that first incorrect issue number. Why the publishers did this is unknown.

The &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Flying Saucers From Other Worlds&amp;apos;&amp;apos; May, 1958 Issue No. 29 was the last one by that title. In the July-August 1958 Issue No. 30 the name of the magazine was changed to &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Flying Saucers, The Magazine of Space Conquest&amp;apos;&amp;apos;. Ray Palmer was still editor at that time.

An important &amp;quot;first&amp;quot; is found in the &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Flying Saucers&amp;apos;&amp;apos; edition of November 1963.  In an article &amp;quot;The Swofford UFO Detector&amp;quot;, written by 16-year-old Gregory Swofford of Milwaukee, Wisconsin, the author coined the term &amp;quot;ufology&amp;quot;.{{Cn|date=October 2012}}

==References==
{{Reflist|2}}

{{DEFAULTSORT:Flying Saucers (Magazine)}}
[[Category:Paranormal magazines]]


{{US-lit-mag-stub}}&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
