<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Vojta Beneš"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Vojta Beneš" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Unreferenced|date=December 2009}}
&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Vojta Beneš&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (May 17, 1878 – November 20, 1951) was a [[Czechoslovakia|Czechoslovak]] educator and political leader and brother of [[Edvard Beneš]].

Vojta Beneš was born in [[Kožlany]], [[Bohemia]], then a province of the [[Austro-Hungarian Empire]]. Beneš began his professional life as an educator at various institutions, and from 1913 to 1914 visited the United States to study its school systems. Returning to the United States with his wife, Emilie, and their children in 1915, he criss-crossed North America agitating for Czechoslovak independence from Austria.  For this and similar activities in the US during [[World War II]], he became known as &amp;quot;the Czech [[Paul Revere]].&amp;quot;

After freedom from Austrian rule and the establishment of the Czechoslovak republic in 1918, Vojta Beneš was active as both an educator and public servant. He worked as a provincial school inspector, and, from 1937, as the chief inspector of the national school system. A member of the Czech [[social democracy]], he served as a deputy in the Czechoslovak parliament from 1925 to 1935, and as senator in 1935, resigning the latter post upon his brother&amp;apos;s election to the presidency the following year. Beneš was additionally an official of the Czechoslovak legionary community and of the union of Czechoslovak teachers.

With the conclusion of the [[Munich Agreement]] in 1938 and the subsequent [[Nazism|Nazi]] conquest of Czechoslovakia, Beneš narrowly escaped to the U.S., where he began anew his campaigning for Czechoslovak freedom after nearly twenty-five years.

After the liberation of Czechoslovakia by [[Allied]] forces in 1945, Vojta Beneš returned to public life in his country, serving from 1946 to 1948 in the Constituent National Assembly.  Following the [[Stalinist]] accession to state power in 1948, Beneš, aided by the persuasive efforts of his daughter in [[Illinois]], returned for the third and final time to North America with the help of the U.S. [[State Department]].  He died in [[South Bend]], [[Indiana]], in 1951.  His remains were eventually returned to his homeland and interred in a cemetery in Prague.

He was the author of a number of works, including the war-time books &amp;apos;&amp;apos;The Mission of a Small Nation&amp;apos;&amp;apos; and &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Ten Million Prisoners&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, an illustrated volume of poetry for children, &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Naše Maminka&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (Our Mother), and others.

[[Emilie Benes Brzezinski]], a sculptor, is his granddaughter.

==See also==
* [[History of Czechoslovakia]]

{{Authority control|VIAF=13170291}}
{{Persondata &amp;lt;!-- Metadata: see [[Wikipedia:Persondata]]. --&amp;gt;
| NAME              = Benes, Vojta
| ALTERNATIVE NAMES =
| SHORT DESCRIPTION =
| DATE OF BIRTH     = May 17, 1878
| PLACE OF BIRTH    =
| DATE OF DEATH     = November 20, 1951
| PLACE OF DEATH    =
}}
{{DEFAULTSORT:Benes, Vojta}}
[[Category:1878 births]]
[[Category:1951 deaths]]
[[Category:People from Kožlany]]
[[Category:Czechoslovak politicians]]
[[Category:Czech people of World War II]]
[[Category:Recipients of the Order of Tomáš Garrigue Masaryk]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
