<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Quartermaster Center and School"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Quartermaster Center and School" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Use dmy dates|date=February 2013}}
{{Coord|37|14|39.8|N|77|20|47.6|W|display=title}}
[[Image:Qmschool patch.gif|thumb|Quartermaster Center and School shoulder sleeve insignia]]
The &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Quartermaster Center and School&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (QMCS) is a subordinate command of the [[United States Army]]&amp;apos;s [[Combined Arms Support Command]] and is located at [[Fort Lee, Virginia]].

==Shoulder Sleeve Insignia==

===Description===
On a buff lozenge shaped field with rounded points, 2 inches (5.08&amp;amp;nbsp;cm) in width and 3 inches (7.62&amp;amp;nbsp;cm) in height overall, a blue (ultramarine) torch with blue flames surmounted by a blue key and blue sword crossed in saltire.

===Symbolism===
Buff and blue are the colors of the Quartermaster Corps. The key and sword are taken from the Quartermaster Corps insignia.  The torch signifies knowledge and alludes to training in Quartermaster.

===Background===
The shoulder sleeve insignia was originally approved for the Quartermaster Training Command on 7 Nov 1956. It was redesignated for the U.S. Army Quartermaster Center and U.S. Army Quartermaster School on 23 Oct 1962. On 24 Nov 1975 the insignia was amended to change the colors of the insignia.

==Distinctive Unit Insignia==
[[Image:QMSchool-DUI.jpg|thumb|Quartermaster Center and School distinctive unit insignia]]

===Description===
Buff, a bend Azure fimbriated Argent, between in sinister chief the Liberty Bell and in dexter base the Lamp of Knowledge upon a closed book, all Proper (bronze bell, dark oak yoke, black iron bolts and straps; bronze lamp, red flame, blue book with gold lines and edges).

===Symbolism===
The distinctive insignia is the shield of the coat of arms of the U.S. Army Quartermaster School. The shield is buff, the color of the Quartermaster Corps, which with the blue bend gives the colonial colors and indicates the early organization of the Corps. The Liberty Bell suggests the city which gave birth to the Corps and in which the School originated.

===Background===
The distinctive unit insignia was originally approved for the Quartermaster Corps School on 16 Dec 1929.  It was redesignated for the U.S. Army Quartermaster School on 20 Dec 1967. On 9 Jun 1981 the insignia was amended to extend authorization for wear to personnel assigned to the U.S. Army Quartermaster Center.

==Device==
[[Image:QMSchool-Device.jpg|thumb|Quartermaster Center and School device]]

===Blazon===
====Shield====
Buff, a bend Azure fimbriated Argent, between in sinister chief the Liberty Bell and in dexter base the Lamp of Knowledge upon a closed book, all Proper (bronze bell, dark oak yoke, black iron bolts and straps; bronze lamp, red flame, blue book with gold lines and edges).
====Crest====
On a wreath of the colors (Argent and Buff) the insignia of the Quartermaster Corps Proper (as of 1925).

====Motto====
FAMAM EXTENDIMUS FACTIS (We Spread Our Fame by Our Deeds).

===Symbolism===
The shield is buff, the color of the Quartermaster Corps which with the blue bend gives the colonial colors and indicates the early organization of the Corps. The Liberty Bell suggests the city which gave birth to the Corps and in which the School originated.

===Background===
The device was originally approved for the Quartermaster School on 7 May 1925. It was redesignated for the U.S. Army Quartermaster School on 20 Dec 1967. On 10 Apr 1986 the device was amended to correct the wording of the blazon for the crest.

[[Image:QMCenter-Flag.jpg|thumb|Quartermaster Center flag]]
[[Image:QMSchool-Flag.jpg|thumb|Quartermaster School flag]]

== Flags ==
The flag for the U.S. Army Quartermaster School is buff with light blue fringe. The device of the School is centered on the flag (TIOH drawing 5 January 245). The flag for the U.S. Army Quartermaster Center is buff with light blue fringe. The insignia for the Quartermaster Center is centered on the flag (TIOH drawing 5-1-76).

==Structure==
*Quartermaster Center and School
**[[File:23 QM Bde DUI.jpg|35px]] 23rd Quartermaster Brigade
***HHC, 23rd Quartermaster Brigade
***[[File:244 QM Bn DUI.gif|25px]] 244th Quartermaster Battalion
****Companies A, E, G, J, M
***[[File:262 QM Bn DUI.gif|25px]] 262nd Quartermaster Battalion
****Companies C, R, U, V
***[[File:266 QM Bn DUI.gif|25px]] 266th Quartermaster Battalion
****Companies B, P, T, W
***[[United States Marine Corps]] Detachment
***[[United States Air Force]] Detachment
***[[United States Navy]] Detachment

==External links==
* [http://www.quartermaster.army.mil/ United States Army Quartermaster Corps]
* {{Internet Archive short film|id=gov.archives.arc.2569463|name=Big Picture: Enough and on Time}}

{{TRADOC}}

[[Category:Buildings and structures in Prince George County, Virginia]]
[[Category:Quartermasters|Center and School]]
[[Category:United States Army schools]]
[[Category:Education in Prince George County, Virginia]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
