<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Slurry wall"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Slurry wall" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;[[Image:SlurrywallEquipment.jpg|thumb|upright|Slurry wall excavator]]
[[Image:SlurryWallGuideWall.jpg|thumb|A set of Slurry wall guide walls before excavation]]

{{Refimprove|date=September 2009}}
A &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;slurry wall&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is a technique used to build [[reinforced concrete]] walls in areas of soft earth close to open water or with a high [[ground water]] table.&amp;lt;ref name=GwSlurryWall1994&amp;gt;
{{cite news
| url         = http://www.cee.vt.edu/ewr/environmental/teach/gwprimer/slurry/slurry.html
| title       = Slurry Walls
| publisher   = [[Virginia Tech]]
| year        = 1994
| accessdate  = 2012-01-05
| quote       =
| page        =
| author      = Gutberle
}}
[http://www.webcitation.org/query?url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.cee.vt.edu%2Fewr%2Fenvironmental%2Fteach%2Fgwprimer%2Fslurry%2Fslurry.html&amp;amp;date=2012-01-05 mirror]
&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;
This technique is typically used to build diaphragm (water-blocking) walls surrounding [[tunnel]]s and open cuts, and to lay [[foundation (engineering)|foundations]].

A trench is excavated to create a form for each wall, then filled with cement [[slurry]]; it is kept full of slurry at all times.  The slurry prevents the trench from collapsing by providing outward pressure which balances the inward hydraulic forces and prevents water flow into the trench.  Reinforcement is then lowered in and the trench is filled with concrete, which displaces the slurry.

Slurry walls are typically constructed by starting with a set of guide walls, typically 1&amp;amp;nbsp;metre (3.3&amp;amp;nbsp;ft) deep and 0.5&amp;amp;nbsp;metre (1.6&amp;amp;nbsp;ft) thick. The guide walls are constructed on the ground surface to outline the desired slurry trench(es) and guide excavation. Excavation is done using a special clamshell-shaped [[excavator|digger]] or a [[hydromill trench cutter]]. The excavator digs down to design depth, or bedrock, for the first cut.  The excavator is then lifted and moved along the trench guide walls to continue the trench with successive cuts as needed.  The trench is kept filled with [[slurry]] (usually a mixture of [[bentonite]] and water) at all times to prevent collapse.

Once a particular length is reached, a [[rebar|reinforcing]] cage is lowered into the slurry-filled pit and the pit is filled with [[concrete]] from the bottom up using [[tremie]] pipes. The concrete displaces the bentonite slurry, which is pumped out and recycled.

Slurry walls are built to enclose the desired area, blocking water and softened earth from flowing into it.  On completion of concreting, digging within the now concrete wall-enclosed area can proceed. To prevent the concrete wall from collapsing into the newly open area, temporary supports such as [[Tieback (geotechnical)|tieback]]s are installed. When completed, the structure built within the walled-off area supports the wall, so that tiebacks and/or other temporary bracing may be removed.

Slurry wall construction was used to construct the [[the Bathtub|&amp;quot;bathtub&amp;quot;]] that surrounded most of the [[World Trade Center site]]. Slurry walls were also used heavily in Boston&amp;apos;s [[Big Dig (Boston, Massachusetts)|Big Dig]] tunnel project.

==See also==
* [[Retaining wall]]
* [[Building of the World Trade Center]]
* [[Grout curtain]]

==References==
&amp;lt;references/&amp;gt;

==External links==
{{Commonscat}}
*[http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0rl1DNduT2w Video Overview of Slurry Wall Construction]
*[http://www.icanda.com/world.html WTC-slurry wall construction-1967]
*[http://www.icanda.com/services.html#SLURRY  Slurry Trenches]
*[http://www.geo-solutions.com/construction-technologies/slurry-walls.asp Video of slurry wall construction]
*[http://www.slurrywall.com A technical resource for slurry wall construction, slurry trenches and cut-off walls]
*[http://www.umich.edu/~urecord/9394/Mar28_94/27.htm Natural shale appears to be ideal material for landfill liners]
*[http://books.nap.edu/openbook.php?record_id=5539&amp;amp;page=133 Barrier technologies for environmental management]
*[http://www.geo-solutions.com/what-we-do/slurry-walls]
*[http://www.foundationengineering.info/photo_galleries/16/slurry_walls Pictures of slurry walls]

{{Geotechnical engineering}}

[[Category:Geotechnical engineering]]
[[Category:Structural system]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
