<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Energy flow (ecology)"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Energy flow (ecology)" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Refimprove|date=December 2009}}

&amp;lt;div class=&amp;quot;thumb tright&amp;quot; style=&amp;quot;background:#f9f9f9; border:1px solid #ccc; margin:0.5em;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
[[File:EnergyFlowFrog.jpg|200px]][[File:EnergyFlowTransformity.jpg|200px]]
&amp;lt;div style=&amp;quot;border: none; width:375px;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;div class=&amp;quot;thumbcaption&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Left:&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; Energy flow diagram of a frog. The frog represents a node in an extended food web. The energy ingested is utilized for metabolic processes and transformed into biomass. The energy flow continues on its path if the frog is ingested by predators, parasites, or as a decaying [[Carrion|carcass]] in soil. This energy flow diagram illustrates how energy is lost as it fuels the metabolic process that transform the energy and nutrients into biomass.&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Right:&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; An expanded three link energy food chain (1. plants, 2. herbivores, 3. carnivores) illustrating the relationship between food flow diagrams and energy transformity. The transformity of energy becomes degraded, dispersed, and diminished from higher quality to lesser quantity as the energy within a food chain flows from one trophic species into another. Abbreviations: I=input, A=assimilation, R=respiration, NU=not utilized, P=production, B=biomass.&amp;lt;ref name=&amp;quot;Odum88&amp;quot;&amp;gt;{{cite journal | last1=Odum | first1=H. T. | year=1988 | title=Self-organization, transformity, and information | journal=Science | volume=242 | issue=4882 | pages=1132–1139 | jstor=1702630 | doi=10.1126/science.242.4882.1132 | pmid=17799729}}&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;

In [[ecology]], &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;energy flow&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, also called the &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;calorific flow&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, refers to the flow of [[energy]] through a [[food chain]]. In an [[ecosystem]], [[ecologist]]s seek to [[quantification|quantify]] the relative importance of different component [[species]] and feeding relationships.

A general energy flow scenario follows:
*[[Solar energy]] is fixed by the [[photoautotroph]]s, called primary producers, like green [[plant]]s. [[Primary consumers]] absorb most of the stored energy in the plant through [[digestion]], and transform it into the form of energy they need, such as [[adenosine triphosphate]] (ATP), through [[cellular respiration|respiration]]. A part of the energy received by primary consumers, [[herbivore]]s, is converted to [[thermoregulation|body heat]] (an effect of respiration), which is [[radiant energy|radiated]] away and lost from the system. The loss of energy through body heat is far greater in [[warm-blooded]] animals, which must eat much more frequently than those that are [[cold-blooded]]. Energy loss also occurs in the expulsion of [[digestion|undigested]] food (egesta) by [[excrement|excretion]] or [[regurgitation (digestion)|regurgitation]].
*Secondary consumers, [[carnivore]]s, then consume the primary consumers, although [[omnivore]]s also consume primary producers. Energy that had been used by the primary consumers for growth and storage is thus absorbed into the secondary consumers through the process of digestion. As with primary consumers, secondary consumers convert this energy into a more suitable form (ATP) during respiration. Again, some energy is lost from the system, since energy which the primary consumers had used for respiration and regulation of body temperature cannot be utilised by the secondary consumers.
*Tertiary consumers, which may or may not be [[apex predator]]s, then consume the secondary consumers, with some energy passed on and some lost, as with the lower levels of the food chain.
*A final link in the food chain are [[decomposer]]s which break down the [[organic matter]] of the tertiary consumers (or whichever consumer is at the top of the chain) and release [[nutrient]]s into the [[soil]]. They also break down plants, herbivores and carnivores that were not eaten by organisms higher on the food chain, as well as the undigested food that is excreted by herbivores and carnivores. [[Saprotrophic nutrition|Saprotrophic]] [[bacteria]] and [[fungi]] are decomposers, and play a pivotal role in the [[nitrogen cycle|nitrogen]] and [[carbon cycle]]s.

The energy is passed on from [[trophic level]] to trophic level and each time about 90% of the energy is lost, with some being lost as heat into the environment (an effect of [[respiration (physiology)|respiration]]) and some being lost as incompletely digested food (egesta). Therefore, primary consumers get about 10% of the energy produced by autotrophs, while secondary consumers get 1% and tertiary consumers get 0.1%. This means the top consumer of a [[food chain]] receives the least energy, as a lot of the food chain&amp;apos;s energy has been lost between trophic levels. This loss of energy at each level limits typical food chains to only four to six links.

==See also==
* [[Ecological stoichiometry]]

==References==
{{Reflist}}

{{modelling ecosystems|state=expanded}}

{{DEFAULTSORT:Energy Flow}}
[[Category:Ecology terminology]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
