<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Julia Antonia"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Julia Antonia" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{for|other Roman women named Julia Caesaris|Julia Caesaris}}
&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Julia Caesaris&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (104 BC-after 39 BC) or &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Julia Antonia&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (known from the sources to distinguish her from the other Juliae Caesares) was a daughter to [[Lucius Julius Caesar (consul 90 BC)|Lucius Julius Caesar]], the consul of 90 BC, and mother to the future [[triumvir]] and deputy of Caesar, [[Mark Antony]]. She was a sister to the [[Lucius Julius Caesar (consul 64 BC)|Lucius Julius Caesar who was consul in 64 BC]]. Her mother is unknown. She was born and raised in Rome. Julia was a cousin to [[Julius Caesar]].

Julia married [[Marcus Antonius Creticus]], a man of a senatorial family. Their sons were the Triumvir [[Mark Antony]], [[Gaius Antonius]] and [[Lucius Antonius]]. Because of their kinship through her, [[Julius Caesar|Gaius Julius Caesar]] was obliged to promote the political careers of her sons, despite his distaste for their father and his generally low opinion of their abilities. After Julia’s first husband died in 74 BC, she married [[Publius Cornelius Lentulus (Sura)]], a politician, who in 63 BC, was involved in the [[Catiline]] conspiracy and was executed on the orders of [[Cicero]].

Julia had raised her sons through her marriages. [[Plutarch]] describes her as one of ‘&amp;apos;&amp;apos;most nobly born and admirable women of her time,’&amp;apos;&amp;apos; though most other sources are considerably less flattering (and likely more accurate). The following clause from &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Plutarch - Antony, Clause 1&amp;apos;&amp;apos; describes her relationship with her first husband:

&amp;apos;&amp;apos;His father was Antony, surnamed of Crete, not very famous or distinguished in public life, but a worthy good man, and particularly remarkable for his liberality, as may appear from a single example. He was not very rich, and was for that reason checked in the exercise of his good nature by his wife. A friend that stood in need of money came to borrow of him. Money he had none, but he bade a servant bring him water in a silver basin, with which, when it was brought, he wetted his face, as if he meant to shave, and, sending away the servant upon another errand, gave his friend the basin, desiring him to turn it to his purpose. And when there was afterwards a great inquiry for it in the house, and his wife was in a very ill humour, and was going to put the servants one by one to the search, he acknowledged what he had done, and begged her pardon.&amp;apos;&amp;apos;

More on her character from &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Plutarch - Antony, Clause 20&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, regarding the proscription of 43 BC, during the [[Second Triumvirate]]:

&amp;apos;&amp;apos;His uncle, Lucius Caesar, being closely pursued, took refuge with his sister, who, when the murderers had broken into her house and were pressing into her chamber, met them at the door, and spreading out hands, cried out several times. &amp;quot;You shall not kill Lucius Caesar till you first dispatch me who gave your general his birth!&amp;quot; and in this manner she succeeded in getting her brother out of the way, and saving his life.&amp;apos;&amp;apos;

During the [[Battle of Perugia|Perusian War]] (modern [[Perugia]]) between 41 BC-40 BC, Julia left Rome, although Octavian (future Roman Emperor [[Augustus]]) treated her with kindness. She never trusted [[Sextus Pompeius]]. When Sextus Pompeius was in [[Sicily]], Julia had sent to [[Greece]] for Antony, a distinguished escort and convoy of [[Trireme]]s. After the reconciliation of the triumvirs, Julia returned with Antony to [[Italy]] in 39 BC and was probably present at the meeting with Sextus Pompeius at [[Misenum]].

== Sources ==
* [[Plutarch]] - Antony
* http://www.ancientlibrary.com/smith-bio/1748.html

{{Persondata &amp;lt;!-- Metadata: see [[Wikipedia:Persondata]]. --&amp;gt;
| NAME              = Antonia, Julia
| ALTERNATIVE NAMES =
| SHORT DESCRIPTION =
| DATE OF BIRTH     =
| PLACE OF BIRTH    =
| DATE OF DEATH     =
| PLACE OF DEATH    =
}}
{{DEFAULTSORT:Antonia, Julia}}
[[Category:Julio-Claudian dynasty]]
[[Category:Ancient Roman women]]
[[Category:1st-century BC Romans]]
[[Category:Iulii]]
[[Category:104 BC births]]
[[Category:Year of birth unknown]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
