<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Unionist Party of Northern Ireland"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Unionist Party of Northern Ireland" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Infobox political party
|name = Unionist Party of Northern Ireland
|logo =
|leader = [[Brian Faulkner]] (1974-1976) [[Anne Dickson]] (1976-1981)
|leader1_title = Deputy Leader
|leader1_name = [[Leslie Morrell]] (1974-1978)
|founded = September 1974
|dissolved = Autumn 1981
|split = [[Ulster Unionist Party]]
|headquarters =
|newspaper =
|student_wing =
|youth_wing =
|ideology = [[Ulster unionism]]
|national =
|international =
|colours =
|state = Northern Ireland
}}
{{refimprove|date=April 2008}}
The &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Unionist Party of Northern Ireland&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; was a political party founded by [[Brian Faulkner]] in September 1974.

==Formation==
The party emerged following splits in the [[Ulster Unionist Party]] in 1973 and 1974 over the British government&amp;apos;s [[white paper]] &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Northern Ireland Constitutional Proposals&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, the [[Northern Ireland assembly elections, 1973]], and the [[Sunningdale Agreement]]. Faulkner had led the majority of the UUP into a power-sharing coalition but in January 1974 he was deposed as leader as the anti-Sunningdale faction of the party won control. In the [[United Kingdom general election, February 1974|February 1974 general election]] a number of Faulkner&amp;apos;s followers (including several sitting MPs) stood as &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Pro Assembly Unionists&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; against a coalition of the [[Ulster Unionist Party]], the [[Vanguard Progressive Unionist Party]] and the [[Democratic Unionist Party]]. They failed to win a single seat at Westminster, and this defeat contributed to the downfall of the power sharing Executive established by Sunningdale. However they remained active and in September constituted themselves as the Unionist Party of Northern Ireland, committed to a return to powersharing as a settlement for Northern Ireland.

==Electoral history==
The party did not prosper. In the [[United Kingdom general election, October 1974|October 1974 general election]] they again failed to make much ground. The weakness of Faulkner&amp;apos;s position within Unionism was reflected in the fact that only about a dozen of the 250 odd local councillors elected for the UUP in 1973 chose to join the new party. The 1975 elections to the [[Northern Ireland Constitutional Convention]] were another blow to the party. Of 13 UPNI candidates elected as UUP members in 1973, only 5 succeeded in holding their seats, compared to 47 seats won by other Unionist candidates. The 5 UPNI members included Faulkner who suffered a personal setback in his South Down constituency. He finished in 7th place with 6000 first preference votes in an area where he had topped the poll with 16,000 votes just 2 years earlier. Consequently the influence of both the UPNI and Faulkner waned.

In 1976 Faulkner had stepped down as leader of the party (and withdrew from active politics) and was succeeded by [[Anne Dickson]], the first woman to lead a political party in Northern Ireland. However the party continued to make little ground.  In [[Northern Ireland local elections, 1977|1977]], UPNI won just 6 local council seats. The [[1979 UK general election|1979 Westminster election]] proved to be a further disappointment, as the main consequence of the party standing seemed to be to split the centre vote. In North Belfast, Dickson&amp;apos;s 4,000 votes were greater than the DUP majority of 1,000 over the UUP. Similarly in East Belfast the DUP finished 64 votes ahead of the UUP and 900 ahead of the Alliance party with [[Norman Agnew]] taking 2,000 votes for UPNI.

In 1981 the party admitted the weakness of its own position during the local government election campaign admitting that power sharing on the 1973 model was no longer a viable option. The party fought the [[Northern Ireland local elections, 1981|1981]] local elections in an electoral pact with the [[Ulster Popular Unionist Party]] but only won 2 seats. As a result in Autumn 1981 the UPNI was formally dissolved. William Bailie, their last remaining councillor, joined the [[Alliance Party of Northern Ireland|Alliance Party]] and was re-elected as an Alliance councillor in North Down.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;[http://www.ark.ac.uk/elections/85-89lgnorthdown.htm Local Government Elections 1985 - 1989: North Down] ARK - Access Research Knowledge&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

==Leadership==
Faulkner himself died in a riding accident in 1977.

==References==
&amp;lt;references /&amp;gt;

{{Defunct political parties in Northern Ireland}}

{{DEFAULTSORT:Unionist Party Of Northern Ireland}}
[[Category:Defunct political parties in Northern Ireland]]
[[Category:History of Northern Ireland]]
[[Category:Political parties established in 1974]]
[[Category:Political parties disestablished in 1981]]
[[Category:Ulster unionism]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
