<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Birmingham Dribbler"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Birmingham Dribbler" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Use dmy dates|date=July 2013}}
[[File:Züricher Spielzeugmuseum 1000752.jpg|thumb|A &amp;apos;Birmingham Dribbler&amp;apos;, Stevens&amp;apos;s Model Dockyard, England, around 1890]]
&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Birmingham Dribbler&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; or &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;carpet railway&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; describes a type of very early [[model railroad|model railway]].&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;[http://www.antiques-bible.com/ppf/term/Birmingham+Dribblers/definition.asp Birmingham Dribblers] at antiques-bible.com&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt; It is a bit of a misnomer, as the railway featured a model [[live steam]] railway locomotive, but no track – the locomotive was simply run across the floor. In some cases, the front wheels were even made steerable so that they could be run in a circle without track. They first appeared in the 1840s and became very popular [[Victorian era|Victorian]] [[model railway]] [[toy]]s.

The [[steam locomotive]]s were very simple, usually made in [[brass]], with a pair of simple [[Oscillating cylinder steam engine|oscillating cylinders]] driving the main wheels. They were basically a [[pot boiler|boiler]] mounted on wheels, although simple decoration (usually bands of lacquer) was sometimes applied.  Track was not used – the boiler was filled with water, the burner lit, and when steam was being produced, the locomotive was placed on the floor and allowed to run until either the water or fuel ran out or the engine crashed into the furniture.  Very quickly, after a number had exploded, simple safety valves were fitted.

They quickly gained the nickname of &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Birmingham Dribblers&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (or sometimes &amp;quot;Piddlers&amp;quot;), as large numbers of them were made in [[Birmingham]], England, and they had the unfortunate habit of leaving a trail of water behind them as they ran across the floor.  Very often this trail would be mixed with the fuel used for the burner, and there were numerous incidents of fires caused by the locomotive crashing into furniture and over-turning so that the burning fuel was spilled over the floor. The fuel inside has also been known to explode {{Citation needed|date=September 2012}}, but this is incredibly rare. As time passed, embellishments were added, such as wooden buffer beams, buffers and steam whistles.

==Recent models==
&amp;lt;!-- Despite the vague information, I think it worth advising people that more modern examples are available. --&amp;gt;
Not all Birmingham Dribblers are Victorian antiques. In the 1980s and 1990s,{{clarify|reason=date is approximate, based on forum discussions of the products|date=November 2010}} a brass, self-assembly kit for a Birmingham Dribbler model was manufactured by Maxwell Hemmens Precision Steam Models of Yorkshire, UK.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;{{cite web|title=Scratch built and model live steam engines|url=http://www.mikes-steam-engines.co.uk/scratch_built.htm |work=(Photographs of Maxwell Hemmens&amp;apos; made and un-made kits)&amp;lt;!-- includes photos of the boxes! --&amp;gt;|accessdate=26 November 2010}}&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt; The models are still available from John Hemmens.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;[http://steamengines.co.uk/BIRMINGHAM-DRIBBLER.aspx Birmingham Dribblers from John Hemmens]&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

==References==
{{Reflist}}

[[Category:Miniature railways]]
[[Category:Rail transport modelling]]
[[Category:Steam power]]


{{Model-rail-stub}}&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
