<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Lists of games"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Lists of games" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;The following articles contain &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;lists of games&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, by type of game:

*[[List of board games]]
*[[List of card games]]
*[[List of dice games]]
*[[Lists of video games]]

==Miscellaneous games==
*[[The Give Game]] - a game played in the swimming pool, in which people float on the beach ball, floatie or any other blow-up object and they must for as long as they can to see if they or the object gives. If the player falls off unintentionally, the ball doesn&amp;apos;t give and they earn a point but if the player doesn&amp;apos;t give or nobody gives, they lose a point and they&amp;apos;re automatically eliminated from the game. Whoever gives and stays on the longest wins. Plus, everyone playing must repeat the phrase &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Someone&amp;apos;s gotta give!&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; over and over again.
*[[Choking game|The Choking Game]] - a game played anywhere, where a group of buddies get together and sit down. They all choke themselves and whoever passes out first loses and everybody else wins.
*[[Swiss Family Robinson (film)|Fritz and Ernst]] - Another game played in the swimming pool, in which the player must reenact the scene from the hit 1960 [[The Walt Disney Company|Disney]] film [[Swiss Family Robinson (film)|Swiss Family Robinson]], where Fritz, Ernst, and Roberta are going through an extended, long trailing swimming pool to get back home when all of a sudden, a HUGE snake appears and Fritz attacks it, Ernst grabs the knife, and starts beating on the snake with it until it&amp;apos;s finally gone and then when the fight&amp;apos;s over, Roberta pleads to go home and Fritz agrees while Ernst discovers his [[Compass]] is gone and tries searching for it with no success. Fritz suggests to get along without it, but Ernst refuses and wants to keep looking until he&amp;apos;s convinced by Fritz to give up and Fritz tells him he&amp;apos;ll have to trust his judgement from now on. This can be both a Single and Multi-Player game, has no winners or losers, and is exclusive to [[Summer]].
*[[Truth or Dare?]] - a game that is mostly played at parties. One player starts the game by asking another to choose &amp;quot;Truth or Dare?&amp;quot; If the player chooses &amp;quot;truth&amp;quot;, then the first player poses a question, usually an embarrassing one, which the second player must answer truthfully. If the player instead chooses &amp;quot;dare&amp;quot;, then the first player sets them a task, often an embarrassing or dangerous one, which player two must perform. After answering the question or performing the dare, that player asks &amp;quot;Truth or Dare?&amp;quot; of another player, and the game continues. Other options are commonly included. A variation frequently used by Australian teenagers asks: &amp;quot;Truth, Dare, Double Dare, Kiss, Love, or Torture?&amp;quot;, the definitions of the options varying between communities. &amp;quot;Double Dare&amp;quot; often requires the group to pose a dare that will be carried out by both the player asking and the player receiving the question. &amp;quot;Kiss&amp;quot; asks them to kiss (or hug) someone; the person to be kissed could be part of the command or left up to choice. &amp;quot;Torture&amp;quot; often varies but might include the respondent having to choose between &amp;quot;tickle torture&amp;quot; (getting tickled by the group) and &amp;quot;truth torture&amp;quot; (having to answer a truth from every player).
*[[Hide-and-seek]] - a game that can be played both indoors and outdoors. a number of players conceal themselves in the environment, to be found by one or more seekers. The game is played by one player (designated as being &amp;quot;it&amp;quot;) counting to a predetermined number while the other players hide. After reaching the number, the player who is &amp;quot;it&amp;quot; tries to find the other players. The game is an example of an oral tradition, as it is commonly passed down by children to younger children. After the player designated as &amp;quot;it&amp;quot; finds another player, the found player must run to base, before he/she is tagged by &amp;quot;it.&amp;quot;.

[[Category:Lists of lists|Games]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
