<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Flag of Bahrain"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Flag of Bahrain" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;[[File:Flag of Bahrain.svg|thumb|208px|[[File:FIAV 111111.svg|23px]] Flag Ratio: 3:5]]

The national &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[flag]] of [[Bahrain]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; ({{lang-ar|علم البحرين}}) consists of a white band on the left, separated from a red area on the right by five triangles that serve as a serrated line.

Red is the traditional colour for flags of the Arab states of the [[Persian Gulf]]. The white is on the hoist side; the five points represent the five pillars of Islam. It is very similar to the [[flag of Qatar]], which has more points and has a darker red.

==Design==
The white colour comprises 32.5% of the flag area, while the red colour comprises 67.5% of the area.
[[File:Bahrain flag design.gif|thumb|208px|Measurements of the construction of the flag]]

===Colour===
The colour specification is red: Pantone 186 c / CMYK (%) C 0 – M 90 – Y 80 – K 5&amp;lt;ref name=&amp;quot;National Flag of Bahrain&amp;quot;&amp;gt;{{cite web|first=BBC|title=National Flag of Bahrain|url=http://news.bbc.co.uk/dna/place-lancashire/plain/A1094203|accessdate=16 June 2012}}&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

==Use==
The flag is used on land and at sea as a national, civil and war ensign. In 2002, the King of Bahrain [[Hamad bin Isa Al Khalifa]], issued Decree by Law No.(4) for 2002, which pertained to the flag:

*&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Article 1&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;: The Flag of the Kingdom of Bahrain shall take a rectangular shape, and shall be divided into two main sections; the first in red, and the other in white color.
*&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Article II&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;: The King shall have his own flag, for which a royal order shall be issued to determine its shape, measures, and places.
*&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Article III&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;: The Flag of the Kingdom of Bahrain shall be hoisted on the Royal Court, Palaces, governmental buildings, public establishments, embassies, Bahraini bureaus abroad, and Bahraini ships.
*&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Article IV&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;: Each non-Bahraini ship entering the territorial waters of the Kingdom of Bahrain shall hoist the Flag of the Kingdom, and shall keep the flag hoisted till it departs from the territorial waters of the Kingdom.
*&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Article V&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;: The Flag shall be hoisted on governmental buildings, public institutions during public holidays and occasions from sun-rise to sun-set.
*&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Article VI&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;: The Flag of the Kingdom of Bahrain shall not be hoisted on vehicles, except on the official protocol vehicles.
*&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Article VII&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;: The Flag of the Kingdom of Bahrain shall be hoisted half mast at the state of mourning.
*&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Article VIII&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;: The Flag of the Kingdom of Bahrain shall not be used for commercial purposes.
*&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Article IX&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;: In case the Flag is used otherwise, and not as stipulated in the above law, a punishment of one month of imprisonment as a maximum, or a fine not exceeding than [[Bahraini Dinar|BD]] 100, or both shall be inflicted.&amp;lt;ref name=&amp;quot;National Flag of Bahrain&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;

==History==
The oldest known flags of Bahrain were plain red. In 1820, Bahrain signed [[The General Maritime Treaty with Britain|a treaty]] with the [[United Kingdom of Great Britain and Ireland|United Kingdom]], and a white stripe was added to the flag to indicate the truce. In 1932, a serrated edge was added to distinguish the flag of Bahrain from those of its neighbours.&amp;lt;ref name=history&amp;gt;{{FOTW|id=bh_hist|title=Historical flags of Bahrain}}&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

The flag originally had twenty-eight white points, but this was reduced to eight in 1972.&amp;lt;ref name=history/&amp;gt; On 14 February 2002, the number was again reduced to five, so that each of the points could stand for one of the [[Five Pillars of Islam]].&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;{{FOTW|id=bh|title=Bahrain}}&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

&amp;lt;gallery&amp;gt;
File:Flag of Bahrain (before 1820).svg|Flag used prior to 1820.
File:Flag of Bahrain (1820-1932).svg|Flag used from 1820 to 1932.
File:Flag of Bahrain (1932 to 1972).svg|Flag used from 1932 to 1972.
File:Flag of Bahrain 1972.svg|Flag used from 1972 to 2002.
File:Royal Standard of Bahrain.svg|[[King of Bahrain|Royal Standard]] since 2002.
&amp;lt;/gallery&amp;gt;

== References ==
&amp;lt;references /&amp;gt;

{{Asia topic|Flag of|title=[[Flags of Asia]]}}
{{nationalflags}}&amp;lt;!-- to edit this table, go to [[Template:Nationalflags]] --&amp;gt;

{{DEFAULTSORT:Bahrain, Flag of}}
[[Category:National symbols of Bahrain]]
[[Category:National flags]]
[[Category:Red and white flags]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
