<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Xiamen University Libraries"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Xiamen University Libraries" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Lead too short|date=January 2011}}
{{Unreferenced|date=August 2011}}
{{Infobox library
| library_name = Xiamen University Libraries
| library_logo =
| image = Xiamen University Main library.jpg
| established = 1921
| location = [[Xiamen]], [[Fujian]], China
| type =
| num_branches = 5
| collection_size =n/a
| annual_circulation =
| pop_served =
| budget =
| director =
| num_employees = n/a
| website =http://library.xmu.edu.cn/
}}
&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Xiamen University Libraries&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, [[Xiamen]], [[Fujian]], China, founded in 1921, over years of development finally took its site on the current location in 1987, covering an area of 18,000 square meters.

== History ==
After the 2001 and 2008 reconstruction, the total area extended to 26,000 square meters. Currently the library enjoys a collection of 3.5 million volumes, covering subjects such as the [[biology]], [[chemistry]], [[economics]], [[history]], [[management]], [[mathematics]], [[medicine]], [[oceanography]], [[philosophy]], [[physics]], Southeast Asia and Taiwan studies and so on.

== Facilities ==
[[Xiamen University]] Libraries consists of a general library and 5 branch libraries. The departments include the Administration, [[Procurement|Acquisition]], [[Cataloging]], Conservation &amp;amp; Preservation, [[Library circulation|Circulation]], Reference, Periodicals, and Information Technology Department. Various services are available to all campus users, which include lending, reading, reference, consultation, research project review, inter-library loan, self-service photocopying, and so on. Currently there are over 20 study rooms and more than 4,000 seats available to the readers in the libraries. In 1993, computerized circulation system was adopted in the main library. In 1994, An integrated management system was set up and been upgraded in 1999 and 2007 respectively. Digital library project initiated since 2000, with an aim to provide a growingly richer resource onto the internet.

The past decade has witnessed the radical restructuring of public service system in the libraries. In 1998, two branch libraries, namely the Economic and Management Branch Library and the Law Branch Library were established. The later half of 1999 witnessed the set-up of Biological and Medical Branch Library. Then, a university wise framework of collection and information sharing was launched among the libraries in different colleges, institutes and departments. In September 2001, Eastern Campus Branch Library was set up in Zengcuo&amp;apos;an dormitory zone. Later in August 2003, students in the Zhangzhou Campus had their own library——the [[Zhangzhou]] Campus Library, which boasted of exquisite facilities and rich collection.

With time, the Xiamen University Libraries will increasingly become an institute for wisdom and self-fulfillment.

==Photo gallery==
&amp;lt;gallery&amp;gt;
Image:Xiamen University Eastern Campus Branch Library.JPG|Eastern Campus Branch Library
Image:Xiamen University Economic and Management Branch Library.JPG|Economic and Management Branch Library
Image:Xiamen University Law Branch Library .JPG|Law Branch Library
Image:Xiamen University Zhangzhou Campus Library.jpg|Zhangzhou Campus Library
&amp;lt;/gallery&amp;gt;

== References ==
{{Reflist}}

==External links==
* [http://library.xmu.edu.cn/ Xiamen University Libraries’ website]
* [http://dspace.xmu.edu.cn/dspace/ Xiamen University Institutional Repository]
* [http://210.34.4.28/ Xiamen University Libraries’ WebPAC]
* [http://210.34.4.13:8080/books/ undergraduate courses and teaching reference information]
* [http://210.34.4.13:8080/lunwen/ ETDs database]
* [http://210.34.4.12/gateway/ Digital Multimedia Center]

[[Category:Buildings and structures in Xiamen]]
[[Category:Academic libraries in China]]
[[Category:Library buildings completed in 1987]]
[[Category:1921 establishments in China]]
[[Category:Libraries established in 1921]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
