<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Communication Access Real-Time Translation"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Communication Access Real-Time Translation" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Communication Access Real-Time Translation (CART)&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, also called &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;open captioning&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; or &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;real-time stenography&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, or simply real-time captioning, is the general name of the system that [[court reporters]], [[closed captioning|closed captioners]], and others use to convert speech to text.  A trained operator uses keyboard or [[stenography]] methods to transcribe spoken speech into written text.

While real time speech to text serves many with hearing loss and deafness, it is also useful for people whose first language is different from the language being used, to understand speakers with different voices and accents in many group situations (at work, in education, community events), to have a &amp;quot;transcript&amp;apos;, and for learning languages. CART professionals have qualifications for added expertise (speed and accuracy) as compared to court reporters and other stenographers.

Another emerging method is voicewriting. The voicewriter uses speech recognition software that instantly translates the spoken text into written text.

&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Remote CART&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is done with the trained operator at a remote location.  A voice connection such as a telephone, cellphone, or computer microphone is used to send the voice to the operator, and the [[real-time text]] is transmitted back over a modem, Internet, or other data connection.

Some people use CART as the short form of Computer Assisted Realtime Transcription.  The service is identical.

In other countries, CART may be referred to as Palantype, Velotype, STTR (speech to text reporting).

==External links==
*[http://www.michdhh.org/assistive_devices/cart.html E-Michigan Deaf and Hard of Hearing People: Communication Access Realtime Translation (CART)]
*[http://deafness.about.com/cs/cart/a/cart.htm About.com Guide: Accessibility - Communication Access Realtime Translation (CART)]

{{deaf-stub}}

[[Category:Assistive technology]]
[[Category:Writing systems]]
[[Category:Deafness]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
