<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Courts Malaysia"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Courts Malaysia" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Infobox company
| company_name  = Courts Malaysia
| company_logo  = [[Image:CourtsLogo.gif]]
| company_type  = [[Public company|Public]]
| foundation    = 1986
| founder       =
| slogan        =
| location      = Malaysia
| logistics centre =
| area_served   =  [[Singapore]], [[Malaysia]], [[Indonesia]] and [[Thailand]]
| key_people    =
| genre         = [[Retailer|Retail (Specialty)]]
| products      = [[Furniture]], [[Electronics]]
| revenue       =
| net_income    =
| num_employees =
| homepage      = [http://www.courts.com.my/html/index.html  Official Site]
}}

&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Courts Malaysia&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, is the largest consumer electronics and furniture retailer in [[Malaysia]] with a network of 60 stores nationwide and a staff strength of 1,100. [[Courts]] has been operating in Malaysia for 26 years.

==History==

Incorporated on 23 July 1986 as a private limited company under the name Courts Furnishers (Malaysia) Sdn. Bhd, Courts changed its name to Courts Sdn Bhd on 30 June 1997. Courts subsequently converted into a public company and assumed its present name, Courts Sdn Bhd on 1 July 1997. Courts was listed on the Main Board of the Kuala Lumpur Stock Exchange (now known as Bursa Malaysia Securities Berhad) on October 11, 2000 and delisted again from bursa Malaysia 3 September 2007 markets following the completion of ownership engagement with Malaysia Retail Group. Courts is now located in [[Singapore]], [[Malaysia]], [[Indonesia]] and [[Thailand]].

==Re-branding ==

Courts has been undergoing various stages of a re-branding initiatives since 2006. Phase 1 of the reformatting of its urban stores adopting the ‘refreshed’ look and feel with an expanded product range in contemporary furnishing and in electronics.

Courts entered Phase 2 of its re-branding with the launch of Courts Megastore in December 2007. Phase 2, also includes the refurbishment of the rest of the Courts outlets scheduled to be completed in March 2009.

==Courts Megastore==
Courts Malaysia is planning to open its first &amp;apos;Big-Box&amp;apos; Megastore in Malaysia in the early second half of 2013. This will be sited on the ground and first floor of the 8trium building in Sri Damansara. This 108,000 sq ft store will be the ultimate one-stop lifestyle destination built on a retail proposition to provide choice, value, experience, service and payment options of credit, cash or credit card to consumers.

The concept of launching Courts Megastore targets the urban consumer’s evolving tastes and needs as well as appealing to a broader market which may not be aware of Courts. Courts Megastore will offer many first-in-Malaysia concepts such as Hot off the Docks, Countdown Corner, Dr. Digital, Sleep Clinic, made-to-order and many more.

==References==
* [http://www.courts.com.my/html/about/about.html Courts - About Us]

==External links==
* [http://www.courts.com.my/html/index.html Official website]

[[Category:Furniture retailers]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
