<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Ruthenians and Ukrainians in Czechoslovakia (1918–1938)"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Ruthenians and Ukrainians in Czechoslovakia (1918–1938)" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Unreferenced|date=March 2007}}
[[Subcarpathian Ruthenia]] (later briefly independent as [[Carpatho-Ukraine]]) was economically [[Czechoslovakia]]’s poorest region. In 1914 the region was referred to by one historian as &amp;quot;little more than a [[Magyars|Magyar]] deer park.&amp;quot; Its people were wretchedly poor, having for centuries supplemented the meagre living the mountainous area afforded with seasonal agricultural labor and service in the Hungarian infantry.

Тhe Subcarpathian region was a hotbed of secessionist sentiment throughout the inter-war period. These were manifested by strong cultural and linguistic links with the [[Ukrainians]], in the [[Soviet Union]] and interwar [[Poland]]. There were also calls for Ukrainian autonomy within the [[Czechoslovakia|Czechoslovak Republic]], and calls for the formation of a [[Lemko-Rusyn Republic]] on the northern side of the Carpathians, attempted to unite with this faction.

During [[World War I]], [[Ruthenia]]n leaders had reached an agreement with [[Tomáš Masaryk]] to extend autonomy to Ruthenia within a future Czechoslovak Republic. The agreement received international sanction in the 1919 [[Treaty of Saint-Germain]]. The [[Paris Peace Conference, 1919|Paris Peace Conference]] had also stipulated earlier that year that Subcarpathian Ruthenia be granted full autonomy and promised the territory a diet having legislative power in all matters of local administration. However, the [[Czechoslovak Constitution of 1920|constitution of 1920]] limited the provision on autonomy, making reference to the requirements of the unity of the state. All Ruthenian legislation was made subject to approval by the president of the republic, and the governor of Ruthenia was to be nominated by the president. As a result, even the constitutional provision for Ruthenian autonomy was never implemented; the Ruthenian diet was never convened. The issue of autonomy became a major source of discontent. Other grievances included the placement of the western boundary—which left 150,000 Ruthenians in Slovakia—and the large numbers of [[Czechs]] brought to Ruthenia as administrators and educators. Post-World War I Ruthenia was characterized by a proliferation of political parties and a diversity of cultural tendencies. All Czechoslovak political parties were represented, and a number of indigenous parties emerged as well. Of particular significance were the Ukrainophiles, Russophiles, Hungarians, and [[communist]]s.

==Political movements==

Ukrainophile and Russophile tendencies were strengthened by the large influx of émigrés following the war.

The Ukrainophiles were largely members of the [[Eastern Catholic Churches]] and espoused autonomy within Czechoslovakia. Some favored union with Soviet Ukraine. The Ukrainophiles were represented by the Ruthenian National Christian Party led by [[Avhustyn Voloshyn]].

The [[Ukrainian Russophiles|Russophile Ruthenians]] were largely [[Eastern Orthodox Church|Greek Orthodox]] and also espoused Ruthenian autonomy. They were organized politically in the Agricultural Federation, led by [[Andrej Brody]], and the fascist-style [[Fencik Party]].

Hungarians populated a compact area in southern Ruthenia. They were represented by the Unified Magyar Party, which consistently received ten percent of the vote in Subcarpathian Ruthenia and was in permanent opposition to the government.

The communists, strong in the poor province, attempted to appeal to the Ukrainian element by espousing union with Soviet Ukraine. In 1935 the communists polled 25 percent of the Ruthenian vote. The elections of 1935 gave only 37 percent of the Ruthenian vote to political parties supporting the Czechoslovak government. The communists, Unified Magyars, and autonomist groups polled 63 percent.

{{Reflist}}
{{Ethnic minorities in Czechoslovakia}}

{{DEFAULTSORT:Ruthenians and Ukrainians in Czechoslovakia (1918-1938)}}
[[Category:Carpathian Ruthenia]]
[[Category:Ethnic groups in Czechoslovakia]]
[[Category:Ukrainian diaspora by country]]
[[Category:Ukrainian population groups]]
[[Category:Interwar period]]
[[Category:Rusyn diaspora]]
[[Category:Rusyn people]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
