<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="SylvaC"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="SylvaC" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Orphan|date=February 2009}}
[[Image:Onions 516.jpg|thumb|A SylvaC onion &amp;apos;face pot&amp;apos;]]
&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;SylvaC&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (with a deliberate capital C at the end) is a brand of British [[ornament (architecture)|ornamental]] [[pottery]] characterised primarily by figurines of animals and [[Toby Jugs]]. The SylvaC company ceased production in 1982 although reproductions of SylvaC pieces were made by third parties after this date.

The company was founded in 1894 by [[William Copestake]] and William Shaw. They gave their names to the fledgling company - Shaw and Copestake. Copestake left in 1895, however, and Richard Hull became Shaw&amp;apos;s partner. Hull&amp;apos;s son joined in 1936 and in 1938 the Thomas Lawrence [[Falcon Pottery]] was bought (which produced pottery with the distinctive &amp;apos;falcon&amp;apos; mark on it). However, the Shaw and Copestake company maintained its original name right up until the end.

Central to the SylvaC line throughout its history were figurines of animals, and rabbits in particular. Dogs were also popular and virtually every breed ended-up being characterised in pottery. Many variations of Toby Jugs were produced, including &amp;apos;character&amp;apos; versions which celebrated events or tied into product advertising.

Although many colours and glazes were used, most people remember the distinctive orange or green glazes most.

SylvaC pieces are not rare; however, they are becoming collectable, and the best pieces can fetch high prices.

The Company was purchased  and registered in July of 2012 by Rolf Groth of Liverpool in England with the intent of trading in vintage and special edition pieces.

==External links==

* [http://www.worldcollectorsnet.com/sylvac/ World Collectors&amp;apos; Net: SylvaC]
* [http://www.stoke.gov.uk/ccm/museums/museum/2006/collections/ceramics/information-sheets/shaw-and-copestake-ltd-sylvac.en Sylvac dates, company history and reading list]

{{Industry-stub}}
{{UK-company-stub}}
{{ceramics-stub}}

[[Category:Ceramics manufacturers of England]]
[[Category:Staffordshire pottery]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
