<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Blanchard Springs Caverns"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Blanchard Springs Caverns" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;[[Image:Blanchard Springs II.jpg|thumb|300px|Speleothems in the cave|alt=View inside the caverns at Blanchard Springs, Arkansas.]]
&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Blanchard Springs Caverns&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is a [[cave]] system located in the [[Ozark National Forest]] in [[Stone County, Arkansas|Stone County]] in northern [[Arkansas]], 2 miles off Highway 14 a short distance north of [[Mountain View, Arkansas|Mountain View]].&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;http://www.uark.edu/~siggamep/blanchard/ Blanchard Springs Caverns, The University of Arkansas&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt; Blanchard Springs Caverns is a three-level cave system, two of which are open for guided tours. The [[Dripstone]] Trail runs through the upper level of the caverns. The Discovery Trail on the second level opened in 1977 and runs through the middle of the cavern. Also offered is a &amp;quot;Wild Cave&amp;quot; tour which allows access to undeveloped parts of the cave to more adventurous visitors.

The temperature is a constant, year-round 58°F (14°C). The [[limestone]] rock from which the caves and their formations developed was laid down in an ancient sea more than 350 million years ago. It remains a &amp;quot;living&amp;quot; cave in part because of the care given by visitors and the [[United States Forest Service]]. Living caves are ones in which slow metamorphosis due to minerals deposited by seeping and dripping water is still in process.

== History ==

Local residents knew about the caves by the 1930s when the first attempts to explore the caverns occurred. The first systematic exploration of the cave began in 1955 and went for five years. Additionally in 1955, explorers discovered a 1000-year-old [[Indigenous peoples of the Americas|Native American]] skeleton in the cave. The skeleton had a fractured skull, fractured ribs, and a fractured leg. How this explorer entered the cave is unknown. The caverns were opened to the public in 1973 after ten years of development on the Dripstone Trail. Blanchard Springs Caverns received its name from the cave&amp;apos;s source, Blanchard Springs.

== References ==
{{Reflist}}

== External links ==
{{commonscat}}
* [http://www.blanchardspringscaverns.org Blanchard Springs Caverns Website produced by the Stone County Tourist Guide]
* [http://www.fs.fed.us/oonf/ozark/recreation/caverns.html USDA Forest Service Page for Blanchard Springs Caverns]
{{coord|35|57|49.26|N|92|10|45.58|W|display=title}}

[[Category:Caves of Arkansas]]
[[Category:Native American archeology]]
[[Category:Show caves in the United States]]
[[Category:Limestone caves]]
[[Category:Geography of Stone County, Arkansas]]
[[Category:Protected areas of Stone County, Arkansas]]
[[Category:Ozark–St. Francis National Forest]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
