<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Double parking"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Double parking" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{morerefs|date=December 2012}}
&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Double parking&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; can refer to one of three practices:

==Parking parallel to a car already parked at the curb==
[[File:DOUBLE PARKED CARS ON MANHATTAN&amp;apos;S 172ND STREET - NARA - 549829.jpg|thumb|250px|Cars double-parked on New York City street]]
[[Image:Double parked car with diplomatic tags.jpg|right|thumb|250px|The car in the cycling lane is double-parked. Since it has [[Diplomatic_license_plates_in_the_United_States#Diplomatic_license_plates|Diplomatic License Plates]], the driver would not be obliged to pay any citation issued.]]
&amp;quot;Double parking&amp;quot; means standing or parking a vehicle on the roadway side of a vehicle already stopped, standing or parked at the curb.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;[http://www.nyc.gov/html/dof/html/parking/park_tickets_violations.shtml New York City Violation Codes, Fines, Rules &amp;amp; Regulations] (&amp;quot;double parking&amp;quot; is code 46)&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt; This often prevents some of the vehicles in the first row from departing and always obstructs a traffic lane or bike lane (to the extent of often making the street impassable in one-way single-lane situations). Even though it is illegal, double parking is quite common in large urban areas. In some areas, people double parking their cars leave the [[hand brake]] off, allowing the drivers of the cars next to the curb to push the double parked car a little forward or backward, in order to allow departing from the parking spot.  Double parking in this fashion, where illegal, is often punished by ticketing or towing the offending vehicle.

==Double parking in attended lots and garages==
Attended lots and garages frequently use double parking to maximize vehicle storage density.  A driver who double-parks in an attended lot leaves the vehicle&amp;apos;s keys with the attendant.  If the driver of the blocked car returns first, then the attendant can move the blocking car so that the blocked car can leave.  This practice is especially common for valet lots, in which attendants have the keys to all vehicles.

==Multi-space parking==
[[File:Parking violation Vaughan Mills.jpg|thumb|A Ford Mustang occupying two spaces at [[Vaughan Mills]] mall, Ontario.]]
The term &amp;quot;double parking&amp;quot; is sometimes used erroneously to describe parking over the lines separating two designated parking spaces in a parking lot and is derived from situations where cars take more spaces than necessary. Though this practice is most commonly a result of the driver disregarding the separating lines, it may also occur when the driver avoids parking too close to a large vehicle (such as a [[truck]] or [[SUV]]) in a narrow space, or to a vehicle which is poorly centered in the adjacent space.  Sometimes parking in this fashion, if the vehicle is large, is an attempt by the driver of the vehicle to avoid damage to the vehicle or to nearby vehicles when the doors are opened, or to ensure enough space for loading and unloading various content.  The egregiousness of double parking in this fashion is usually judged depending on parking space availability.  It can provoke anger and even vandalism towards the offending vehicle when parking is scarce.

==References==
{{reflist}}

{{traffic law}}

[[Category:Parking]]
[[Category:Traffic law]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
