<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Triptolemus"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Triptolemus" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{for|the moth|Hemeroplanes triptolemus}}
[[File:NAMA Triade éleusinienne.jpg|thumb|right|200px|Triptolemus standing between Demeter and Kore, relief from the [[National Archaeological Museum of Athens]]]]
{{Greek myth (earth)}}
&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Buzyges&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; redirects here. For the genus of grass skipper butterflies, see [[Buzyges (butterfly)]].&amp;apos;&amp;apos;

&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Triptolemus&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; ({{lang-el|Τριπτόλεμος}}, lit. &amp;quot;threefold warrior&amp;quot;; also known as &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Buzyges&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;), in [[Greek mythology]] always connected with [[Demeter]] of the [[Eleusinian Mysteries]], might be accounted the son of King [[Celeus]] of [[Eleusis]] in [[Attica, Greece|Attica]], or, according to the Pseudo-Apollodorus (&amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Bibliotheca (Pseudo-Apollodorus)|Bibliotheca]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos; I.V.2), the son of [[Gaia (mythology)|Gaia]] and [[Oceanus]]—another way of saying he was &amp;quot;primordial man&amp;quot;.

While [[Demeter]] (in the guise of an old woman named Doso) was searching for her daughter [[Persephone]], who had been abducted by [[Hades]], she received a hospitable welcome from Celeus. He asked her to nurse [[Demophon of Eleusis|Demophon]]&amp;amp;mdash;&amp;quot;killer of men&amp;quot;, a counterpart to Triptolemus&amp;amp;mdash; and Triptolemus, his sons by [[Metanira]]. As a gift to Celeus, in gratitude for his hospitality, Demeter secretly planned to make Demophon immortal by burning away his mortal spirit in the family hearth every night. She was unable to complete the ritual because Metanira walked in on her one night. Instead, Demeter chose to teach Triptolemus the art of agriculture and, from him, the rest of Greece learned to plant and reap crops.  He flew across the land on a winged chariot while Demeter and Persephone, once restored to her mother, cared for him, and helped him complete his mission of educating the whole of Greece in the art of agriculture.

When Triptolemus taught [[Lyncus]], King of the [[Scythia]]ns, the arts of agriculture, Lyncus refused to teach it to his people and then tried to kill Triptolemus.  Demeter turned him into a [[lynx]]. Triptolemus was equally associated with the bestowal of hope for the afterlife associated with the expansion of the Eleusinian Mysteries (Kerenyi 1967 p 123).

In the archaic [[Homeric Hymn|Homeric Hymn to Demeter]], Triptolemus is briefly mentioned as one of the original priests of Demeter, one of the first men to learn the secret rites and mysteries of [[Eleusinian Mysteries]]: [[Diocles (mythology)|Diocles]], [[Eumolpos]], [[Celeus]] and [[Polyxeinus]] were the others mentioned of the first priests. The role of Triptolemus in the Eleusinian mysteries was exactly defined: &amp;quot;he had a cult of his own, apart from the Mysteries. One entered his temple on the way to the closed-off sacred precinct, before coming to the former [[Hectate|Hekataion]], the temple of [[Artemis]] outside the great Propylaia.&amp;quot; (Kerenyi).  In the 5th-century bas-relief in the National Museum, Athens (&amp;apos;&amp;apos;illustration&amp;apos;&amp;apos;), which probably came from his temple, the boy Triptolemus stands between the Two Goddesses, Demeter and the [[Persephone|Kore]], and receives from Demeter the ear of grain (of gold, now lost).

[[Porphyry (philosopher)|Porphyry]] (&amp;apos;&amp;apos;On Abstinence&amp;apos;&amp;apos; IV.22) ascribes to Triptolemus three commandments for a simple, pious life: &amp;quot;Honor your parents&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Honor the gods with fruits&amp;quot;—for the Greeks, &amp;quot;fruits&amp;quot; would include the grain—and &amp;quot;Spare the animals&amp;quot; (Kerenyi, p128).

Triptolemus is also depicted as a young man with a branch or diadem placed in his hair, usually sitting on his winged chariot, adorned with [[Serpent (symbolism)|serpents]].  His attributes include a plate of grain, a pair of wheat or barley ears and a [[scepter]].

Celeus or the peasant [[Dysaules]] may be substituted for Triptolemus as the primordial Eleusinian recipient of the first gifts of the Mysteries.

==References==
{{Commonscat|Triptolemus}}
*[[Karl Kerenyi|Kerenyi, Karl]], 1967. &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;quot;Eleusis: Aretypal Image of Mother and Daughter&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (Princeton:Bollingen Series LXV.4)
==See also==
*[[Indra]]

[[Category:Greek mythology]]
[[Category:Attic culture heroes]]
[[Category:Eleusinian mythology]]
[[Category:Demeter]]
[[Category:Chthonic]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
