<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Chiranjivi"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Chiranjivi" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Chiranjivi&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; ([[Sanskrit]] nominative sing. &amp;apos;&amp;apos;ciranjīvī&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, चिरंजीवी) are permanent lived beings in [[Hinduism]] who are to remain alive through this [[Kali Yuga]] until the next [[Satya Yuga]].

==Etymology and scriptural context==
The term is a combination of &amp;apos;&amp;apos;chiram&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, or &amp;apos;permanent&amp;apos;, and &amp;apos;&amp;apos;jīvi&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, or &amp;apos;lived&amp;apos;. It is same &amp;apos;&amp;apos;as&amp;apos;amaratva&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, which refers to true immortality. At the end of the last [[Kalpa (aeon)|Kalpa]], a demon attempted to become immortal by swallowing the Vedas as they escaped from the mouth of [[Brahma (god)|Brahma]]. The scripture was retrieved by the first avatar of [[Vishnu]], [[Matsya]]. Incarnations of Vishnu also later fought and killed two other [[asura]]s, [[Hiranyakasipu]] and [[Ravana]], who tried to become immortal through obeisance to [[Shiva]]. In Hinduism, immortal does not mean [[eternity|eternal]], as all physical bodies are foretold to become immaterial at the [[end time|end of time]], along with [[Brahma]] himself.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;Bhāgavata Purāṇa 3.32.8-10&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

==Attributes==
[[Purana]]s, the [[Mahabharata]] and the [[Ramayana]] describe eight long lived personalities in the [[Hindu pantheon]]. They existed in past ages, [[Satya Yuga]], [[Treta Yuga]], and [[Dvapara Yuga]], and are alive today in our current [[Kali Yuga]]. Each represents a different attribute of man, which as long as they live, will exist amongst humanity.&amp;lt;ref name=&amp;quot;Paryatanam&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Malayalam book Bharata Paryatanam (A journey through the Mahabharata) by Kuttikrishana Marar.&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

The chiranjivi are as follows:
*[[Markandeya]], an ancient sage from the Hindu tradition, born in the clan of Brigu Rishi.
*[[Ashwatthama]], the son of [[Drona]], a great warrior. He acted out of cowardice to avenge the killing of his father, resulting in a curse of immortality.
*[[Mahabali|Bali Chakravarthi]], granted a boon by Vishnu that he would be the next [[Indra]], before merging with Vishnu. He expounds virtues of valour and charity.
*[[Hanuman]], avatar of [[Shiva]], who served Rama. He stands for selflessness, courage, devotion, strength, and righteous conduct.
*[[Kripa]], military guru of the princes in the &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Mahabharata]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos;.
*[[Parashurama]], 6th [[avatar]] of [[Vishnu]], master of all astras, sastras and divine weapons. The [[Kalki Purana]] writes that he will re emerge at [[end time]] to the martial guru of [[Kalki]]. He will then instruct the final avatar to undertake penance to receive celestial weaponry, required to save mankind at [[end time]].
*[[Vibhishana]], brother of [[Ravana]]. Vibhishana surrendered to [[Rama]] before his battle with Ravana. Later, he was crowned king of [[Lanka]] after Ravana was killed by Rama. He stands for righteousness. Vibhishana is not a true Chiranjeevi, as his boon of longevity is to remain on the earth only until the end of Treta Yuga.
*[[Vyasa]], a sage who narrated the &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Mahabharata&amp;apos;&amp;apos;. He represents erudition and wisdom.He was the son of Rishi Prashar and grandson of Rishi vashist. He was born in almost last of Tretayug, lived to see the whole Dwaparyug and also had seen the initial phase of Kalyug.

Hindu scripture contains a mantra about the seven immortals, in which their names are recited for luck and longevity:

::Ashwathaama Balir Vyasaha Hanumanthra vibeeshanaha
::Kriba Parasuramas cha
::Saptaitey Chiranjeevinaha{{Cn|date=December 2012}}


Om Namah Shivay

It is specified that Markandeya had boon that he will never die and is blessed with immortality. However it is not clear as to why the name of Markandeya has not appeared in above mantra.

==References==
{{Reflist}}

==External links==
*[http://www.veda.harekrsna.cz/encyclopedia/general.htm#6 Ciranjivas]

{{HinduMythology}}

[[Category:Chiranjivins| ]]
[[Category:Non-human races in Hindu mythology]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
