<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Ikari III: The Rescue"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Ikari III: The Rescue" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{primarysources|date=July 2008}}
{{no footnotes|date=March 2013}}
{{Infobox VG
|title = Ikari III: The Rescue
|image = [[Image:Ikari III.png|frameless|Ikari III: The Rescue]]
|caption = Arcade flyer
|developer = [[SNK Playmore|SNK]]
|publisher = SNK
|designer =
|release = 1989
|genre = [[Shoot &amp;apos;em up#Run and gun|Run and gun]]
|modes = Up to 2 players simultaneously
|cabinet = Upright
|cpu = Main CPU : 68000 (@ 10 MHz)&amp;lt;BR&amp;gt;
Sound CPU : Z80 (@ 4&amp;amp;nbsp;MHz)&amp;lt;BR&amp;gt;
Sound Chips : YM3812 (@ 4 MHz), UPD7759 (@ 640 kHz)
|display =  Vertical orientation, 256 x 224 pixels, 60 Hz refresh rate, 2048 Colors
|input = [[Joystick]] (12-way rotary), 3 buttons
|platforms =
}}

&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Ikari III: The Rescue&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (also known as &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Ikari Warriors III: The Rescue&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;), known simply as {{nihongo|&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Ikari III&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;|怒Ⅲ}} in [[Japan]], is an [[Arcade game|arcade]] [[beat &amp;apos;em up]].  It was ported to the [[Nintendo Entertainment System|NES]], [[DOS]], and [[Commodore 64|C64]]. It is the second sequel to the original &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Ikari Warriors]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, following &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Victory Road (video game)|Victory Road]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos;.

==Arcade version==
Unlike the previous two games, this game features hand-to-hand combat as well as weapons. The characters had more &amp;quot;life-like&amp;quot; designs (instead of the &amp;quot;[[super deformed]]&amp;quot; versions in the previous two games).

===Story===
The presidential candidate&amp;apos;s child has been kidnapped by an enemy terrorist party. Top officials have asked the 2 best soldiers to secretly take action on this matter.

===Game play===
While the game still uses the [[rotary switch|rotary]] joystick, a version exists that forgoes the rotary feature altogether.

The weapon selection is greatly reduced from prequels, and there are no player usable vehicles. Weapons are much rarer, which makes the game more focused on hand to hand combat.

====Controls====
*Punch: It delivers more rapid hits than kick.
*Kick: It has longer range than punch.
*Jump Kick

====Weapons====
*Knife
*Machine gun: It is limited to 20 rounds.

====Item====
*Oil drum: It explodes when thrown to enemy.
*Dynamite: It explodes after it finishes flashing.

====Stages====
For the first time in the series, there are discrete stages.

==NES version==
[[Image:Ikari3b.gif|frame|right|Ikari Warriors 3 (NES version).]]

It maintains the characters design and basic game play over the arcade version.

===Story===
The story is different from the arcade version:

It is the end of the 20th century. A worldwide economic recession wreaks havoc with the nation and the planet. The impending threat of anarchy has given rise to a secret vice organization called &amp;apos;Crime Ghost.&amp;apos; Dangerously poised to take over the world with its diabolic strategy, &amp;apos;Crime Ghost&amp;apos; has infiltrated every country simultaneously. There is one President who has initiated a plan to wipe out the association, but now his home has been attacked and his daughter Elise abducted. A letter has arrived demanding that he resign his powerful position within a number of days, or else his beautiful Elise will be executed in a most unpleasant manner.  The letter is signed &amp;apos;Faust&amp;apos;, the notorious mastermind of Crime Ghost. The president knows to whom he must turn. The President has summoned two men known as Paul and Vince, the incredible Ikari Warriors. Now, YOU become Paul and Vince.  You must go to the enemy hideout, rescue the lovely Elise, fight Crime Ghost, and destroy them all.  To do this, you will use your undersea scuba tactics; your guerilla fighting power with machine guns and grenades; and your own brute strength, together with your superior Martial Arts skills, performing kicks, round-house kicks, jump kicks, punches, and more. Ikari Warriors, save the world from chaos! Now!

===Game play===
Warrior now includes a life bar. Exclusive to the NES Port is a vertical shoot &amp;apos;em up segment which takes place underwater.

====Weapons====
Grenade is added in this game. In addition, Machine Gun&amp;apos;s ammo is reduced to 10 rounds.

====Enemies====
New enemy line up is used, which includes Green Soldier, Scuba Diver, Knife Man, Land Mine Soldier, Boomerang Soldier, Blue Ninja, Jetpack Soldier, Jason, Suohmaru.

Bosses include Armored Tank, Todd Manor, Brother Cheng, Aquarius, Armored Train, Faust.

==References==
*Lau, Wilson: [http://web.archive.org/web/20091021040714/http://geocities.com/TimesSquare/Realm/4610/games/ikari_warriors_iii_faq.txt Ikari III The Rescue FAQ/Walkthrough], 2003.

==External links==
*[http://www.arcade-history.com/?n=ikari-iii-the-rescue&amp;amp;page=detail&amp;amp;id=1177 Arcade history page]
*{{moby game|id=/ikari-iii-the-rescue|name=&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Ikari III: The Rescue&amp;apos;&amp;apos;}}
*[http://www.klov.com/game_detail.php?game_id=8179 Ikari III: The Rescue at the KLOV]

[[Category:1989 video games]]
[[Category:Arcade games]]
[[Category:SNK games]]
[[Category:Nintendo Entertainment System games]]
[[Category:PlayStation Network games]]
[[Category:Beat &amp;apos;em ups]]
[[Category:Video game sequels]]
[[Category:Video games set in the 21st century]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
