<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Self-pollination"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Self-pollination" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Unreferenced|date=December 2009}}
&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Self-pollination&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is a form of [[pollination]] that can occur when a [[flower]] has both [[stamen]] and a [[carpel]] (pistil) in which the [[cultivar]] or [[species]] is [[Self-fertilization|self fertile]] and the stamens and the sticky [[carpel|stigma]] of the carpel contact each other in order to accomplish pollination. The term is inaccurately used in many cases where an outside [[pollinator]] is actually required; such plants are merely self-fertile, or self [[pollenizer|pollenizing]].
__TOC__

Few plants actually self-pollinate. The mechanism is seen most often in some [[legume]]s such as [[peanut]]s. In another legume, [[soybean]]s, the flowers open and remain receptive to insect cross pollination during the day. If this is not accomplished, the flowers self-pollinate as they are closing. Among other plants that can self-pollinate are many kinds of [[orchid]]s, [[pea]]s, [[sunflower]]s and [[tridax]].  Most of the self-pollinating plants have small, relatively inconspicuous flowers that shed pollen directly onto the stigma, sometimes even before the bud opens. Self-pollinated plants expend less energy in the production of pollinator attractants and can grow in areas where the kinds of insects or other animals that might visit them are absent or very scarce—as in the Arctic or at high elevations.

Self-pollination limits the variety of progeny and may [[Inbreeding depression|depress plant vigor]].  However, self-pollination can be advantageous, allowing plants to spread beyond the range of suitable pollinators or produce offspring in areas where pollinator populations have been [[pollinator decline|greatly reduced]] or are naturally variable.

Pollination can also be accomplished by [[cross-pollination]]. Cross-pollination is the transfer of pollen, either by wind or insect, from the anther to the stigma between different flowers.

== Types of self pollination ==
There are two types of self-pollination:

In &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Type I&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; self pollination, pollen is transferred from the anther to the stigma of the same flower.  Such flowers are hermaphrodites, which have both sexes.

In &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Type II&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; pollen is transferred from the anther of one flower to the stigma of another flower from the same plant.

== Types of Flowers That Self Pollinate ==
Both [[hermaphrodite]] and [[monoecious]] species have the potential for self-pollination leading to self-fertilization unless there is a mechanism to avoid it.  Eighty percent of all flowering plants are hermaphrodite, meaning they contain both sexes, while 5 percent of plant species are monoecious, or unisexual.

== Advantages of self-pollination ==
There are several advantages for self-pollinating flowers. If a given genotype is well-suited for an environment, self-pollination helps to keep this trait stable in the species. Not being dependent on pollinating agents allows self-pollination to occur when bees and wind are nowhere to be found. Self-pollination can be an advantage when the number of flowers are small or widely spaced.

== Disadvantages of self-pollination ==
The disadvantages of self-pollination come from a lack of variation that allows no adaptation to the changing environment or potential pathogen attack. Self-pollination can lead to inbreeding depression, or the reduced health of the species, due to the breeding of related specimens. This is why many flowers that could potentially self-pollinate have a built-in mechanism to avoid it, or make it second choice at best.The genetic defects in the plant cannot be eliminated.

==See also==
*[[Cleistogamy]]
*[[Pistil]]
*[[Pollination]]
*[[Plants]]

{{DEFAULTSORT:Self-Pollination}}
[[Category:Pollination]]

{{Botany-stub}}

[[it:Impollinazione#Autoimpollinazione]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
