<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Wikipedia:Articles for deletion/Banana-Spirulina Pancakes"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Wikipedia:Articles for deletion/Banana-Spirulina Pancakes" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{| class=&amp;quot;messagebox&amp;quot;
|style=&amp;quot;padding-left:.2em;&amp;quot;| This page is preserved as an archive of the associated article page&amp;apos;s &amp;quot;votes for deletion&amp;quot; debate (the forerunner of [[WP:AFD|articles for deletion]]). &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Please do not modify this page, nor delete it as an orphaned talk page&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;.
|}

[[Banana-Spirulina Pancakes]]

There were no objections [http://en2.wikipedia.org/w/wiki.phtml?title=Wikipedia:Votes_for_deletion&amp;amp;diff=1901595&amp;amp;oldid=1901591] to deleting this when it was listed on VfD last time so I deleted it. I changed my mind and undeleted it following [[User:Quercusrobur|Quercusrobur]]&amp;apos;s query (see [[WP:VfU]]) as to why it was deleted. Should it be redeleted? [[User:Angela|Angela]][[User talk:Angela|.]] 02:23, 11 Dec 2003 (UTC)

:I am not sure why recipes are considered candidates for deletion.  Look at what&amp;apos;s been done off of [[List of cocktails]]: there are several dozen cocktail recipes here, at least.  If them, why not this?  (I though [[spirulina]] was some kind of algae, anyways.  So it may be bogus for other reasons.) -- [[User:Ihcoyc|Smerdis of Tlön]] 04:35, 11 Dec 2003 (UTC)

Spirulina is a health food.  Beyond that, I don&amp;apos;t see why recipes should be deleted.  We have several.  [[User:RickK|RickK]] 04:37, 11 Dec 2003 (UTC)

Most dishes are prepared in different ways by different people, so an individual recipe is usually just one person&amp;apos;s point of view on how a dish should be prepared, which doesn&amp;apos;t fit in with the NPOV policy. If for some dish there is a particular recipe that is more notable than the others - for example if it is the earliest known, or is interesting for another reason - then that recipe could perhaps be included in the general article on the dish, with an explanation of where it came from, and why it is notable. If a recipe is not particularly notable in connection with the dish it is for, then it could instead be included in another article, perhaps relating to the person who made up the recipe. For example, if someone can write a whole article on [[Mrs. Beeton&amp;apos;s pancake recipes]] (I don&amp;apos;t even know if she wrote any, but this is hypothetical!), then it could perhaps be illustrated with examples. However, note that Wikipedia is not a repository of source texts, so they shouldn&amp;apos;t take up most of the article. If a recipe isn&amp;apos;t even referenced, as was the case here, there is no way of judging its significance. For all we know, it could have been made up by the contributor. -- [[User:Oliver Pereira|Oliver P.]] 21:19, 11 Dec 2003 (UTC)

Keep. [[User:BL|BL]] 18:38, 16 Dec 2003 (UTC)&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
