<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Red-legged Partridge"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Red-legged Partridge" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Taxobox
| name = Red-legged Partridge
| status = LC | status_system = IUCN3.1
| status_ref = &amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;{{IUCN2006|assessors=BirdLife International|year=2004|id=47004|title=Alectoris rufa|downloaded=11 May 2006}}&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;
| image = AlectorisRufa.jpg
| image_width = 240px
| regnum = [[Animal]]ia
| phylum = [[Chordate|Chordata]]
| classis = [[bird|Aves]]
| ordo = [[Galliformes]]
| familia = [[Phasianidae]]
| subfamilia = [[Perdicinae]]
| genus = &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Alectoris]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos;
| species = &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;A. rufa&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;
| binomial = &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Alectoris rufa&amp;apos;&amp;apos;
| binomial_authority = ([[Carolus Linnaeus|Linnaeus]], 1758)
}}
[[File:Perdrix rouge MHNT.jpg|thumb| &amp;apos;&amp;apos; Alectoris rufa rufa &amp;apos;&amp;apos;]]

The &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Red-legged Partridge&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Alectoris rufa&amp;apos;&amp;apos;) is a [[gamebird]] in the pheasant family [[Phasianidae]] of the order [[Galliformes]], gallinaceous birds. It is sometimes known as &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;French Partridge&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, to distinguish it from the Grey or [[Grey Partridge|English Partridge]].

It is a rotund bird, with a light brown back, grey breast and buff belly. The face is white with a black gorget. It has rufous-streaked flanks and red legs. When disturbed, it prefers to run rather than fly, but if necessary it flies a short distance on rounded wings.

This is a seed-eating species, but the young in particular take [[insect]]s as an essential [[protein]] supply. The call is a three-syllable &amp;apos;&amp;apos;ka-chu-chu&amp;apos;&amp;apos;.

==Habitat==
This [[partridge]] breeds naturally in southwestern [[Europe]], in [[France]] and [[Iberian Peninsula|Iberia]]. It has become naturalised in flat areas of [[England and Wales]], where it was introduced as a game species, and has been seen breeding as far north as [[Lancashire]] and Eastern [[Yorkshire]] and the western [[Isle of Man]]. It is replaced in southeastern Europe by the very similar [[Rock Partridge]] (&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Alectoris graeca&amp;apos;&amp;apos;). It is a [[bird migration|non-migratory]] terrestrial species, which forms flocks outside the breeding season.

This species breeds on dry lowlands, such as farmland and open stony areas, laying its [[Egg (biology)|egg]]s in a ground nest.

== Taxonomy ==

===Subspecies===
There are three recognized [[subspecies]]:
* &amp;apos;&amp;apos;A. r. hispanica&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (Seoane, 1894)  - northern and western [[Iberian Peninsula]]
* &amp;apos;&amp;apos;A. r. intercedens&amp;apos;&amp;apos; ([[Alfred Brehm|Brehm]], 1857) - eastern and southern Iberian Peninsula and [[Balearic Islands]]
* &amp;apos;&amp;apos;A. r. rufa&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (Linnaeus, 1758) - nominate - [[France]], northwest [[Italy]], [[Elba]] and [[Corsica]]

==Description==
[[File:Alectoris rufa -Kirkmichael, Scotland-8.jpg|right|thumb|In Scotland]]
Adult Red-legged Partridges are sandy-brown above, pinkish-buff on the belly, and pale grey on the breast, with a prominent gorget of black streaking, bold rufous and black flank-bars, a cream throat, pink legs, and a red bill and eye ring.

The crown and upper nape of adult Red-legged Partridge are a warm pinkish-brown; the fore crown and lateral edges of the crown are pale blue-grey, and the bird has a narrow off-white [[supercilium]] running from above the lores to the sides of the lower nape. The lores have a solid bar of black feathering above a patch of pinkish-red skin. This black colouration continues behind the eye, where it broadens, and then extends down around the throat-patch to meet the upper edge of the gorget. There is a patch of pale buff-brown feathering on the ear-coverts, adjoining the black. The eye is surrounded by a bright red eye-ring.

The chin and upper throat are creamy-white, and are bordered behind and below by a solid black gorget. The black colour continues down onto the lower throat as a patch of broad triangular black streaks on a pale sandy-grey background. Similar, but narrower, black streaks are present on a pale blue-grey background on the upper neck-sides, while the lower neck-sides are warm pinkish-brown.  The breast is pale blue-grey, and the belly pinkish-buff. The flanks are marked with bold bright rufous-brown bars, typically between eight and ten; each bar has a narrow black leading edge, the background colour is off-white in front of each bar, and pale grey behind. The upper parts are plain, unmarked dark sandy-grey. The uppertail-coverts are similar in colour, and contrast with the pinkish-rufous tail-feathers.

The bill is bright red, the iris is medium brown, and the legs are pinkish-red.

== Cultivation and consumption ==

[[File:Red-legged Partridge at butchers in Ludlow.JPG|thumb|Red-legged Partridge hanging for sale outside a butcher&amp;apos;s shop in [[Ludlow]], Shropshire, England.]]

Red-legged Partridge are bred for shooting, and sold and eaten as [[Game (food)|game]].

==References==
{{reflist}}

==External links==
* [http://www.ibercajalav.net/img/141_RedleggedPartridgeArufa.pdf Ageing and sexing (PDF; 4.3 MB) by Javier Blasco-Zumeta &amp;amp; Gerd-Michael Heinze]

{{English Game}}

[[Category:Alectoris]]
[[Category:Birds of Europe]]
[[Category:Non-native fauna of the British Isles]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
