<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Cephissus (Athenian plain)"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Cephissus (Athenian plain)" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{unreferenced|date=September 2008}}

[[File:20090426 Kifissos river view from a bridge Athens.jpg|thumb|250px|Cephissus river view from above - from a bridge at the highway Athens-Lamia.]]
[[File:20090426 Kifissos river under the highway view Athens.jpg|thumb|250px|Cephissus river view under the highway Athens-Lamia.]]

&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Cephissus&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (Athenian plain) ({{lang-el|Κηφισός; Κηφισσός}}, &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Kifissós&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Kephissós&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Kêphissos&amp;apos;&amp;apos;) or &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Cephisus&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, is a river flowing through the Athenian plain.

The &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Bibliotheca (Pseudo-Apollodorus)|Bibliotheca]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (3.15.1) declares that [[Erechtheus]]&amp;apos; wife Praxithea was daughter of Phrasimus (otherwise unknown to us) by Diogenia (otherwise unknown to us) daughter of Cephissus.

This river is found in the western part of the valley. Today much of the river flows adjacent to the [[Greek National Road 1|freeway]] linking Athens and Thessaloniki, and east of mountains of [[Parnitha]] and [[Aegaleo]].

*Length: ?km/?mi
*Empties into: [[Saronic Gulf]]

In the southern part, the river flows for 15&amp;amp;nbsp;km under (but originally in the middle of) the highway named Kifissou Avenue.

==Kifissou Avenue Freeway==

After the [[2004 Summer Olympics|Olympics of 2004]], the Kifissou Avenue freeway, now with three to four lanes, runs for 15&amp;amp;nbsp;km over the river because of lack of space of housing in the Athens area.  It will also  connect [[Piraeus]], from the northern suburbs and the communities of south suburban [[Athens]] from [[Varkiza]] to [[Phaleron|Phaliron]].  This will decongest Athens&amp;apos; downtown streets.

===History===
Construction began in 1995 and with four bridges being torn down for widening.  Work has continued for nearly eight years.  However, heavy rains and flooding delayed work over the river (first week of August 1997) causing a cement truck to wash away.  In 1999, the reconstruction of Treis Gephyres, (the Three Bridges) was being repaired for widening.

In the later phases of construction, the new freeway extended to near Peiraiôs Avenue when heavy rains delayed the construction in mid and late 2002, one in mid-[[July 2002|July]], and about three in [[September 2002|September]].  Flooding has also occurred.  Gates were being put to prevent flooding.  This was the year of heavy rains.  The freeway over the Kifissos or the Cephissus made it down to the freeway (not far where the river ends) linking the southern suburbs and Athens from Piraeus which is also Poseidonos Avenue for its final phases owidening GR-1.  This will end with opening a southern junction near the new Olympic facility.  It will open around mid-2004.

{{Streets in Athens}}
{{commons category|Kifissou Avenue}}

[[Category:Rivers of Greece]]
[[Category:Greek gods]]
[[Category:Sea and river gods]]
[[Category:Greek mythology]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
