<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Xaltocan"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Xaltocan" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{About|pre-Columbian city-state and island in the Valley of Mexico|modern-day municipality in the state of Tlaxcala|Xaltocan, Tlaxcala}}
[[Image:Lake Texcoco c 1519.png|thumb|right|200px|Map of the [[Valley of Mexico]] at the time of the [[Spanish Conquest of Mexico|Spanish Conquest]] showing the location of lake Xaltocan.]]

&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Xaltocan&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; was a [[pre-Columbian]] [[city-state]] and island in the [[Valley of Mexico]], located in the center of [[Lake Xaltocan]], part of an interconnected shallow lake system which included [[Lake Texcoco]]. The site was originally settled by the [[Otomi people]], but following a war in the late fourteenth century where the Otomi were defeated by an alliance of [[Tepanec]]s and [[Aztec|Mexica]] the Otomi were driven off the island and relocated to [[Otompan|Otumba]], Metztitlan and [[Tlaxcala (Nahua state)|Tlaxcala]]. The island of Xaltocan was then resettled by [[Nahuatl]] speakers.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;Davies, 1980 p. 233-34&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;Morehart 2012&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

==Overview==
Xaltocan is known to have been inhabited in the [[Mesoamerican chronology#Postclassic Era|Postclassic]] period. Ceramics and other archaeological remains dating to this period have been recovered in excavations at the site.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;Brumfiel, E (2005)&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt; It is thought to have been a local center of power capable of exacting tribute from other city-states in the area.

The founding of Xaltocan is described in the mytho-historical documents, the &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Historia Tolteca-Chichimeca]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos; and &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Anales de Cuauhtitlan]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos;. According to the &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Anales&amp;apos;&amp;apos; the Xaltocameca (people of Xaltocan) were among the [[Chichimec]] tribes that left the mythical place of origin, [[Aztlán]], under a leader named &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Quauhtliztac&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (&amp;quot;White Eagle&amp;quot;). The &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Historia&amp;apos;&amp;apos; also identifies the Xaltocameca as belong to the Otomi ethnic group.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;Davies, 1980 p. 91-93&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt; In this document, written by [[Fernando de Alva Cortés Ixtlilxochitl|Ixtlilxochitl]], the first leader of the Xaltocameca is named as &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Iztacquauhtli&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, which also means &amp;quot;White Eagle&amp;quot; in [[Nahuatl language|Nahuatl]].

In the 13th century Xaltocan were involved in a prolonged war with the [[Nahua peoples|Nahua]] city-state of [[Cuautitlán|Cuauhtitlan]]. Xaltocan was initially the strongest but around 1395 the ruler of Cuauhtitlan, Xaltemoctzin, allied himself with [[Tezozomoc (Azcapotzalco)|Tezozomoc]] of [[Azcapotzalco]] and his subjects the [[Mexica]] of [[Tenochtitlan]] and finally managed to conquer Xaltocan. The Otomi inhabitants fled north to the Otomian city-state of Metztitlan and to [[Tlaxcala]], while others were allowed to resettle on the lands of [[Texcoco (altepetl)|Texcoco]] in the place that was henceforth called [[Otompan|Otumba]] - &amp;quot;Place of the Otomies&amp;quot;.

During the next 100 years the site was resettled by Nahua peoples. After the [[Aztec Triple Alliance]] defeated the Tepanecs of Azcapotzalco, Xaltocan became an Aztec subject city and paid tribute to Tenochtitlan, mainly in the form of woven blankets. In 1521 during the [[Spanish conquest of Mexico]] the army of [[Hernán Cortés]] razed Xaltocan and burned it to the ground.

==Notes==
{{Reflist|1}}

==References==
* Brumfiel, E.M. &amp;amp; M.G. Hodge, 1996, &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Interaction in the basin of Mexico: The case of Postclassic Xaltocan&amp;apos;&amp;apos;- Arqueología mesoamericana: homenaje a William T. Sanders
* Brumfiel, Elizabeth M., Ed. 2005, &amp;quot;Production and Power at Postclassic Xaltocan&amp;quot; &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Arqueología de México&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, No. 6, published by University of Pittsburgh Latin American Archaeology Publications and Instituto Nacional de Antropología e Historia (México, D.F.)389 pp.&amp;amp;nbsp;ISBN 1-877812-81-1.
* Brumfiel, Elizabeth M., 1996, &amp;quot;The Quality of Tribute Cloth: The Place of Evidence in Archaeological Argument&amp;quot; in  &amp;apos;&amp;apos;American Antiquity, Vol. 61&amp;apos;&amp;apos;
* Davies, Nigel, 1980, &amp;apos;&amp;apos;The Toltec Heritage - from the fall of Tula to the rise of Tenochtitlan&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, University of Oklahoma Press.
* Hodge, Mary G., and Hector Neff 2005 Xaltocan in the Economy of the Basin of Mexico: A View from Ceramic Tradewares. In Production and Power at Postclassic Xaltocan. Elizabeth M. Brumfiel, ed. Pp. 319–348. Mexico City : Instituto Nacional de Antropología e Historia.
* Morehart, C. T. (2012), What If the Aztec Empire Never Existed? The Prerequisites of Empire and the Politics of Plausible Alternative Histories. American Anthropologist, 114: 267–281.
*Morehart, Christopher T. and Dan T.A. Eisenberg 2010 Prosperity, Power, and Change: Modeling Maize at Postclassic Xaltocan, Mexico. Journal of Anthropological Archaeology 29(1):94–112.
*Romero Navarrete Omar 2007 La gloria de Xaltocan: los guerreros del sol. Mexico , D.F. : Talleres de Luis Gonzalez Obregon

{{coord missing|Mexico}}

[[Category:Archaeological sites in Mexico]]
[[Category:Mesoamerican sites]]
[[Category:Aztec sites]]
[[Category:Former populated places in Mexico]]
[[Category:Otomi sites]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
