<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="The Naturist Society"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="The Naturist Society" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;The Naturist Society&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (often abbreviated to &amp;quot;TNS&amp;quot;) is an American [[naturist]] organization based in [[Oshkosh, Wisconsin]], [[USA]]. It publishes a [[quarterly]] [[periodical]] called &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Nude &amp;amp; Natural]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos; which contains articles on naturist activities and issues related to naturism. The Naturist Society was established by [[Lee Baxandall]] in 1980. Baxandall was the Society president for a number of years.  Baxandall formulated the initial TNS motto:  &amp;quot;Body acceptance is the goal, nude recreation is the way.&amp;quot;  This statement incorporates the belief that the human body is not intrinsically offensive and that the practice of social nudity can be affirming, not degrading.

==Membership==
The TNS Naturist Network includes both private nudist resorts and naturist social clubs that agree to TNS principles and standards. Most TNS-affiliated nudist resorts are also chartered by the [[American Association for Nude Recreation]], and the TNS membership card usually has equal status to the AANR membership card at resorts. TNS includes an equal opportunities statement in its participating agreement&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;{{cite web|url=http://www.naturistsociety.com/organizations/CurrentPA.pdf |title=Current Participating Agreement}}&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt; for its Naturist Network, which includes nudist resorts. It notes that its members must not &amp;quot;discriminate on the basis of age, sex, race, national origin, religion, disability, or sexual orientation.&amp;quot;  But &amp;quot;TNS acknowledges that single male visitors may be subject to a quota if a club or resort deems this unavoidable.&amp;quot;  The Naturist Society issues joint membership cards to same-sex couples.

Membership in The Naturist Society includes a subscription to N magazine.

==Politics and education==
In the 1990s, TNS established two nonprofit adjunct organizations, governed by a board of directors elected by the TNS membership:  The [[Naturist Action Committee]], its political and legislative lobbying adjunct, and the [http://www.nef.oshkosh.net/ Naturist Education Foundation]. TNS advocates for the acceptance of skinny-dipping and nude sunbathing at designated clothing-optional public beaches. A 2006 Roper Poll commissioned by the Naturist Education Foundation found that 74% of Americans accept this idea.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;{{cite web|url=http://www.naturisteducation.org/Projects/NEF-Roper_Poll_2006/nef-roper_poll_2006.html |title=2006 Roper Poll}}&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

==Purpose and activities==
TNS publishes a [[quarterly]] [[periodical]] called &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Nude &amp;amp; Natural]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (commonly called &amp;apos;&amp;apos;N&amp;apos;&amp;apos; magazine) which contains articles on naturist activities and issues related to naturism. TNS launched in 1981 its magazine, initially called &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Clothed with the Sun&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, which was edited by TNS founder Lee Baxandall. The magazine was renamed &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Nude &amp;amp; Natural&amp;apos;&amp;apos; in 1989.

The organization believes naturism is more than just being nude. &amp;quot;Naturism is about much more than clothing-optional recreation. It&amp;apos;s a natural way of living. And recognizing our interdependency with Nature, we as naturists can affirm the goodness of being and appearing fully human while acknowledging our need to tread wisely and kindly on the Earth. To this end TNS wishes to cultivate a heightened respect for Nature.&amp;quot;{{fact|date=November 2011}}

TNS organizes several annual gatherings in various regions of North America, such as the Western Naturist Gathering and the Eastern Naturist Gathering (the largest such event, held in Massachusetts since 1997).  The gatherings feature workshops and seminars on many topics, especially those that relate to body health and ongoing legal issues.{{fact|date=November 2011}}

TNS also supports various [[Special Interest Group]]s for TNS members who share hobbies or other interests such as [[amateur radio]].

==Publications==
*[[Nude &amp;amp; Natural|N Magazine]]
*&amp;apos;&amp;apos;The World’s Best Nude Beaches and Resorts - The top 1,000 places to get naked&amp;apos;&amp;apos;

==See also==
*[[American Association for Nude Recreation]] (AANR)
*[[Clothes free movement]]
*[[Gymnophobia]]
*[[Issues in social nudity]]
*[[List of public outdoor clothes free places]]
*[[Public nudity]]
*[[Skinny dipping]]
*[[American Nudist Research Library]]

==References==
{{Reflist}}

==External links==
*[http://www.naturist.com The Naturist Society Web Site]
*[http://www.inaro.com The Naturist Amateur Radio SIG]

[[Category:Clothes free organizations|Naturist Society, The]]
[[Category:Naturism in the United States]]
[[Category:1980 establishments in the United States]]
[[Category:Organizations established in 1980]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
