<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Symphony No. 13 (Haydn)"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Symphony No. 13 (Haydn)" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;[[Joseph Haydn]]&amp;apos;s &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Symphony No. 13 in D major&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; was written in 1763 for the [[orchestra]] of Haydn&amp;apos;s patron, Prince [[Nikolaus Esterházy]], in [[Eisenstadt]].

The work can be precisely dated thanks to a dated score in Haydn&amp;apos;s own hand in the National Library of [[Budapest]]. Two other Haydn symphonies are known to have been written in the same year: the [[Symphony No. 12 (Haydn)|Symphony No. 12]] and the [[Symphony No. 40 (Haydn)|Symphony No. 40]].

==Movements==
A typical symphony at this time was written for a pairs of [[oboe]]s and [[Horn (instrument)|horn]]s and [[string instrument]]s, but the Eisenstadt orchestra had recently taken on two new horn players, and Haydn wrote this symphony for an expanded ensemble of one [[flute]], two oboes, four horns, [[timpani]] and strings ([[violin]]s divided into firsts and seconds), [[viola]]s, [[cello]]s and [[double bass]]es), with [[bassoon]] doubling the bass-line. The timpani part in the autograph score is not in Haydn&amp;apos;s hand, but it is quite possibly authentic: he may have written it on a separate sheet, with somebody else adding it to the score at a later date.

#[[Tempo#Italian tempo markings|Allegro]] molto, 4/4
#[[Tempo#Italian tempo markings|Adagio]] cantabile, 4/4
#[[Minuet|Menuet]] &amp;amp; Trio, 3/4
#Finale. Allegro molto, 2/4

The first movement opens with held chords in the winds and the strings playing a simple figure based on an [[arpeggio]]:

[[Image:Haydn-symph-13-opening.png]]

The movement can be considered to be in [[sonata form]], with a repeated first half beginning in the home [[key (music)|key]] of [[D major]] and [[modulation (music)|modulating]] to [[A major]], then a second half beginning with a development of previously heard material (passing through [[B minor]]) followed by a recapitulation of the first half, now entirely in D major (this second half also repeated). However, there is little &amp;quot;second subject&amp;quot; to speak of - following the key change in the first half, the music is mainly based on simple scale passages.

The second movement, marked &amp;apos;&amp;apos;adagio cantabile&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (slowly, singing), in [[G major]], features a solo cello playing a melody against simple chords from the rest of the strings. The winds do not play in this movement. In Haydn&amp;apos;s day, the cello part would have been played by the principal cellist of the Eistenstadt orchestra, [[Joseph Franz Weigl]].

The D major third movement is a [[minuet]] and [[trio (music)|trio]] in [[ternary form]], with the flute prominently featured in the trio. The last movement is based around a four-note figure which seems to foreshadow the last movement of [[Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart|Mozart]]&amp;apos;s &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Jupiter Symphony]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos;:

[[Image:haydn-symph-13-last-mvmt.png]]

The figure, which appears in various keys throughout the movement, is treated in a manner which hints at [[fugue]]. Near the end it is heard in the strings in &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[stretto]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (overlapping entries, a new one beginning before the last has ended).

A typical performance of the whole piece will last a little over twenty minutes.

==References==
*[[H. C. Robbins Landon]] (ed.), &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Joseph Haydn: The Complete Symphonies&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, volume II (Philharmonia/[[Universal Edition]], 1964)

==External links==
*The William and Gayle Cook Music Library at the Indiana University School of Music has posted the [http://www.dlib.indiana.edu/variations/scores/ahb9900/index.html score] of the symphony.

{{HaydnSymphonies}}

[[Category:Symphonies by Joseph Haydn|Symphony 013]]
[[Category:1763 compositions]]
[[Category:Compositions in D major]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
