<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Noctis Labyrinthus"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Noctis Labyrinthus" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{MarsGeo-Valley
|image=[[Image:Noctis Labyrinthus.jpg|200px]]
|caption=In this [[Viking 1]] image, the canyons are filled with mist from frost sublimated by the early-morning sun. Courtesy NASA/JPL-Caltech.
|name=Noctis Labyrinthus
|latitude=7.0
|N_or_S=S
|longitude=102.2
|E_or_W=W
|length=1,263.0
}}
[[Image:M09 mtvs4187 45.gif|thumb|right|[[Mariner 9]] view of the Noctis Labyrinthus &amp;quot;labyrinth&amp;quot; at the western end of Valles Marineris on Mars. Linear graben, grooves, and crater chains dominate this region, along with a number of flat-topped mesas. The image is roughly 400 km across, centered at 6 S, 105 W, at the edge of the Tharsis bulge. North is up. Image located in [[Phoenicis Lacus quadrangle]]]]

&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Noctis Labyrinthus&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, &amp;quot;the labyrinth of the night&amp;quot;, is a region of [[Mars]] between [[Valles Marineris]] and the [[Tharsis]] upland. It is located in the [[Phoenicis Lacus quadrangle]].  The region is notable for its maze-like system of deep, steep-walled valleys. The valleys and canyons of this region formed by faulting and many show classic features of [[graben]]s, with the upland plain surface preserved on the valley floor. In some places the valley floors are rougher, disturbed by [[landslide]]s, and there are places where the land appears to have sunk down into pit-like formations.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;http://cmex.ihmc.us/cmex/data/voviews/Canyons/Noctis.htm&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt; It is thought that this faulting was triggered by volcanic activity in the Tharsis region.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;[http://themis.asu.edu/feature_noctis Mars Odyssey Mission THEMIS: Feature Image: Noctis Labyrinthus Landslides&amp;lt;!-- Bot generated title --&amp;gt;]&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;  Research described in December 2009 found a variety of minerals, including clays, sulfates, and hydrated silicas, in some of the layers. &amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;http://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2009/12//091216205910.htm&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

==Gallery==
&amp;lt;gallery&amp;gt;
Image:Eastern Tharsis and Noctis Labyrinthus.png|Noctis Labyrinthus in the lower right. The three large mountains on the left are [[Tharsis Montes]]
Image:Part_of_Noctis_Labyrinthus_taken_with_the_Mars_Global_Surveyor_-_20060529.jpg|Part of Noctis Labyrinthus taken with Mars Global Surveyor.  Courtesy NASA/Malin Space Science Systems.
Image:Noctis_Labyrinthus.JPG|Layers in the wall of Noctis Labyrinthus taken with Mars Global Surveyor.  Courtesy NASA/Malin Space Science Systems.
Image:Noctis Labyrinthus formation on Mars.jpg|Layers in the lower portion of two neighbouring buttes within the Noctis Labyrinthus formation on Mars are visible in this image.
Image:25970noctuslayers.jpg|Section of layers near top of Noctis Labyrinthus, as seen by HiRISE under [[HiWish program]].
Image:25970bottomlayers.jpg|Group of layers near the bottom of Noctis labrinthus, as seen by HiRISE under HiWish program.
Image:CtxnoctisP11 005334 1717.jpg|Wide view of cliff with layers in Noctis Labyrinthus.
Image:26682layersclose.jpg|Close-up of part of previous image of layers in Noctis Labyrinthus, as seen by HiRISE under HiWish program.
Image:ESP 026682 1700 RED abrowse.jpg|Wide view of floor of Noctis Labyrinthus, as seen by HiRISE under HiWish program.
Image:26682dunes.jpg|Close-up of complex, dark dunes in the previous image of the floor of Noctis Labyrinthus, as seen by HiRISE under HiWish program.
Image:26682layersnorth.jpg|Close-up of some layers in wall of Noctis Labrinthus, as seen by HiRISE under HiWish program.
Image:ESP_027526_1685noctis.jpg|Layers on floor of Noctus Labyrinthus, as seen by HiRISE under HiWish program.  Layers probably contain a variety of minerals that were formed with groundwater.
Image:ESP_027592_1685close.jpg|Close-up of layers on floor of Noctus Labyrinthus, as seen by HiRISE under HiWish program.  This is an enlargement from the center of the previous picture.
&amp;lt;/gallery&amp;gt;

==References==
{{Reflist}}

==External links==
*{{cite news|title=Images from ESA Mars Express|date=December 3, 2007|publisher=[[European Space Agency]]|url=http://www.esa.int/SPECIALS/Mars_Express/SEMWBK73R8F_0.html|accessdate=2007-12-03}}
{{Mars}}
{{portal bar|Mars}}
[[Category:Valleys and canyons on Mars]]

{{mars-stub}}
{{crater-stub}}&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
