<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Quality bias"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Quality bias" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Multiple issues|
{{original research|date=October 2009}}
{{unreferenced|date=January 2008}}
}}

&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Quality bias&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; in [[price indexes]] occurs when an index ignores changes in the quality of the goods it measures. An example would be enhanced performance of personal computers.  Generally speaking, greater and greater speeds and features have become available, without substantial increases in price. Quality bias can cause a [[consumer price index]] (CPI) to be overestimated, since a CPI may not completely reflect quality improvements.

==Determining quality==
{{off topic|date=April 2013}}
Quality bias can work both ways.  Faster computers with enhanced performance require greater [[Memory (computers)|memory]] and more expensive support [[software]].  Most [[personal computer]]s were previously [[Product bundling|bundled]] with software, but now come only with a basic [[operating system]] and a requirement for the purchaser to purchase the bundled software after a &amp;quot;trial period&amp;quot;, so the actual &amp;apos;&amp;apos;value&amp;apos;&amp;apos; per dollar is much lower.  [[Obsolescence]] is built into most personal electronics, shortening their useful live, again lowering the actual value.  All these issues make the quality bias tend to be negative rather than positive.  As products and the manufacturing methodology advances, the cost of manufacture is expected to go down, and improved products are part of every product life cycle, and many products go through repeated cycling.  An example is the automobile.  Quality bias is most often seen in a negative manner in the cases of mature products as companies lower their acceptance standards in order to increase their [[profit margin]]s.  There is no effective measure for declining quality, unfortunately, which is why some nations such as Germany and Japan have developed very meticulous standards for nearly everything, including services.  The [[Deutsches Institut für Normung|DIN]] and [[Japanese Industrial Standards|JIS]] enable anyone to evaluate whether or not an article has been properly produced.  There is no such standard in the U.S., except for some scattered attempts by insurers to control electrical quality (such as [[UL (safety organization)|UL]]). Engineering standards, such as [[ASME]] and [[ASTM]]; Automotive, such as [[Automotive Service Excellence|ASE]] and [[ISO]] are not effective standards and do not compare with JIS or DIN because it is self-imposed, self-regulated, and self-inspected by the very people it is designed to regulate.

{{DEFAULTSORT:Quality Bias}}
[[Category:Consumer theory]]
[[Category:Price indices]]
[[Category:Price index theory]]

{{econ-stub}}&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
