<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Fallacy of composition"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Fallacy of composition" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;The &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;fallacy of composition&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; arises when one infers that something is true of the &amp;apos;&amp;apos;whole&amp;apos;&amp;apos; from the fact that it is true of some &amp;apos;&amp;apos;part&amp;apos;&amp;apos; of the whole (or even of &amp;apos;&amp;apos;every&amp;apos;&amp;apos; [[proper part]]). For example: &amp;quot;This fragment of metal cannot be fractured with a hammer, therefore the machine of which it is a part cannot be fractured with a hammer.&amp;quot; This is clearly fallacious, because many machines can be broken-apart, without any of those parts being fracturable.

This [[fallacy]] is often confused with the fallacy of [[hasty generalization]], in which an unwarranted inference is made from a statement about a sample to a statement about the population from which it is drawn.

The fallacy of composition is the converse of the [[fallacy of division]]. The fallacy of composition is also known as the &amp;quot;un-ecological fallacy.&amp;quot;

==Examples==
If someone stands up out of his seat at a baseball game, he can see better. Therefore, if everyone stands up they can all see better.

If a runner runs faster, she can win the race. Therefore if all the runners run faster, they can all win the race.

In economics, the famous [[Paradox of thrift|Paradox of Thrift]], is held to answer a fallacy of composition:

::A. &amp;apos;&amp;apos;If a household saves more money now, instead of spending, it will have more money to spend in the future.&amp;apos;&amp;apos;
::B. &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Therefore, if all households save more money now, instead of spending, they will all have more money to spend in the future.&amp;apos;&amp;apos;

The Paradox of Thrift shows this syllogism to be a fallacy of composition, in that the syllogism presumes that what is true for one household must be true for all households in the aggregate.  The Paradox of Thrift lies in the observation that, in fact, if all households in a society increase their saving, all other things remaining unchanged, the reduction in buying will also reduce revenues and, thereby, incomes, paradoxically leaving households with &amp;apos;&amp;apos;less&amp;apos;&amp;apos; money to spend than they otherwise would have had.  The common-sense presumption that, because thrift is beneficial to a single household, or to many, it must be beneficial to most, or to all, thus depends upon a fallacy of composition.

In [[voting theory]], the [[Condorcet paradox]] demonstrates a fallacy of composition: Even if all voters have rational [[preferences]], the collective choice induced by [[majority rule]] is not transitive and hence not rational.  The fallacy of composition occurs if  from the rationality of the individuals one infers that society can be equally rational.  The principle generalizes beyond the aggregation via majority rule to any reasonable aggregation rule, demonstrating that the aggregation of individual preferences into a [[Social welfare function]] is fraught with severe difficulties (see [[Arrow&amp;apos;s impossibility theorem]] and [[Social choice theory]]).{{cn|date=May 2012}}

==&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Modo hoc&amp;apos;&amp;apos; fallacy==

The &amp;apos;&amp;apos;modo hoc&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (or &amp;quot;just this&amp;quot;) fallacy is the informal error of assessing meaning to an existent based on the constituent properties of its [[matter|material makeup]] while omitting the matter&amp;apos;s arrangement.&amp;lt;ref name=&amp;quot;Carrier&amp;quot;&amp;gt;{{cite book |last=Carrier |first=Richard |title=Sense and Goodness Without God: A Defense of Metaphysical Naturalism |publisher=Prometheus Books |year=2005 |page=130 |isbn=1-4208-0293-3}}&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt; For instance, [[metaphysical naturalism]] states that while matter and [[Motion (physics)|motion]] are all that comprise [[man]], it cannot be assumed that the characteristics inherent in the elements and physical reactions that make up man ultimately and solely define man&amp;apos;s meaning; for, a cow which is alive and well and a cow which has been chopped up into meat are the same matter but it is obvious that the &amp;apos;&amp;apos;arrangement&amp;apos;&amp;apos; of that matter clarifies those different situational meanings.&amp;lt;ref name=&amp;quot;Carrier&amp;quot; /&amp;gt;

==References==
{{Use dmy dates|date=November 2011}}
{{Reflist}}

{{Informal fallacy}}

{{DEFAULTSORT:Composition}}
[[Category:Inductive fallacies]]
[[Category:Verbal fallacies]]
[[Category:Relevance fallacies]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
