<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Woodland Kingfisher"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Woodland Kingfisher" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Taxobox
| name = Woodland Kingfisher
| status = LC
| status_system = IUCN3.1
| status_ref = &amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;{{IUCN|id=106001106 |title=&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Halcyon senegalensis&amp;apos;&amp;apos; |assessors=[[BirdLife International]] |version=2012.1 |year=2012 |accessdate=16 July 2012}}&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;
| image = WoodlandKingfisher.jpg
| image_width =
| regnum = [[Animal]]ia
| phylum = [[Chordate|Chordata]]
| classis = [[bird|Aves]]
| ordo = [[Coraciiformes]]
| familia = [[Halcyonidae]]
| genus = &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Halcyon (genus)|Halcyon]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos;
| species = &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;H. senegalensis&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;
| binomial = &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Halcyon senegalensis&amp;apos;&amp;apos;
| binomial_authority = ([[Carolus Linnaeus|Linnaeus]], 1766)
}}

The &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Woodland Kingfisher&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Halcyon senegalensis&amp;apos;&amp;apos;) is a [[tree kingfisher]].

==Description==
This is a medium-sized kingfisher, 20–23&amp;amp;nbsp;cm in length. The adult has a bright blue back, wing panel and tail. Its head, neck and underparts are white, and its shoulders are black. The flight of the Woodland Kingfisher is rapid and direct. The large bill has a red upper mandible and black lower mandible. The legs are bright red. Some birds may have greyish heads, causing confusion with Mangrove Kingfisher.

However, the lores are dark, creating a dark stripe through the eye (the stripe does not extend through the eye in Mangrove Kingfisher), and the underwing, primaries and secondaries are black with white underwing coverts (there is a black carpal patch on the white coverts in Manrgove Kingfisher). The inner webs of the base of the flight feathers are white, creating an indistinct white wingbar (white completely absent from wings in Mangrove Kingfisher). The breast is white (tends to be much greyer in Mangrove Kingfisher).  The sexes are similar, but juveniles are duller than adults and have a brown bill.

==Distribution and habitat==
The Woodland Kingfisher is widely distributed in tropical [[Africa]] south of the [[Sahara]] and from [[Pretoria]] northwards. This [[kingfisher]] is essentially resident within 8° of the equator, but northern and southern populations are [[bird migration|migratory]], moving into the equatorial zone in the dry season.

It is a common species of a variety of wooded habitats with some trees, especially [[Acacia]]s, including around human habitation. Although it is a &amp;quot;kingfisher&amp;quot;, it prefers drier habitats in more traditional woodland and can be far from water. It is often solitary but can occur in small groups.
[[File:Woodland Kingfisher ( Halcyon senegalensis) RWD.jpg|thumb|Woodland Kingfisher, Tanzania]]

==Behaviour==
The Woodland Kingfisher  is aggressively territorial, attacking intruders including humans. It has a striking display in which the wings are spread to show the white linings.

===Breeding===
The nest is a tree hole excavated by a [[woodpecker]] or [[Lybiidae|barbet]]. A single clutch of three round white eggs is typical.

===Food===
It hunts from an exposed perch, often on a dead branch of a tree, or perches quietly in semi-shade while seeking food.

===Call===
The call of this noisy kingfisher is a loud trill sounding like a nail run down the teeth of a comb.

==References==
{{Reflist}}&amp;lt;!-- FieldianaZool34:35,51:91. --&amp;gt;
{{commons category|Halcyon senegalensis}}
* &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Kingfishers, Bee-eaters and Rollers&amp;apos;&amp;apos; by Fry, Fry and Harris, ISBN 0-7136-8028-8

==External links==
* Woodland Kingfisher - [http://sabap2.adu.org.za/docs/sabap1/433.pdf Species text in The Atlas of Southern African Birds].

[[Category:Halcyon (genus)]]
[[Category:Birds of Cameroon]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
