<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Via Panisperna boys"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Via Panisperna boys" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;[[File:Ragazzi di via Panisperna.jpg|thumb|Enrico Fermi and the &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Via Panisperna boys&amp;apos;&amp;apos; in the courtyard of Rome University&amp;apos;s Physics Institute in Via Panisperna, about 1934. From Left to right:  [[Oscar D&amp;apos;Agostino]], [[Emilio Segrè]], [[Edoardo Amaldi]], [[Franco Rasetti]] and Enrico Fermi]]

The &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Via Panisperna boys&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (Italian: &amp;apos;&amp;apos;I ragazzi di Via Panisperna&amp;apos;&amp;apos;) were a group of young scientists led by [[Enrico Fermi]]. In Rome in 1934, they made the famous discovery of [[slow neutron]]s which later made possible the [[nuclear reactor]], and then the construction of the first [[atomic bomb]].
The nickname of the group comes from the address of the Physics Institute, at the [[University of Rome La Sapienza]]. The Via Panisperna, a street of [[Rioni of Rome|Rione]] [[Monti (rione of Rome)| Monti]] in the city center, got its name from a nearby monastery, [[San Lorenzo in Panisperna]].

The other members of the group were [[Edoardo Amaldi]], [[Oscar D&amp;apos;Agostino]], [[Ettore Majorana]], [[Bruno Pontecorvo]], [[Franco Rasetti]] and [[Emilio Segrè]]. All of them were physicists, except for D&amp;apos;Agostino who was a chemist.

==The growth of the group==
The group grew under the supervision of the physicist, minister, senator and director of the Institute of physics [[Orso Mario Corbino]]. Corbino recognized the qualities of Enrico Fermi and led the commission who appointed him in 1926 as professor of one of the three first Chairs of [[Theoretical Physics]] in Italy. &amp;lt;ref name=se45&amp;gt;
{{cite book
 |last=Segrè |first=Emilio
 |title=Enrico Fermi, Physicist
 |year=1970 |publisher=[[University of Chicago Press]]
 |isbn=0-226-74473-6
 |page=45
}}&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt; From 1929, Fermi and Corbino dedicated themselves to the transformation of the institute into a modern research centre.

==Research==
The first version of their research laboratory was mainly dedicated to atomic and molecular [[spectroscopy]]; afterwards they moved towards experimental studies of the [[atomic nucleus]]. Research included the bombarding of various substances with [[neutrons]], obtained by irradiating [[beryllium]] with [[alpha particle]]s emitted by [[radon]], which is a strongly [[radioactive]] gas that renders possible numerous stable artificial radioactive elements. On the theoretical side, the work of [[Ettore Majorana]] and [[Fermi]] enabled the understanding of the structure of the atomic nucleus and the forces acting in it, known as the [[Majorana Forces]]. In 1933 and 1934 they published the fundamental theory of [[beta decay]].

==The group disperses==
In 1938, because of the general climate in Europe, and in particular in Italy the group dispersed and most of its members emigrated. The head of the group, Prof. Fermi, was also forced to emigrate, since the passing of the [[Fascism|Fascist]] [[racial laws]] were  damaging his wife, who was Jewish, and his academic career. Fermi left the fascist Italy with his family for Stockholm to receive the Nobel Prize on the 6th December 1938, and from there they reached the States.
Oscar D&amp;apos;Agostino and Edoardo Amaldi were the only ones who remained in Italy. In the post-war reconstruction of Italian physics, Amaldi contributed significantly to the foundation of [[CERN]].

==In the media==
The movie director [[Gianni Amelio]] has told their story in a TV-movie which became a film, &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[I ragazzi di via Panisperna]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (1989).

The building in Via Panisperna, lying on the [[Viminale]] hill, is today included in the complex of the Ministry of the Interior. The edifice is planned to host a centre for research and a museum of physics named after Enrico Fermi. &amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;{{cite web|url=http://library.web.cern.ch/library/Webzine/7/papers/3/|accessdate=8 May 2012|title=The Istituto Fisico on Via Panisperna:
the new Museo Storico della Fisica e Centro Studi e Ricerche &amp;quot;Enrico Fermi&amp;quot; di Roma|publisher=CERN. High Energy Physics Libraries Webzine}} &amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

==See also==
{{Wikipedia-Books|Via Panisperna Boys|position=left}}

== References ==
*&amp;apos;&amp;apos;La scienza. Molecole, atomi, particelle.&amp;apos;&amp;apos; Vol. 12. La biblioteca di Repubblica. Rome, La Repubblica-UTET, 2005.

== External links ==
*{{it}} [http://www.phys.uniroma1.it/DipWeb/museo/fermi.html Enrico Fermi and the Via Panisperna Boys] from the Museum of Physics of [[Sapienza University of Rome|&amp;quot;La Sapienza&amp;quot; University in Rome]]

==References==
{{Reflist|30em}}

{{DEFAULTSORT:Via Panisperna Boys}}

[[Category:Italian nuclear physicists]]
[[Category:Sapienza University of Rome]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
