<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Syphax"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Syphax" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;:&amp;apos;&amp;apos;For the Canadian mountain, see [[Mount Syphax]]. For the mythological figure, see [[Sufax]]. There is also a genus of fossil spiders [[Syphax (spider)|Syphax]] ([[Thomisidae]]).&amp;apos;&amp;apos;

&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Syphax&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; was a king of the ancient [[Algeria]]n tribe [[Masaesyli]] of western [[Numidia]] during the last quarter of the 3rd century BC. His story is told in [[Livy]]&amp;apos;s &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Ab Urbe Condita (book)|Ab Urbe Condita]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (written &amp;apos;&amp;apos;ca.&amp;apos;&amp;apos; 27-25 BC).

==Biography==
When in 218 BC, war broke out between [[Ancient Carthage|Carthage]] and [[Ancient Rome|Rome]], Syphax was initially sympathetic to the [[Roman Empire|Romans]] and in 213 BC, he concluded an alliance with the Romans and they sent military advisers to help Syphax train his troops. He then attacked the eastern Numidians, the Massylians, ruled by king [[Gala (Numidian king)|Gala]]; at that time allied to the Carthaginians. When Gala died in 206 BC, his sons [[Massinissa]] and Oezalces quarreled about the inheritance, and Syphax was able to conquer considerable parts of the eastern Numidian kingdom.

After the Roman general Publius Cornelius Scipio ([[Scipio Africanus]]) met with victory in the [[Battle of Ilipa]] (206 BC), he sent his friend [[Gaius Laelius]] to visit Syphax to ratify the treaty with Rome. Syphax however, refused to ratify any treaty except with Scipio, so Scipio sailed with two [[quinquereme]]s to meet with Syphax, taking a considerable risk in doing so. In fact he arrived at the Numidian harbor, at exactly the same time as [[Hasdrubal (Barcid)|Hasdrubal]] (who had fled from Spain) anchored there on his way back to Carthage. However, Scipio&amp;apos;s ship managed to make harbor before Hasdrubal&amp;apos;s seven [[triremes]] could make out to intercept them, and in a neutral harbor, Hasdrubal dared not act against the Romans. Syphax invited both to dinner, where both Syphax and Hasdrubal were taken in by Scipio&amp;apos;s charm.

Meanwhile, Massinissa had concluded that Rome was winning the war against Carthage and therefore decided to switch sides. Having lost the alliance with Massinissa, Hasdrubal started to look for another ally, which he found in Syphax, sealing the alliance by offering his daughter [[Sophonisba]] in marriage, although until 206 BC she had been betrothed to Massinissa.

With the reversal of alliances it looked like Carthage and Syphax were in a strong position in Africa, certainly during the early stages of Scipio&amp;apos;s campaign in North Africa, the joined forces of Syphax and [[Hasdrubal Gisco]] were able to force Scipio to abandon the siege of [[Utica, Tunisia|Utica]]. However, in the [[Battle of Bagbrades]] (203 BC), Scipio overcame Hasdrubal and Syphax and while the Roman general concentrated on Carthage, Laelius and Massinissa followed Syphax to [[Cirta]].

During the pursuit, Syphax was threatened with desertion by his army when Laelius and Massinissa&amp;apos;s army approached the Numidian battle line. In a brave attempt to rally his troops, Syphax rode alone, straight towards the Roman cavalry, but in this desperate attempt his badly wounded horse threw him off. Syphax was pounced upon immediately by Roman soldiers and taken to the ecstatic Massinissa.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;Livy, 30.12&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt; Syphax&amp;apos;s troops retreated to the capital city which later fell as Massinissa claimed his kingdom. Syphax was delivered to Scipio and was taken as a prisoner, dying in Tibur (modern [[Tivoli, Italy|Tivoli]]) in 203 or 202 BC.

In a twist of fate, Sophonisba then married Massinissa. However, Scipio, suspicious of Sophonisba, demanded that she be taken to Rome and appear in the [[Roman Triumph|triumphal parade]]. To spare her such humiliation, Massinissa sent her poison, with which she killed herself.

The [[Tunisia]]n city [[Sfax]] is said to be named after King Syphax.

==References==
{{Reflist}}
{{Reflist|group=Cambridge University}}

==External links==
* [http://www.livius.org/su-sz/syphax/syphax.html Livius.org: Syphax]

{{Persondata &amp;lt;!-- Metadata: see [[Wikipedia:Persondata]]. --&amp;gt;
| NAME              = Syphax
| ALTERNATIVE NAMES =
| SHORT DESCRIPTION = King of Numidia
| DATE OF BIRTH     =
| PLACE OF BIRTH    =
| DATE OF DEATH     =
| PLACE OF DEATH    =
}}
[[Category:Kings of Numidia]]
[[Category:Second Punic War commanders]]
[[Category:Year of birth missing]]
[[Category:200s BC deaths]]
[[Category:Ancient Algeria]]
[[Category:Ancient Tunisia]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
