<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Yemenite step"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Yemenite step" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{JewishMusic}}

The &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Yemenite step&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; ({{Lang-he|צעד תמני}}) is a [[Dance move|dance step]] widely used in [[Yemenite Jews|Yemenite]] [[Jewish]] dancing and [[Israeli folk dancing]].

==History==
Yemenite step came into being when the Jews were not allowed to dance in public in Yemen. Yemenite dance has stationary hopping and posturing and could be performed in confined space. Today, Yemenite step is a popular dance performed Jews during weddings and other Jewish occasions. &amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;http://www.buzzle.com/articles/traditional-jewish-dance.html&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

==Description==
The basic Yemenite step provides a swaying movement that changes the dancer&amp;apos;s direction of motion, although the dancer may face forward throughout the step. It is usually a sideways movement, but may be done moving backward and forward (or vice-versa). It consists of three steps, with a short pause on the final step for a &amp;quot;quick, quick, slow&amp;quot; tempo.

The most common variations are known as a right Yemenite (or Yemenite right), and left Yemenite (or Yemenite left). (The alternate form of each name—placing the adjective after the noun—is due to a common preference among dance teachers to emphasize the name of the step rather than its direction.) Each of these names specifies both the direction of the first movement, and the foot on which the movement begins (and ends).

The following description of the right Yemenite step explains the footwork and direction of movement:&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;[http://www.imber.com.au/ifd/glossary.htm Israeli Folk Dancing Glossary] by Martin Imber. Retrieved August 25, 2009.&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;
#Beginning with weight on left foot, step sideways to the right. Weight moves right, onto the right foot.
#Shift weight left, onto the left foot, which may stay in place or move slightly backward.
#Cross right foot in front of and slightly past the left foot, and step on right foot. Weight moves left, onto the right foot.
#Hold. Weight stays on right foot. Left leg remains behind and slightly to the right, with toe on the ground for balance.
Reversing the above footwork and direction of movement will give the details of the left Yemenite step.

==Terminology==
Dance teachers have also applied the name Yemenite to steps that differ from the classic Yemenite step but retain enough similarity to make the name helpful for teaching or descriptive purposes. Thus the back Yemenite, the name of which specifies the direction of the first movement and can be expanded to specify the starting foot. Similarly, some teachers may use phrases such as Yemenite-hop, or Yemenite-pivot to describe an otherwise-normal Yemenite step that ends with the specified movement rather than a hold.

==See also==
*[[Folk dance]]
*[[International folk dance]]
*[[Dance in Israel]]
*[[Jewish dance]]

==References==
{{reflist}}

==External links==
*{{cite journal
  | last = Staub
  | first = Shalom
  | title = Repertoire, Values, and Social Meaning in the Wedding Dances of a Yemenite Jewish Village in Israel
  | journal = Dance Research Journal
  | volume = 17
  | issue = 2
  | pages = 55–63
  | publisher = Congress on Research in Dance
  | date = Autumn 1985
  | jstor =  1478082
  | accessdate = December 16, 2012}}
*[http://www.phantomranch.net/folkdanc/dances/haeerbea.htm &amp;quot;Ha&amp;apos;eer Beafor&amp;quot; dance description]

[[Category:Dance moves]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
