<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Infrastructure Canada"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Infrastructure Canada" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Advert|date=June 2013}}

{{no footnotes |date= June 2012}}

&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Infrastructure Canada&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; leads federal efforts to ensure that [[Canadians]] benefit from world-class, modern [[public infrastructure]]. The department is a key funding partner, working with provinces, territories, municipalities, the private sector and [[non-profit organizations]], along with other [[Structure of the Canadian federal government|federal departments]] and agencies to help build and revitalize the infrastructure Canadians need and use every day.

The [[Minister of Transport, Infrastructure and Communities]] is responsible for the department. The current Minister is the Honourable [[Denis Lebel]].

== About Infrastructure Canada ==
Infrastructure Canada is part of the Transport, Infrastructure and Communities portfolio of the [[Government of Canada]]. It is the lead federal department responsible for infrastructure policy development and program delivery.

In [[2007 Canadian federal budget|Budget 2007]], Infrastructure Canada launched the seven-year $33 billion Building Canada Plan addressing local and regional infrastructure needs, while advancing national priorities that are important to all Canadians: a stronger economy, a cleaner environment, and better communities. This plan covers infrastructure investments in water, wastewater, public transit, and other key national priorities and will continue to run to 2014.

In [[2009 Canadian federal budget|Budget 2009]], the Government of Canada announced that it would be delivering short-term stimulus programs as part of its Economic Action Plan to fight the effects of the global recession. The Economic Action Plan infrastructure programs that were delivered by Infrastructure Canada helped communities across the country by funding projects that were ready to start quickly. This funding enabled communities to repair roads and bridges, build public spaces, invest in community facilities and improve drinking water facilities.

In [[2011 Canadian federal budget|Budget 2011]], the Government of Canada committed to working with partners and stakeholders to develop a long-term plan for public infrastructure that will continue after the Building Canada Plan winds down in 2014.

== Branches ==
The department is made up of four branches:
* The Policy and Communications Branch
* The Program Operations Branch
* The Corporate Services Branch
* The [[Audit]] and Evaluation Branch

== Infrastructure Programs ==
Infrastructure Canada creates partnerships and makes investments to build, upgrade and renew public infrastructure. These investments help ensure that national priorities are met, while supporting important national, regional and local infrastructure needs.

Through the Government of Canada&amp;apos;s Economic Action Plan, Infrastructure Canada has supported about 6,400 projects.

===Building Canada Plan===
The seven-year, $33 billion Building Canada Plan will continue to run to 2014. As part of the Building Canada Plan, Infrastructure Canada is contributing to projects through both the Building Canada Fund and the Provincial-Territorial Base Fund, which will continue to create jobs and result in long-term benefits for Canadians.

As part of the Building Canada Plan, the Gas Tax Fund also delivers $2 billion per year. These investments provide predictable, long-term funding for municipal infrastructure that contributes to cleaner air, cleaner water and reduced greenhouse gas emissions. Through legislation, the Government of Canada has made the Gas Tax Fund permanent at $2 billion per year beyond its current expiry in 2014.

In addition to these initiatives, Infrastructure Canada continues to manage or has managed other infrastructure programs over the years:
* Infrastructure Stimulus Fund (2009-2010 to 2011-2012)
* Municipal Rural Infrastructure Fund (2004-2005 to 2013-2014)
* Border Infrastructure Fund (2003-2004 to 2013-2014)
* Canada Strategic Infrastructure Fund (2003-2004 to 2012-2013)
* G8 Legacy Fund (2009-2010 to 2010-2011)
* Infrastructure Canada Program (2000-2001 to 2010-2011)
* National Recreational Trails (2009-2010)
* Public Transit Fund (2005-2006)

== External links ==
* [http://www.infrastructure.gc.ca/index-eng.html Infrastructure Canada Website]
* [http://www.infrastructure.gc.ca/feed-fil/itn-eng.xml Infrastructure Canada web feed - English]
* [http://www.infrastructure.gc.ca/feed-fil/itn-fra.xml Infrastructure Canada web feed - French]

{{Government Departments of Canada}}

[[Category:Canadian federal departments and agencies]]
[[Category:Investment agencies]]
[[Category:Funding bodies of Canada]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
