<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Sociedad Estatal de Participaciones Industriales"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Sociedad Estatal de Participaciones Industriales" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Multiple issues|
{{Unreferenced|date=March 2013}}
{{No footnotes|date=March 2013}}
{{Underlinked|date=April 2013}}
}}
[[File:Sede de la SEPI (Madrid) 01.jpg|thumb|320px|SEPI&amp;apos;s head offices, in [[Madrid]].]]

&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Sociedad Estatal de Participaciones Industriales&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;SEPI&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;) is a Spanish Public Law entity, whose activities follow the private legal system, and which is attached to the Ministry of Finance and Public Administrations - Ministerio de Hacienda y Administraciones Públicas-, and reports directly to the Minister.

It was created in 1995, by Royal Law Decree 5/1995, on June 16, validated on January 10th, 1996, through Act 5/1996 for the Creation of Certain Public Law Entities. Its creation took place, within the framework of the process for the reorganization and modernization of the state-owned entrepreneurial sector, in order to manage the industrial shareholdings owned by the State and which came from the former entities Instituto Nacional de Industria (INI) and Instituto Nacional de Hidrocarburos (INH), which were liquidated by the above mentioned norm.

==SEPI Group==

SEPI has a direct and majority participation in 19 companies, which make up the Grupo SEPI, with a final workforce over 80,000 workers. It also has competences on the Corporación Radiotelevisión Española and on the Ente Público RTVE, which is attached to this state-owned enterprise, as well as on a controlled public foundation. Equally, it has minority direct shareholdings in 7 companies, and indirect shareholdings in more than 100 companies.

The SEPI Group is organized into 4 categories taking into account the activity and the functions which these companies carry out:

===Division of investee companies in the &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Energy industry===
* ENSA,
* GRUPO ENUSA,
* GRUPO HUNOSA,
* GRUPO SEPIDES.
Here are included the minority shareholdings in the following companies: ENAGÁS (listed in the Stock Exchange), ENRESA (SEPI 20% and CIEMAT 80%) and RED ELÉCTRICA CORPORACIÓN (listed in the Stock Exchange).

===Division of investee companies in the &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Defense industry===
* DEFEX,
* IZAR Construcciones navales en liquidación,
* GRUPO NAVANTIA.
Here are included the minority shareholdings in the following companies: EADS NV (listed in the Stock Exchange) and HISPASAT.

===Division of investee companies in the Food and the &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Environment industry===
* CETARSA,
* HIPÓDROMO DE LA ZARZUELA,
* MAYASA,
* GRUPO MERCASA,
* SAECA,
* GRUPO TRAGSA,
* ALIMENTOS Y ACEITES (It has a shareholding in EBRO FOODS).

===Division of investee companies in the &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Communication industry===
* AGENCIA EFE,
* CORPORACIÓN RTVE,
* ENTE PÚBLICO RTVE (Attached entity),
* GRUPO COFIVACASA,
* GRUPO CORREOS.

It is also in charge of the overview of the trust FUNDACIÓN SEPI.

Here are included the minority shareholding in the following companies: INTERNATIONAL AIRLINES GROUP (IAG) (listed in the Stock Exchange) and ESPAÑA EXPANSIÓN EXTERIOR (Spain Business Overseas).

Besides the companies which make up the SEPI Group, this state-owned company has indirect shareholdings in more than 100 other companies.

==External links==
{{Portal|Spain|Companies}}
*[http://www.sepi.es/default.aspx?cmd=0001&amp;amp;IdContainer=3&amp;amp;idLanguage=_EN&amp;amp;idContraste= Company website]
*[http://www.sepionline.com/ Company website] {{es icon}}

[[Category:Government-owned companies of Spain]]
[[Category:Companies of Spain]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
