<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Military tactics"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Military tactics" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{History of war}}

&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Military tactics&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, the science and art of organizing a [[military]] force, and the techniques for using weapons or military units in combination for engaging and defeating an enemy in [[battle]].&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;{{cite book |last=[[Clausewitz]] |first= [[Carl von Clausewitz|Carl]]|title= [[On War]]|year= 1832}}&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt; Changes in philosophy and technology over time have been reflected in changes to military tactics. In current military thought, tactics are the lowest of three planning levels. The highest tier of planning is the [[military strategy|strategy]], which is about how force is translated into political objectives, or more specifically how you bridge the means and ends of war together. An intermediate level, which converts strategy into tactics is the [[Operational warfare|operational level]] that deals with formations of units. In common vernacular, &amp;quot;tactical&amp;quot; decisions are those made to achieve greatest immediate value and &amp;quot;strategic&amp;quot; decisions are those made to achieve the greatest overall value irrespective of immediate return.

==Concept==
[[Image:Disguisetactics.jpg|thumb|right|[[German Empire|German]] [[World War I]] [[observation post]] disguised as a tree.]]

Military tactics are both a science and an art. They answer the questions of how best to deploy and employ forces on a small scale.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;{{cite encyclopedia |author=[[Clifford J. Rogers|Rogers, Clifford J.]]|editor=[[James C. Bradford|Bradford, James C]]|encyclopedia=International Encyclopedia of Military History |title=Strategy, Operational Design, and Tactics |year=2006|publisher=Routledge |location=New York}}&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;  Some practices have not changed since the dawn of warfare: ambushes, seeking and turning flanks, maintaining reconnaissance, creating and using obstacles and defences, etc. Using ground to best advantage has not changed much either. Heights, rivers, swamps, passes, choke points, and natural [[cover (military)|cover]], can all be used in multiple ways. Before the nineteenth century, many military tactics were confined to [[battle]]field concerns: how to maneuver units during combat in open terrain. Nowadays, specialized tactics exist for many situations, for example for securing a room in a building.

What does change constantly is the technological dimension, as well as the sociology of combatants. One might wish to reflect on the differences in the technology and society that produced such different types of soldier or warrior as the Greek [[Hoplite]], the Roman [[Legionary]], the Medieval [[Knight]], the Turk-Mongol [[Horse Archer]], the Chinese [[Crossbowman]], the British [[Red coat (British army)|Redcoat]], or an [[Air Cavalry]] trooper. Each, constrained by his weaponry, [[logistics]] and his [[social conditioning]], would use a battlefield differently, but would usually seek the same outcomes from their use of tactics. In many respects the First World War changed the use of tactics used as advances in technology rendered prior tactics useless.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;{{cite book|title=Battle Tactics of the Western Front: The British Army&amp;apos;s Art of Attack, 1916-18|page=20|author=[[Paddy Griffith]]|publisher=Yale University Press|year=1994}}&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

==See also==
* [[List of military tactics]]

==References==
===Notes===
{{reflist}}

===Bibliography===
*{{cite book | title=How to win on the battlefield : 25 key tactics to outwit, outflank, and outfight the enemy | publisher=Thames &amp;amp; Hudson | author=Johnson, Rob, Michael Whitby, John France | year=2010 | isbn=978-0-500-25161-4}}
* {{cite web | title=German Tactics in the Italian Campaign | url=http://www.larchivio.org/xoom/gerhardmuhm2.htm | last = Muhm | first = Gerhard}}
* Gerhard Muhm : La Tattica nella campagna ass d’Italia, in LINEA GOTICA AVAMPOSTO DEI BALCANI, (Hrsg.) Amedeo Montemaggi - Edizioni Civitas, Roma 1993

==External links==
* [http://www.everycitizenasoldier.org/index.html Everycitizenasoldier.org - tactical principles]
* [http://www.dtic.mil/doctrine/jel/service_pubs/mcdp1.pdf Contemporary Marine tactics for war fighting]
* [http://napoleonistyka.atspace.com/Napoleon_tactics.htm Napoleon&amp;apos;s tactics and strategy]
* [http://allworld.startlogic.com/Small-Unit-Actions-During-German-Campaign-in-Russia.html Small Unit Actions during German Campaign in Russia]

[[Category:Military tactics| ]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
