<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Disc tumbler lock"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Disc tumbler lock" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{refimprove|date=June 2009}}
[[File:Disc tumbler lock.JPG|thumb|The underside of a disc tumbler lock]]

A &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;disc tumbler lock&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; or &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Abloy Disklock&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is a lock composed of slotted rotating detainer discs. Considered very secure and almost impossible to pick, the lock was invented by a Finnish mechanic [[Emil Henriksson]] in 1907 and manufactured by [[Abloy]]. Nearly all the houses in Finland use Abloy keys, although they are also widely used in various locales worldwide.

== Design ==

Disc tumbler locks are composed of slotted rotating detainer discs. A specially cut key rotates these discs like the tumblers of a safe to align the slots, allowing the sidebar to drop into the slots, thus opening the lock. Unlike a [[wafer tumbler lock]] or a [[pin tumbler lock]], this mechanism does not use springs. Because they do not contain springs, they are better suited for areas with harsh conditions and are often used at outdoor locations like railroad and public utility installations.&amp;lt;ref name=picking&amp;gt;{{cite web|title=Notes on Picking Pin Tumbler Locks|url=http://www.crypto.com/papers/notes/picking/|accessdate=30 June 2011}}&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

The classical Abloy design consists of a notched hemicylindrical key, and a lock with detainer discs with holes ranging from a hemicircle (180°) to a 3/4 circle (270°). The key is inserted and rotated 90 degrees. Notches, machined to an angle, correspond to complementary angles in the holes of the discs. For example, if the hole is 270°, the key is 180°, and if the hole is 240° (270° minus 30°), the key is 150° (180° with 30° notch) of the circle. In addition, there is a notch in the perimeter of each disc. A sidebar inside an opening in the lock cylinder around the discs, and an edge in the casing obstructs the movement of the cylinder beyond the 90°.

When a correct key is inserted and turned, all the discs will rotate such that notches in the perimeters line up. This allows a sidebar to drop from the cylinder into the groove made by the lined-up notches in the disks, so that it does not obstruct the cylinder, allowing the cylinder to rotate and open the lock.

The lock is locked again by rotating it into the other direction, sliding the sidebar back into the cylinder opening and allowing the straight edge of the key to return the discs to the scrambled &amp;quot;zero&amp;quot; position.

== Lockpicking ==

Disk tumblers are difficult to [[lockpicking|pick]],&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;[http://yarchive.net/security/abloy.html &amp;quot;Abloy locks&amp;quot;] from yarchive&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;{{cite web|url=http://www.data-security-safe.com/abloy-locks.shtml |title=Abloy Locks |publisher=Data-security-safe.com |date= |accessdate=2010-06-10}}&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;{{cite web|url=http://blackbag.nl/wp-content/uploads/2009/06/abloy-stairway-key-copy.jpg |title=showing the angles on an Abloy key |date= |accessdate=2010-06-10}}&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt; and are sold as &amp;quot;high security&amp;quot; locks. Picking the lock is not impossible, but requires a lot of time, a dedicated, professionally made tool and special expertise. The disc tumbler lock cannot be [[lock bumping|bumped]]. This level of difficulty tends to drive attention to alternative methods of gaining entry.

The locking mechanism can be disabled destructively by drilling into the lock to destroy the sidebar. Anti-drilling plates can be installed to prevent this.

== Use ==

The lock was invented by [[Emil Henriksson]] in 1907 and manufactured by [[Abloy]]. Nearly all the houses in Finland use Abloy keys, although they are also widely used in various locales worldwide.

[[ABUS]] manufactures padlocks and cycle locks employing disc tumbler cylinders in their Plus line.

== References ==

{{reflist}}

== External links ==

* {{youtube.com|wyB7DFtVRBk|Video of the mechanism}}

{{Locksmithing}}

[[Category:Locks]]
[[Category:Locksmithing]]
[[Category:Finnish inventions]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
