<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Unilateral disarmament"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Unilateral disarmament" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Unilateral disarmament&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is a [[policy]] option, to renounce weapons without seeking equivalent concessions from one&amp;apos;s actual or potential rivals. It was most commonly used in the twentieth century in the context of &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[unilateral nuclear disarmament]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, a recurrent objective of [[peace movement]]s in countries such as the USA and the UK.

Nations do not often choose to dismantle their entire military capability. Unilateral disarmaments are usually sought in one technical competency, such as [[Weapons of Mass Destruction]]. Non-violent political movements from that of [[Mahatma Gandhi]] to the [[Campaign for Nuclear Disarmament]] have recommended unilateral disarmament as a simple step toward world peace.

==By country==
===Costa Rica===
The only recent candidate for having performed an act of complete disarmament is [[Costa Rica]], which unilaterally disarmed itself in 1948, writing its non-military status into its constitution in 1949. In a public ceremony to mark the occasion, the existing Commander-in-Chief handed the keys to Army HQ to the Minister of Education, for use as a school. Since that time, Costa Rica has been briefly invaded once, by [[Nicaragua]], but has maintained its territorial integrity through reliance on diplomacy within international structures such as the [[Organization of American States|OAS]]. Costa Rica&amp;apos;s [[peace dividend]] has been reinvested well, as evidenced by infant mortality rates, life expectancy and literacy rates that are on a par or better than those of most developed countries.

===USA===
President [[Richard Nixon]]&amp;apos;s unilateral discontinuation of biological weapons development in 1972 is often characterized a &amp;apos;unilateral disarmament&amp;apos;.

==External links==
*[http://www.unidir.org United Nations Institute for Disarmament Research]

[[Category:Political terminology]]

{{poli-term-stub}}&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
