<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Deirdre Gogarty"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Deirdre Gogarty" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{BLP sources|date=May 2010}}
&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Deirdre Gogarty&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (born November 10, 1969) is a [[Women&amp;apos;s boxing|female boxer]] who was born in [[Drogheda]], [[Ireland]].&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;http://www.wban.org/biog/dgogarty.htm&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;
Due to legal issues regarding Women&amp;apos;s Boxing in [[Ireland]] at the time, Gogarty could not engage in competition there. She currently fights out of [[New Orleans]], [[Louisiana]]. However, before the law was passed in Ireland, preventing women from engaging in [[boxing]] events, Gogarty was able to begin her career there with a six round decision win against [[Anne-Marie Griffin]]. The law preventing females from participating in the sport of boxing in Ireland has since been revoked and there is an increasing number of females becoming involved with the sport thanks to its Olympic acceptance and the consistent international success of [[Katie Taylor]].

After leaving [[Ireland]], Gogarty&amp;apos;s next three fights took her to [[London]] and [[Kansas City, Missouri]]. In London, she defeated [[Jane Johnson (boxer)|Jane Johnson]] twice, by a four round [[knockout]] and by and eight round decision. In Kansas City, she drew after six rounds with [[Stacy Prestage]] After the rematch with Johnson, she obtained her first knockout in the first round, beating [[Jane McGhee]]. Another win followed this and she was matched with Prestage again, resulting in another draw after six rounds.

Following the emerging pattern, another win followed this tie and she was matched against Prestage for a rubber match. However, this time Gogarty suffered her first loss when Prestage won a ten round decision over her. Two more wins followed this defeat, including a six round knockout of the top contender [[Carol Brown (boxer)|Carol Brown]] and a first round knockout win over [[Missy Buchanan]]. In spite of this winning streak, Gogarty next lost a six round decision when she faced [[Mary Anne Almager]].

Gogarty followed this defeat with a win, after which she was matched with [[Isra Girgrah]], who Gogarty knocked out in three rounds. This is considered her biggest win to date. She ten boxed another of Female Boxing&amp;apos;s top competitors when she faced [[Laura Serrano]], who beat Gogarty by a knockout in round seven. A knockout win followed this defeat in the first round when she fought [[Jessica Breitfelder]]. Gogarty then participated in the fight many credit as putting Female Boxing on the sports&amp;apos; fan page: she and [[Christy Martin (boxer)|Christy Martin]] faced each other in a six round match that was televised by [[Showtime (TV network)|Showtime]]. This fight made the covers of many magazines. Many fans of Women&amp;apos;s Boxing considered it the female version of the [[Thrilla in Manila]]. Martin won by a six round decision.

Gogarty succeeded in winning another three fights consecutively before she challenged [[Bonnie Canino]] for the [[Women&amp;apos;s International Boxing Federation]]&amp;apos;s Women&amp;apos;s World Featherweight Champtionship. Gogarty became a World Champion after winning the fight on a ten round decision. She defended her title against [[Monique Strohman]] and [[Debra Strohman]]. Both were defeated in first round knockouts. In her last fight to date, Gogarty lost her title to [[Beverly Szymanski]] on a ten round decision.

Gogarty co-wrote her memoir, &amp;apos;&amp;apos;My Call to the Ring: A Memoir of a Girl Who Yearns to Box&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, with [[Darrelyn Saloom]]. The book was published by Glasnevin Publishing on August 8, 2012.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;http://www.amazon.com/My-Call-Ring-Memoir-ebook/dp/B008VI1JMQ/ref=sr_1_9?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1344605773&amp;amp;sr=8-9&amp;amp;keywords=my+call+to+the+ring&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt; The very next day, [[Katie Taylor]] won a gold Medal for Ireland in the 2012 Summer Olympics, which included women&amp;apos;s boxing for the first time in history.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/london-olympics-2012/news/Irelands-Katie-Taylor-claims-womens-boxing-gold/articleshow/15424099.cms&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

== References ==
{{Reflist}}

== External links ==
*[http://boxrec.com/list_bouts.php?human_id=18488&amp;amp;cat=boxer Deirdre Gogarty&amp;apos;s boxing record]

{{Persondata &amp;lt;!-- Metadata: see [[Wikipedia:Persondata]]. --&amp;gt;
| NAME              = Gogarty, Deirdre
| ALTERNATIVE NAMES =
| SHORT DESCRIPTION = Irish boxer
| DATE OF BIRTH     = November 10, 1969
| PLACE OF BIRTH    =
| DATE OF DEATH     =
| PLACE OF DEATH    =
}}
{{DEFAULTSORT:Gogarty, Deirdre}}
[[Category:1969 births]]
[[Category:Irish boxers]]
[[Category:Living people]]
[[Category:Women boxers]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
