<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Free German Trade Union Federation"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Free German Trade Union Federation" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Unreferenced|date=December 2009}}
[[Image:FDGBPOWER.jpg|400px|right]]
The &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Free German Trade Union Federation&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, in [[German language|German]] &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Freier Deutscher Gewerkschaftsbund&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (FDGB), was the [[trade union]] federation in [[East Germany]]. It was part of the [[National Front (East Germany)|National Front]] and had representatives in the [[Volkskammer]].

On paper the FDGB, a member of the [[World Federation of Trade Unions]], was actually the umbrella organization for about  15 individual [[labor union|trade unions]] (e.g.  &amp;apos;&amp;apos;IG Metall&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, &amp;apos;&amp;apos;IG Transport&amp;apos;&amp;apos; etc.), but in reality most members did not even realise that was the case. Only a handwritten note on the last page of the standard red membership booklet mentioned the individual trade union they belonged to.

==Structure==
[[image:Bundesarchiv Bild 183-1983-0321-416, Harry Tisch.jpg|thumb|200px|Harry Tisch, FDGB chairman from 1975 to 1989.]]
The bureaucratic union apparatus was a basic component and tool of the [[Socialist Unity Party of Germany|SED]]’s power structure, constructed on the
same strictly centralist hierarchical model as all other major [[East Germany|GDR]] organizations.

The smallest unit was a &amp;quot;Kollektiv&amp;quot;, which nearly all workers in any organisation belonged to, including state leaders and party functionaries. They recommended trustworthy people as the lowest FDGB functionaries and voted for them in open-list ballots. The higher positions ranged from &amp;quot;Departmental Union Leader&amp;quot; (&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Abteilungsgewerkschaftsleiter&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, AGL) to Leader of the &amp;quot;Central BGL&amp;quot; (&amp;apos;&amp;apos; Betriebsgewerkschaftsleitung&amp;apos;&amp;apos; - Company Union Leadership in combines); they were normally full-time and held by SED members with a history of toeing the party line, or in some cases bloc party members. Their jobs, like those of the FDGB district leaders, were assured until they retired as long as they did not stray from party policy.

The chairman of the FDGB was [[Herbert Warnke]] until his death on March 26, 1975 when he was replaced by [[Harry Tisch]], a member of the [[Socialist Unity Party of Germany|SED]]’s [[Politburo]], who kept the post until the political turnaround in 1989.
[[Image:Bundesarchiv Bild 183-82830-0002, Helsinki, MS &amp;quot;Fritz Heckert.jpg|thumb|200px|FDGB&amp;apos;s cruise ship MS &amp;quot;Fritz Heckert&amp;quot; in [[Helsinki]] (May 1961).]]

==Membership==
Officially, membership in the FDGB was voluntary, but unofficially it was hardly possible to develop a career without joining {{Citation needed|date=December 2007}}. In 1986, 98% of all workers and employees were organized in the FDGB which had 9.6 million members. This meant that it was nominally one of the world’s largest [[trade union]]s. As well as improving members’ career chances, the FDGB also offered various &amp;quot;concessions&amp;quot;.

==Function==
In the [[German Democratic Republic|East German]] system, the FDGB was in charge of ideological control and conformity in companies, as well as social tasks such as hospital visits, presenting  awards, giving gifts on special anniversaries, even extending as far as organizing health spas and the hard-to-get holiday bookings. The FDGB’s own holiday service was responsible for the latter.

The single trade union was also very important as a source of new blood for the military. Using small benefits as an [[incentive]], and if necessary gentle pressure, large numbers of workers and employees were recruited to what were known as &amp;quot;[[Kampfgruppen der Arbeiterklasse|Combat Groups of the Working Class]]&amp;quot;.

==German reunification==
In May 1990, shortly before [[German reunification]], the FDGB was dissolved. Many former members did not join the West German (now German) unions as their previous experience had led them to associate unions with state nannying, especially as old GDR functionaries had managed to get new positions there. Moreover, because of the lightning [[privatization]] of the GDR many had simply lost their jobs.

[[Category:National trade union centers of Germany]]
[[Category:Organisations based in East Germany]]
[[Category:Organizations disestablished in 1990]]
[[Category:1990 disestablishments in East Germany]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
