<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Gylfi"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Gylfi" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{About|King of Scandinavia|Icelandic footballer|Gylfi Sigurðsson}}

[[Image:Odens_ankomst_till_Sverige_och_förening_med_Gylfe_by_Hugo_Hamilton.jpg|right|thumb|Gylfi greets Odin]]
In [[Norse mythology]], &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Gylfi&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Gylfe&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Gylvi&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, or &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Gylve&amp;apos;&amp;apos; was the earliest recorded king in Scandinavia. He often uses the name Gangleri when appearing in disguise. The traditions on Gylfi deal with how he was tricked by the gods and his relations with the goddess [[Gefjon]].

==The creation of Zealand==
The &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Ynglinga saga]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos; section of Snorri&amp;apos;s &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Heimskringla]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos; and the Eddic poem &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Ragnarsdrápa]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos; tell a legend of how Gylfi was seduced by the goddess Gefjon to give her as much land as she could plow in one night. Gefjon transformed her four sons into oxen and took enough land to create the [[Denmark|Danish]] island of [[Zealand (Denmark)|Zealand]], leaving the Swedish lake [[Mälaren]].

==Meeting the Æsir==
[[Image:Manuscript Gylfi.jpg|right|thumb|Gylfi is tricked in an illustration from [[Icelandic Manuscript, SÁM 66]] ]]

&amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Gylfaginning]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos; in the &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Prose Edda]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos; and the &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Ynglinga saga&amp;apos;&amp;apos; tell how the supposedly historic (Non-deified version of Odin) [[Odin]] and his people the [[Æsir]] and [[Vanir]], who later became the Swedes, obtained new land where they built the settlement of [[Old Sigtuna]]. In Snorri&amp;apos;s account Gylfi is supposedly deluded by the Æsir into accepting their religion; hence the name &amp;quot;Gylfaginning:&amp;quot; the Deluding of Gylfi. Gylfi and the remaining older bronze-age inhabitants of the land then supposedly adopted the religion of the Æsir and began to live under their rule. Snorri presents an outline of [[Norse mythology]] through a dialogue between Gylfi and three rulers of the Æsir.
It is possible that Snorri&amp;apos;s account is based on an old tradition tracing particular beliefs or foundations of particular Norse cults to this legendary Gylfi. However, it is much more likely that the Historic King Gylfi was simply already a follower of the Ancient Norse Religion; and, as such, could easily have passed on these beliefs or stories. The Christianization of the myths, a perversion of their ancient stories, was a sad historical loss; a loss suffered by the stories on their path from the mouths of newly converted Scandinavians through the pen of a Christian writer. The loss of original and more diverse manuscripts of the Old Norse Stories, through the burning of buildings known to house them during the Scandinavian reformation period, was extremely detrimental to the true representations of Gods and Kings in the oral tradition. Very little of the long-held view that the Ancient Scandinavian people actually had of their Gods and stories still survives for us today.

==Other appearances==
In one version of &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Hervarar saga]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, king Gylfi married his daughter Heiðr to [[Sigrlami]], the king of [[Garðaríki]] (Russia).&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;[http://www.home.ix.netcom.com/~kyamazak/myth/norse/kershaw/NLS-hervor-is.htm Sigrlami átti Heiði, dóttur Gylfa konungs; þau attu sun saman, sá hèt Svafrlami.] in N. M. Petersen&amp;apos;s edition of &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Hervarar saga]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos;.&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt; Heiðr and Sigrlami had the son Svafrlami who forced the two dwarves [[Dvalinn|Dvalin]] and [[Durin (Norse mythology)|Durin]] to forge the magic sword [[Tyrfing]].

==Notes==
{{reflist}}

{{s-start}}
{{succession box|title=[[Mythological king of Sweden]]|years=|before=New creation|after=[[Odin]]}}
{{s-end}}

[[Category:Mythological kings of Sweden]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
