<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Yazid ibn al-Muhallab"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Yazid ibn al-Muhallab" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Yazid ibn al-Muhallab&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (672–720) was a provincial governor in the time of the [[Umayyad dynasty]] and the progenitor of the [[Muhallabid]] family that became important in early [[Abbasid]] times.

In [[Anno Hegirae|A.H.]] 78 (697-698 CE) [[al-Hajjaj ibn Yusuf]], the Caliphate&amp;apos;s viceroy of the eastern provinces, appointed Yazid&amp;apos;s father [[al-Muhallab ibn Abi Suffrah]] as governor of [[Greater Khorasan|Khurasan]]. In A.H. 82 (701-702) al-Muhallab&amp;apos;s son Mughirah died and al-Muhallab sent Yazid to replace him. Soon afterwards al-Muhallab died and al-Hajjaj appointed Yazid governor of [[Greater Khorasan|Khorasan]].  There Yazid confronted external and internal enemies, including some rebels entering his province who were supporters of Abd al-Rahman ibn Muhammad ibn al-Ash&amp;apos;ath. Yazid defeated them. Yazid seized Nizak&amp;apos;s fortress and made peace with him.

In A.H. 85 (704-705) al-Hajjaj replaced Yazid naming his younger brother [[al-Mufaddal ibn al-Muhallab|al-Mufaddal]] governor of Khurasan.  Various reasons are suggested, including that al-Hajjaj encountered a prophecy that his successor would be named Yazid and al-Hajjaj considered this Yazid the only one threatening enough to worry about.  Al-Hajjaj imprisoned and tortured Yazid. In A.H. 90 (708-709) Yazid disguised escaped and made his way to Palestine where he was granted refuge by [[Suleiman ibn Abd al-Malik]]. Al-Hajjaj pressed Caliph [[al-Walid I]] who commanded his brother to send him Yazid in chains. Suleiman had his own son chained to Yazid approach the caliph and speak favouring Yazid&amp;apos;s safety. Al-Walid accepted this and told al-Hajjaj to desist. Yazid returned to Suleiman and the two were very close to each other.

When Suleiman came to the throne in A.H. 96 (715), he appointed Yazid to govern [[Iraq]]. The next year Suleiman appointed Yazid governor of Khurasan. Yazid fought in Jurjan and Tabaristan, personally engaging in combat. In A.H. 99 (717-718) the new caliph [[Umar ibn Abd al-Aziz]] dismissed Yazid due to his tortures against people of conquered territories, especially [[Turkic peoples|Turks]] and [[Sogd]]s.  Yazid was captured on his way to Basra and brought before Umar who intensely disliked him. Umar imprisoned Yazid. In A.H. 101 (719-720) when Umar fell ill, Yazid escaped. Umar died.

Yazid approached Basra. Many joined him. He refused to swear allegiance to the new caliph, [[Yazid II]]. He attacked those holding his brothers, defeated them and freed his brothers. His son Khalid was arrested in Kufah and sent to Damascus where he remained in prison until he died. Yazid was advised to head east, but he declined to follow this advice. In A.H. 102 (720-721) [[Maslamah ibn Abd al-Malik]] and [[al-Abbas ibn al-Walid]] led forces against him. On August 25, Maslamah&amp;apos;s troops advanced to battle, frightening some of Yazid&amp;apos;s men who fled. Yazid had these beheaded. He then rode directly at Maslamah. Maslamah&amp;apos;s cavalry intercepted him and cut him down.

Fighting continued. In Wasit, Yazid&amp;apos;s son Mu&amp;apos;awiyah on news of his father&amp;apos;s death executed some prisoners, including [[&amp;apos;Adi ibn Artah al-Fazari|Adi ibn Artat]], the Basran governor who had sent Yazid to Umar in A.H. 99. Mu&amp;apos;awiyah and other surviving members of the Yazid&amp;apos;s family sailed to Bahrayn, then near Kirman. They advanced to Qandabil where they were denied entrance. There was a glorious fight in which all but two died, those two making their way to Zabulistan. Some captured boys were sent to Yazid II who beheaded them.

==See also==
* [[Farrukhan the Great]]
* [[Qutaibah bin Muslim]]
* [[Muhammad bin Qasim]]
* [[Al Muhallab ibn Abi Suffrah]]

==References==
*[[Muhammad ibn Jarir al-Tabari]], v. 23 &amp;quot;The Zenith of the Marwanid House,&amp;quot; transl. Martin Hinds, SUNY, Albany, 1990; v. 24 &amp;quot;The Empire in Transition,&amp;quot; transl. David Stephen Powers, SUNY, Albany, 1989

{{s-start}}
{{succession box|title=[[List of Umayyad Governors of Iraq|Governor of Iraq]]|before=[[Yazid ibn Abi Kabshah al-Saksaki|Yazid ibn Abi Kabshah]]|after=|years=715&amp;amp;ndash;718}}
{{succession box|title=Governor of [[Greater Khorasan|Khurasan]]|before=[[al-Muhallab ibn Abi Suffrah]]|after=[[al-Mufaddal ibn al-Muhallab]]|years=702&amp;amp;ndash;704}}
{{s-end}}

{{Authority control|VIAF=66232076}}
{{Persondata &amp;lt;!-- Metadata: see [[Wikipedia:Persondata]]. --&amp;gt;
| NAME              = Yazid Ibn Al-Muhallab
| ALTERNATIVE NAMES =
| SHORT DESCRIPTION = Umayyad governor
| DATE OF BIRTH     = 672
| PLACE OF BIRTH    =
| DATE OF DEATH     = 720
| PLACE OF DEATH    =
}}
{{DEFAULTSORT:Yazid Ibn Al-Muhallab}}
[[Category:672 births|Muhallab]]
[[Category:720 deaths|Muhallab]]
[[Category:Umayyad governors of Khurasan]]
[[Category:Umayyad governors of Iraq]]
[[Category:People killed in action]]
[[Category:Muhallabids]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
