<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Cittaslow"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Cittaslow" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Primary sources|date=January 2008}}

[[File:Citta slow marchio alta risoluzione.jpg|thumb|The Cittaslow logo.]]

&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Cittaslow&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is a movement founded in [[Italy]] in October 1999. The inspiration of Cittaslow was the [[Slow Food]] organization. Cittaslow&amp;apos;s goals include improving the quality of life in towns by slowing down its overall pace, especially in a city&amp;apos;s use of spaces and the flow of life and traffic through them.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;{{cite book|last1=Parkins|first1=Wendy|last2=Craig|first2=Geoffrey|title=Slow Living|url=http://books.google.com/books?id=QNZ_XU85jLkC&amp;amp;pg=PA79|year=2006|publisher=Berg|isbn=978-1-84520-160-9|page=79}}&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt; Cittaslow is part of a cultural trend known as the [[Slow movement]].

Cittaslow has expanded broadly beyond Italy. By 2006, national Cittaslow networks existed in Germany, Norway and the United Kingdom. By mid-2009, fourteen countries had at least one officially accredited Cittaslow community. In July 2009, the small seaside village of [[Cowichan Bay]] in Canada became the North American continent&amp;apos;s first Cittaslow town.

== Membership ==
There are three categories of membership: Cittaslow town (population less than 50,000); Cittaslow Supporter (population more than 50,000);&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;http://www.cittaslow.org.uk/supporters/&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt; and Cittaslow Friend (individual or family) &amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;http://www.cittaslow.org.uk/about-us/join-us/&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

Like Slow Food, Cittaslow is a membership organisation. Full membership of Cittaslow is only open to towns with a population under 50,000. To become eligible for membership, a town must normally score at least 50 percent in a self-assessment process against the set of Cittaslow goals, and then apply for admission to the appropriate Cittaslow national network. An annual membership fee is payable by towns.

The first town in England to become a Cittaslow city was [[Ludlow]]; the first in Wales was [[Mold, Flintshire|Mold]].&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;{{cite book|last1=Robinson|first1=Peter|last2=Heitmann|first2=Sine|last3=Dieke|first3=Peter U.C.|title=Research Themes for Tourism|url=http://books.google.com/books?id=219aFMSRPqgC&amp;amp;pg=PA118|year=2011|publisher=CABI|isbn=978-1-84593-684-6|page=118}}&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt; Slow cities have been introduced{{When|date=February 2011}} not only in South Korea but in the whole of [[Asia]].&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;http://news.sbs.co.kr/section_news/news_read.jsp?news_id=N1000348056 Slow cities for the first time as Asian nations. (아시아 최초로 &amp;apos;국제 슬로시티&amp;apos; 지정) 2007-12-10&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

== The goals and aims ==
There are 50 goals and principles that each Cittaslow town commits to work to achieve. Although there will always be place for improvement these goals serve as tangible benchmarks to improve the quality of life in the city.

The main aims of the movement are:
*making life better for everyone living in an urban environment
*improving the quality of life in the cities
*resisting the homogenization and globalization of towns around the globe
*protecting the environment
*promoting cultural diversity and uniqueness of individual cities
*provide inspiration for a healthier lifestyle

&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;
&amp;quot;Cittaslow is about more than a set of 50 goals and principles. It is a way of thinking. It is about caring for your town and the people who live and work in it or visit it. It is about celebrating and promoting diversity and avoiding the ‘sameness’ that afflicts too many towns in the modern world. It is about finding a place in a changing world where values are often uncertain and the needs and aspirations of local communities can often be overlooked.&amp;quot;&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;http://www.cittaslow.org.uk/index.php?Pid1=1&amp;amp;PLv=1&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;

==See also==
* [[Slow food]]
* [[Slow architecture]]

==References==
{{Reflist}}

==External links==
* [http://www.cittaslow.org/ Homepage of the Cittaslow movement]
* [http://www.cittaslow.org/index.php?method=network&amp;amp;action=country&amp;amp;id=2 Cittaslow International Network] (lists certified Cittaslow cities by country)
* [http://www.cittaslowusa.org/ Cittaslow USA website]

[[Category:Slow movement]]
[[Category:Cittaslow|*]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
