<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Unclassified language"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Unclassified language" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Unreferenced|date=June 2012}}
&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Unclassified languages&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; are languages whose genetic affiliation has not been established by means of [[historical linguistics]]. If this state of affairs continues after significant study of the language and efforts to relate it to other languages, as in the case of [[Basque language|Basque]], it is termed a [[language isolate]]; an unclassified language is therefore one which may belong to an established family once better data or research is available. Languages can be unclassified for a variety of reasons, mostly due to a lack of reliable data but sometimes due to the confounding influence of [[language contact]]. Some poorly known extinct languages, such as [[Gutian language|Gutian]], are simply unclassifiable.

An example of a language that has caused multiple problems for classification is [[Mimi of Decorse]] in [[Chad]]. This language is only attested in a single word list collected ca. 1900. At first it was thought to be a [[Maban language]], because of similarities to [[Maba language|Maba]], the first Maban language to be described. However, as other languages of the Maban family were described, it became clear that the similarities were solely with Maba itself, and the relationship was too distant for Mimi to be related specifically to Maba and not equally to the other Maban languages. The obvious similarities are therefore now thought to be due to borrowings from Maba, which is the socially dominant language in the area. When such loans are discounted, there is much less data to classify Mimi with, and what does remain is not particularly similar to any other language or language family. Mimi might therefore be a language isolate, or perhaps a member of some other family related to Maban in the proposed but as-yet undemonstrated [[Nilo-Saharan]] phylum. It would be easier to address the problem with better data, but no-one has been able to find speakers of the language again.

It also happens that a language may be unclassified within an established family. That is, it may be obvious that it is, say, a [[Malayo-Polynesian language]], but not clear in which branch of Malayo-Polynesian it belongs. When a family consists of many similar languages with a lot of confusing contact, a large number of languages may be effectively unclassified. Families where this is a substantial problem include Malayo-Polynesian, [[Bantu languages|Bantu]], [[Pama–Nyungan]], and [[Arawakan]].

==Examples by reason==
There are hundreds of unclassified languages, mostly extinct. There are relatively few that are still spoken.

===Absence of data===
* [[Sentinelese language|Sentinelese]] (Andaman Islands; no contact for 300 years, and not a single word is known)
* [[Weyto language|Weyto]]† (Ethiopia)
* [[Nam language|Nam]]† (Chinese–Tibetan border; data is undeciphered)
* [[Indus Valley Language]] (Northern Indian subcontinent 5th-1st Century BC; script indecipherable)

===Scarcity of data===
* [[Bung language|Bung]] (Cameroon)
* [[Kujarge language|Kujarge]] (Chad)
* [[Lufu language|Lufu]] (Nigeria)
* [[Luo language (Atta)|Luo of Atta]] (Nigeria)
* [[Mawa language (Nigeria)|Mawa of Bauchi]]† (Nigeria)
* [[Solano language|Solano]]† (Mexico)

===Unrelated to nearby languages and not commonly examined===
* [[Bangi-me]] (Mali)
* [[Jalaa language|Jalaa]] (Nigeria)
* [[Mpre language|Mpre]] (Ghana)
* [[Kwaza language|Kwaza]] (Brazil)

===Basic vocabulary unrelated to other languages===
* [[Laal language|Laal]] (Chad)
* [[Bayot language|Bayot]] (Senegal)

===Not closely related to other languages and no academic consensus===
* [[Ongota language|Ongota]] (Ethiopia)
* [[Shabo language|Shabo]] (Ethiopia)

===Languages of dubious existence===
{{main|Spurious languages}}
* [[Oropom language|Oropom]] (Uganda) (extinct, if it existed)
* [[Imraguen language|Imraguen]] (Mauritania)
* [[Nemadi language|Nemadi]] (Mauritania)
* [[Rer Bare]] (Ethiopia) (extinct, if it existed)
* [[Wutana language|Wutana]] (Nigeria) (extinct, if it existed)

Some &amp;apos;languages&amp;apos; turn out to be fabricated, as [[Kukurá language|Kukurá]] of Brazil.

==See also==
* [[:Category:Unclassified languages]]
* [[List of unclassified languages according to the Ethnologue]]
* [[List of unclassified languages of North America]]
* [[List of unclassified languages of South America]]
* [[Language isolate]]
* [[List of language families]] (including isolates and unclassified languages)

==External links==
* [http://www.ethnologue.com/show_family.asp?subid=6-16 Ethnologue: Unclassified languages]

{{language-stub}}

[[Category:Unclassified languages|*]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
