<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Wax paper"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Wax paper" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Refimprove|date=October 2011}}

[[Image:waxedpaper.jpg|thumb|wax paper]]

&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Wax paper&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (&amp;apos;&amp;apos;waxed paper),&amp;apos;&amp;apos; also known as  &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Paraffin wax|paraffin]] paper&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, is [[paper]] that is made moisture-proof through the application of [[wax]].

The practice of oiling [[parchment]] or paper in order to make it semi-translucent or moisture-proof goes back at least to [[medieval times]]. Paper impregnated or coated with purified [[beeswax]] was widely used throughout the 19th century to retain or exclude moisture, or to wrap odorous products. [[Gustave Le Gray]] introduced the use of waxed paper for [[photographic negative]]s in 1851.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;{{Cite web|url=http://jawadonweb.com/?page_id=900|date=December 29, 2008|title=9 Inventions Edison Did Not Make|author=Jawad Shuaib|accessdate=28 October 2011}}&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;  Natural wax was largely replaced for the making of wax paper (or paraffine paper) after [[Herman Frasch]] developed ways of purifying paraffin and coating paper with it in 1876.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;{{Cite CAB|Frasch, Herman|short=x}}&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt; Wax paper is commonly used in [[cooking]], for its non-stick properties, and wrapping food for storage, such as [[cookie]]s, as it keeps water out or in. It is also used in [[handicraft|arts and crafts]].

== Food preparation ==

&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Oven&amp;apos;&amp;apos;: wax paper is not recommended for baking use as it will smoke.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;[http://reynoldspkg.com/reynoldskitchens/en/faq_detail.asp?info_page_id=756&amp;amp;prod_id=1799&amp;amp;cat_id=1337] Reynolds company, frequently asked questions. Retrieved December 2, 2011&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Microwave&amp;apos;&amp;apos;: wax paper can be used to prevent splatters by covering the food when [[microwave cooking]]. Since the paper is mostly unaffected by [[microwaves]], it will not heat to the point of [[combustion]] under normal usage. This makes wax paper more functional than [[plastic wrap]] which will melt at higher temperatures, or [[aluminium foil]] which is not safe for use in most [[microwave oven]]s.

== Other uses ==
Safety [[safety razor|razor blades]] are traditionally wrapped in wax paper to make handling them less dangerous.{{citation needed|date=December 2011}} Wax paper can also be used to make long lasting paper boats because of its high resistance to water.

From the early 1950s to the mid-1990s, wax paper was used as a common wrapping for sports card packages (Oh-Pee-Chee, Topps, Donruss, etc.). It was notorious for leaving wax markings on the back card where the wax paper was heated to be sealed. Wax paper was used as a way to keep the enclosed piece of [[bubble gum]] protected.

In the mid-1990s, sports card manufacturers stopped including pieces of bubble gum in packs of sports cards, thus ending the need for wax paper packs. Plastic (mylar) or other plastic/paper blends were used from then on.

Wax paper is also commonly used to attach pattern pieces to fabric while cutting it for sewing. One presses an iron over the wax paper briefly and attaches it to the cloth, making it easier to trace while cutting.{{citation needed|date=December 2011}}

Wax paper&amp;apos;s particularly high [[dielectric strength]] makes it a practical [[electrical insulator]], although modern materials have surpassed and mostly replaced it. Common applications are coil winding separators and [[capacitor]] dielectrics, and other applications requiring resilience against a potential difference up to the order of a few thousand volts per layer.

== Environmental issues ==
There are multiple environmental issues concerned with wax paper. Though it is biodegradable, synthetic additives such as petroleum mean that it is inadvisable to do so. Wax paper also cannot be recycled.{{citation needed|date=December 2011}}

==See also==
* [[Glassine]]
* [[Parchment#Plant-based parchment|Parchment]]
* [[Parchment paper (baking)]]

== References ==
{{reflist}}

{{Paper}}

[[Category:Paper]]
[[Category:Cooking utensils]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
