<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="German Institute of Science and Technology (Singapore)"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="German Institute of Science and Technology (Singapore)" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;The &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;German Institute of Science and Technology&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (abbreviated &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;GIST&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;) is an institute for research and education situated in Singapore, formed by a collaboration between the [[Technical University of Munich]], the [[National University of Singapore]], [[Nanyang Technological University]] and the [[Singapore Institute of Technology]]. It is also known as [http://www.tum-asia.edu.sg GIST-TUM Asia], being the full subsidiary of the [[Technische Universität München]] (abbreviated &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;TUM&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;).

== A German Education in Asia ==

As the first German academic venture abroad, [http://www.tum-asia.edu.sg GIST-TUM Asia] opened its doors in Singapore in 2002. Though situated in an Asian country, the academic model employed by [http://www.tum-asia.edu.sg GIST-TUM Asia] is nevertheless German in its roots, with an emphasis on industry readiness and innovation. Over the last 10 years, [http://www.tum-asia.edu.sg GIST-TUM Asia] has seen more than 300 graduates come through its Master programmes, including graduates from various countries in Asia and Europe such as China, India, Thailand, the Philippines, Indonesia, Nigeria, France, Germany, Poland etc.

[http://www.tum-asia.edu.sg GIST-TUM Asia] currently offers 5 Master of Science programmes, MSc in Industrial Chemistry; MSc in Integrated Circuit Design; MSc in Microelectronics; MSc in Aerospace Engineering; and MSc in Transport and Logistics. The former four programmes are run jointly with either [[Nanyang Technological University]] (NTU) or [[National University of Singapore]] (NUS) and the latter programme is a pure TUM programme. Lecturers and professors hail from as far as Germany and their wealth of knowledge from various fields provide a spectrum of experience for the students to glean from.

== A One-Stop Higher Education Facility in Singapore ==

Recognizing the demand for engineering excellence, [http://www.tum-asia.edu.sg GIST-TUM Asia] partnered [[Singapore Institute of Technology]] (SIT) to offer Bachelor of Science programmes in Electrical Engineering and Information Technology and Chemical Engineering in 2010. Admitted students undergo a 2 ½ year programme that includes a 2 to 4 month overseas exchange at the Munich campus. In addition, Singapore Workforce Development Agency (WDA) has launched a series of Executive Education programmes with TUM Asia, tapping on TUM’s engineering expertise in various industrial sectors to develop professionals in the workforce.

[http://www.tum-create.edu.sg TUM CREATE], a research initiative by [http://www.tum-asia.edu.sg GIST-TUM Asia], was incepted in June 2010 to propagate research programmes where scientists and researchers from both Germany and Singapore can work together for the advancement of science and technology. With the research agreement in TUM CREATE Centre for Electromobility in Megacities sealed between [http://www.tum-asia.edu.sg GIST-TUM Asia] and National Research Foundation of Singapore (NRF), the research programme will focus on developing innovative systems that incorporate safety and reliability with functionality and energy efficiency in electric vehicles.

==External links==
* [http://www.tum-asia.edu.sg/ Official Website]
* [http://www.facebook.com/tum.asia/ GIST - TUM Asia on Facebook]

{{coord missing|Singapore}}

[[Category:Universities in Singapore]]
[[Category:National University of Singapore]]
[[Category:Research institutes in Singapore]]
[[Category:International research institutes]]
[[Category:Research institutes]]
[[Category:Engineering universities and colleges]]
[[Category:Nanyang Technological University]]
[[Category:Germany–Singapore relations]]

{{asia-university-stub}}
{{singapore-stub}}&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
