<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Arverni"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Arverni" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{for|the hazardous lakes|Avernus}}
[[Image:Gaul, 1st century BC.gif|thumb|A map of [[Gaul]] in the 1st century BC, showing the relative position of the Arverni tribe.]]
[[File:Averni coin depicting warrior 5th to 1st century BCE.jpg|thumb|Arverni coin depicting warrior, 5th-1st century BCE.]]
The &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Arverni&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; were a [[Gauls|Gallic]] tribe living in what is now the [[Auvergne (region)|Auvergne]] region of [[France]] during the last centuries BC. One of the most powerful tribes in ancient [[Gaul]], they opposed the [[Ancient Rome|Romans]] on several occasions. Their most important stronghold was [[Gergovia]], near the present-day commune of [[Clermont-Ferrand]].

==Early history==
The Arverni had once been the most powerful tribal hegemony in Gaul during the 3rd and 2nd centuries BC under their king, [[Luernios]], but when his son (or grandson) [[Bituitus]] was defeated by the [[Ancient Rome|Romans]] in 121 BC, their ascendancy passed to the [[Aedui]] and [[Sequani]]. Unlike the [[Allobroges]], who were brought under direct Roman rule as a result of the Celtic wars of the 120s, the Arverni negotiated a treaty that preserved their independence, though their territory was diminished. No further Arvernian kings are mentioned in the historical record, and they may have adopted a constitutional [[oligarchy]] at this time. However, there were at least two later attempts to re-establish rulership. The defeat of the Arverni led directly to the establishment of &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Gallia Narbonensis]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos; as a [[Roman province]], referred to simply as the &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Provincia&amp;apos;&amp;apos; so often that a part of the ancient region is today known as [[Provence]].

The King Luernios was mentioned in writing by the Greek ethnographer Posidonius. Luernios was known to have scattered gold and silver coins to his followers while riding in his chariot. Under Luernios, the Arverni was at the head of a formidable Gallic military hegemony which stretched from the Rhine to the Atlantic coast.

==Gallic Wars==
[[Image:Vercingetorix stater CdM.jpg|thumb|left|Gold stater of [[Vercingetorix]], [[Cabinet des Médailles]].]]
The Arverni later played an important role in the [[Gallic Wars]] of [[Julius Caesar]] from 58 BC to 51 BC. At first the Arvenian nobles tried to avoid confronting Caesar during his early incursions. They executed the leader [[Celtillus]], evidently for trying to gain sovereignty over all the Gauls.&amp;lt;ref name=&amp;quot;Commentarrii7&amp;quot;&amp;gt;[[Julius Caesar]], [[s:Commentaries on the Gallic War/Book 7|&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Commentarii de Bello Gallico&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, book 7, ch. 4]].&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt; In 52 BC, Celtillus&amp;apos; son [[Vercingetorix]] rallied his supporters to fight the Romans, but was expelled from Gergovia by the nobles, including his uncle Gobanitio. He then raised a great army in the country, and returned to the city where he ejected his opponents and was declared king.&amp;lt;ref name=&amp;quot;Commentarrii7&amp;quot;/&amp;gt; This accomplished, Vercingetorix forged an alliance with many other Gallic tribes, and led them in the last significant Gallic offensive against the Romans. Vercingetorix was defeated by Caesar at the [[Battle of Alesia]], after which he surrendered.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;[[Julius Caesar]], [[s:Commentaries on the Gallic War/Book 7|&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Commentarii de Bello Gallico&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, book 7, ch. 89]].&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt; The Arverni territories were subsequently incorporated into the Roman imperium.

==See also==
*[[Quintus Fabius Maximus Allobrogicus]]: conquered King Bituitus
*[[Alba Fucens]]: town where Bituitus was held after capture

==References==
{{reflist}}

{{peoples of Gaul}}

[[Category:Ancient peoples]]
[[Category:Tribes of ancient Gaul]]
[[Category:Tribes involved in the Gallic Wars]]
[[Category:History of Auvergne]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
