<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Yale School of Nursing"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Yale School of Nursing" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Infobox University
|name           = Yale School of Nursing
|image_name     = Yale School of Nursing.png
|established    = 1923
|free_label     = Dean
|free           = Margaret Grey
|faculty        =
|type           = [[Private university|Private]]
|city           = {{flagicon|USA}} [[New Haven, Connecticut|New Haven]]
|state          = [[Connecticut]]
|country        = [[United States|U.S.]]
|students       =
|postgrad       =
|website        = [http://nursing.yale.edu/ http://nursing.yale.edu]
}}
[[Image:Yale School of Nursing, 100 Church Street South, October 20, 2008.jpg|200px|thumb]]
Established in 1923 in [[New Haven, Connecticut]], [[United States|U.S.]], &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Yale School of Nursing&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (YSN) has become a leading school of [[nursing]] in the United States with a reputation for excellence in teaching, research and clinical practice. The school is ranked in the top ten graduate schools of nursing in the United States by [[U.S. News and World Report]] and among nursing institutions that have received support from the [[National Institutes of Health]].&amp;lt;ref name=&amp;quot;ysnabout&amp;quot;&amp;gt;[http://nursing.yale.edu/about-ysn About Yale Nursing]&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

==Academics==

Yale School of Nursing offers degrees in Nursing, including a Doctor of Philosophy and [[Master of Science in Nursing|Master of Science in Nursing (MSN)]] degree with [[Nurse Practitioner]], Nursing Management, Policy and Leadership, and [[Nurse midwife|Nurse-Midwifery]] specialties.  The school also has the Graduate Entry Prespecialty in Nursing (GEPN) program, which is intended for students with a bachelor&amp;apos;s degree but no background in nursing. Joint degree programs are available with [[Yale School of Public Health]] and [[Yale Divinity School]].

In addition to degree programs, YSN offers pre and post doctoral research training and post-master&amp;apos;s certificates in various Nurse Practitioner specialities.&amp;lt;ref name=&amp;quot;ysnabout&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;

==History==
The Yale School of Nursing was founded in 1923 with funding from the Rockefeller Foundation. It was the first independent University-based school for the education of nurses.

YSN was the first school on nursing to have the autonomy of a school of nursing with its own Dean, faculty, budget, and degree meeting the standards of the university and on a parity with the other schools and colleges of the University rather than organized under another department or school or encompassing a diploma in nursing. [[Annie Warburton Goodrich]] was appointed the first Dean of YSN and was the first woman Dean at Yale University.

In 1934, bachelor&amp;apos;s degrees were required for admission and Yale Corporation authorized the Master of Nursing degree. This program, allowing students with no prior background in nursing graduate entry, would continue until 1956 when the Master of Science in Nursing (MSN) program began. The MSN required students to have a prior background in nursing in order to gain entry into the program. The Nurse Practitioner track within the MSN degree was established in 1971 with the offering of the Pediatric Nurse Practitioner specialty. This was expanded in 1972, when the Family Nurse Practitioner specialty began. By 1975 YSN offered 10 specialty programs and tracks, and was at the vanguard of the education of nurse practitioners at the graduate level along with clinical nurse specialists and nurse-midwives. In 1974, YSN reopened admission for students with no prior background in nursing through its Three-Year Program for Non-Nurse College Graduates (later called the GEPN program).&amp;lt;ref name=&amp;quot;ysnhistory&amp;quot;&amp;gt;[http://doc.med.yale.edu/nursing/historical/ History and Contributions of the Yale University School of Nursing]&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

==Deans&amp;lt;ref name=&amp;quot;ysnhistory&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;==
*Annie W. Goodrich (1923-1934)
*Effie Jane Taylor (1934-1944)
*Elizabeth Seelye Bixler Torrey (1944-1959)
*[[Florence Wald|Florence Schorske Wald]] (1959-1966)
*Margaret Gene Arnstein (1967-1972)
*Donna Kaye Diers (1972-1984)
*Judith Belliveau Krauss (1985-

==Notable faculty&amp;lt;ref name=&amp;quot;ysnhistory&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;==

*Lucy Conant
*Donna Diers
*James Dickoff
*[[Rhetaugh Graves Dumas]]
*Annie W. Goodrich
*[[Virginia Henderson|Virginia Avenel Henderson]]
*Patricia James
*Tish Knobf
*Ruth McCorkle
*Douglas Olsen
*Ida Jean Orlando
*[[Rachel Robinson]]
*[[Florence Wald|Florence Schorske Wald]]
*[[Ernestine Wiedenbach]]
*Helen Varney Burst

==References==
{{reflist}}

==External links==
* [http://nursing.yale.edu/ Official Website]

{{Yale}}

{{coord|41.2995|-72.9303|display=title}}

[[Category:Yale University schools|Nursing]]
[[Category:Nursing schools in Connecticut]]
[[Category:Educational institutions established in 1923]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
