<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Izzy and Moe"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Izzy and Moe" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{About|the film &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Izzy &amp;amp; Moe&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;|an article about the people who inspired the film|Izzy Einstein and Moe Smith}}
{{Infobox Film
 | name = Izzy &amp;amp; Moe
 | writer = [[Steven Patrick Bell]]&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;[[Robert Boris]]
 | starring = [[Jackie Gleason]]&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;[[Art Carney]]
 | director = [[Jackie Cooper]]
 | producer =
 | distributor = [[CBS|CBS Television]] (USA)
 | released = September 23, 1985
 | runtime =
 | language = English
 | budget =
 |
 | image= Izzy and Moe VideoCover.png
}}
&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Izzy &amp;amp; Moe&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is a [[1985 in film|1985]] [[Television movie|made for TV]]  [[crime]]/[[comedy film]], starring [[Jackie Gleason]] and [[Art Carney]]. It is a fictional account of two actual [[Prohibition]]-era policemen, [[Izzy Einstein and Moe Smith]], and their adventures in tracking down illegal bars and gangsters.

==Plot details==
During the [[Prohibition]] era of the 1920s, a gangster named John Vanderhoff, alias &amp;quot;The Dutchman&amp;quot;, was killing off the competition and setting up his own [[speakeasy]]s. To fight the  crime, the [[Prohibition Bureau]] needed to get some extra men. Izzy Einstein ([[Jackie Gleason]]) volunteers; he is desperate to have a steady paycheck to support his wife, mother-in-law and four daughters. Einstein wants to disprove his mother-in-law&amp;apos;s claim that he is just a &amp;quot;bum&amp;quot;.

When the agent in charge of the local Prohibition Unit office tells him there is no job, Einstein makes a speech: &amp;quot;This is America. And I&amp;apos;m &amp;apos;&amp;apos;proud&amp;apos;&amp;apos; to be an American...&amp;quot; When the chief tells Einstein that he is &amp;quot;too old&amp;quot; for this kind of job, Izzy quickly suggests taking a partner.  Moe Smith ([[Art Carney]]) recently had his underground bar discovered by the police and is spending too much time alone and drinking. Einstein meets with Smith and asks for his help. The idea of a steady paycheck convinces him.

When they first try to raid one of Dutch&amp;apos;s bars, they find the gangster has converted it into a &amp;quot;reading hall&amp;quot;. Izzy and Moe decide to use different tactics. After spotting a local baseball team, they ask their boss for 10 more men. They all dress as baseball players, and tell the gatekeeper at the bar they want to celebrate a win. They gain entry and enjoy it - then whip out their badges and arrest everyone in the bar.

Soon, Izzy and Moe have their own division within the unit; they work alone as a pair, get various costumes, and offer no explanations of their tactics.  Izzy and Moe soon successfully raid underground bars all over the city, and arrest such high-profile people as the district attorney. After their boss threatens to fire them, Izzy and Moe meet the press, and Izzy gives his &amp;quot;This is America&amp;quot; speech.  They are reinstated.

Moe, a widower, is attracted to Dallas Carter, an entertainer at one of the bars. He falls in love. Upset at losing so much money and booze to the cops, Dutch lures the pair to where a large shipment of [[Bourbon whiskey|bourbon]] is being kept. Izzy and Moe evade the trap, but Moe gets shot in the arm, and one of the agents is killed. The agents&amp;apos; death effects Moe, who had considered quitting again, and he decides to stay, giving his own version of the &amp;quot;This is America&amp;quot; speech to reporters. Izzy and Moe then proceeded to rob the Dutch&amp;apos;s big shipment of Bourbon that he is expecting, with help from Dallas, and also take the truck and its treasure to a police impound site.

The Dutchman finds out about Dallas tipping off the shipment, takes her hostage and tells Izzy and Moe to bring the bourbon for an exchange.  They go to his estate, dodging the bullets and capturing the corrupt police chief. When Moe confronts Dutch, the gangster is pointing a gun at Dallas&amp;apos; head. Moe offers himself; with Dutch about to shoot him, a gun blast knocks the gun away. Izzy emerges from hiding with a rifle. Moe says, &amp;quot;How could you chance taking a shot like that?&amp;quot; Izzy says, &amp;quot;I just pretended he had an apple on your head.&amp;quot;

==Cast==
{{Expand section|date=October 2010}}&amp;lt;!-- Plz see WP:FILMCAST --&amp;gt;
*[[Jackie Gleason]] as Izzy Einstein
*[[Art Carney]] as Moe Smith
*[[Cynthia Harris]] as Dallas Carter
*[[Zohra Lampert]] as Esther Einstein
*[[Dick Latessa]] as Lieut. Murphy

==References==
{{Unreferenced|date=October 2010}}
{{Reflist}}

==External links==
&amp;lt;div class=&amp;quot;references-small&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
*{{imdb title|id=0089358|title=Izzy &amp;amp; Moe}}
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;

{{DEFAULTSORT:Izzy And Moe}}
[[Category:1986 films]]
[[Category:Criminal comedy films]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
