<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Wikipedia:Articles for deletion/Open source concept"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Wikipedia:Articles for deletion/Open source concept" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;Article [[Open source concept]] listed on [[WP:VFD]] Apr 21 to Apr 27 2004, consensus was to delete.  Discussion:

Nonsense. --[[User:Faradn|Faradn]] 01:50, 21 Apr 2004 (UTC)

Kill, void content. [[User:Pfortuny|Pfortuny]] 08:20, 21 Apr 2004 (UTC)

This is the concept that desparately needs to be clarified. My attempt might not be perfect, but it is a good start.

*Delete. Sense lost in translation? -- [[User:Zigger|Zigger]] 20:33, 2004 Apr 21 (UTC)
*Delete. If there&amp;apos;s anything to be salvaged from this one sentence, it can be added to [[open source]]. And there&amp;apos;s not much sense in [[internet democracy]] either. And [[Open-Source Government]]. Can all these please be rationalised? [[User:Sjorford|sjorford]] 10:04, 22 Apr 2004 (UTC)
* You might be right it should be about [[open source]]. But open source is already linked too hard to software development, ignoring the pure essence. That is not good, because it leaves people miss the clear point of this idea. That is the reason I felt an urge to introduce [[open source concept]] as the essence of the open source, that has to be linked to open source software development and other things that use thsi pricniple.
* Delete.  [[User:Postdlf|Postdlf]]  00:21  23 Apr 2004 (UTC)
* Delete. Useless as-is, and anything it could conceivably be expanded to belongs in existing articles on open source. [[User:Jeeves|Jeeves]] 01:53, 23 Apr 2004 (UTC)
* Keep. The argument you are using is the same one as if I decided not to put a steering drive as a new term, because we are allready talking about cars, airplanes etc. Makes no sense for any reasonable mind.
* Keep. [[open source concept]] is the basic principle of all open structures that got their true life through the Internet. It can be thought of as an essence of [[open source]] or [[Open-Source Government]] because these two things are just a product of this principle.
* Keep. Sure, maybe the name is not ideal but I think he&amp;apos;s got a point. It IS important to differentiate an underlaying concept from it&amp;apos;s instances.
** Comment: Unsigned votes and those from anons are not normally counted, and these last three votes are both. Create a userid if you wish to contribute to VfD. If you have a good contribution history (and there&amp;apos;s provision for getting credit for anonymous edits you do before creating the user id) then your opinion will count far more here. [[User:Andrewa|Andrewa]] 04:58, 25 Apr 2004 (UTC)
*Delete - just a list of links (claiming to be examples) - delete or merge with [[Open source]] - [[User:Texture|T&amp;amp;#949;x]][[User Talk:Texture|&amp;lt;font color=red&amp;gt;&amp;amp;#964;&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;]][[User:Texture|ur&amp;amp;#949;]] 15:38, 26 Apr 2004 (UTC)

&amp;apos;&amp;apos;End discussion&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
