<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Yeast extract"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Yeast extract" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;[[File:Marmite.jpg|thumb|right|280px|Marmite Yeast Extract]]
{{Use British English|date=March 2013}}
&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Yeast extract&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is the common name for various forms of processed [[yeast]] products made by extracting the cell contents (removing the cell walls); they are used as food additives or flavourings, or as nutrients for bacterial culture media.  They are often used to create savoury flavours and [[umami]] taste sensations, and can be found in a large variety of packaged food including frozen meals, crackers, [[junk food]], gravy, stock and more. Yeast extracts in liquid form can be dried to a light paste or a dry powder.

==Autolyzed yeast==

[[Autolysis (biology)|Autolyzed]] yeast (containing the cell walls) or autolyzed yeast extract consists of concentrations of [[yeast]] cells that are allowed to die and break up, so that the yeasts’ endogenous [[digestion|digestive]] enzymes break their [[protein]]s down into simpler compounds ([[amino acids]] and [[peptides]]).

Yeast autolysates are used in [[Vegemite]] ([[Australia]]), [[Marmite]], [[Promite]], [[Oxo (food)|Oxo]] ([[Republic of Ireland|Ireland]], [[New Zealand]], [[South Africa]] and the [[United Kingdom]]), [[Cenovis]] ([[Switzerland]]) and Vitam-R ([[Germany]]). [[Bovril]] ([[Republic of Ireland|Ireland]] and the [[United Kingdom]]) switched from beef extract to yeast extract for 2005 and most of 2006, but later switched back.

The general method for making yeast extract for food products such as [[Vegemite]] and [[Marmite]] on a commercial scale is to add [[sodium chloride]] (salt) to a suspension of yeast, making the solution [[hypertonic]], which leads to the cells shrivelling up; this triggers [[autolysis]], in which the yeast self-destructs. The dying yeast cells are then heated to complete their breakdown, after which the husks (yeast with thick cell walls) are separated.  Removing the cell walls concentrates the flavours and changes the texture.

Yeast extract is commonly used as a flavour enhancer in processed foods of all kinds.

==Hydrolyzed yeast==

[[Hydrolysis|Hydrolyzed]] yeast or hydrolyzed yeast extract is another version used as a flavour enhancer. Exogenous enzymes or acids are used to hydrolyze the proteins.

==Controversy==

Yeast extract contains naturally occurring [[Glutamic acid (flavor)|glutamic acid]] or [[monosodium glutamate]]; this is produced from an acid-base fermentation cycle, and is only found in some yeasts, typically ones bred for use in baking.

Many food producers have replaced monosodium glutamate with yeast extract, which requires no E-number labeling, and allows food producers to claim their product is &amp;apos;all natural&amp;apos; or &amp;apos;with natural flavorings&amp;apos;. Health proponents claim this is a subversive move by the industry to hide an additive since the MSG contained within the yeast extract does not require explicit labeling. Food industry bodies &amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;http://www.dsm.com/en_US/foodandbeverages/public/home/downloads/Eurasyp_brochures.pdf&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt; state:

:Yeast extract is often confused with monosodium glutamate (MSG) – a common flavor enhancer – despite the fact that these ingredients differ strongly, both in composition and function. While yeast extract is made up of a rich mix of proteins, vitamins and amino acids, MSG is composed exclusively of glutamate salt. As a result, monosodium glutamate does not have a taste of its own and is only used to make existing flavors stronger.

== References ==
{{more footnotes|date=June 2012}}
{{reflist}}
* {{cite book
  | last = Herbst
  | first = Sharon
  | authorlink = Sharon Herbst
  | coauthors =
  | title = Food Lover&amp;apos;s Companion
  | publisher = [[Barron&amp;apos;s Educational Series, Inc.]]
  | year = 2001
  | location = [[Hauppauge, New York]]
  | pages =
  | url =
  | id = }}

==External links==
* [http://www.justhungry.com/2006/11/marmite_vegemite_andcenovis_a.html A salty tale of yeast spreads]
* [http://www.yeastextract.info yeastextract.info]: Homepage of Eurasyp (European Association of Specialty Yeast Products)
* [http://www.livestrong.com/article/71755-autolyzed-yeast-extract/ What is Autolyzed Yeast Extract?], Live Strong
* {{cite journal | pmid = 12042423 | year = 2002 | last1 = Edens | first1 = NK | last2 = Reaves | first2 = LA | last3 = Bergana | first3 = MS | last4 = Reyzer | first4 = IL | last5 = O&amp;apos;Mara | first5 = P | last6 = Baxter | first6 = JH | last7 = Snowden | first7 = MK | title = Yeast extract stimulates glucose metabolism and inhibits lipolysis in rat adipocytes in vitro | volume = 132 | issue = 6 | pages = 1141–8 | journal = The Journal of nutrition}}

{{DEFAULTSORT:Yeast Extract}}
[[Category:Food ingredients]]
[[Category:Microbiological media ingredients]]
[[Category:Yeast extract spreads|*]]
[[Category:Umami enhancers]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
