<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Duelling pistol"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Duelling pistol" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Refimprove|date=April 2013}}
A &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;duelling pistol&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is a type of [[pistol]] that was manufactured to be used in a [[duel]], when duels were customary and not illegal. Duelling pistols are often [[single-shot]] [[flintlock]] or [[percussion cap|percussion]] [[Black powder|black-powder]] pistols which fire a [[lead]] [[musket ball]]. They were made in identical pairs to put both duellists on the same footing.

== Design ==
[[File:dueling pistols.JPG|thumb|Matched pair of engraved and gilded French percussion lock duelling pistols in the [[Philadelphia Museum of Art]]]]
Standard flintlock pistols have a noticeable delay between pulling the trigger and actually firing the bullet. Purpose-built duelling pistols have various improvements to make them more reliable and accurate, such as longer, heavier [[gun barrel|barrels]], a spur on the trigger guard, saw handles, [[platinum]]-lined touch-holes and [[hair trigger]]s. All component parts were manufactured, hand-finished and then adjusted with great care and precision, which made duelling pistols much more costly than standard firearms of the period. Special care was taken when [[molding (process)|moulding]] the lead bullets to ensure that there were no voids which would affect accuracy.  Pistols were carefully  loaded identically, and one of the duellists was offered his choice of two indistinguishable loaded pistols. As duels were generally fought at short distances which were paced out, typically {{convert|30|to|40|ft|0}},&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;http://www.exetermemories.co.uk/EM/_events/last_duel.php&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt; between stationary opponents, extreme accuracy was not required.

Duelling pistols had long barrels (typically {{convert|10|in|abbr=on}}) and fired large, heavy bullets. Pistols with calibers of {{convert|0.45|in|abbr=on}}, {{convert|0.52|in|abbr=on}}, {{convert|0.58|in|abbr=on}} or even {{convert|0.65|in|abbr=on}} were common. The bullets loaded in them could weigh half an [[ounce]] ({{convert|214|gr}}) in .52 caliber, or more in larger calibers. Bullets were fired with a [[muzzle velocity]] of approximately {{convert|800|ft/s}}, which made a .52 caliber bullet about as lethal as a current  [[.45 ACP]] round, capable of inflicting very severe [[Gunshot wound|wounds]]. These injuries, coupled with the primitive state of [[emergency medicine]] at the time when duels were commonplace, meant that pistol duels frequently resulted in fatalities, either immediately or afterwards. This was the fate of [[Alexander Pushkin]], a highly experienced pistol duellist who had fought 29 duels before being wounded in the stomach by [[Georges-Charles de Heeckeren d&amp;apos;Anthès]] on 8 February 1837. Pushkin managed to return fire, slightly wounding d&amp;apos;Anthès, but died two days later.

Most duelling pistols had smooth bores, though some had &amp;apos;&amp;apos;scratch rifling&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, a subtle form of [[rifled barrel|rifling]] which was difficult to see with the naked eye. Pistols with rifled barrel spin-stabilise the shot when it is fired, resulting in much improved accuracy. As a result, duelling pistols with rifled barrels were considered unsporting by many, although there was no unfairness so long as the pistols were identical.

== Manufacturers ==
The use of pistols in duels became popular in [[United Kingdom|Britain]], [[France]] and [[Colonial America|America]] during the mid-eighteenth century. Initially standard holster or travelling pistols were mainly used, but by the end of the century special-purpose duelling pistols were being made by craftsmen in [[England]], [[France]] [[Germany]], [[Austria]] and [[Colonial America|America]].

The most famous and innovative manufacturers were [[London]]-based companies such as [[Wogdon &amp;amp; Barton]], [[Durs Egg]], [[Joseph Manton|Manton]], Mortimer, Nock, and [[James Purdey and Sons|Purdey]].{{Citation needed|date=November 2009}}

Pairs of duelling pistols were often supplied in compartmentalised wooden cases along with a powder flask, rods for cleaning and loading, spare [[flint]]s and a bullet mould.

==Gallery==
&amp;lt;gallery&amp;gt;
Image:Pistolets-de-duel-Negative0-02-02(1).jpg|Late model [[England|English]] duelling pistols fired by [[percussion cap]], bearing the [[Royal Warrant]] on the case
Image:Hamilton-Burr pistols.jpg|Earlier English [[flintlock]] duelling pistols made by [[Wogdon &amp;amp; Barton]], used in the fatal [[Burr-Hamilton duel]] of 1804
&amp;lt;/gallery&amp;gt;

== See also ==

* [[Code duello]]
* [[Alexander Pushkin]] (died in 1837, of wounds received in a pistol duel)
*[[Burr–Hamilton duel]]

== References ==

{{reflist}}

== External links ==
* [http://www.armesanciennes.fr/index.php?id=55 18th and 19th French weapons]
* [http://www.nma.gov.au/collections/mitchell_duelling_pistols Sir Thomas Mitchell duelling pistols], [[National Museum of Australia]]

[[Category:Single shot pistols]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
