<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Tavastia (historical province)"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Tavastia (historical province)" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{unreferenced|date=August 2008}}
[[Image:Häme.vaakuna.svg|right|150px]]
&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Tavastia&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Tavastland&amp;apos;&amp;apos; or &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Häme&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, Russian &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Yam&amp;apos;&amp;apos; or &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Yemi&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, is a [[Historical provinces of Finland|historical province]] in the south of [[Finland]]. It borders [[Finland Proper]], [[Satakunta]], [[Ostrobothnia (region)|Ostrobothnia]], [[Savonia (historical province)|Savonia]] and [[Uusimaa (historical province)|Uusimaa]].

== Administration ==

From 1997 to 2010 Tavastia was divided between the administrative provinces of [[Southern Finland]] and [[Western Finland]]. However, these provinces have been abolished, and Tavastia is now divided between four [[regions of Finland]]: mainly [[Tavastia Proper]] and [[Päijänne Tavastia]], with smaller parts in [[Pirkanmaa]] and [[Central Finland]].

== History ==
[[Image:Historical province of Tavastia in Finland.png|left|150px|thumb|Historical province of Tavastia&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;(borders of the modern provinces&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;in pink)]]
The prehistoric era of Tavastia can be said to end with the [[Second Swedish Crusade]] in 1239 or 1249, when it became part of [[Sweden]]. The construction of the [[Hämeenlinna]] ({{lang-sv|Tavastehus}}) castle began in the 1260s, on the orders of [[Birger Jarl]]. It was to be the centre of the three &amp;quot;castle counties&amp;quot;, the other two being the castle of [[Turku]] ({{lang-sv|Åbo}}) in [[Finland Proper]] and [[Viipuri]] ({{lang-sv|Viborg}}) castle in [[Finnish Karelia|Karelia]]. After the peace [[Treaty of Nöteborg]] in 1323 the castle lost some of its importance as a defence against the East but remained an administrative centre. When Finland was ceded to [[Russia]] in 1809, the province ceased to be a part of Sweden. The [[Provinces of Sweden|provinces]] have no administrative function today but live on as a historical legacy in both Finland and Sweden.

The province has been inhabited since the [[Stone Age]]. Northern Tavastia was for a long time a wilderness inhabited by [[Sami people|Sami]] hunter-gatherers and frequented also by Finnish hunters. Only during the late [[Middle Ages]] was [[agriculture]] slowly introduced to the northern parts of the province. In the 19th century, the growth of the forest industry started to bring new wealth to the area. The waterways of [[Näsijärvi]] and [[Vanajavesi]] provided easy transport for timber. The most notable centres of the paper industry were, and still are, [[Mänttä]] and [[Valkeakoski]]. The most notable industrial center in historical Tavastia, however, is [[Tampere]], where a number of large textile mills and metal factories have been operating since the early 19th century.

== Geography ==
Western Tavastia extends over both sides of the great [[Kokemäenjoki]] [[drainage basin]]. In Eastern Tavastia, the regions of [[Päijänne Tavastia]] and [[Central Finland]] are located around the southern part of Lake [[Päijänne]]. The Southern borders of the province roughly follow the [[Salpausselkä]] ridge. The Southern parts of the province consist of [[plain]]s intermixed with fields and forests. Towards the north, the land gradually rises and becomes more hilly. At the same time, the proportion of cultivated land decreases, and forest and heath become increasingly dominant. The northern boundary of Tavastia is in [[Central Finland]]. As this area was settled only at the time of the replacement of the old [[Provinces of Sweden|provincial system]] with the [[Counties of Sweden|county system]], the ancient provincial boundary is uncertain in this area. The same applies to the northwestern border with Satakunta, which is located in [[Pirkanmaa]].

As a result of the original pattern of settlement, the inhabited areas are located around the waterways, fields encircling especially the largest lakes. The lakes are navigable but the rapids of [[Kymijoki]] and [[Kokemäenjoki]] restrict navigation to the sea. Similarly, the lakes form three separate navigable areas. Lake [[Näsijärvi]] can be navigated for over 100 kilometers north of [[Tampere]], while the lakes [[Pyhäjärvi]], [[Vanajavesi]] and [[Roine_(Finland)|Roine]] have been connected by canals since the 19th century, forming another significant waterway. Lake [[Päijänne]], on the other hand, connects [[Lahti]] and [[Päijät-Häme]] to [[Central Finland]] and [[Jyväskylä]].

== Heraldry ==

Arms granted at the burial of [[Gustav I of Sweden]] in 1560. The arms are crowned by a ducal coronet, though by Finnish tradition this more resembles a Swedish count&amp;apos;s coronet. Blazon: &amp;quot;Gules, a lynx passant or, ear tufts sable; in chief three mullets of six, in base four roses, all argent&amp;quot;.

{{-}}
{{Historical provinces of Finland}}

{{coord missing|Finland}}

[[Category:Historical provinces of Finland]]
[[Category:Tavastia Proper]]
[[Category:Southern Finland]]
[[Category:Western Finland]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
