<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Kanklės"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Kanklės" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;[[File:Zemaiciu-kankles.jpg|right|300px|thumb|Kanklės of the Žemaitija regional style]]
The &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;kanklės&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (pronounced {{IPA-lt|ˈkʌŋkles|}}) is a Lithuanian plucked string musical instrument ([[chordophone]]), of the [[zither]] family. The instrument is similar in construction and origin to the Latvian [[kokle]], Russian [[gusli]], Estonian [[kannel (music)|kannel]] and Finnish [[kantele]].

==Construction==
The body of the kanklės is constructed of one [[trapezoid]]al piece of [[hardwood]], hollowed out to make a cavity. A thin sheet of [[softwood]] (usually [[spruce]]) is used to make a [[sounding board]], which covers the body. Sound holes, which traditionally take the shape of a stylized flower or star, are cut into the sounding board, allowing sound to project outward.

At the narrowest side of the body a metal bar is attached, to which the strings made of wire or [[Catgut|gut]] are anchored. The opposite ends of the strings are attached to a row of [[tuning peg]]s inserted into holes at the opposite side of the body.

==Playing==
It is usually rested on the player&amp;apos;s lap and played with the fingers or a pick made of bone or quill.

==Regional types==
[[Image:Lithuanian musicians Rasa.jpg|thumb|Large kanklės used by a Lithuanian traditional dance troupe along with [[birbynė]]]]
Within Lithuania, there are three basic regional types of kanklės, although there are variations within each type and some overlap of areas. Each type has its own playing technique.

===Northeastern Aukštaitija===
The simplest and most ancient form, most frequently having five strings, and having a rounded bottom like a boat.

===Žemaitija and Northwestern Aukštaitija===
Somewhat larger than those of Northeastern Aukštaitija, usually having between eight and twelve strings. They have a flat bottom, and in some cases, the shortest end is carved with the stylized figure of a bird&amp;apos;s or fish&amp;apos;s tail.

===Suvalkija and Northwestern Žemaitija===
Usually the most highly decorated type, and kanklės used in concert performance are most often based on this variety. The most prominent identifying feature is the addition of a carved spiral figure to the point of the instrument&amp;apos;s body and sometimes, the rounding of the narrow end of the body. Typically these instruments have between nine and thirteen strings.

==External links==
*[http://www.tvfolk.net/artistVideo.php?ID=270&amp;amp;resolution=high&amp;amp;scale=100 Video of performance by Regimantas Zitkauskas] at TVfolk.net
*[http://discovery.ot.lt/cfair2000/kankles/a_kankle.htm Lithuanian stringed instrument kankles]{{dead|date=June 2012}}
*[http://ausis.gf.vu.lt/eka/EWG/default.htm Anthology of Lithuanian Ethnoculture]{{dead|date=June 2012}}
*[http://www.folkinstruments.lt/eng/kankles_instr.htm/ Lithuanian Folk Instruments]

==References==
{{no footnotes|date=June 2012}}
*[http://kankles.mch.mii.lt/ Ancient Lithuanian Kanklės], Romualdas Apanavičius, Institute of Ethnomusic, Vilnius, Lithuania

[[Category:Box zithers]]
[[Category:Lithuanian musical instruments]]

[[cs:Kokle]]
[[lv:Kokle]]
[[pl:Kokle]]
[[sv:Kokle]]
[[bat-smg:Konklē]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
