<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Montmin"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Montmin" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Infobox French commune
|image=montmin panorama.jpg
|image-desc=Panoramic of Montmin
|name                   = Montmin
|region                 = [[Rhône-Alpes]]
|department             = [[Haute-Savoie]]
|arrondissement         = Annecy
|canton                 = Faverges
|INSEE                  = 74187
|postal code            = 74210
|mayor                  = Anne Bondon
|term                   = 2008 - 2014
|intercommunality       = Pays de Faverges
|longitude              = 06.265
|latitude               = 45.8033
|elevation m            =
|elevation min m        = 635
|elevation max m        = 2338
|area km2               = 16.29
|population             = 319
|population date        = 2008
}}
&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Montmin&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is a [[Communes of France|commune]] in the [[Haute-Savoie]] &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Departments of France|département]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos; in the [[Rhône-Alpes]] [[Regions of France|region]] in south-eastern [[France]].

Inhabitants of the commune are known as Montminois (male) and Montminoises (female).

==Geography==
The seven hamlets occupy a four-mile long valley which is bordered on the west by [[Mont Chenevier]], and on the east by the impressive and snow-capped [[Tournette]] massif. According to locals, [[Noah&amp;apos;s Ark]] landed at the [[Col de l&amp;apos;Aulp]], whose valley is indeed shaped like a ship; [[Noah]], Biblical father of viticulture, would have planted the lakeside vineyards of [[Talloires]], which produced wines and brandy until the 1950s. The mean elevation of the village is 1000 meters, or 3250 feet above sea level.

==History==
First settled in the early [[Middle Ages]], shortly after the year 1000, the hamlets were farming communities that existed almost entirely independently of the outside world until the advent of modern transportation.

==Tourism==
With the arrival of modern roads and vehicles, Montmin has become a tourist attraction renowned for the scenic [[Col de la Forclaz (France)|Col de la Forclaz]] mountain pass, one of the premier [[hang gliding]] and [[paragliding]] sites in [[Europe]]. Montmin hosted the 1995 Hang Gliding Championships of France. And in July 1997 Montmin watched the [[1997 Tour de France|Tour de France]] bicycle race come through the community, up from [[Faverges]], over the Col de la Forclaz and back down toward [[Bluffy, Haute-Savoie|Bluffy]] and the high [[Alps]] to the east.

Unlike its neighbors in the high Alps ([[La Clusaz]], [[Megève]], etc.), Montmin has not become a vast urbanized winter playground crisscrossed with ski lifts and dotted with large hotels and apartment buildings. Cautious zoning and deliberately limited development have allowed Montmin to retain much of its charm as a quiet agricultural community, even though it is a mere twenty minutes from downtown [[Annecy]].

In the winter, Montmin&amp;apos;s small ski lifts are known as a good place for beginning and intermediate skiers; many of the villagers are certified ski instructors, and many children of the Annecy and Faverges area first learned to ski in Montmin. In the summer, the same lifts are used for summer gliding sports. Montmin&amp;apos;s principal claim to fame is as the starting point of several popular hiking trails, including the scenic climb up Mt. Tournette, the tallest of the mountains overlooking [[Lake Annecy]].

A hotel and several restaurants at the Col de la Forclaz mountain pass receive thousands of tourists who come to enjoy the excellent view of Lake Annecy. These facilities offer comfortable accommodations and traditional [[Savoy]] country cooking.

==Miscellaneous==
The local [[cheese]] dairy farms produce the renowned [[Tomme]] and [[Reblochon]] cheeses for which the area is famous.

At the dawn of the 21st century, Montmin&amp;apos;s population is beginning to grow again as the village finds a new role as a dormitory for the cities of Annecy and Faverges, though it retains much of its rustic charm.

==See also==
*[[Communes of the Haute-Savoie department]]

==References==
*[http://www.insee.fr/en/home/home_page.asp INSEE]
{{Reflist}}

==External links==
*[http://www.sav.org/montmin/ Montmin]
*[http://www.sav.org/montmin/webcam.html Montmin/Lake Annecy Webcam]
*[http://www.sav.org/e/reblo.html Reblochon Cheese]

{{Haute-Savoie communes}}

[[Category:Communes of Haute-Savoie]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
