<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Grangegorman Development Agency"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Grangegorman Development Agency" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;[[Image:Grangegorman penitentiary.JPG|thumb|right|This is the administration annexe of St. Brendan&amp;apos;s Psychiatric Hospital, Grangegorman, formerly the [[Richmond General Penitentiary]] ]]

{{main|Grangegorman}}

&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Grangegorman Development Agency&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is an agency of the [[Government of Ireland]] charged with redevelopment of the Grangegorman Campus, formerly within the curtilage of [[St. Brendan&amp;apos;s Hospital (Grangegorman)|St. Brendan&amp;apos;s Hospital]].  &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Grangegorman]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; ({{Irish place name|Gráinseach Ghormáin|no_translate=yes}}) itself is an inner city area on the [[Northside (Dublin)|Northside]] of [[Dublin]], [[Republic of Ireland|Ireland]].
Grangegorman, at 29 [[hectare]]s, is the largest undeveloped site in the [[City of Dublin]].

==Grangegorman Quarter==
The &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Grangegorman Urban Quarter&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is a proposed education, health and community development by the &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Grangegorman Development Agency&amp;apos;&amp;apos; for [[Dublin Institute of Technology]] and the [[Health Service Executive]]. The site&amp;apos;s design has been provided by the American architectural firm of Moore Ruble Yudell under the direction of Irish-born Architect James Mary O&amp;apos;Connor. The surrounding community is an equal stakeholder in the project and receives technical support from the Grangegorman Community Forum. On July 17, 2012 The Grangegorman Development Agency was awarded funding from the Irish Government as a part of a €2.5billion stimulus package for the country.

===Dublin Institute of Technology (DIT) Grangegorman Campus===
The first construction work to take place as part of the new DIT campus is to start in 2013 with the temporary refurbishment of several listed buildings. These will acoommodate 1,400 staff and students, who move in 2014. A further 10,000 staff and students will move by 2017 into two major quads which are being built a public private partnerships. When fully completed Grangegorman will cater for up to 20,000 staff and students and for the first time all 39 sites which DIT occupy will be in one place.

===Transport Links===
The campus will be linked to the [http://www.luascrosscity.ie LUAS Cross City Line] from the city centre to [[Broombridge railway station]]. Stops will be &amp;apos;Grangegorman&amp;apos; and &amp;apos;Broadstone-DIT&amp;apos;.

===HSE Facilities===
The new replacement facility for St. Brendans Hospital, the Phoenix Care Centre, was opened 1st March 2013.  Plans for a new primary care centre is in design phase.

==St. Brendan&amp;apos;s Hospital, Grangegorman==
{{Main|St. Brendan&amp;apos;s Hospital (Grangegorman)}}
Officially opened in 1815, although it received its first patients in 1814, the Richmond Lunatic Asylum was initially created as a national institution for the reception of recoverable lunatics. On the 30 July 1830 the asylum was incorporated into the national system of district asylums and was renamed the Richmond Lunatic District Asylum. Under the district asylum system it received patients resident in the city and county of Dublin and the counties of Louth, Meath, Wicklow and the town of Drogheda. On 19 May 1921 its name was changed to the Grangegorman Mental Hospital. On 17 April 1958 its name was changed to St. Brendan&amp;apos;s Hospital, which it retains to this day.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;Joseph Reynolds, &amp;quot;Grangegorman: Psychiatric Care in Dublin since 1815&amp;quot;, Dublin, 1992.&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

In the mid-twentieth century, Grangegorman Mental Hospital had patient population of approximately 2,000 people. Its branch hospital, St. Ita&amp;apos;s, Portrane, would have housed a similar number of patients. Although the original building of the Richmond Lunatic Asylum has now been largely destroyed, St. Brendan&amp;apos;s Hospital continues as a psychiatric hospital and currently has five wards with a total of eighty-two psychiatric beds. It forms part of the HSE Dublin North West Mental Health Service and its catchment area is north-west Dublin.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;Inspector of Mental Health Services, [http://www.mhcirl.ie/Inspectorate_of_Mental_Health_Services/AC_IRs/st_brendans_report_2009.pdf &amp;quot;Report of the Inspector of Mental Health Service&amp;quot;], Dublin, 2009.&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

==References==
{{Reflist}}

==External links==
*[http://www.grangegormandevelopmentagency.ie/ Grangegorman Development Agency]
*[http://www.dit.ie/about/grangegorman/ DIT Grangegorman Campus]
*[http://www.luascrosscity.ie LUAS Cross City Project Website]

{{Coord|53|21.3|N|6|16.6|W|region:IE_type:city|display=title}}

[[Category:Dublin Institute of Technology|G]]
[[Category:Government agencies of the Republic of Ireland]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
