<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Robert J. Cenker"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Robert J. Cenker" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{No footnotes|date=March 2010}}
{{BLP sources|date=March 2010}}
{{Infobox astronaut
| name          =Robert Joseph Cenker
| image         =Robert Cenker.jpg
| type          =[[RCA]] Payload Specialist
| nationality   =[[United States|American]]
| birth_date    =November 5, 1948
| birth_place   =[[Uniontown, Pennsylvania]]
| occupation    =[[Engineer]]
| selection     =
| time          =6d 02h 03m
| mission       =[[STS-61-C]]
| insignia      =[[Image:STS-61-c-patch.png|30px]]
|}}
&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Robert Joseph Cenker&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is an [[engineer]] and aerospace systems consultant who flew aboard Space Shuttle mission [[STS-61-C]] as [[Payload Specialist]] for RCA.

==Personal ==
Born November 5, 1948 and raised near [[Uniontown, Pennsylvania]]. Married to Barbara Ann (Cosentino) Cenker. They have two sons named Daniel and Brian and one daughter named Laura.

==Education==
* Bachelor&amp;apos;s and Master&amp;apos;s degrees in Aerospace Engineering from [[Penn State]]
* Master&amp;apos;s degree in [[Electrical Engineering]] from [[Rutgers]]

==Organizations==
* Associate Fellow in the AIAA
* Senior Member of the IEEE
* Life Member of the Penn State Alumni Association
* Life Member of the [[Association of Space Explorers]]
* Registered Professional Engineer in the state of [[New Jersey]]
* [[Tau Beta Pi]]
* [[Sigma Gamma Tau]]

==Career==
Cenker currently consults with various firms in the areas of spacecraft design, assembly, and flight operations, and micro-gravity research. This has included launch vehicle evaluation and systems engineering support for [[Motorola]] on [[Iridium]]; avionics architecture, generation of performance specification, and generation of performance map for small expendable launch vehicle; and constellation configuration and launch vehicle performance definition for proprietary smallsat communications system. Last two years with [[RCA]] were spent as Manager of Payload Accommodations on EOS Platform. Prior assignments at RCA included Integration and Test Manager for the Satcom D &amp;amp; E spacecraft, responsible for implementation of all launch site activities, and Spacecraft Bus Manager on the Spacenet/Gstar programs, responsible for satisfaction of multiple launch vehicle interfaces (Delta, STS and Ariane) by the spacecraft bus design. Other efforts include systems engineering and operations support for INTELSAT on Intelsat K and Intelsat VIII; AT&amp;amp;T on Telstar 401 and 402; Fairchild Matra on SPAS III; and Martin Marietta on Astra 1B, BS3N, ACTS, and Series 7000 communications satellites. Systems engineering and architecture for various spacecraft studies, ranging from individual Smallsats, military communications constellations, and large, assembled-in-orbit platforms.

Former member of the technical staff at the RCA/GE Astro Space Division. In 18 years with [[GE]] (formerly RCA) he worked in a variety of functions, including satellite attitude control and in-orbit operations; spacecraft assembly, test, and pre-launch operations; and satellite hardware and system design. Approximately two years of this experience were with a [[United States Navy|Navy]] navigation satellite program, with the remaining time spent on various commercial communications satellite efforts.

==Spaceflight experience==
Selected by RCA as a [[Payload Specialist]]; and approved by [[NASA]] to fly on the [[space shuttle]] &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Space Shuttle Columbia|Columbia]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos; on Space Shuttle Mission [[STS-61-C]]. During the six-day mission, (January 12 to 18, 1986) he performed a variety of physiological tests, observed the deployment of the RCA Satcom Ku-1 satellite, and operated primary experiment, an infrared imaging camera. In completing this flight, Cenker traveled over 2.1 million miles in 96 Earth orbits and logged over 146 hours in space.

==External links==
*[http://www.jsc.nasa.gov/Bios/PS/cenker.html NASA biography of Cenker]
*[http://www.spacefacts.de/bios/astronauts/english/cenker_robert.htm Spacefacts biography of Robert J. Cenker]

{{Persondata &amp;lt;!-- Metadata: see [[Wikipedia:Persondata]]. --&amp;gt;
| NAME              = Cenker, Robert J.
| ALTERNATIVE NAMES =
| SHORT DESCRIPTION =
| DATE OF BIRTH     = November 5, 1948
| PLACE OF BIRTH    = [[Uniontown, Pennsylvania]]
| DATE OF DEATH     =
| PLACE OF DEATH    =
}}
{{DEFAULTSORT:Cenker, Robert J.}}
[[Category:1948 births]]
[[Category:Living people]]
[[Category:American astronauts]]
[[Category:Pennsylvania State University alumni]]
[[Category:Senior Members of the IEEE]]
[[Category:NASA civilian astronauts]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
