<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="North Kalimantan Communist Party"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="North Kalimantan Communist Party" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Refimprove|date=December 2009}}
{{Politics of Malaysia}}
&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;North Kalimantan Communist Party&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; was a [[communism|communist]] [[political party]] based in the [[Malaysia]]n province of [[Sarawak]] in northern [[Borneo]]. It was founded on September 19, 1971. Before that, the group had been operating under the name Sarawak Communist Organization. The chairman of the NKCP was Wen Min Chyuan. He had been a leading member of the [[Sarawak United People&amp;apos;s Party]] 1960-1964.

The membership of NKCP was predominantly [[Chinese race|ethnically Chinese]]. The armed wing of NKCP was Pasukan Rakyat Kalimantan Utara (PARAKU).

==History==
[[Left-wing politics|Left-wing]] and [[communism|communist]] [[Covert cell|cell groups]] had grown rapidly among Sarawak&amp;apos;s urban Iban and Chinese communities since the 1950s and later became the nucleus of the anti-Malaysia North Kalimantan People&amp;apos;s Army (PARAKU), which was the armed wing of the party.

The party supported and propagated the unification of all Borneo territories under British control to form an independent leftist [[North Borneo Federation|North Kalimantan]] state. This idea was idea originally proposed by [[A. M. Azahari]], leader of the [[Brunei People&amp;apos;s Party|Parti Rakyat Brunei]] (Brunei People’s Party), who had forged links with [[Sukarno]]&amp;apos;s nationalist movement, together with Ahmad Zaidi, in [[Java]] in the 1940s.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;Pocock p. 129&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

The North Kalimantan (or Kalimantan Utara) proposal was seen as a post-[[decolonization]] alternative by local opposition against the Malaysia plan. Local opposition throughout the Borneo territories was primarily based on economic, political, historical and cultural differences between the Borneo states and [[Federation of Malaya|Malaya]], as well as the refusal to be subjected under peninsular political domination.

In the aftermath of the [[Brunei Revolt]], possibly fearing British reprisals (which never eventuated), many Chinese communists, possibly several thousand, fled Sarawak.  Their compatriots remaining in Sarawak were known as Pasukan Gelilya Rakyat Sarawak (Sarawak People’s Guerilla Force). Soebandrio met with a group of their potential leaders in Bogor, and Nasution sent three trainers from [[Resimen Para Komando Angkatan Darat]] (RPKAD) Battalion 2 to Nangabadan near the Sarawak border, where there were about 300 trainees. Some 3 months later two lieutenants were sent there.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;Conboy p. 93-95&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

The PGRS numbered about 800, based in [[West Kalimantan]] at Batu Hitam, with a contingent of 120 from the Indonesian intelligence agency and a small cadre trained in China.  The PKI (Indonesian Communist Party) was strongly in evidence and led by an ethnic Arab revolutionary, Sofyan. The PGRS ran some raids into Sarawak but spent more time developing their supporters in Sarawak.  The Indonesian military did not approve of the leftist nature of the PGRS and generally avoided them.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;Conboy p. 156&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

==Current status==
In 1974 a break-away group led by Bong Kee Chok signed a peace treaty with the state government. The Bong Kee Chok faction was larger than the remaining Wen Min Chyuan faction.

The NKCP gradually declined. In 1989 [[CIA]] estimated that the group had around 100 fighters. On October 17, 1990, the NKCP signed a peace-treaty with the state government and dissolved. Several guerrilla fighters were reintegrated into civilian life.

==References==
{{reflist}}

[[Category:Communist parties in Malaysia]]
[[Category:Defunct political parties in Malaysia]]
[[Category:Defunct Communist parties]]
[[Category:1971 establishments in Malaysia]]
[[Category:Political parties established in 1971]]
[[Category:Political parties in Sarawak]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
