<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="P4 gauge"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="P4 gauge" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Infobox Model Rail Scale
| name = P4
| image_filename =
| image_caption =
| widthpx =
| scale = 4 mm to 1 ft
| ratio = 1:76.2
| gauge = {{RailGauge|18.83mm}}
| prototype_gauge = [[Standard gauge]]
}}

&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;P4&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; or &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Protofour&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is a set of standards (of which the article name &amp;quot;P4 gauge&amp;quot; is a misnomer as the standards concern much more than simply the gauge of the track) for [[model railway]]s allowing a more accurate construction of models to a scale of 4&amp;amp;nbsp;mm to 1 foot (1:76.2), the predominant scale of model railways of the British prototype.  For historical reasons almost all manufacturers of British prototype models use the inaccurate [[00 gauge]] (1:76.2 models running on under-scale {{RailGauge|16.5mm}} gauge track).  P4 represents the most significant development of a movement that started in the 1950s to model accurately to the 4&amp;amp;nbsp;mm to 1 foot scale.

The P4 standards specify a scale model track gauge of {{RailGauge|18.83mm}} for [[standard gauge]] railways. The late Joe Brook Smith was the first to use of an exact scale track gauge in July 1964, when also the term “Protofour” was invented by Malcolm Cross.  The standards were later published in Model Railway News by the Model Railway Study Group in August 1966.

Just as in the prototype railway, on a model the wheel/rail interface is the fundamental aspect of reliable operation. So as well as a track gauge, P4 also specifies the wheel profile and track parameters to use, which are largely a scaled down version of real life standards with some allowances for practical manufacturing tolerances.

P4 standards have been extended to several other prototypes.  Broader than standard gauges have been modelled using P4 standards, including [[Brunel gauge|Brunel&amp;apos;s]] {{RailGauge|84in}} gauge, modelled with {{RailGauge/todo|28.08mm}} track and Irish P4, the {{RailGauge|5ft3in}}  [[Irish gauge|Irish broad gauge]] modelled in P4 in 4&amp;amp;nbsp;mm scale with {{RailGauge|21mm}}  gauge track.  Several successful models of narrow gauge prototypes with a correspondingly accurate track gauges have also been produced to P4 standards.

P4 standards are promoted worldwide by the Scalefour Society, which is based in the United Kingdom. The EM Gauge Society also provides support for modelling to P4 standards: many P4 modellers belong to both societies.  The standards can be downloaded from [http://scalefour.org/downloads/P4-standards.pdf download P4-standards] and also viewed at [http://www.clag.org.uk/p4standards.html P4 standards]

The P4 standards include options with reduced tolerances and an increased back-to-back measurement that are an exact scaling down of prototype dimensions, and which are referred to as S4 standards.  These are chosen by railway modellers who wish to avoid the minor compromises designed into P4 standards.

==See also==
* [[Model railway scales]]
* [[Rail transport modelling scales]]

==External links==
* [http://www.scalefour.org Scalefour Society, supporting modelling to P4 and S4 standards]
* [http://www.emgs.org EM Gauge Society, supporting modelling to both EM and P4 standards]
* [http://www.clag.org.uk CLAG - a group of finescale modellers based around London, England interested in building visually accurate working scale models in 4mm scale {{RailGauge|18.83mm}} gauge]
* [http://website.lineone.net/%7Esjohnson40/]

[[Category:4mm scale]]


{{model-rail-stub}}&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
