<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Appellate jurisdiction"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Appellate jurisdiction" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Globalize|date=July 2012}}

&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Appellate jurisdiction&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is the power of a court to review decisions and change outcomes of decisions of lower courts. Most appellate jurisdiction is legislatively created, and may consist of appeals by leave of the appellate court or by right. Depending on the type of case and the decision below, appellate review primarily consists of: an entirely new hearing (a non trial de novo); a hearing where the appellate court gives deference to factual findings of the lower court; or review of particular legal rulings made by the lower court (an appeal on the record).

==Courts of the United States==

Under [[Article Three of the United States Constitution]], the judicial power of the United States is vested in the [[Supreme Court of the United States]] and the inferior courts established by law. The [[Federal Rules of Appellate Procedure]] govern appellate proceedings.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;[http://www.uscourts.gov/rules/appel2007.pdf Federal Rules of Appellate Procedure]&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

== Standard of review ==
Under its standard of review, an appellate court decides the extent of the deference it would give to the lower court&amp;apos;s decision, based on whether the appeal was one of fact or one of law.

In reviewing an issue of fact, an appellate court ordinarily gives deference to the trial court&amp;apos;s findings. It is the duty of trial judges or [[jury|juries]] to find facts, view the evidence firsthand, and observe witness testimony.  When reviewing lower decisions on an issue of fact, courts of appeal generally look for &amp;quot;clear error.&amp;quot; The appellate court reviews issues of law de novo (anew, no deference) and may reverse or modify the lower court&amp;apos;s decision if the appellate court believes the lower court misapplied the facts or the law. An appellate court may also review the lower judge&amp;apos;s discretionary decisions, such as whether the judge properly granted a new trial or disallowed evidence.  The lower court&amp;apos;s decision is only changed in cases of an &amp;quot;abuse of discretion&amp;quot;. This standard tends to be even more deferential than the &amp;quot;clear error&amp;quot; standard.  Before hearing any case, the Court must have jurisdiction to consider the appeal.

== See also ==
* [[Original jurisdiction]]
* [[Court of last resort]]
* [[Court of first instance]]
* [[Judicial review]]
* [[Exclusive jurisdiction]]
* [[Concurrent jurisdiction]]

==Notes==
{{reflist}}

== References ==
*United States Constitution, Article III (1783).  [http://www.law.cornell.edu/constitution/constitution.articleiii.html]

{{UnitedStatesCode|28|1291}}:

:The courts of appeals  (other than the [[United States Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit]]) can have jurisdiction of appeals from all last decisions of the  courts of the [[United States of America]], the [[District Court of Guam]], and the [[District Court of the Virgin Islands]], except where a direct review may be had in the Supreme Courts. The jurisdiction of the United States Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit shall be limited to the jurisdiction described in sections 1292 (c) and (d) and 1295 of this title.
*[http://www.uscourts.gov/about.html U.S. Courts website]

Mandatory appellate jurisdictions must hear all properly filed appeals.
Discretionary appellate jurisdictions may pick and choose which cases are to be reviewed again and again.

[[Category:Appellate review]]
[[Category:Jurisdiction]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
