<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Thomas Coram Foundation for Children"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Thomas Coram Foundation for Children" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;[[File:Foundling Museum.jpg|thumb|right|The former headquarters of the Thomas Coram Foundation for Children in Brunswick Square. Above the door is a bust of the charity&amp;apos;s founder.]]

The &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Thomas Coram Foundation for Children&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is a large children&amp;apos;s [[charitable organization|charity]] in [[London]] which uses the working name &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Coram&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (formerly &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Coram Family&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;).&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;{{EW charity|312278|Thomas Coram Foundation for Children (formerly Foundling Hospital)}}&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

It is one of [[England]]&amp;apos;s oldest children&amp;apos;s charities, established by royal charter in 1739 as the [[Foundling Hospital]].

==Activities==
The headquarters of the charity are at Mecklenburgh Square in London. It works with children separated from their parents, supports vulnerable families, and lobbies on policy and practice issues in childcare through its various services, such as Adoption, Housing and Support (formerly Leaving Care Services and Creative Therapies), and the Parents&amp;apos; Centre (which was a pilot project for Sure Start).

&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Coram Life Education&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is the largest health education program for children in the UK, with a fleet of nearly 100 mobile classrooms that visit 4,000 schools around the country.

Coram [[Children&amp;apos;s Legal Centre]] provides the free national Child Law Advice Line, a 24-hours service covering education, immigration and family law issues. It also provides extensive international consultancy.

==Officers==
The Chief Executive of Coram since 2007 is Dr Carol Homden. Its Chair of Board of Trustees is Edward Hartill OBE, former City Surveyor of the City of London Corporation and its President is Sir Michael Bear.

==History==
{{main|Foundling Hospital}}

The [[Foundling Hospital]] was begun by the philanthropic sea captain [[Thomas Coram]], who was appalled to see abandoned babies and children starving and dying in the streets of London. In 1742–1745 a building was erected north of [[Lamb&amp;apos;s Conduit Street]] in [[Bloomsbury]]. Boys were housed in the West Wing of the new home. The East Wing was built in 1752 to house girls.

Popular artists of the 18th century became patrons and governors of the [[Foundling Hospital]] and donated some of their work to the foundation. The art collection contains works by [[William Hogarth]], [[Thomas Gainsborough]] and Sir [[Joshua Reynolds]], including a full-length portrait of [[Thomas Coram]] himself, along with musical scores by [[Handel]] including a fair copy of [[The Messiah|&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Messiah&amp;apos;&amp;apos;]] bequeathed in his will.

The Foundling Hospital became fashionable as a cause, a gallery and a concert hall. Governors of the hospital decided in 1926 to realise the value of the London site (it was sold for £2 million) and to build a new hospital on the [[Ashlyns School|Ashlyns]] site at [[Berkhamsted]]. The children were sent to temporary premises in [[Redhill, Surrey|Redhill]] until 1935 when the Georgian-style buildings in Berkhamsted were ready for occupation.

[[Hertfordshire]] County Council took responsibility for the school part of the hospital when it became Ashlyns School in 1951. Boarders at The Thomas Coram Foundation for Children were &amp;apos;phased out&amp;apos; by 1955, when the Foundation sold the buildings to the [[County Council]].

==Foundling Museum==
{{main|Foundling Museum}}
The historic collections of the Foundling Hospital were moved in the 1920s to [[Brunswick Square]], London, where a museum was established. In 1998 the building and collections were formally constituted as a separate charity, the [[Foundling Museum]].&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;{{EW charity|1071167|The Foundling Museum}}&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

==See also==
*[[List of organisations with a British royal charter]]

==References==
{{reflist}}

==External links==
*[http://www.coram.org.uk Coram]
*[http://www.foundlingmuseum.org.uk The Foundling Museum]
*[http://www.oca1947.co.uk Old Coram Association]

{{DEFAULTSORT:Thomas Coram Foundation For Children}}


[[Category:Organizations established in 1739]]
[[Category:Charities based in London]]
[[Category:Children&amp;apos;s charities based in England]]
[[Category:1739 establishments in England]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
