<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Zagreb Film"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Zagreb Film" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;[[File:Zagreb film ploča.jpg|thumb|Zagreb Film]]
&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Zagreb Film&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is a [[Croatia]]n [[film]]-producing company from [[Zagreb]], founded in 1953. They have produced hundreds of [[animated film]]s, [[documentaries]], [[television commercial]]s, [[educational film]]s and several [[feature film]]s.

Their probably most famous product was the [[cartoon]] series &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Professor Balthazar]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos; ({{lang-hr|Profesor Baltazar}}), created by [[Zlatko Grgić]], about an amusing professor who solved various imaginative problems. Another popular cartoon of theirs was &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Inspector Mask]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos; ({{lang|hr|&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Inspektor Maska&amp;apos;&amp;apos;}}).

Zagreb Film was founded in 1953 with the main profile of an animated films production company. Since then, more than 600 animated films, 14 feature films, about 600 documentaries and 800 commercials as well as 600 educational films were produced in this studio.  Also we have to mention 30,000 meters of archive material that was shot about the city of Zagreb and another 30 hours of material was shot on a DVCAM. The company operates on three locations; one with ateliers for artists, shooting equipment, small theatre and one with film warehouse, video multiplication room and administration. The third location is used for commercial purposes.  During all these years, Zagreb Film received more than 400 awards on Festivals all over the world. Among them is the Academy Award - Oscar for the best animated short film in 1962. [[Dušan Vukotić]] had become the first non-American author to win the Oscar award for &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Ersatz (film)|Ersatz]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos;. Wealth of genres and different styles that were growing in Zagreb was the reason for Georges Sadoul, the French film theorist, critic and historian to coin the term «Zagreb school of animation», what became the trademark for top grade and innovative animated films made in Zagreb.  Besides artistic films Zagreb film produced films and TV series for children like &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Inspector Mask]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Professor Balthazar]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[The Little Flying Bears]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Maxi Cat]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos;. Most of these films were distributed internationally. The biggest global success was with the famous character of Professor Balthazar.
http://www.zagrebfilm.hr/onama_e.asp

==Compilations of Zagreb animation==
* The Best of Zagreb Film: Be Careful What You Wish For/The Classic Collection (2000) [http://www.amazon.com/dp/630583671X/]

==See also==
*[[Zagreb school of animated films]]

[[Category:Film production companies of Croatia]]
[[Category:Companies based in Zagreb]]
[[Category:Croatian animation]]
[[Category:Media in Zagreb]]

{{Film-company-stub}}
{{Croatia-stub}}
{{Euro-company-stub}}&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
