<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Scottish Labour Party (1976)"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Scottish Labour Party (1976)" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{PoliticsScotland}}

The &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Scottish Labour Party&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (SLP) was formed on January 18, 1976, as a breakaway from the UK [[Labour Party (UK)|Labour Party]], by members disaffected with the then Labour Government&amp;apos;s failure to secure a devolved [[Scottish Assembly]], as well as with its social and economic agenda. The formation of the SLP was led by [[Jim Sillars]], then MP for [[South Ayrshire (UK Parliament constituency)|South Ayrshire]], [[John Robertson (Scottish Labour Party founder)|John Robertson]], then MP for [[Paisley (UK Parliament constituency)|Paisley]] and [[Alex Neil (politician)|Alex Neil]], the UK Labour Party&amp;apos;s senior Scottish researcher.

The split came just before the resignation of [[Harold Wilson]] as prime minister and party leader and the election of [[James Callaghan]] as his successor.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;[http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/special/politics97/background/pastelec/ge79.shtml]&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

By 1979 the Scottish Labour Party had lost its seats in the House of Commons, and in 1981 it was formally disbanded.

Almost immediately the SLP became the focus for [[entryism]] from the [[International Marxist Group]] (IMG), and at the party&amp;apos;s first congress in October 1976 the IMG was expelled, along with a number of branches whose members were not associated with the IMG.  According to Henry Drucker&amp;apos;s account, the IMG&amp;apos;s role was rather limited; Sillars used this as an excuse for purging anyone he did not see entirely eye-to-eye with or represented a significant threat to his leadership.

The expellees formed a rival Scottish Labour Party (Democratic Wing), and this in turn later renamed itself the Scottish Socialist League (SSL). Gradually, those members of the SSL who had not been associated with the IMG drifted out, and the SSL was reabsorbed into the [[Trotskyism|Trotskyist]] [[Reunified Fourth International|Fourth International]].

The SLP had little electoral success, winning only three council seats at the [[Scottish District local elections, 1977|1977 local elections]]. It polled only 583 votes in the [[Glasgow Garscadden by-election, 1978|Garscadden by-election in 1978]]. At the [[1979 UK general election]], the SLP fought three seats, including Sillars&amp;apos; attempt at being re-elected (Robertson chose to step down). Sillars came close to retaining his seat in South Ayrshire, but this was clearly a personal vote built up over the years he had already served as an MP, as the other two candidates polled poorly indeed.

This failure prompted the SLP to disband; and members either fell out of active politics, re-joined the Labour Party, or chose to join the [[Scottish National Party]] (SNP), which both Sillars and Neil did, with both rising to high office in the SNP.

The SLP adventure is generally looked upon as an ambitious failure, but Sillars has himself put this down to a lack of planning before the decision to launch the party. Unlike the SLP, the [[Social Democratic Party (UK)|Social Democratic Party]] (SDP) meticulously planned their breakaway from the Labour Party, and were much more successful. Sillars has claimed that the SLP did at least provide a forerunner to the SNP&amp;apos;s later dialogue with the left.

The SLP had a number of members who would later go on to achieve a name for themselves as a mainstream Labour politician, including [[John McAllion]] who became MP and then MSP for [[Dundee East (UK Parliament constituency)|Dundee East]], [[Maria Fyfe]] one time MP for [[Glasgow Maryhill (UK Parliament constituency)|Glasgow Maryhill]], [[Colin Boyd, Baron Boyd of Duncansby|Colin Boyd]], the former [[Lord Advocate]], and [[Charlie Gordon]], the former MSP for [[Glasgow Cathcart (Scottish Parliament constituency)|Glasgow Cathcart]]. These individuals chose to join (or in some cases re-join) the Labour Party rather than follow Sillars into the SNP.

==See also==
*[[Scottish Workers Republican Party]]

==References==

&amp;lt;references /&amp;gt;
*H.M.Drucker: &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Breakaway: The Scottish Labour Party&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, Edinburgh: EUSPB (1977)

[[Category:Political parties established in 1976]]
[[Category:International Marxist Group]]
[[Category:Home rule in the United Kingdom]]
[[Category:Defunct political parties in Scotland|Labour Party, Scottish]]
[[Category:Labour Party (UK) breakaway groups]]
[[Category:Scottish National Party]]
[[Category:1976 establishments in Scotland]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
