<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="X-Alfonso"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="X-Alfonso" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Infobox musical artist &amp;lt;!-- See Wikipedia:WikiProject_Musicians --&amp;gt;
| name                = X Alfonso
| image                 = X-alfonso_cuba.jpg
| caption            = X Alfonso.
| image_size            = 200
| background          = group_or_band
| alias               =
| origin              = [[Havana]], [[Cuba]]
| genre               = [[Fusion (music)|Fusión]]&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;[[hip hop music|Hip hop]]&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;[[Son (music)|Son Cubano]]&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;[[Afro-rock]]
| years_active        = 1990–present
| label               =
| associated_acts     =
| website                 =
| current_members     =
| past_members        =
| notable_instruments =
}}

&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;X-Alfonso&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (born c. 1974 as Equis Alfonso) is a Cuban [[hip hop music|hip hop]] and [[afro-rock]] musician, who played with [[Audioslave]] in a concert in Havana on May 7, 2005 in &amp;quot;Tribuna Anti-imperialista&amp;quot;.

==Life and career==
&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;X Alfonso&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; has been playing music since he was seven years old, “ When I was around 16 or 17, I started playing [[jazz]] and [[fusion music]], working with troubadours and putting together my own arrangements and recordings.” X Alfonso started his career with a group called [[Estado de Animo]] while he was still at the music school. From early 1990s, when he graduated, he joined the Cuban group [[Síntesis]] led by his parents [[Carlos Alfonso]] and [[Ele Valdès]], as singer and composer or co-composer.
“I arrived just as the group’s keyboard player was leaving, so I started off playing keyboards. Then I found myself on percussion and vocals. That’s how I learned to play the instruments, through necessity.”
The group started as a vocal quartet, then turned to symphonic rock before going on to explore a fusion between [[Afro-Cuban music]]—Cuban roots—and [[contemporary music]].
&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;X Alfonso&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; explains: “my music has always revolved around roots and exploration. That’s what I’m always trying to convey; I draw on folklore, on Cuba.” X Alfonso made six records with “Síntesis” and has released four records of his own and is now working on releasing his fifth. X Alfonso started his solo career in 1998. His first record “[[Mundo Real]]” in 2000 is a mix of jazz and [[Fusion (music)|fusion]]. The second “[[X moré]]” is more hip-hop, based on a blend of Big Band hits from the forties and the fifties. The third “[[Delirium Tremens]]” is more progressive, combining [[African drums]], [[symphonic orchestra]] and [[flamenco]]. The fourth, “[[Civilización]]”, pulls together material from the first three records, and the fifth is a new record: “I’m currently working on “[[Revoluxion]]” (with an X). “Revoluxion” reflects a different style and another aspect of Cuban folklore, [[rumba]], drawing on Afro-Cuban culture through a mix of rumba and [[funk]], which is what I’m into now.”

==Musical Influence==
X Alfonso finds that today’s new Cuban generation is made of fusion, like his music,  “Cubans today are a mix of Spanish, African, English, French, Chinese... A melting pot that has a lot to offer to the pages of history.” And it’s this culture that X Alfonso tries to show in his music. “The people who come to see me are rappers, rockers, salseros, young, old.... I have a really broad audience because of the range of music I cover. I try to reflect all of this as a musician, drawing on different rhythms, melodies and harmonies. I’m always amazed to find myself exploring one area then something completely different—total opposites—and when I mix the two together it seems totally normal.”

What interests X Alfonso about Cuba is the people, the people in the streets and the generations of young artists putting their art out there. “I’m basically working with street talent, and I try to show that Havana and Cuba have a whole lot to offer, like every country. It goes far beyond a simple performance.”

==Discography==
*[[Mundo Real (album)|Mundo Real]] (2000)
*[[X Moré (album)|X Moré]] (2001)
*[[Civilización (album)|Civilización]] (2005)
*Revoluxion (2007)
*Reverse (2011)

==External links==
*http://www.worldmusiccentral.org/artists/artist_page.php?id=815
*http://www.imdb.com/name/nm1309263/
*http://www.stageplanet.net
*http://www.havana-cultura.com/html/en/cuban-music/x-alfonso/afro-cuban-music.html

[[Category:Cuban musicians]]
[[Category:Cuban people of African descent]]
[[Category:1970s births]]
[[Category:Living people]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
