<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Kysuce"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Kysuce" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;[[Image:Velka raca.jpg|thumb|right|Kysuce region around Veľká Rača]]

&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Kysuce&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is a traditional informal name of a region in north-western [[Slovakia]], situated around the [[Kysuca]] river and bordering the [[Orava region]] in the east and the [[Czech Republic]] in the west. It consists of two [[Districts of Slovakia|districts]], [[Čadca District|Čadca]] and [[Kysucké Nové Mesto District|Kysucké Nové Mesto]]. The region is surrounded by the numerous mountain ranges, for example [[Javorníky]] in the west, or the [[Moravian-Silesian Beskids]] in the north. The highest hill is [[Veľká Rača]] (1236 m). In the past, Kysuce region was part of the [[Trenčín county]].

==Settlement==

The oldest known settlement in the Kysuce region is Kysucké Nové Mesto, which was first mentioned in 1321 as a toll collecting place, which was part of a trade route between Žilina and Těšín via [[Jablunkov Pass]], but otherwise the region was relatively uninhabitated.

Kysuce region began to be settled in the 16th and 17th centuries at the time of Valach colonization. The new inhabitants were mostly Slovaks, from foreign settlers Rusyns, Poles and Romanians, but also Czechs and Germans. Many towns were established first around this time, for example Čadca in 1572. Many people live in small villages or lone cottages in the mountains (which are called &amp;apos;&amp;apos;kopanice&amp;apos;&amp;apos;). Today main towns in the Kysuce region are [[Kysucké Nové Mesto]], [[Čadca]] and [[Turzovka]].

==Climate==
[[Image:Hluz-U34_901.jpg-skanzen.jpg|thumb|right|Steam locomotive on the switchback railway, Nová Bystrica, part Vychylovka]]

Like the neighboring Orava region, Kysuce region has long winters and long-lasting snow cover, and cold and rainy weather in general, what forces local people to heat their homes from September/October until May, and during winter months, many of the villages and cottages are difficult to access.

==Economy==
[[Image:Kaplnka zo Zborova nad Bystricou.jpg|thumb|right|Chapel from the village [[Zborov nad Bystricou]], now located in the open-air museum of Kysuce village]]
Traditionally, Kysuce is considered to be one of the poorest regions in Slovakia. Inhabitants of Kysuce have to commute for work elsewhere, for example to the coal mines in the Ostrava Region in the [[Czech Republic]], as the region has little industry, particularly today. The worst situation was in the 1990s when many factories were shut down or reduced. However, the regional economy is now recovering and growing thanks to the good ski and cross-country conditions and the &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Snow Paradise&amp;apos;&amp;apos; center in Veľká Rača-Oščadnica is one of the most developed ski resorts in Slovakia. There are also many other tourist attractions available, for example [[The Historical Logging Switchback Railway in Vychylovka|the switchback railway]] near [[Nová Bystrica]], or museum of the Kysuce village also near Nová Bystrica, which was created in 1974 primarily for the purpose of saving buildings from the villages inundated by the Nová Bystrica reservoir.

==Transport==
The region is located at the main road and railway between [[Žilina]] and [[Ostrava]], as well to [[Poland]]. The first railroad that connected Kysuce to the other parts of Austria-Hungary was built in 1871 as part of the [[Košice-Bohumín Railway]]. Currently, there is only one short part of the [[Motorway D3 (Slovakia)|D3 motorway]] between [[Oščadnica]] and [[Čadca]]. Connection to Orava is currently under construction and should be opened in 2008. It should replace the original road, which was inundated along with the construction of Nová Bystrica reservoir, leaving 11 km gap between the two ends of formerly compact road.

==External links==
* [http://www.e-kysuce.sk/ Official site of the Kysuce region] {{sk icon}}
* [http://www.kysuckemuzeum.sk/index.php Kysucké múzeum Čadca (includes museum of the Kysuce village and switchback railway)] {{sk icon}}

{{Cadca District}}
{{Kysucke Nove Mesto District}}

{{coord missing|Slovakia}}

[[Category:Traditional regions of Slovakia]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
