<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Underwurlde"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Underwurlde" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Infobox VG
|title = Underwurlde
|image = [[Image:Underwurlde title.gif|Underwurlde]]
|caption = Title screen
|developer = [[Tim and Chris Stamper]]
|publisher = [[Ultimate Play The Game]]
|designer =
|engine =
|released = [[1984 in video gaming|1984]]
|genre = [[Arcade adventure]]; [[Maze]]; [[Platform game|Platform]]
|modes = [[Single player]]
|ratings = N/A
|platforms = [[ZX Spectrum]]&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;[[Commodore 64]]
|media = [[Compact audio cassette|Cassette]]
|requirements = 48K [[RAM]] (Spectrum)
}}

&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Underwurlde&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is a [[video game]] for the [[ZX Spectrum]] and [[Commodore 64]] developed and released by [[Ultimate Play The Game]] in 1984.  The game is the second in the [[Sabre Man|Sabreman]] series, following on from his adventures in &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Sabre Wulf]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos;.  The format of the game is a 2D side view [[flip-screen]] platform game.  The aim is to escape from the &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Underwurlde&amp;apos;&amp;apos; via one of the three exits, to go to either &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Knight Lore]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Pentagram (video game)|Pentagram]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos; or &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Mire Mare]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos;.

==Plot==
A traveller visits the &amp;quot;Underwurlde&amp;quot;, but finds himself trapped when previously dormant creatures and carnivorous plants wake in the hope of a meal. The traveller must travel farther down into the Underwurlde to confront the ultimate evil and make his escape.

==Gameplay==
[[Image:Underwurlde 2.gif|left|thumb|256px|A typical in-game screenshot]]
Again taking on the role of Sabreman, the player must navigate a flip-screen maze (597 screens) that encompasses a [[castle]] and the large system of [[cave]]rns beneath it.  Unlike the maze in &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Sabre Wulf]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, which is viewed from above, rooms here are viewed from the side, and play takes the form of a [[platform game]].  Sabreman must make his way through the maze to one of three exits (one for each of the [[sequel]]s to &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Underwurlde&amp;apos;&amp;apos;).  To get to the three exits, three different guardians must be defeated, but the guardians are vulnerable to different weapons hidden in the maze. Each cavern has one guardian, who rests beneath an enormous [[stalactite]], requiring that the monster be destroyed in order to pass. The location of all the weapons, other than the slingshot (which does not affect any guardians) is different each time, out of a variety of places.

Along the way, Sabreman is attacked by a range of enemies from winged [[harpy|harpies]] to floating [[jellyfish]].  Oddly bereft of his [[trademark]] [[sabre]], Sabreman can fend off these adversaries with the weapons he collects on his journey (a [[slingshot]] in the screenshots below).  Contact with enemies does not directly cause damage, their aim instead is to cause fatal falls by knocking the player off platforms. After one of the first two guardians is destroyed (the third one cannot be accessed except through passing the second one), two more enemies are added, one that resembles a seal and otherwise acts like the starting enemies, and the eagle, which has the added ability of picking up Sabreman, and possibly dropping him from an enormous height. Although Sabreman is tough enough to survive short drops, the caverns are full of chasms deep enough for a lethal fall.  However, there is one item, the blue gem, that makes him temporarily invincible. These may only be found on ledges in vertical shafts in the caves. The only other item found besides gems and weapons are the extra lives, which are in fixed locations.

Climbing in and out of these pits can be achieved in several ways.  Firstly, Sabreman can make rather athletic bounds between platforms.  Alternatively, in the caverns he can make use of conveniently placed ropes to safely ascend or descend, but there is a risk of falling stalactites that will fall down the middle of the shaft, and even touching this obstacle when not affected by the Gem is instantly fatal.  Also, in some parts of the maze, [[liquid bubble|bubble]]s of [[volcano|volcanic]] [[gas]] can carry Sabreman up the chasms.

==Reception==
The ZX Spectrum version was voted the 17th best game of all time in a special issue of &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Your Sinclair]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos; magazine in 2004.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;{{cite journal|title=Top 50 Games of All Time|journal=Your Sinclair|year=2004|month=November|publisher=Imagine Publishing}}&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

==References==
{{reflist}}

==External links==
* [http://www.ultimate-wurlde.com/games/underwurldeintro.shtml &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Underwurlde&amp;apos;&amp;apos;] at Ultimate Wurlde
* {{WoS game|id=0009446}}
* [http://www.crashonline.org.uk/12/underw.htm &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Underwurlde&amp;apos;&amp;apos; review] at [[CRASH (magazine)|&amp;apos;&amp;apos;CRASH&amp;apos;&amp;apos; magazine]]
* [http://video.google.com/videoplay?docid=-2346406581630684461 A walkthrough video of &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Underwurlde&amp;apos;&amp;apos; on the ZX Spectrum]
*{{dmoz|Games/Video_Games/Action/S/Sabre_Man_Series/Underwurlde}}
* [http://www.retrogaminghistory.com/home/2670-underwurlde.html &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Underwurlde&amp;apos;&amp;apos; review at Retrogaming History]{{dead link|date=May 2010}}

{{Ultimate Play The Game series}}

[[Category:1984 video games]]
[[Category:Commodore 64 games]]
[[Category:Rareware games]]
[[Category:ZX Spectrum games]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
