<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Dave Hollins: Space Cadet"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Dave Hollins: Space Cadet" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Use dmy dates|date=November 2012}}
{{Unreferenced stub|auto=yes|date=December 2009}}

&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Dave Hollins: Space Cadet&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; was a series of five sketches on the [[BBC Radio 4]] series &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Son of Cliché]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, produced by [[Rob Grant]] and [[Doug Naylor]]. The main characters were Dave Hollins (voiced by [[Nick Wilton]]) and the computer Hab (voiced by [[Chris Barrie]]). The popular BBC sci-fiction comedy television show &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Red Dwarf]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos; was based on these radio sketches.

The first sketch was the only one to appear in &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Son of Cliché&amp;apos;s&amp;apos;&amp;apos; first series, and was apparently intended to be a one-off sketch only. Hab wasn&amp;apos;t in this sketch, and Dave was on a different ship to the one he is on in the others (Psion IV, rather than Melissa V). In this sketch Dave meets some weird aliens and ends up being killed at the end by decapitation (apparently, exchanging heads for an hour is a polite greeting for these aliens).

The other four sketches were in the second series, with a new ship, Dave somehow alive once more and with the computer Hab. In these sketches Dave is 7 trillion years from Earth (or 300 years, as it was changed to later on), having placed himself in suspended animation when the rest of the crew were devoured by a chameleonic monster (presumably similar to [[Red Dwarf]]&amp;apos;s [[Red Dwarf characters#The Polymorph|Polymorph]]). In the fourth sketch Dave does make it back to Earth, but leaves again after he finds that fruit flies are now the dominant species (over beetles and P.E. teachers).

When Grant and Naylor started planning to make a TV series based on one of the sketches from &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Son of Cliché&amp;apos;&amp;apos; they chose to base it on Dave Hollins: Space Cadet (having considered the other recurring sketches &amp;quot;Asso - Spanish Detective&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Captain Invisible and the See-Thru Kid&amp;quot;). The 7 trillion year figure was first changed to 7 billion years and then to 3 million and the characters of [[Arnold Rimmer]] and [[Cat (Red Dwarf)|the Cat]] were created. The name Dave Hollins was changed to [[Dave Lister (Red Dwarf)|Dave Lister]] when a football player called Dave Hollins became well-known, and Hab was replaced by [[Holly (Red Dwarf)|Holly]].

One of the voice actors from &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Son of Cliché&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, Chris Barrie went on to portray Arnold Rimmer in the &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Red Dwarf&amp;apos;&amp;apos; TV series.

Episodes of Dave Hollins can be found on the 2 disc Red Dwarf DVD sets starting with series 5 and ending with series 8.

{{Red Dwarf}}

{{Grant Naylor}}

[[Category:Red Dwarf]]


{{Sci-fi-stub}}
{{UK-radio-show-stub}}&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
