<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Chosen-plaintext attack"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Chosen-plaintext attack" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Merge from|Gardening (cryptanalysis)|date=August 2010}}
{{Refimprove|date=January 2013}}

A &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;chosen-plaintext attack&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;CPA&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;) is an [[attack model]] for [[cryptanalysis]] which presumes that the attacker has the capability to choose arbitrary [[plaintext]]s to be encrypted and obtain the corresponding [[ciphertext]]s.&amp;lt;ref name=&amp;quot;RASE&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Ross Anderson, &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Security Engineering: A Guide to Building Dependable Distributed Systems&amp;apos;&amp;apos;. The first edition (2001): http://www.cl.cam.ac.uk/~rja14/book.html&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt; The goal of the attack is to gain some further information which reduces the security of the encryption scheme.  In the worst case, a chosen-plaintext attack could reveal the scheme&amp;apos;s secret [[key (cryptography)|key]]. For some chosen-plaintext attacks, only a small part of the plaintext needs to be chosen by the attacker: such attacks are known as &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;plaintext injection&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; attacks.

This appears, at first glance, to be an unrealistic model; it would certainly be unlikely that an attacker could persuade a human cryptographer to encrypt large amounts of plaintexts of the attacker&amp;apos;s choosing. Modern cryptography, on the other hand, is implemented in software or hardware and is used for a diverse range of applications; for many cases, a chosen-plaintext attack is often very feasible.  Chosen-plaintext attacks become extremely important in the context of [[public key cryptography]], where the encryption key is public and attackers can encrypt any plaintext they choose.

Any cipher that can prevent chosen-plaintext attacks is then also guaranteed to be secure against [[known-plaintext attack|known-plaintext]] and ciphertext-only attacks; this is a conservative approach to security.

Two forms of chosen-plaintext attack can be distinguished:

*&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Batch chosen-plaintext attack&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, where the cryptanalyst chooses all plaintexts before any of them are encrypted. This is often the meaning of an unqualified use of &amp;quot;chosen-plaintext attack&amp;quot;.
*&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Adaptive chosen-plaintext attack&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, where the cryptanalyst makes a series of interactive queries, choosing subsequent plaintexts based on the information from the previous encryptions.

A technique termed &amp;quot;[[Gardening (cryptanalysis)|Gardening]]&amp;quot; was used by Allied codebreakers in [[World War II]] who were solving messages encrypted on the [[Enigma machine]]. Gardening can be viewed as a plaintext injection attack.

==See also==
* [[Known-plaintext attack]]
* [[Chosen-ciphertext attack]]
* [[Adaptive chosen-ciphertext attack]]
* [[Related-key attack]]

==References==
{{Reflist}}

{{DEFAULTSORT:Chosen-Plaintext Attack}}
[[Category:Chosen-plaintext attacks| ]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
