<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Hanga Roa"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Hanga Roa" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{about|the main town on Easter Island|the Hangaroa zone in New Zealand|Hangaroa River}}
[[Image:Easter Island map-en.svg|thumb|left|Easter Island, map showing Hanga Roa, [[Terevaka]], [[Rano Kau]], and [[Mataveri International Airport]], as well as the main tourist attractions [[Orongo]], [[Rano Raraku]], [[Ahu Tongariki]] and [[Anakena]]]]
[[Image:Hangaroa Moais.jpg|thumb|Several Hanga Roa moai, including Ko Te Riku (with a [[pukao]] on its head). In the mid-ground is a side view of an [[Easter Island#Ahu|ahu]] with five moai. The Mataveri end of Hanga Roa is visible in the background with [[Rano Kau]] rising above it.]]

[[File:Hanga Roa Harbour.jpg|thumb|Harbour scene in Hanga Roa]]
[[File:Hanga Roa Post Office.jpg|thumb|Post office in Hanga Roa]]

&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Hanga Roa&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is the main town, harbour and capital of the [[Chile]]an province of [[Easter Island]]. It is located in the southern part of the island&amp;apos;s west coast, in the lowlands between the extinct volcanoes of [[Terevaka]] and [[Rano Kau]].

The population of 3,304 (2002 census) comprises 87 percent of the total population of the island.  For much of the twentieth century, the rest of the island was leased to the [[Williamson-Balfour Company]] and closed to the [[Rapanui]]; in 1914, the population of Hanga Roa was just 250 and the rest of the island was inhabited by large populations of sheep.

The island&amp;apos;s main avenue, Avenida Atamu Tekena (formerly Avenida Policarpo Toro), is the heart of the town. Many stores, hotels, restaurants, and the island&amp;apos;s only supermarket and pharmacy are found alongside this road. In 1998, the road was renamed after nineteenth century Rapanui hero Atamu Te Kena; it had previously been named after Captain [[Policarpo Toro]], the Chilean Naval officer who annexed Easter Island to Chile in 1888.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;Steven R Fischer The island at the end of the world. Reaktion Books 2005 ISBN 1-86189-282-9 page 248&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt; The island&amp;apos;s museum and also the [[Roman Catholic]] church, are located in the center of town. With the advent of the [[internet]] and the expansion of communication services by the Chilean government, many internet cafes and even several [[automated teller machine]]s (ATM) have appeared in recent years.

Hanga Roa has a multi-use stadium, [[Estadio de Hanga Roa]], which is the home ground of the Easter Island [[association football|football]] team.

The town has a number of hotels and guesthouses which cater for tourists who come to see the island&amp;apos;s [[World Heritage Site]]s, in particular the famous [[moai]] statues. Hanga Roa and the surrounding area have a number of impressive moai, but there are larger ones elsewhere on the island.

The actual hotel capacity is about 600 beds and the lodging offer goes from little hostels and luxury hotels. Rates range from US&amp;amp;nbsp;$60 to US$&amp;amp;nbsp;800 dollars per person.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;[http://www.letsgochile.com/locations/central-zone/pacific-islands/easter-island Easter Island article] in Letsgochile.com&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

In addition to tourism, other businesses in Hanga Roa include fishing, farming and administration (several Chilean government departments including the [[Chilean Navy]] maintain a presence on the island).

The island&amp;apos;s only airport, [[Mataveri International Airport]], is served by [[LAN (airline)|LAN Airlines]], [[Chile]]&amp;apos;s national carrier, which offers direct flights to [[Santiago, Chile|Santiago]], [[Papeete]] and [[Lima]]. It is the only commercial carrier that regularly serves the island.

As well as a small local fishing industry, the harbour has a shipping service to [[Valparaiso]], Chile.

== References ==
{{reflist}}

==See also==
{{Portal|Chile}}
* [[List of towns in Chile]]

{{List of Oceanian capitals by region}}

{{coord|27|09|S|109|26|W|region:CL_type:city(3300)|display=title}}

[[Category:Hanga Roa| ]]
[[Category:Capitals of Chilean provinces]]
[[Category:Communes of Chile]]
[[Category:Geography of Easter Island]]
[[Category:Port settlements in Chile]]
[[Category:Populated places in Isla de Pascua Province]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
