<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="The Redhead from Wyoming"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="The Redhead from Wyoming" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Infobox Film
| name           = The Redhead from Wyoming
| director       = [[Lee Sholem]]
| image          = The Redhead from Wyoming FilmPoster.jpeg
| caption        = Theatrical poster
| border         = yes
| producer       = Leonard Goldstein
| writer         = {{plainlist|
*[[Polly James]]
*Herb Meadow
}}
| starring       = {{plainlist|
*[[Maureen O&amp;apos;Hara]]
*[[Alex Nicol]]
}}
| music          = [[Herman Stein]]
| cinematography = David M. Walsh
| editing        = Milton Carruth
| distributor    = [[Universal Studios]]
| released       = {{film date|1953|01|08}}
| runtime        = 81 minutes
| language       = English
| gross          = $1.1 million (US)&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;&amp;apos;The Top Box Office Hits of 1953&amp;apos;, &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Variety&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, January 13, 1954&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;
}}

&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;The Redhead from Wyoming&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is a 1953 American [[Western (genre)|Western]] drama film produced by Leonard Goldstein and directed by [[Lee Sholem]]. It stars [[Maureen O&amp;apos;Hara]] as a saloon proprietress who becomes embroiled in a cattle war and [[Alex Nicol]] as the sheriff who tries to prevent it. The supporting cast includes [[William Bishop]] as a politician who provokes the war and [[Alexander Scourby]] as a prominent cattle rancher.

==Cast==
*[[Maureen O&amp;apos;Hara]] as Kate Maxwell, a stage performer with a checkered history in Texas
*[[Alex Nicol]] as Sheriff Stan Blaine, a drifter whose family was killed in a Texas cattle war when he was a boy
*[[William Bishop (actor)|William Bishop]] as Jim Averell, a scheming politician who once betrayed Kate in Texas
*[[Robert Strauss (actor)|Robert Strauss]] as &amp;quot;Knuckles&amp;quot; Hogan, Kate&amp;apos;s bodyguard
*[[Alexander Scourby]] as Reece Duncan, an established cattle rancher
*[[Gregg Palmer]] as Hal Jessup (as Palmer Lee), a young settler
*[[Jack Kelly (actor)|Jack Kelly]] as Sandy
*[[Jeanne Cooper]] as Myra, a showgirl, Hal&amp;apos;s sweetheart
*[[Dennis Weaver]] as Matt Jessup, a settler
*[[Stacy Harris (actor)|Stacy Harris]] as Chet Jones

==Plot==
The film begins with scenes of life in [[Wyoming Territory]], where new settlers join the cattle business by finding stray, unbranded cattle, called &amp;quot;mavericks&amp;quot;, on public land. The narrator explains that established ranchers use the so-called &amp;quot;maverick law&amp;quot; against the settlers, while &amp;quot;sharp-witted men&amp;quot; take advantage of the resulting conflict. After this introduction, Jim Averell ([[William Bishop|Bishop]]) is shown exhorting settlers to elect him governor to defend them against cattle barons such as Reece Duncan ([[Alexander Scourby|Scourby]]). When Averell&amp;apos;s speech is over, the famous stage performer Kate Maxwell ([[Maureen O&amp;apos;Hara|O&amp;apos;Hara]]) arrives with a group of showgirls. Averell has arranged for Kate to operate both a cattle-buying business and a saloon. Duncan warns Kate that he will kill anyone caught stealing cattle on his land, and Sheriff Stan Blaine ([[Alex Nicol|Nicol]]) warns her of an impending war over the cattle business.

The tension between Duncan and the settlers rises as the settlers search for mavericks on Duncan&amp;apos;s land and outlaws hired by Averell steal Duncan&amp;apos;s cattle. Averell designed the &amp;quot;K-M&amp;quot; brand for Kate&amp;apos;s cattle business in such a way that her branding iron completely covers Duncan&amp;apos;s &amp;quot;bar double check&amp;quot; brand when applied directly over it. When Averell explains this trick to Kate, he makes it clear to her that she will be hanged as a rustler if she informs the authorities, and Duncan refuses her offer to support him against Averell.

Meanwhile, unknown gunfighters assemble in the nearby hills, and one of them shoots a settler. After Duncan attempts to stop a cattle roundup organized by Averell and the settlers, one of his men is killed, with Kate&amp;apos;s branding iron left near the body. To further increase the tension, Averell offers Duncan his support against the settlers immediately after inciting their anger against Duncan. Averell&amp;apos;s plan is to ignite a cattle war and promote his own political career by providing leadership once the war has begun.

However, Blaine discovers Averell&amp;apos;s plan. After Blaine and Kate have explained it to their men, they stage a fake war, and Blaine forces Averell to signal his men. When the outlaws ride into town, they begin a gunfight against both Duncan&amp;apos;s men and the settlers. After Averell shoots Blaine, Kate catches him stealing money from the saloon, and when he tries to shoot her, she and Blaine kill him. After the fight, Blaine prepares to leave town, but Kate persuades him to stay with her. The film ends as they ride away to inspect some farmland for a new home.

== References ==
{{reflist}}

== External links ==
{{imdb title|id=45077}}

{{DEFAULTSORT:Redhed from Wyoming, The}}
[[Category:1953 films]]
[[Category:American films]]
[[Category:English-language films]]
[[Category:Films set in Wyoming]]
[[Category:1950s Western (genre) films]]
[[Category:Films directed by Lee Sholem]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
