<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Yaba, Lagos"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Yaba, Lagos" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Other uses|Yaba (disambiguation)}}
[[Image:2011 Yaba Lagos Nigeria by Louisven Panoramio 5375583542.jpg|thumb|right|Yaba, Lagos, Nigeria, 2011]]
&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Yaba&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is a suburb of [[Lagos]], [[Nigeria]]. Institutions of higher learning in the area include [[Queen&amp;apos;s College Lagos|Queen&amp;apos;s College]], the [[Nigerian Institute of Medical Research]], the [[Yaba College of Technology]], [[Igbobi College]], the [[University of Lagos]], the Federal School Science and Technical College, and the Federal College of Education.
Yaba has one of the busiest market sites in Lagos, known as Tejuosho Market, Nigeria.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;http://www.yabatech.edu.ng&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

==See also==
* [[Yaba monkey tumor virus]]
Yaba Local council development area as it is today has its secretariat at 198, Herbert Macaulay Street, Yaba. It was carved out of the old Lagos Mainland local government which was created in 1977 as a separate Local government following the national reform of Local government in September 1976. Lagos Mainland carved out of Lagos city council which administered the Lagos Metropolitan city; this consists of Lagos Island and Lagos Mainland. So with the creation of three more Local government on the 27th August 1991, the former lagos mainland was re-constituted with Surulere carved out of it.

Yaba Local council Development area as one of the Thirty Seven (37) newly created Local council Development areas was created out of Lagos Mainland by the administration of Senator Bola Ahmed Tinubu after the state assembly passed a law creating new local council Development areas.

The present Yaba local council area wears an urban setting; some part however mirrored rural features and these areas are simply referred to as blighted areas like Makoko and Iwaya. Nonetheless, Yaba Local council development area is the commercial nerve centre for all regardless of their political and cultural affiliations.

==References==
{{reflist}}
{{coord missing|Nigeria}}

[[Category:Lagos]]


{{LagosNG-geo-stub}}&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
