<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Iris pigment epithelium"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Iris pigment epithelium" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Unreferenced|date=March 2009}}
{{main|iris (anatomy)}}
The &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;iris pigment epithelium&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (IPE) is a two-cell thick layer of cuboidal cells lying behind the [[iris (anatomy)|iris]]. Both layers are jet black due to the numerous large [[melanosome]]s which pack the cytoplasm of each cell. Towards the central axis, the IPE terminates at the pupillary margin.  Peripherally, the IPE is continuous with the [[ciliary epithelium]], also double-layered but pigmented in only one layer. The ciliary epithelium is continuous in its turn with the multilayered [[retina]], which has an outermost pigmented layer, the [[retinal pigment epithelium]] (RPE). Despite their very different functions and histological appearances, these regions have a common origin from the two layers of the embryological [[optic cup (embryological)|optic cup]]. The melanosomes of the IPE are distinctive, being larger, blacker and rounder than those in the ciliary epithelium or RPE.

Iris pigment epithelium is the scientific name for the color of an iris in the eye.

== Pathology ==
The IPE is affected by [[glaucoma]], [[diabetes]], and iris inflammations and atrophies of various kinds, generally responding by showing patchy thinning and depigmentation. In albinism, it is fully or partially nonpigmented and translucent, which contributes to the photophobia of that condition.  However, diseases specific to the IPE itself are almost non-existent, and it seems to be a highly differentiated, stable cell type that almost never gives rise to malignancies, unlike the melanocytes of the iris stroma. Reports of adenomas and adenocarcinomas of the IPE exist, but some of these are debatable.






{{eye-stub}}

[[Category:Human eye anatomy]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
