<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Yeungjin College"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Yeungjin College" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Infobox Korean name
|hangul={{linktext|영|진|대|학}}
|hanja= {{linktext|永|進|大|學}}
|rr=Yeongjin Daehak|mr=Yŏngjin Taehak}}
&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Yeungjin College&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, also &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Yeungjin Junior College&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, is a private technical college located in Buk-gu, [[Daegu]], [[South Korea]].   [[Information technology]] is the principal academic focus; however, courses of study in other fields such as nursing and international tourism are also provided.

Yeungjin College also operates Yeungjin Cyber College, which since 2002 has offered its own two-year courses of study in fields such as computer science and multimedia, e-management, social welfare, and real estate.  The cyber college employs seven full-time instructors and 41 adjunct faculty, teaching a virtual student body of about 800.



== History ==

The school first opened its doors as Yeungjin Technical School on March 12, 1977.  It became a college in 1985.

Yeungjin College&amp;apos;s newest project is the Daegu English Village, located outside of Waegwan.

==Sister colleges==

Yeungjin maintains sisterhood relationships with a total of 34 institutions around the world.  A significant number of these are in the Philippines, as during the 1990s Yeungjin College was actively involved in developing IT programs at many Philippine universities.  Others are located in the United States, Taiwan, China, Japan, Australia, New Zealand, and Switzerland.  The first sisterhood ties established were with [[Ertong Technical College]] of Taiwan in 1981.

== See also ==
* [[List of Korea-related topics]]
* [[List of colleges and universities in South Korea]]
* [[Education in South Korea]]
Yeungjin College also sends its freshmen students to Philippine universities to learn English so that they will be globally competitive and conversant in terms of conversation with other nationalities.

== External links ==
* [http://www.yjc.ac.kr/www/eng/01welcome/01welcome_01.jsp Official school website, in English and Korean]

== References ==
{{reflist}}

{{coord missing|South Korea}}

[[Category:Universities and colleges in Daegu]]

{{ROK-university-stub}}&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
