<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="National Centre Party (Ireland)"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="National Centre Party (Ireland)" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{for|the Irish Centre Party founded in 1919|Stephen Gwynn}}
{{Infobox political party
|country = the Republic of Ireland
|name_english = National Centre Party
|name_native =
|logo =
|leader = [[Frank MacDermot]]
|chairman =
|secretary_general =
|leader1_title =
|leader1_name =
|foundation = 1932
|dissolution = 1933
|headquarters =
|ideology = [[Christian democracy]],&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;[[Conservatism]],&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;[[Centrism]]
|position = [[Centre-right]]
|merged = [[Fine Gael]]
|colorcode = {{National Centre Party (Ireland)/meta/color}}
}}
The &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;National Centre Party&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;,  initially known as the &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;National Farmers and Ratepayers League&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, was a short-lived political party in the [[Irish Free State]]. It was founded in December 1932 with the support of several sitting [[Teachta Dála|TD]]s, including the four [[Farmers&amp;apos; Party (Ireland)|Farmers&amp;apos; Party]] members and thirteen [[Independent (politics)|Independent]]s, all of whom feared for their political future if they did not coordinate in a common organisation. Prominent among the latter were party leader [[Frank MacDermot]], a TD for [[Roscommon (Dáil Éireann constituency)|Roscommon]] since the [[Irish general election, 1932|general election of February 1932]], and [[James Dillon (Fine Gael politician)|James Dillon]], a TD for [[Donegal (Dáil Éireann constituency)|Donegal]], who was the son of [[John Dillon]], the last leader of the [[Irish Parliamentary Party]].

The party&amp;apos;s policies included the establishment of a central bank (at this time, the Free State was still part of the [[Pound sterling|sterling]] area, and the [[Bank of Ireland]] served as lender to the government), [[deflation]] through pay cuts, [[protectionism]], an end to the [[Anglo-Irish Trade War]] and the removal of [[Rates (tax)|rates]] on agricultural land. The party was strongly opposed to [[Fianna Fáil]], despite apparent similarities of policy, perhaps because most National Centre Party deputies represented rural constituencies. Fianna Fáil, with its strength among small farmers and increasing popularity among the rural middle-class, was the most obvious threat to a rural-based party at this time.

In the [[Irish general election, 1933|general election of January 1933]], the new party won eleven seats. During this election, the party&amp;apos;s opponents in Fianna Fáil disrupted National Centre Party meetings, often with the assistance of the prohibited [[Irish Republican Army]]. These incidents contributed to the rise of the [[Army Comrades Association]], which was formed to protect the establishment conservative parties from the perceived threat of political violence. Fianna Fáil formed a [[majority government]] after the election. During the first Fianna Fáil government, the National Centre Party aligned with the largest opposition party, [[Cumann na nGaedheal]], on almost all issues of political or economic importance. However, Frank MacDermot rejected a suggestion that the two parties should merge.

The opposition parties united in mutual self-defence when the government banned the Army Comrades Association in August 1933. The two parties and the ACA merged to form [[Fine Gael]] in September, just eleven months after the formation of the National Centre Party. Although MacDermot became a Vice-President of Fine Gael at its foundation, he differed from most of his party colleagues on issues such as the degree of emphasis to be given to Ireland&amp;apos;s membership of the [[Commonwealth of Nations|British Commonwealth]]. He ultimately resigned from the party, to sit as an Independent.

==See also==
*[[:Category:National Centre Party (Ireland) politicians]]

==References==
* Barberis, Peter, John McHugh and Mike Tyldesley, 2005. Encyclopedia of British and Irish Political Organisations. London: Continuum International Publishing Group. ISBN 0-8264-5814-9, ISBN 978-0-8264-5814-8
* Manning, Maurice, 1972. Irish Political Parties: An Introduction. Dublin: Gill and Macmillan. ISBN 978-0-7171-0536-6

{{Historic Irish parties}}

[[Category:Defunct political parties in the Republic of Ireland]]
[[Category:Political parties established in 1932]]
[[Category:Political parties disestablished in 1933]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
