<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="X-Perts"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="X-Perts" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Infobox VG
|title = X-Perts
|image = [[Image:XpertsFront.jpg|frameless|X-Perts]]
|caption = North American cover art
|developer = Abalone
|publisher = Deep Water ([[Sega]])
|released = {{vgrelease|NA=1996&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;{{cite web | url = http://www.gamefaqs.com/console/genesis/data/586621.html| title = Release date | publisher = [[GameFAQs]]| date = | accessdate = 2009-03-11}}&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;}}
|designer = [[Glyn Anderson]]
|genre = [[Action game|Action]]
|modes = [[Single-player video game|Single-player]]
|ratings = {{vgratings|ESRB=Teen &amp;lt;small&amp;gt;(T)&amp;lt;/small&amp;gt;}}
|platforms = [[Mega Drive|Sega Mega Drive/Genesis]]
|media = [[ROM cartridge|Sega Genesis cartridge]]
}}

&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;X-Perts&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is a [[side-scrolling]] [[beat-&amp;apos;em-up|fighting action]] video game produced by [[Sega|Sega of America]] and released only in [[North America]] for the [[Mega Drive|Mega Drive/Genesis]] in {{vgy|1996}}. It is a spin-off of &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Eternal Champions]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos; starring the assassin Shadow Yamoto, who is depicted in her design from &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Eternal Champions: Challenge from the Dark Side]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos;.

==Story==
The game&amp;apos;s plot is based on an alternate timeline in which Shadow Yamoto was not killed by the Black Orchid in 1993. According to the instruction manual, she escaped the Black Orchid, and formed an anti-corruption group in revenge for their attempt on Shadow&amp;apos;s life.

A group of terrorist took over an undersea weapons factory. Unless the [[United Nations]] give into their demands, the terrorists will [[detonate]] a [[thermonuclear]] device that will destroy the earth.

==Gameplay==
Shadow leads a group of fellow X-perts in sabotage and other various missions. All three characters have character-specific special moves with differing attributes, along with three unique torture moves, which are used to interrogate various enemies.

Players are able to switch characters mid-game in order to carry out different tasks.

==Development==
This game was made as an answer from [[Sega]] to Nintendo&amp;apos;s [[Donkey Kong Country]].As such the graphics were pre-rendered in 3D then converted into sprite form which is similar to the method used in that game.

==Reception==
Despite what was considered &amp;quot;revolutionary&amp;quot; high resolution graphics on the Sega Genesis, virtually every aspect of this game was harshly panned by critics, notably gaming magazines &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[GamePro]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos; and &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Electronic Gaming Monthly]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos;. Despite having &amp;quot;unique&amp;quot; attributes, all three of the playable characters were virtually identical in gameplay.  Each featured unique Death Moves and Interrogation Moves, but otherwise played identically and had no specific advantage or skill that would be required to advance in the game.  Interrogation moves were necessary to progress in the game but, as they were performed with identical button commands to Death Moves, often did not work at all leaving players stuck and unable to advance.

Static and stilted animations with an overall awful gameplay were the primary target of critical reception, as the game did not play or control well when compared to other games of the day. Even games several years older that were similar such as &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Cyborg Justice]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos; played much better and were more fluid. Even the title of the game, which was considered goofy and mockingly described as a bad adult film title was not safe from critical panning. &amp;apos;&amp;apos;X-Perts&amp;apos;&amp;apos; received low scores across the board from major gaming magazines and stood out as one of the worst of the final generation of Genesis-exclusive titles before gaming transitioned into the [[PlayStation (console)|PSX]] and [[Nintendo 64]] era of gaming.

==References==
{{reflist}}

==External links==
*[http://www.mobygames.com/game/x-perts/ &amp;apos;&amp;apos;X-Perts&amp;apos;&amp;apos;] at [[MobyGames]]

[[Category:1996 video games]]
[[Category:Eternal Champions]]
[[Category:Sega video games]]
[[Category:Sega Genesis-only games]]
[[Category:North America-exclusive video games]]
[[Category:Ninja video games]]
[[Category:Video games developed in the United States]]
[[Category:Video game spin-offs]]
[[Category:Video games with 2.5D graphics]]
[[Category:Video games with pre-rendered 3D graphics]]

{{Eternal Champions}}

{{Action-videogame-stub}}&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
