<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Precocial"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Precocial" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Refimprove|date=January 2009}}
[[Image:Quail chick 02.jpg|thumb|right|[[California Quail]] chick (&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Callipepla californica&amp;apos;&amp;apos;), a precocial chick]]

In [[biology]], the term &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;precocial&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; refers to species  in which the young are relatively mature and mobile from the moment of birth or hatching. The opposite developmental strategy is called  &amp;quot;[[altricial]]&amp;quot; where the young are born or hatched helpless. Extremely precocial species may be called &amp;quot;[[superprecocial]]&amp;quot;. These three categories form a continuum, without distinct gaps between them. Precocial species are normally [[nidifugous]], meaning that they leave the nest shortly after birth or hatching.

The span between precocial and altricial species is particularly broad in [[bird]]s. Precocial birds are born with their eyes open. They are covered with downy feathers that soon grow to adult feathers after hatching.&amp;lt;ref name=creatures&amp;gt;{{cite book |title= Creatures of the Air and Sea|author=Edward S. Brinkley|year= 2000|publisher= Reader&amp;apos;s Digest Children&amp;apos;s Books|location= Singapore|isbn= 0-7944-0353-0|pages= 34, 35|url= }}&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt; These kind of birds can also swim and run much sooner after their birth than other birds, such as songbirds.&amp;lt;ref name=creatures/&amp;gt; Very precocial birds can be ready to leave the nest in a short period of time following hatching (e.g. 24 hours). Many precocial chicks are not independent in [[thermoregulation]] (the ability to regulate their own body temperatures), and they depend on the attending parent(s) to brood them with body heat for a short period of time.  Precocial birds find their own food, sometimes with help or instruction from the parents. Examples of precocial birds include the domestic [[chicken]], many species of [[duck]]s and [[goose|geese]], [[wader]]s, [[rail (bird)|rail]]s and the [[Hoatzin]]. The most extreme, [[superprecocial]] birds are the [[megapode]]s, where the newly-hatched chicks dig themselves out of the nest mound without parental assistance, and fly on the first day after hatching.

Precociality is found in many other animal groups. Familiar examples of precocial [[mammal]]s are most [[ungulate]]s, the [[guinea pig]], and most species of [[hare]]. This last example demonstrates that precociality is not a particularly conservative characteristic, in the evolutionary sense, since the closely related [[rabbit]] is highly [[altricial]].

Precocial species typically have a longer [[gestation]] or [[incubate (biology)|incubation]] period than related altricial species, and smaller litters or clutches, since each offspring has to be brought to a relatively advanced (and large) state before birth or hatching.

The phenomenon of [[Imprinting (psychology)|imprinting]] studied by [[Konrad Lorenz]] is characteristic of precocial birds.

==Etymology==
The word &amp;quot;precocial&amp;quot; is derived from the same root as &amp;apos;&amp;apos;precocious&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, implying in both cases early maturity.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Webster&amp;apos;s New World Dictionary&amp;apos;&amp;apos;. David B. Guralnik, Editor in Chief. New York:[[Simon and Schuster]], 1984.&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

==Phylogeny==
Precociality is thought to be ancestral in birds. Thus, altricial birds tend to be found in the most derived groups. There is some evidence for precociality in [[Protobird]]s (Elzanowski, 1995.) and [[Troodontid]]s (Varricchio et al. 2002).

==See also==
*[[Precocious puberty]]
*[[Altricial]]
*[[Parental investment]]

==References==
===Footnotes===
&amp;lt;references /&amp;gt;

===Notations===
*Starck J.M., Ricklefs R. E. Patterns of Development: The Altricial - Precocial Spectrum. In; Avian Growth and Development. [[Oxford University Press]], New York, NY, 1998.

[[Category:Developmental biology]]
[[Category:Ornithological terminology]]

&amp;lt;!-- Please respect alphabetical order --&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
