<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Sicarii"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Sicarii" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{For|other uses|Sicarius (disambiguation)}}
{{For|the [[Haredi]] gang named after the Sicarii|Sikrikim}}

&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Sicarii&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (Latin plural of &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Sicarius&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; &amp;quot;dagger-men&amp;quot; or later [[contract-killer]], Hebrew סיקריקים) is a term applied, in the decades immediately preceding the [[Siege of Jerusalem (70)|destruction of Jerusalem in 70 CE]], (probably) to an extremist splinter group&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;Nachman Ben-Yehuda, [http://www.bibleinterp.com/articles/masadamyth2.htm The Masada Myth: Scholar presents evidence that the heroes of the Jewish Great Revolt were not heroes at all.], The Bible and Interpretation&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt; of the [[Jew]]ish [[Zealots]], who attempted to expel the [[Roman Empire|Romans]] and their partisans from [[Judaea (Roman province)|Judea]] using concealed daggers (&amp;apos;&amp;apos;sicae&amp;apos;&amp;apos;).&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;Martin Goodman, &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Rome and Jerusalem: The Clash of Ancient Civilisations&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (2008,:407) talks of &amp;apos;&amp;apos;sicarii&amp;apos;&amp;apos;  practising &amp;quot;terrorism within Jewish society&amp;quot;.&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

==History==
The Sicarii are mentioned by [[Josephus]] in &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Jewish Antiquities&amp;apos;&amp;apos;: &amp;quot;When [[Lucceius Albinus|Albinus]] reached the city of Jerusalem, he bent every effort and made every provision to ensure peace in the land by exterminating most of the Sicarii (xx.208).

The Sicarii carried &amp;apos;&amp;apos;sicae,&amp;apos;&amp;apos; or small daggers, concealed in their cloaks, hence their name. At public gatherings, they pulled out these daggers to attack Romans or Roman sympathizers, [[Herodians]] and wealthy Jews comfortable with Roman rule, lamenting ostentatiously after the deed to blend into the crowd to escape detection. Literally, Sicarii meant &amp;quot;dagger-men&amp;quot;.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;[http://www.meridianmagazine.com/ideas/040607Sicarii.html Essay on the Sicarii]&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

Victims of the Sicarii included [[Jonathan (High Priest)|Jonathan]] the High Priest, though it is possible that his murder was orchestrated by the Roman governor [[Antonius Felix|Felix]]. Some murders were met with severe retaliation by the Romans on the entire Jewish population of the country. On some occasions, they could be bribed to spare their intended victims.  Once, Josephus relates, after kidnapping the secretary of Eleazar, governor of the Temple precincts, they agreed to release him in exchange for the release of ten of their captured assassins.

At the beginning of the [[First Jewish–Roman War|Jewish Revolt of 66 CE]], the Sicarii, and (possibly) Zealot helpers (Josephus differentiated between the two but did not explain the main differences in depth), gained access to Jerusalem and committed a series of atrocities, in order to force the population to war. In one account, given in the [[Talmud]], they destroyed the city&amp;apos;s food supply so that the people would be forced to fight against the Roman siege instead of negotiating peace. Their leaders, including Menahem ben Jair, [[Eleazar ben Ya&amp;apos;ir]], and [[Simon Bar Giora]], were important figures in the war, and Eleazar ben Ya&amp;apos;ir eventually succeeded in escaping the Roman onslaught. Together with a small group of followers, he made his way to the abandoned fortress of [[Masada]] where he continued his resistance to the Romans until 73 CE, when the Romans took the fortress and, according to Josephus, found that most of its defenders had committed suicide rather than surrender.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;[http://www.preteristcentral.com/articles-preterist-massada_josephus.htm The Credibility of Josephus], a critical report, comparing Josephus&amp;apos; account with archaeological evidence&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;
[[Image:Masada04.JPG|right|thumb|Masada, looking towards the Dead Sea.]]

In Josephus&amp;apos; &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Jewish War&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (vii), after the fall of the Temple in 70 CE, the &amp;apos;&amp;apos;sicarii&amp;apos;&amp;apos; became the dominant revolutionary Jewish party, scattered abroad. Josephus particularly associates them with the mass suicide at [[Masada]] in 73 CE and to the subsequent refusal &amp;quot;to submit to the taxation census when Cyrenius was sent to Judea to make one&amp;quot; (Josephus) as part of their religious and political scheme as resistance fighters:
:&amp;quot;Some of the faction of the &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Sicarion&amp;apos;&amp;apos;...not content with having saved themselves, again embarked on new revolutionary scheming, persuading those that received them there to assert their freedom, to esteem the Romans as no better than themselves and to look upon God as their only Lord and Master&amp;quot; (quoted by Eisenman, p 180).

==See also==
* [[Cloak and dagger]]
* [[Assassins]]

==References==
{{Reflist}}

==Further reading==
* Mark Andrew Brighton, &amp;apos;&amp;apos;The Sicarii in Josephus&amp;apos;s Judean War: Rhetorical Analysis and Historical Observations&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (Atlanta, Society of Biblical Literature, 2009) (Early Judaism and Its Literature, 27).
* {{JewishEncyclopedia|article=Sicarii|author=[[Richard Gottheil]] and [[Samuel Krauss]]|url=http://www.jewishencyclopedia.com/view.jsp?artid=681&amp;amp;letter=S}}

[[Category:Assassins]]
[[Category:Jews and Judaism in the Roman Empire]]
[[Category:Jewish religious terrorism]]
[[Category:Organized crime terminology]]
[[Category:Ancient hitman groups]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
