<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Designer"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Designer" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Infobox occupation
| name           = Designer
| image          = &amp;lt;!-- [[Image:Architect.png|300px]] --&amp;gt;
| caption        = MUSA&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;
| official_names =
&amp;lt;!------------Details-------------------&amp;gt;
| type               = [[Profession]]
| activity_sector    =
| competencies       = Technical&amp;amp;nbsp;knowledge,&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;teamwork&amp;amp;nbsp;abilities,&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;artistic&amp;amp;nbsp;skills (varies)
| formation          =
| employment_field   = &amp;apos;&amp;apos;see [[#Design professions|Design professions]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos;
| related_occupation =
}}
A &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;designer&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is a person who [[design]]s. More formally, a designer is an [[Agency (philosophy)|agent]] that &amp;quot;specifies the structural properties of a design [[Object (philosophy)|object]]&amp;quot;.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;Ralph, P. and Wand, Y. (2009). A proposal for a formal definition of the design concept. In Lyytinen, K., Loucopoulos, P., Mylopoulos, J., and Robinson, W., editors, Design Requirements Workshop (LNBIP 14), pp. 103–136. Springer-Verlag, p. 110&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt; In practice, anyone who creates tangible or intangible objects, such as consumer products, processes, laws, games and graphics, is referred to as a designer.
[[File:Cuckoo clock by Pascal Tarabay.jpg|thumb|left|200px| Designer [[cuckoo clock]] by Pascal Tarabay.]]
Classically, the main areas of design were only [[painting]], [[sculpture]] and [[architecture]], which were understood as the major arts. The design of [[clothing]], [[furniture]] and other common artifacts were left mostly to tradition or artisans specializing in hand making them.

With the increasing complexity of today’s society, and due to the needs of mass production where more time is usually associated with more cost, the production methods became more complex and with them the way designs and their production is created. The classical areas are now subdivided in smaller and more specialized domains of design (landscape design, urban design, exterior design, interior design, industrial design, furniture design, cloth design, and many more) according to the product designed or perhaps its means of production.

The education, experience and genetic blocks that form the base of a competent designer is normally similar no matter the area of specialization, only in a later stages of training and work will designer diverge to a specialized field. The methods of teaching or the program and theories followed vary according to schools and field of study.
Today, a design team, no matter the scale of the equipment, is usually composed by a master designer (the head of the team) that will have the responsibility to take decisions about the way the creative process should evolve, and a number of technical designers (the hands of the team) specialized in diverse areas according to the product proposed. For more complex products, the team will also be composed of professionals from other areas like engineers, advertising specialists, and others as required.
The relationships established between team members will vary according proposed product, the processes of production, the equipment available, or the theories followed during the idea development, but normally they are not too restrictive, giving an opportunity to everyone in the team to take a part in the creation process or at least to express an idea.

==Design professions==
Different types of designers include:
{{columns-list|4|
*[[Costume design]]
*[[Fashion design]]
*[[Furniture design]]
*[[Game design]]
*[[Graphic design]]
*[[Industrial design]]
*[[Interaction design]]
*[[Interior design]]
*[[Jewelry design]]
*[[Landscape design]]
*[[Learning design]]
*[[Lighting design]]
*[[Packaging design]]
*[[Scenic design]]
*[[Sound design]]
*[[Urban design]]
*[[User Experience Design]]
*[[User interface design|User Interface Design]]
*[[Web design]]
*[[Architecture]] as a whole
*[[Engineering]] as a whole
}}

&amp;lt;!-- deleted file removed[[File:By paTrn|evetpx|thumbnail|center|Fan Culp]]--&amp;gt;

==See also==
{{Wiktionary}}
*[[Architect]]
*[[Design]]
*[[Design engineer]]
*[[Design firm]]
*[[Design thinking]]
*[[Visual arts]]

==Footnotes==
{{commonscat|Designers}}
&amp;lt;references /&amp;gt;

{{Design}}

[[Category:Design]]
[[Category:Visual arts occupations]]
[[Category:Design occupations]]

[[id:Desainer]]
[[tr:Tasarım]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
