<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="School of Visual Concepts"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="School of Visual Concepts" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;[[File:Seattle - School of Visual Concepts from Bhy Kracke Park 01.jpg|thumb|School of Visual Concepts (blue building in center) seen from [[Bhy Kracke Park]], 2012.]]
The &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;School of Visual Concepts&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; in [[Seattle]], [[Washington (U.S. state)|Washington]], is a vocational school training students and working professionals in the fields of graphic design, advertising art direction, advertising copywriting, web design, and marketing communications.

Founded in 1971 by the husband-and-wife team of illustrators, Dick and Cherry Brown, the school&amp;apos;s teaching philosophy is based on the premise that working professionals, not career teachers or full-time faculty, can provide the most current, relevant instruction. As such, SVC does not offer degrees, but does provide students with the ability to earn a certificate in their program of study.

In addition to evening courses and daytime workshops in the marketing communications field, SVC also has the largest public letterpress printing teaching shops in the Pacific Northwest region of the United States. The school offers a variety of letterpress classes, giving students access to three Vandercook flatbed proofing presses, three clamshell platen presses, and a completely restored Reliance iron hand press.

==External links==
*[http://www.svcseattle.com/ School of Visual Concepts]

{{coord|47|37|24|N|122|20|36|W|format=dms|display=title|type:landmark_region:US-WA}}

[[Category:Education in Washington (state)]]
[[Category:Universities and colleges in Seattle, Washington]]
[[Category:Design schools in the United States]]
[[Category:Educational institutions established in 1971]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
