<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Queen of the Nile (The Twilight Zone)"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Queen of the Nile (The Twilight Zone)" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{DISPLAYTITLE:Queen of the Nile (&amp;apos;&amp;apos;The Twilight Zone&amp;apos;&amp;apos;)}}
{{Infobox Television episode
| Title = Queen of the Nile
| Series = The Twilight Zone
| Image =&amp;lt;!-- Deleted image removed:  [[File:Queen Of The Nile.JPG|250px]] --&amp;gt;
| Caption = [[Ann Blyth]] as Pamela Morris
| Season = 5
| Episode = 143
| Airdate = March 6, 1964
| Production =2626
| Writer = [[Jerry Sohl]] &amp;lt;br /&amp;gt; (credited to [[Charles Beaumont]])
| Director = [[John Brahm]]
| Guests = [[Ann Blyth]]: Pamela Morris/Constance Taylor &amp;lt;br /&amp;gt; [[Lee Philips]]: Jordan Herrick &amp;lt;br /&amp;gt; [[Celia Lovsky]]: Viola Draper &amp;lt;br /&amp;gt; [[Frank Ferguson]]: Krueger
| Music = [[Lucien Moraweck]]
| Episode list = [[List of Twilight Zone episodes]]
| Prev = [[An Occurrence at Owl Creek Bridge (The Twilight Zone)|An Occurrence at Owl Creek Bridge]]
| Next = [[What&amp;apos;s in the Box]]
}}

&amp;quot;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Queen of the Nile&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;quot; is an episode of the [[American television]] anthology series &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[The Twilight Zone]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos;.

==Plot==

Columnist Jordan Herrick, a noted [[cynicism (contemporary)|cynic]], prepares to interview famed actress Pamela Morris. She is known for her vitality and beauty, and many want to know her secret to staying young and beautiful. Herrick is welcomed to Morris&amp;apos;s sprawling manor by a very aged woman named Viola.  He naturally assumes that this is Morris&amp;apos;s mother, and greets her as such; he is shocked when Viola later confides that she is in fact Pamela&amp;apos;s daughter.

Herrick takes this as a sign of [[senility]], and greets the beautiful Pamela when she comes down the stairs. The two flirt and have drinks, Herrick obviously smitten with the gorgeous actress. The two talk, Pamela all the while hinting at some great secret that she possesses. Herrick&amp;apos;s curiosity and attraction finally win out, and he demands to know the secret. Pamela complies and demonstrates a small [[scarab (artifact)|scarab]] beetle that she hides in a plant. She explains that the beetle, prized in [[ancient Egypt]], is able to drain the life from others, that the owner might apply it to him or herself.

Herrick scoffs at this ridiculous story, but suddenly wonders why Pamela would choose to tell him such bizarre information. Pamela drugged his coffee, and though he tries to escape, he slumps unconscious to her living room floor. Pamela applies the scarab to Herrick&amp;apos;s body and pulls the youth from it, killing the columnist and reducing him to a pile of dust and clothes.

The episode ends with yet another young and handsome columnist arriving to interview Pamela, starting the cycle once again. It is implied that Pamela is actually [[Cleopatra VII]], and that she has been existing this way for centuries. If so, the elderly Viola could indeed be her daughter.

==Production notes==

Apparently, in the original first-draft script, a handsome young policeman turned up at the end of the story, asking Pamela Morris as to the whereabouts of the now missing Jordan Herrick. She begins to flatter and flirt with the cop, setting him up to start the cycle all over again.

==References==
*DeVoe, Bill. (2008). &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Trivia from The Twilight Zone&amp;apos;&amp;apos;. Albany, GA: Bear Manor Media. ISBN 978-1-59393-136-0
*Grams, Martin. (2008). &amp;apos;&amp;apos;The Twilight Zone: Unlocking the Door to a Television Classic&amp;apos;&amp;apos;. Churchville, MD: OTR Publishing. ISBN 978-0-9703310-9-0

==External links==
*{{imdb episode|id=0734616|episode=Queen of the Nile}}

{{Twilight Zone episodes}}

[[Category:1964 television episodes]]
[[Category:The Twilight Zone episodes]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
