<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Plantation desk"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Plantation desk" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Unreferenced|date=December 2009}}
{{Orphan|date=December 2009}}

A &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Plantation desk&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is an antique [[desk]] form.  It is thought to have been originally used as a mail desk by postmen.  The form is known to have been used on Southern plantations in the [[United States]], but it is not limited to them.  For some time communities of [[Shakers]] in New England built a large version of this form of desk. It was quite popular in the 19th century.

Basically, the Plantation desk is a [[Fall front desk]] with a deeper stand or bottom part. The extra space or ledge of the bottom part of the desk serves as a support for the fall front, thus eliminating the need for retractable supports.  Like a normal fall front desk the work surface must be cleared of all materials in order to raise it in a vertical position and thus close off the small drawers and pigeonholes set in front of the user.

While the fall front desk was developed by placing a chest on its side, on a stand made for it, to its exact dimensions (as is the case with the [[Bargueno desk]]), the plantation desk form was devised by placing such a chest on its side, on a table a bit too deep for it.  The fall front usually settles at a slight angle once it is open, in order to give a slanted work surface to the user.

Some plantation desks have two panel doors instead of a fall front and the ledge is hence much deeper since it serves as the main desktop surface.

See also the [[list of desk forms and types]].

{{DEFAULTSORT:Plantation Desk}}
[[Category:Desks]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
