<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Gut loading"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Gut loading" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Gut loading&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is the process by which an [[animal]]&amp;apos;s [[prey]] is raised and fed nutritious [[food]]s with the intention of passing those nutrients to the animal for which the prey is intended.  This term is used most often in reference to the preparation of [[insect]]s, such as [[cricket (insect)|cricket]]s and [[mealworm]]s, or mice which are used as food for [[reptile pet]]s.    Insects that are raised commercially for the pet trade are themselves of little nutritional value.  By providing the prey animals with a high quality diet immediately prior to feeding, they become a more nutritious meal for the [[predator]].&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;[[Merck Veterinary Manual]].  www.merckvetmanual.com&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

Gut loading can be accomplished by providing fruits, vegetables, and cereals or a nutritionally complete manufactured diet.  Several commercial products are available and are fortified specifically for gut loading. These products often include varying combinations of [[carbohydrate]]s, [[fat]]s, [[protein]]s, [[vitamin]]s, [[minerals]], and [[dietary fiber]].


&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Importance of gut loading&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;

Gut loading is considered most important if the primary source of nutrition is from insects, especially crickets. Because crickets are lower in nutritional value than other common insects fed, such as meal worms and wax worms. Larval insects contain more protein and digestible energy than adult insects. In addition, when gut loading larva they will gain the nutrients needed to pupate quickly and therefor will not keep as long.

Gut loading is considered less important when animals such as mice are used as prey. This is because of the large amount of digestible energy and other nutrients a mammal contains in its tissues. It is also a less common practice when rodents are fed, because it is usually preferred to feed pre-killed prey from the store to protect the predator for being bitten.

&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Methods&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;

Gut loading is designed to increase the nutrition of the prey&amp;apos;s body and to fill the digestive tract of the prey with nutrients. As the term suggests, gut loading is usually looked upon as a way to get essential nutrients into a reptile via the ingestion of the digestive tract of the prey. The two methods of nutrient uptake are important due to the ability of the prey to process nutrients into a digestible form for the predator. For example, most prey can digest complex carbohydrates into other forms of nutritional energy which the predator can use. However, gut loading nutrients like calcium do not have to be digested by they prey before its death in order to be available to the predator.

&amp;lt;references/&amp;gt;

{{DEFAULTSORT:Gut Loading}}
[[Category:Pet foods]]
[[Category:Nutrition]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
