<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Junior technician"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Junior technician" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;[[Image:OR3 RAF Junior Technician.svg|right|thumb|80px|Rank badge of an RAF Junior Technician]]
&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Junior technician&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Jnr Tech&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;JT&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; or &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;J/T&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;) is a junior non-commissioned rank in the [[Royal Air Force]], the [[Pakistan Air Force]] and the [[Royal Danish Air Force]].  In the RAF it ranks higher than [[senior aircraftman technician]] (SAC(T)), above [[senior aircraftman]] (SAC) and below [[corporal]] and has a [[NATO]] rank code of OR-2.  Since 2005, no more RAF [[airmen]] have been promoted to this rank, being promoted to SAC technician instead.

==United Kingdom==
The rank of junior technician is only held by airmen in technical trades and by musicians.  Airmen in non-technical trades always progressed directly from senior aircraftman to corporal. Junior technicians are qualified to work alone and supervise untrained airmen working within their area of responsibility. The rank was introduced in 1950 as part of a new grading system for technicians, wearing a single point up [[Chevron (insignia)|chevron]]. In 1964, when the grading system was abolished, JTs were retained, their badge changing to a four-bladed [[propeller]].

In 2000 the Royal Air Force changed the rank to Senior Aircraftman (acting technician), SAC(T). In 2005 promotions to the rank of junior technician ceased. However, those previously promoted continue to be at JT rank until they are promoted to Corporal or leave the service. JT is the most senior rank below Corporal and is considered to be equivalent to Lance Corporal in the Army but without the power to discipline junior ranks.

==Pakistan==
Junior technician is also a rank in the [[Pakistan Air Force]], where it ranks between corporal technician and senior aircraftman. Since 2006 it has been represented by single chevron beneath an eagle with outstretched wings.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;http://www.uniforminsignia.net/?option=com_insigniasearch&amp;amp;Itemid=53&amp;amp;result=2502&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

==Denmark==
Junior technician is the title for personal working in the [[Royal Danish Air Force]] after 2 years seniority as Aircraftman(OR-1) and until the age of 35. If still fit for duty at the age of 35 personal is promoted to Lance Corporal(OR-3).&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;[[Royal Danish Air Force]]&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

==See also==
*[[RAF other ranks]]

==References==
{{Reflist}}

{{UK enlisted ranks}}

[[Category:Military ranks of the Royal Air Force]]
[[Category:Air force ranks]]
[[Category:Technicians]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
