<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Qingzhou"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Qingzhou" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Refimprove|date=July 2009}}
{{coord|36|41|48|N|118|28|47|E|type:city|display=title}}
{{Location map
 |China
 |label=Qingzhou
 | lat_deg=36 | lat_min=41 | lat_sec=48
 | lon_deg=118 | lon_min=28 | lon_sec=47
 |position=left
 |width=250
 |float=right
 |caption=Qingzhou on the map of China
}}

&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Qingzhou&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; ([[Chinese character|Chinese]]: 青州; [[Pinyin]]: Qīngzhōu), formerly &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Yidu County&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (益都县), is a [[county-level city]], which is located in the west of [[Weifang]] City, [[Shandong]] Province, [[China]]. Qingzhou is a dynamic industry city, and also grows a great number of farm products. The local government holds an open policy of introduction of foreign capital, and has established strong business relationships with more than fifty countries and regions.

==History==
Qingzhou is a timehonored city, and its name initially appeared in a geography book called &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Classic of History]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos; chapter Yu Gong (禹贡) composed in the [[Warring States Period]] (403BC － 221 BC). Nonetheless, the history of this centuries old city can date back to the ancient times (twenty two centuries ago) when it was one part of the [[Dongyi]] area.

==Attractions==
[[File:Qingzhou museum 2007 04 21.jpg|thumb|Qingzhou Museum in 2007]]

*[[Fan Gongting]] an ancient pavilion built in Song Dynasty. It was a private garden of Fan Zhongyan who was the most notable poet and prosiast in an age of lively literature prosperous.
*Muslim district, including at least two large and historic mosques. The oldest one is the [[Zhenjiao Mosque]] ({{zh|c={{linktext|真|教|寺}}|p={{linktext|Zhēn|jiào| Sì}}}}). It can date from eight centuries ago, which is one of the three most well-known mosques in Yuan Dynasty.
*[[Ou Yuan]], a Ming Dynasty garden. It turned to be a combination of park and zoo, and is used as a performance area for citizens in the dawn and nightfall.
*[[Qingzhou Museum]], featuring some of the Buddhist statues unearthed in 1996/1997
*[[Tuoshan]]/Yunmenshan (&amp;quot;[[Camel Mountain]]/Cloud Gate Mountain&amp;quot;), which includes an ancient collection of Buddhist grottoes under national protection. The mountain is located approximately 4&amp;amp;nbsp;kilometers southwest of the city center (the coordinates of the peak are {{coord|36|38|54.9|N|118|27|27.5|E}}).
*[[Yang Tian]], a natural park with marverlous surface features. It is covered by virgin forest, through which crystal rivers are flowing, and dotted with quantities of natural rock cavities. What makes this park more amazing is the so-called thousand Buddha&amp;apos;s cave, which is considered as the first cave for the Buddhas. This is because of the huge volume of the cavern and the 1048 Buddhas in it that are in different postures and look extraordinarily vivid.

==Special Products==
*Dish Gardens
*Embroideries
*Flowers
*Hiemal Juicy Peaches
*Mihe Melons
*Tobacco

==Timeline==
*412: The Chinese [[Buddhism|Buddhist]] pilgrim [[Faxian]] landed on the south of [[Shandong peninsula]] at [[Laoshan]], and proceeded to Qingzhou to translate and edit the scriptures he had collected in [[India]].
*1986: The name &amp;quot;Qingzhou&amp;quot; is recovered from &amp;quot;Yi Du&amp;quot;.
*1996: The discovery of over 200 buried [[Buddhism|Buddhist]] statues at Qingzhou was hailed as a major [[archaeology|archaeological]] find.  The statues included early examples of painted figures, and are thought to have been buried due to [[Emperor Huizong of Song China|Emperor Huizong]]&amp;apos;s [[Song Dynasty (960-1279)|Song Dynasty]] repression of Buddhism (he favoured [[Taoism]]).&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;[http://static.royalacademy.org.uk/files/buddha-student-guide-18-18.pdf Royal Academy of Arts exhibition brochure: &amp;quot;Return of the Buddha. The Qingzhou discoveries&amp;quot;]&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

==References==
{{Commonscat}}
{{reflist}}

[[Category:Archaeological sites in China]]
[[Category:Cities in Shandong]]
[[Category:Buildings and structures in Shandong]]
[[Category:Weifang]]

{{Shandong-geo-stub}}&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
