<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="The White Plague"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="The White Plague" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Other uses|White plague (disambiguation)}}
{{Tone|date=December 2007}}

{{Infobox book| &amp;lt;!-- See [[Wikipedia:WikiProject Novels]] or [[Wikipedia:WikiProject Books]] --&amp;gt;
| name          = The White Plague
| title_orig    =
| translator    =
| image         = [[File:Whiteplague.jpg]] &amp;lt;!--prefer 1st edition--&amp;gt;
| caption =
| author        = [[Frank Herbert]]
| illustrator   =
| cover_artist  =
| country       = [[United States]]
| language      = [[English language|English]]
| series        =
| genre         = [[Science fiction]]
| publisher     = [[G.P. Putnam&amp;apos;s Sons]]
| pub_date      = 1982
| english_release_date =
| media_type    = Print ([[Hardcover]] &amp;amp; [[Paperback]])
| pages         = 445 pp
| isbn          = 978-0-399-12721-2
| dewey= 813/.54 19
| congress= PS3558.E63 W55 1982
| oclc= 8432222
| preceded_by   =
| followed_by   =
}}

&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;The White Plague&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (1982) is a [[science fiction]] novel by [[Frank Herbert]].

==Plot==

When an [[Provisional Irish Republican Army|IRA]] bomb goes off, the wife and children of molecular biologist John Roe O&amp;apos;Neill are killed on May 20, 1996. Driven halfway insane by loss, his mind fragments into several personalities that carry out his plan for him. He plans a [[genocidal]] revenge and creates a plague that kills women. O&amp;apos;Neill then releases it in [[Ireland]] (for supporting the terrorists), [[England]] (for oppressing the Irish and giving them a cause), and [[Libya]] (for training said terrorists); he demands that the governments of the world send all citizens of those countries back to their countries, and that they quarantine those countries and let the plague run its course, so they will lose what he has lost; if they do not, he has more plagues to release.

After releasing the plague, he goes to Ireland to hide, planning to offer his services as a molecular biologist in the hopes of sabotaging whatever work is done there on finding a cure. When he arrives in Ireland, he is suspected of being O&amp;apos;Neill (whom the investigatory agencies of the world have deduced is responsible).  To travel to the lab at [[Killaloe, County Clare|Killaloe]], he is forced to walk with a [[priest]], a boy who has taken a vow of silence due to the death of his mother, and Joseph Herity, the IRA bomber who detonated the explosive that killed O&amp;apos;Neill&amp;apos;s wife and children; their purpose is to confirm his identity, either through Herity&amp;apos;s indirect questioning, or the possibility that he will confess to the priest when confronted with the pain his revenge has caused for the boy.

Meanwhile, law and order have broken down in England and Ireland, and the old Irish ways are coming back.  Local IRA thugs appoint themselves &amp;quot;kings of old&amp;quot;, and others recreate ancient [[Celtic polytheism|Celtic pagan]] religions centered on the [[rowan]] tree.  The IRA has effective control of Ireland, but as the governments of the world grow certain that O&amp;apos;Neill is there and essentially in custody, they consider wiping out the three targeted countries to end the lingering threat.

==Major themes==
Most of the drama is mental, political, and communal.  While the story of O&amp;apos;Neill and his revenge is told in full, there is also the larger story of how the governments of the world&amp;apos;s countries deal with the plague, which escapes into limited areas that are quickly sterilized by &amp;quot;panic fire&amp;quot;, which immolates everything and everyone in it.  North Africa is wiped out; [[Boston]] is burned to the ground; [[Rome]] is destroyed with [[atom bomb|atomic bombs]]; and the [[United States|U.S.]] pushes for a moat of [[cobalt]] dust to isolate [[Africa]], which is written off as a total loss.

The world&amp;apos;s armed forces are reorganized under a [[Royal Canadian Navy|Canadian]] [[Admiral]], Francois Delacourt, who heads Barrier Command, responsible for the absolute separation of contaminated and clean areas.  Scientists toy with a conspiracy of intellectuals to override the expected repression of research by governments.  In countries around the world angry mobs lynch Irish, English, Libyans, and anyone too closely resembling them.

The plague also has major social repercussions.  The book implies near the end that [[polyandry]] will necessarily become mandatory, potentially giving women involved in such marriages increased power.

==Awards==
&amp;apos;&amp;apos;The White Plague&amp;apos;&amp;apos; was nominated for a [[Locus Award]] for best science fiction novel in 1983, but lost to [[Isaac Asimov|Isaac Asimov’s]] novel &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Foundation&amp;apos;s Edge]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos;.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;»[http://www.locusmag.com/SFAwards/Db/Locus1983.html 1983 Locus Awards]« The LOCUS Index to SF Awards, LOCUS online. Accessed 2011-10-05.&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

== References ==
{{reflist}}

{{Frank Herbert}}

{{DEFAULTSORT:White Plague, The}}
[[Category:1982 novels]]
[[Category:American science fiction novels]]
[[Category:Novels by Frank Herbert]]
[[Category:Fictional diseases]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
