<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Online consultation"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Online consultation" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Online consultations&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; or e-consultations refer to an exchange between government and citizens using the [[Internet]].  They are one form of [[online deliberation]]. Further, online consultation consists in using the Internet to ask a group of people their opinion on one or more specific topics, allowing for trade-offs between participants.  Generally, an agency consults a group of people to get their thoughts on an issue when a project or a [[policy]] is being developed or implemented, e.g. to identify or access options, or to evaluate ongoing activities.  This enables governments to draft more citizen-centered policy.

As the Internet gains popularity with the public for voicing opinion, citizen participation in policy development through cyberspace is changing the face of democracy.  The rise of the Internet has given way to buzzwords such as [[e-democracy]], referring to citizen participation in politics, government issues and policy development through electronic technologies and the Internet, and [[eGovernment]], pertaining to providing citizens with government information and services online.  Online consultation is an extension of these concepts.  Through online engagement, government is enabled to hold interactive dialogues with the public as they have a more direct route to citizen opinion via the Internet.

While this definition is framed in the [[Canada|Canadian]] context, other countries like the [[United Kingdom|UK]], [[Denmark]], [[Scotland]], and [[Australia]] can also be considered leaders in the field.  These and many other countries are integrating online consultations and engagement using various methods and for a range of purposes. The [[European Union]] also utilises online consultations. These complement face-to-face consultations and help to create greater transparency of the democratic process. Online consultations are also increasingly being used by the [[United Nations]] and its Specialized Agencies. [[FAO|The Food and Agriculture Organization of the UN]] hosts online consultations to allow for more inclusive drafting processes of policy guidelines, reports and strategy papers. The Global Forum on Food Security and Nutrition (FSN Forum) is tasked with carrying out many of these consultations.

==Channels==
Online consultations and engagement activities can utilize:
*[[Website]]s, [[discussion board]]s, and [[electronic mailing list]]s, which have the ability to aid in policy development by providing the public with pertinent information and engaging them in order to extract feedback on issues.
*[[Weblog]]s and real time [[online chat]] that can often put the public in direct contact with government officials, such as their MP, deputy or other political figure with whom they can share opinion and concerns

==See also==
*[[Accessibility]]
*[[Chat room]]s
*[[Collaborative software]]
*[[Direct democracy]]
*[[Intranet]] and [[Extranet]]
*[[Moderation]]
*[[Online deliberation]]
*[[Participatory democracy]]
*[[Privacy]]
*[[Security]]
*[[Usability]]

==External links==
&amp;lt;!-- Please keep this list alphabetized.  Thanks! --&amp;gt;
* [http://epress.anu.edu.au/engage_citation.html Electronic Engagement: A Guide for Public Sector Managers] - Guide to electronic and online consultation published by the Australia and New Zealand School of Government.
*[http://www.crossingboundaries.ca/files/egov_session_summary.pdf E-Government: Governing in the Information Age] ([[Portable Document Format|PDF]])
*[http://km.fao.org/fsn/ Global Forum on Food Security and Nutrition]
*[http://www.hansardsociety.org.uk Hansard Society]
*[http://www.consultations.gov.uk Index of all UK government consultations]
*[http://www.businesslink.gov.uk/consultations Index of UK government consultations relevant to small business on the Business Link website]
*[http://ec.europa.eu/yourvoice/index_en.htm Index of all EU consultations]
*[http://www1.oecd.org/publications/e-book/4201131e.pdf OECD Report: Citizens as Partners] (PDF)
*[http://www.pwgsc.gc.ca/onlineconsultation/text/index-e.html Online Consultation Technologies Centre of Expertise]
*[http://www.publicus.net/articles/consult.html Online Consultations and Events - Top Ten Tips for Government and Civic Hosts]
*[http://www.tellparliament.net TellParliament]

[[Category:E-democracy]]
[[Category:Social research]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
