<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Great Fire of Toronto (1904)"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Great Fire of Toronto (1904)" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{multiple issues|onesource=April 2011|refimprove=April 2011}}
{{History of Toronto}}
The &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Great Fire of Toronto of 1904&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; was the second [[List of historic fires|great fire]] that destroyed a large section of [[Downtown Toronto|Downtown]] [[Toronto]], [[Ontario]], Canada on April 19, 1904.

==Incident==
[[Image:4TorontoFire.jpg|thumb|150px|left|Front Street after the Toronto Fire of 1904]]
The fire was first spotted at 8:04 p.m. by a [[Toronto Police]] [[constable]] on his regular street patrol. The flames were rising from the elevator shaft of the Currie neck wear factory at 58 Wellington Street West, just west of Bay Street (now [[Toronto-Dominion Centre|TD Bank Tower]]). The factory was situated in the centre of a large industrial and commercial area. The exact cause of the fire was never determined, but a faulty heating stove or an electrical problem is suspected.

The fire began on the evening of the 19th and took nine hours to get under control. The glow of the fire could be seen for kilometres in all directions. Firefighters from cities as far away as [[Hamilton, Ontario]] and [[Buffalo Fire Department|Buffalo]] (a long term friendship was established between the &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Queen City of New York&amp;apos;&amp;apos; and the &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Queen City of Canada&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, given their [[Queen City|nicknames]]) came to [[Toronto]]&amp;apos;s aid. The temperature that night was approximately -4 degrees Celsius with winds at 48 kilometres per hour with [[snow]] [[flurries]].
[[File:Area of Great Toronto Fire of 1904 showing the Wholesale district affected (MAPS-R-71).jpg|thumb|right|This fire insurance map shows the area damaged by the fire.]]

The fire destroyed 104 buildings, and claimed one victim; John Croft. Croft Street is a lane-way between Borden and Lippincott Street (near Bathurst and Harbord Streets) was named in his honour.  It caused [[Canadian dollar|$]]10,350,000 in damage and put five thousand people out of work, at a time when the city only had 200,000 inhabitants.  As a result of the fire, more stringent safety laws were introduced and an expansion of the city&amp;apos;s fire department was undertaken.

==Legacy==
It was the largest fire ever in the city, although a previous large fire had consumed many city blocks on April 7, 1849 when the city was much smaller and constructed mostly with wood.

The legacy of this fire includes [[Call Box 12]], which was used to sound the alarm and now is the name for the volunteer canteen truck supporting [[Toronto Fire Services]] today.

Even 17 fire halls, two engine companies and one hose company proved to be no match.

[[Toronto Fire]]&amp;apos;s Public Education Centre and Museum at Station 233 has model displaying the area of the fire.

==Source==
Friebe, Marla. A History of the Toronto Fire Services 1874-2002. Toronto: City of Toronto, 2003.

==See also==
{{Portal|Toronto}}
{{Commons category|Toronto Fire of 1904}}
* [[Toronto Fire Services]]
* [[Buffalo Fire Department]]
* [[List of historic Toronto fire stations]]
* [[List of historic fires]]
* [[Great Fire of London]] – 1666
* [[Great Fire of Pittsburgh]] - 1845
* [[Great Fire of Toronto (1849)]]

==References==

{{reflist}}

==External links==
*[http://www.toronto.ca/fire/news/100/index.htm Silent footage of a wagon responding to the alarm, buildings on fire, and demolition of damaged buildings]
*[http://www.toronto.ca/archives/fire1.htm Pictures of the fire&amp;apos;s aftermath from the City of Toronto Archives site]
*[http://www.archives.gov.on.ca/en/explore/online/fire/index.aspx The Great Toronto Fire, the Archives of Ontario remembers this significant event in the city&amp;apos;s history]
*[http://www.wikito.org/Croft_Street,_Toronto Croft Street, Toronto]

{{Toronto}}

{{coord missing|Ontario}}

[[Category:History of Toronto]]
[[Category:Fires in Canada]]
[[Category:1904 in Canada]]
[[Category:Disasters in Ontario]]
[[Category:1904 fires]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
