<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Western Scheldt"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Western Scheldt" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;[[image:Zeeland_van_boven.jpg|thumb|right|Satellite image of the Scheldt delta showing the Western Scheldt]]
The &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Western Scheldt&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; ({{lang-nl|Westerschelde}}) in the province of [[Zeeland]] in the southwestern [[Netherlands]], is the [[estuary]] of the [[Scheldt]] river. This river once had several estuaries, but the others are disconnected from the Scheldt, leaving the Westerschelde as its only direct way to the sea. It is an important shipping route to the [[Port of Antwerp]], [[Belgium]]. Therefore, unlike the other sea arms, it is not closed by a dam as part of the [[Delta Works]].  Instead, the dykes around it have been heightened and reinforced.

Many ships have sunk in the Western Scheldt. Following an agreement between the Dutch and Flemish governments in 1995, many of these wrecks have been removed to improve shipping access to Antwerp. It was expected that the last 38 wrecks in the shipping channel would be removed during 2003. The largest wreck was the {{convert|131|m|ft|adj=on}} long &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Alan A. Dale]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos; which was removed during June 2003.

The Western Scheldt was freed from German occupation in October and November 1944 by the [[First Canadian Army]] during [[The Battle of the Scheldt]].

==Western Scheldt Tunnel==
{{main|Western Scheldt Tunnel}}
In mid-March 2003, a 6.6&amp;amp;nbsp;km [[tunnel]] under the Western Scheldt was opened, the Western Scheldt Tunnel, running from Ellewoutsdijk (mun. [[Borsele]]) in [[Zuid-Beveland]] to  [[Terneuzen]] in [[Zeeuws-Vlaanderen|Zeelandic Flanders]]. It is the longest road traffic tunnel in the Netherlands. The toll fee (2012) is €5,00 for [[automobile|cars]] and €2,50 for [[motorcycle]]s. The charge for motorcyclists was originally the same as for cars but, following protests, the toll was reduced in 2011. There is a single toll station for both directions, located on the north bank. Pedestrians, cyclists, and moped riders are not allowed in the tunnel and must travel by bus.

==Ferry==
The double-decker car ferries that serviced the two Western Scheldt crossings  until 2003 were sold to Italian companies, where two of them, the Queen Beatrix (renamed Tremestieri) and Prince Johan Friso (renamed Acciarello) were adapted for the crossing between [[Messina]] and [[Villa San Giovanni]] on the Italian mainland.

With the opening of the road tunnel, the [[Breskens]]-[[Vlissingen]] [[ferry]] was restricted to pedestrians and cyclists only. It is operated by [[Veolia]] Fast Ferries Zeeland, part of [[Connex Group|Connex]]. Initially former car ferries were used, but as of 2 May 2004 the service has been operated by two &amp;quot;[[Small Waterplane Area Twin Hull|small waterplane area twinhulls]]&amp;quot; (swaths, similar to [[catamaran]]s), built at the Royal Schelde Group in Vlissingen (Flushing), and named &amp;quot;Prins Willem Alexander&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Prinses Máxima&amp;quot;.

Upstream, the [[Kruiningen]]-Perkpolder ferry was discontinued without direct replacement.

==External links==
*[http://www.bba.nl/1/35/36/ Ferry]
*[http://www.westerscheldetunnel.nl/index.cfm?language=en Tunnel]
*[http://www.zeeland.nl/uploaded_files/1123_oversteek_westerschelde.pdf Ferry and Tunnel] (in Dutch, pdf, 1MB)

{{coord|51|24|N|3|43|E|region:NL-ZE_type:waterbody_source:dewiki|display=title}}
{{Rhine–Meuse–Scheldt delta}}
{{Use dmy dates|date=November 2010}}

[[Category:Rhine–Meuse–Scheldt delta]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
