<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Contemporary architecture in Cluj-Napoca"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Contemporary architecture in Cluj-Napoca" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;[[Image:BRD Cluj.gif|thumb|right|Regional headquarters of the Romanian Bank for Development]]

Since 1989, modern [[skyscraper]]s and glass-fronted [[hotel]]s have altered the skyline of [[Cluj-Napoca]], a city in the [[Transylvania]]n region of [[Romania]].

==Banks==

The Cluj-Napoca regional headquarters of the [[Banca Română pentru Dezvoltare]] ([[Romanian Bank for Development]]) was completed in  1997 after 4 years of work. It is the tallest building in Cluj-Napoca, 50 m or 164 feet. Its 12 stories house offices for the bank and for divisions of several other companies, including insurance and oil companies.

Another [[Architecture|architecturally]] interesting building is the unfinished headquarters of the Banca Agricole (Agricultural Bank), held in the custody of the city due to the failure of that bank and its subsequent purchase by the Reiffeisen Bank. Work ceased in 2000; all that was finished was the exterior, built by the &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Abatech&amp;apos;&amp;apos; firm. The city government proposed that the building be completed and transformed into the Casa Europei (&amp;quot;House of Europe&amp;quot;), but funds were not obtained to complete work. In 2006, it was announced that the building will completed as a &amp;apos;&amp;apos;City Business Center&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, and work resumed. Today the building is functional and bears the nickname &amp;quot;Clădirea biscuite&amp;quot;.

Another building in similar straits is the more recently started Palatul Telefoanelor (Telephone Palace; [[Palatul Telefoanelor|a building of the same name]] exists in [[Bucharest]]), built by [[Romtelecom]] (the national, public phone company), who could not afford to finish the building and auctioned it off. It was bought by [[Banca Transilvania]] for 3 million euros. The financial institution announced it will be used as a &amp;apos;&amp;apos;banking café&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (Romanian: &amp;apos;&amp;apos;cafenea bancară&amp;apos;&amp;apos;), the first of its kind in Cluj (however, since the announcement a rival bank, Banc Post, opened such a café).

Other banks that have constructed modern buildings in Cluj-Napoca include [[Banca Transilvania]], Banca Comercială Română, Banc Post, Banca [[Ion Ţiriac|Ţiriac]], [[ABN Amro Bank]], and [[UniCredit]].

==Government buildings==
Besides banks, Cluj-Napoca features several modern buildings constructed under the aegis of the local government. The most recent is the Octavian Goga Library Building, which also houses information centers for the [[European Union]] and [[NATO]]. This building was started in 2000 and completed in 2003. Other post-Communist-era government buildings include the Avram Iancu Firehouse, [[Cluj-Napoca International Airport]], and the Cluj-Napoca branch of DistriGaz.

==Schools==
Being an academic center, home of six government universities ([[Babeş-Bolyai University]], [http://www.dntcj.ro/edu/aav Academia de Arte Vizuale &amp;quot;Ion Andreescu&amp;quot;], Universitatea de Ştiinţe Agronomice şi Medicină Veterinară, [http://www.utcluj.ro Universitatea Tehnică], [http://www.umfcluj.ro Universitatea de Medicină si Farmacie], [http://www.edu.ro/amcjn.htm Academia de Muzică &amp;quot;Gheorghe Dima&amp;quot;]) and several private ones as well ([http://www.ubv.ro Universitatea Bogdan Vodă], [http://www.ucdc.ro Universitatea Creştină Dimitrie Cantemir]), Cluj-Napoca also features several modern university buildings such as the Department of Political Science at UBB, the Department of Management at UBV, and the Law Department of UCDC.

{{coord missing|Romania}}

[[Category:Buildings and structures in Cluj-Napoca]]
[[Category:Romanian architecture]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
