<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Zanzithophone"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Zanzithophone" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Cleanup-rewrite|date=July 2011}}

[[Image:Casio_dh100.jpg|thumb|300px|The &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Casio DH-100&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, with packaging and user manual.|right]]
The &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;zanzithophone&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is a name given to an electronic [[MIDI]] [[digital wind controller]]/[[synthesizer]]. It is also proper to refer to it as &amp;quot;Digital Horn&amp;quot; as can be seen printed on the instrument itself. It was produced by [[Casio]] in the mid 1980&amp;apos;s as the &amp;apos;&amp;apos;DH-100&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (silver) or &amp;apos;&amp;apos;DH-200&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (black). A later model, &amp;apos;&amp;apos;DH-280&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, was the same basic instrument with an added &amp;quot;accompaniment module&amp;apos;; this module was carried into the &amp;apos;&amp;apos;DH-800&amp;apos;&amp;apos;: a cartridge insert provided four pre-recorded songs: &amp;apos;&amp;apos;When the Saints go Marchig In&amp;apos;&amp;apos;,&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Air on the (sic) G String&amp;apos;&amp;apos;,&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Chopin&amp;apos;s Nocturne&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, and &amp;apos;&amp;apos;I Lost the DOH in my Clarinet&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, each of which could be played with or without melody.  The module also provided sixteen standard rhythms.

Each model has six built in synthesized sounds; saxophone, trumpet, synth-reed, oboe, clarinet, and flute; the tones produced are audibly more electronic than the tones of the real instruments named.  They look like a clarinet/saxophone hybrid.  They can be played with recorder fingering over a two-octave range, or with the &amp;quot;Casio system&amp;quot; (similar to standard brass instrument fingering) which allows for up to 4 octaves to be played.  A transpose button permits the player to change to any chromatic key over a two-octave range.  The &amp;apos;&amp;apos;DH-280&amp;apos;&amp;apos; also had a tuning button.  A key near the top of the instrument allows a [[portamento]]-like slide between notes.  Finally, a switch permitted the instrument to be played without blowing through it, making the keys operate like a digital keyboard.

These instruments were breath-sensitive for volume.  Unlike other digital wind controllers, the breath actually flows through the instrument, making it feel similar to an acoustic woodwind instrument.  Each came with a small built-in speaker, and also had an output cable for external amplification.  [[MIDI]] OUT capability of the instrument means that it can be used to control sounds from other [[MIDI]] synthesizers that offered a [[MIDI]] IN connection.  These features, and its low price (it was initially marketed as a toy) increased its appeal to budget-minded musicians.

Power for the instruments came from five AA batteries, with provision for connecting an aftermarket 7.5 volt AC adaptor.

The instruments are prone to developing a squeal. This is because of a capacitor deteriorating; it can be fixed by replacing the capacitor.  None of the instruments had a read-out display of any type, so transposing, changing tone, and other functions generally required counting button-clicks.

This instrument was most notably used by [[The Elephant 6 Recording Company]] based in [[Athens, Georgia]] and by [[Was (Not Was)]] in live performance of &amp;apos;&amp;apos;I Feel Better than James Brown&amp;apos;&amp;apos;
==References in literature==
The zanzithophone is mentioned in a footnote on page 66 of Kim Cooper&amp;apos;s book &amp;apos;&amp;apos;In the Aeroplane Over the Sea&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (New York: Continuum, 2005).

== External links ==
*[http://homepage.ntlworld.com/paul.fox4/casiofixes.htm Web site with instructions for squeal fix and other fixes for the Casio Digital Horn]
*[http://web.archive.org/web/20050403213740/www.tierrahombre.com/dh100/ Fingering chart and link to manual, MIDI implementation chart, more]
*[http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FHN_q6sK6Fk [[Was (Not Was)]] performing with DH-200]
*[http://www.tedkeys.com/ site for Ted Keys, a professional musician who plays these instruments]
*[http://www.patchmanmusic.com/WindControllerFAQ.html general information on digital wind midi conrollers, including Casio]

{{Casio}}
[[Category:Electronic musical instruments]]
[[Category:Saxophones]]
[[Category:Casio musical instruments]]
[[Category:MIDI instruments]]


{{Electronic-musical-instrument-stub}}&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
