<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Vai people"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Vai people" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Infobox Ethnic group
|group    = Vai people
|image    = [[File:Vai Youth and Maid.jpg|250px]]
|image_caption = A Vai Youth and Maiden
|poptime  = 165,000 [http://www.joshuaproject.net/peoples.php?rop3=110483]
|popplace =
*139,000 in [[Liberia]] [http://www.joshuaproject.net/peoples.php?rop3=110483]
*35,000 in [[Sierra Leone]] (including 20,965 in [[Pujehun District]])[http://www.joshuaproject.net/peoples.php?rop3=110483]
|langs    = [[Vai language]]
|rels     = [[Islam]] 95%, [[Christianity]] 5% &amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;Mind and Social Practice: Selected Writings of Sylvia Scribner By Sylvia Scribner, Ethel Tobach, pg. 193&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;
|related  =
}}
The &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Vai&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; are a [[Mande peoples|Manden]] [[ethnic group]] that live mostly in [[Liberia]] and small minority live in south-eastern [[Sierra Leone]]. The Vai are known for their indigenous [[Syllabary|syllabic]] [[writing systems|writing system]], developed in the 1820s by Duala Bukele and other tribal elders. Over the course of the 19th century, literacy in the writing system became widespread. Its use declined over the 20th century, but modern computer technology may enable a revival.

The Vai people speak the [[Vai language]], which is of the [[Mande languages]]. The Sierra Leonean Vai are predominantly found in [[Pujehun District]] (around the Liberian border) where they make up 10% of the population. Most of the Sierra Leonean villages next to the Liberian border are largely from the Vai ethnic group.

==Economy==
Most Vai make their living by [[farming]] the fertile land. Rice is their staple crop and can be cultivated with other vegetables on upland plots of cleared land. In addition to rice, crops such as cotton, corn, pumpkins, bananas, ginger, coffee, and cocoa are raised. The Vai also gather various nuts and berries from the forests. The palm tree is an important commodity to the Vai. Nuts, butter, wine, fuel, soap, and baskets are among its many derivatives.

== Culture and Education==
In many aspects, the Vai are a unique African ethnicity. Many believe that the region inhabited by the Vai is the original home of the [[Poro]], a male secret society known throughout [[West Africa]]. The Vai are also quite musical. They play many instruments and perform dances on special occasions.

The Vai have three types of schooling. The first and most important is the bush school, where the children learn traditional Vai socialization skills, important survival skills, and other traits of village life for four to five years. Second is the [[English language|English]] school; some Vai children attend English schools to learn the English language. Finally, there are the Quranic schools, where Vai children are taught the [[Arabic language]] under the guidance of the local Muslim religious leader.

==Religion and spiritual belief==
The Vai are predominantly [[Muslim]], and have for centuries practiced traditions rooted in studying the [[Quran]].&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;Mind and Social Practice: Selected Writings of Sylvia Scribner By Sylvia Scribner, Ethel Tobach, pg. 193&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

Most of the Vai are very [[superstitious]] and some practice [[witchcraft]]. They consider themselves to be surrounded by spirits that can change into living creatures or objects. These spirits are believed to have the power to do evil to individuals or to the whole tribe. The Vai perform ceremonies for the dead in which they leave articles of clothing and food near the graves of the deceased.

==Notable Vai people==
*[[Varney Sherman]], Liberian politician
*[[Momolu Duwalu Bukele]], inventor of the Vai script
* [[Hans-Jürgen Massaquoi]], of mixed Liberian Vai and German descent, grew up as a non-Aryan in [[Nazi Germany]] to later become a journalist in the USA.
* Rev. Andrew Momolue Diggs: Former Pastor of the historic Providence Baptist Church in Monrovia, Liberia.

==See also==
* [[Vai language]]
* [[Vai syllabary]]
Charles Dunbar Sherman..politician, graduated from Howard University and The Wharton School of Public finance-University of Pennsylvania. 1st African President of the YMCA.
Hawa Daisy Moore, one of Liberia most popular singer, song writer.

==References==
{{reflist}}

[[Category:Ethnic groups in Liberia]]
[[Category:Ethnic groups in Sierra Leone]]
[[Category:Muslim communities in Africa]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
