<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Yamaha DragStar 1100"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Yamaha DragStar 1100" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Unreferenced|date=December 2011}}
{{Infobox motorcycle
| name = Yamaha DragStar 1100
| image = [[Image:Dragstar1100.JPG|frameless|upright=1.35]]
| aka=Yamaha V Star 1100 - XVS1100/XVS1100A
| manufacturer = [[Yamaha Motor Company]]
| production = Since 1998
| predecessor =
| successor =
| parent_company =
| class = [[Cruiser (motorcycle)|Cruiser]]
| platform =
| engine = {{convert|1063|cc|cuin|abbr=on}} 4-stroke SOHC V-twin
| transmission =
| suspension =
| frame =
| brakes =
| rake =
| trail =
| wheelbase = {{convert|1640|mm|in||abbr=on}}
| length = {{convert|2405|mm|in||abbr=on}}
| width = {{convert|895|mm|in||abbr=on}}
| height= {{convert|1095|mm|in||abbr=on}}
| seat_height = {{convert|690|mm|in||abbr=on}}
| dry_weight = 650 lbs
| fuel_economy =
| fuel_capacity = 4.7 Gallon
| related = [[Yamaha DragStar 650|Yamaha DragStar 650 XVS550/XVS650A]]
| similar =
}}

The &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Yamaha XVS 1100 DragStar&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, sold as the &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;V-Star 1100&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; in North America, is a [[motorcycle]] manufactured by [[Yamaha Motor Corporation]]. It comes in two versions, the XVS1100 Custom and the XVS1100A Classic, the former a more modern style, and the latter a more classic style, with rounder edges and is {{convert|13|kg|lb||abbr=on}} heavier.{{cn|date=September 2012}} The seat height is slightly lower on the Custom.

The 1100, along with its 650 sibling, enjoy a huge following around the world.  Aftermarket companies produce a number of items to customize the model.  Over the lifespan of the model, changes have been evolutionary, with only minor updates.

==Beginnings==
The DragStar began as the XVS650 in 1997 in Europe (400 version available in Japan since 1996), and grew in 1999 to include the XVS1100 Custom.  The 1100 used a reworked version of the venerable [[Yamaha Virago|Virago]] 75-degree, air-cooled v-twin engine which had been in use since the early 1980s.  The Star version offered better torque for the new midsize cruiser bike.  The Star carried over the shaft-drive layout from the Virago, but relied on a new suspension and frame, discarding the outboard dual shocks and stressed-member engine arrangement of the Virago in favor of a single-shock and twin downtubes.  Dual Mikuni 37&amp;amp;nbsp;mm carburetors with throttle-position sensors are used to efficiently meter fuel to the 8.3:1, oversquare engine.

==Classic model added==
The DragStar/V-Star gathered followers early on, which led to the addition in 2000 of the Classic model.  As opposed to the Custom&amp;apos;s bobbed rear fender, 5 and 3/4 headlight, aluminum rims with spokes, exposed forks, 110 front tire and other custom touches, the Classic had longer fenders, floorboards, cast magnesium wheels, thicker brake and shift levers, a 7 inch headlight, substantial fork covers and a 130 front tire.  Later a Silverado model, which included such amenities as a windscreen, sissy bar and soft sidebags was introduced as an upscale model.

==Features==
The V-Star 1100 Classic came with the large fenders which also included the floorboards for the rider as a standard item with the rocker shifter pegs.  The custom models had these items replaced with a the peg configuration and peg up/down shifter.  The customs also replaced the standard large front tire with a minute thinner tire in the category of a 90 series or a 110 series to resemble the [[Harley-Davidson Sportster|Harley-Davidson 1200 Sportster]].

The 1100 models were sought after machines based on the dimensional parameters of an {{convert|1063|cc|cuin|abbr=on}} engine and roughly {{convert|700|lb|kg||abbr=on}} platform, with 130 series front and 170 series rear tires.

== See also ==
*[[Yamaha DragStar]]
*[[Yamaha DragStar 250|Yamaha DragStar 250 XVS250]]
*[[Yamaha DragStar 650|Yamaha DragStar 650 XVS650/XVS650A]]

== External links ==
*[http://www.yamaha-motor.co.jp/global/ Yamaha Motor Co.] global site
*[http://www.yamaha-motor.com.au/motor/index.htm?model_cat.asp?modelcatid=11 Yamaha Cruiser] Australian Site
*[http://www.starmotorcycles.com/ Yamaha Star Motorcycles] USA Site

{{Yamaha motorcycles}}
{{Yamaha motorcycles timeline}}

[[Category:Yamaha motorcycles|DragStar 650]]
[[Category:Cruiser motorcycles]]
[[Category:Motorcycles introduced in 1997]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
