<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Wikipedia:Articles for deletion/Whiteness"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Wikipedia:Articles for deletion/Whiteness" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;The only thing here is a quote from Moby Dick about the state of being white. I can&amp;apos;t imagine any encyclopedic value in it, nor any potential replacement article. [[User:Bryan Derksen|Bryan]] 05:48, 9 May 2004 (UTC)
*Charmingly idiosyncratic. Nevertheless: delete --[[User:Bodnotbod|bodnotbod]] 15:15, May 9, 2004 (UTC)
* Delete -- [[User:Cyrius|Cyrius]]|[[User talk:Cyrius|&amp;amp;#9998]] 16:14, May 9, 2004 (UTC)
* Now look you for&amp;apos;ard on the Pequod, where Queequeg and Stubb sit with yon ill-favored Lascars, worrying at a piece of rope.  With what skill do they fashion it into that knot of all knots, the Turks-Head, that tangled complexity of cunning artifice.  Yet, mark you, landsman, this knot with its sundry mystifications has no use in the fastenings and attachments. Every sheet-bend, inside-clinch, diamond-knot, double-crown, half-hitch, clove-hitch, blackwall-hitch, and carrick-bend has its place in the regulation of the Pequod. The humblest of the bowlines, stings, dead-eyes, splices, reefs, bends, hitches, knots, grommets, tarpaulins, epidydimides, and seizings, keeps our little world sailing on its appointed course. And yet the Turks-Head, which binds no sail, chocks no reeve, fillets no quoin, braces no cutting-spade, like some rough Kabbalah of the folio Parsees, is the Prince of Knots!  Bethink yourself well on it, landsman! Aye, what are your bankers, your stock-brokers, your clergy, your Senators, your professors, your players with railroads, your stackers of wheat, your hog-butchers to the nation, but the Turks-Head Knots of human discourse, while it is the lowest square-knots and sheep-shanks that connect and bind our souls like some fragrant, oleaginous, glutinous, nacreous, viscous antinomian asphodel from the rarest and most prized of the far Barbadoes. Oh, by the way... delete. [[User:Dpbsmith|Dpbsmith]] 01:21, 10 May 2004 (UTC)
* KEEP THIS PAGE!  IT HAS BEEN CHANGED! I have replaced the previous blather with a useful article on the topic. &amp;quot;Whiteness&amp;quot; is a concept from a real and emerging field called Whiteness Studies. Read the new article before voting to delete, PLEASE. [[User:Worldtyrant|Worldtyrant]] 00:33, 12 May 2004 (UTC)
::[[Whiteness studies]] is a valid topic, and I have created an article on it, based on [[User:Worldtyrant|Worldtyrant]]&amp;apos;s work but reworked for a more neutral point of view. That material does not properly belong under [[Whiteness]] and accordingly I have reverted it to the version previously under discussion, until VfD can run its normal course. I wasn&amp;apos;t sure what to do with Worldtyrant&amp;apos;s statement that &amp;quot;Harvard University has proposed to, in their own words; &amp;apos;Abolish the White race&amp;apos;&amp;quot;. This is not correct as stated; a better statement would be &amp;quot;Harvard University graduate Noel Ignatiev, in an article in &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Harvard Magazine&amp;apos;&amp;apos; entitled &amp;quot;Abolish the White race,&amp;quot; describes his [[1992]] founding of the magazine &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Race Traitor.&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;quot; However, I haven&amp;apos;t included this in [[Whiteness studies]] (although I did leave it as an external link) because I am unsure what the relationship is between this article and the general field of Whiteness studies. [[User:Dpbsmith|Dpbsmith]] 22:21, 12 May 2004 (UTC)
* Delete and redirect to Whiteness studies. Maybe find some room for the quote too. [[User:Burgundavia|Burgundavia]] 20:14, May 13, 2004 (UTC)
*Thank you Dpbsmith. I should point out that I did not post the Harvard quote. There is another user (unregistered) who has changed my entries more than once. Even now, I see the page has been changed ONCE AGAIN to be nothing but a Melville quote. What can we do? [[User:Worldtyrant|Worldtyrant]] 22:28, 13 May 2004 (UTC)
Whiteness studies looks fine.  Delete whiteness and redirect to Whiteness studies. --[[User:Starx|Starx]] 00:29, 14 May 2004 (UTC)&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
