<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Jug Rock"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Jug Rock" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;[[Image:Jug Rock.jpg|thumb|right|Jug Rock]]
&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Jug Rock&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is a natural geological formation located outside of [[Shoals, Indiana]], in the valley of the East Fork of the [[White River (Indiana)|White River]].  It is composed of [[sandstone]], and is the largest free-standing table rock formation (also called a &amp;quot;[[tea table]]&amp;quot;) in the [[United States]] east of the [[Mississippi River]].  It is part of the [[Mansfield formation]], laid down in the [[Pennsylvanian]] geological epoch, roughly 325 to 286 million years ago. Erosion along fracture lines separated it from a nearby cliff.  A companion feature, [[House Rock]], stands opposite Jug Rock.
In the &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Second Report of the Geological Survey of Indiana&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, published in 1871, State Geologist E. T. Cox wrote:

&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;One of the most interesting spots to visit, for obtaining a view of this character of scenery, is near the town of Shoals, on the road to the Indian Sulphur Springs. A high ridge of millstone grit, here, terminates within a few yards of the East Fork of White river, from the top of which, there is a projecting mass of conglomerate sandstone, called the &amp;quot;Pinnacle,&amp;quot; which stands one hundred and seventy feet above the level of the stream. Cyclopean blocks, that have broken off, lie around the foot of the ridge, in every conceivable position. On the north side of this ridge, the conglomerate has been cut through by disintegrating forces, which left, at some distance from the main ledge, a tall mass of rock, which has received the name of &amp;quot;Jug Rock,&amp;quot; from the fancied resemblance which it bears to a jug. It is forty-two feet high and supports, on its top, a flat projecting layer, which is called the &amp;quot;stopper.&amp;quot; Just above the bulge of the jug are irregular lines of stratification, known as false bedding. The lower part is thickly set with quartz pebbles. The frontispiece to this volume presents a view of the &amp;quot;Jug Rock&amp;quot; which was copied from a photograph taken by D. Allbright. For this faithful representative of a highly interesting geological scene, I am indebted to B. F. Devol, and D. Allbright, of Shoals.&amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;

Jug Rock is currently part of a [[nature reserve|nature preserve]] owned by the [[Indiana Department of Natural Resources]].

This unusual rock feature gives its name to the team of nearby [[Shoals High School]], &amp;quot;Shoals Jug Rox.&amp;quot; The Jug Rock- named &amp;quot;Roxer Boxer,&amp;quot; is the school&amp;apos;s mascot.

==References==
*Mark J. Camp and Graham T. Richardson, &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Roadside Geology of Indiana&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, (Mountain Press Publishing Co.: Missoula, MT, 1999), p 113.  ISBN 0-87842-396-6
*[http://www.indiana.edu/~libgeol/cox1870/1870martin.html E.T. Cox, &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Second Report of the Geological Survey of Indiana, made during the year 1870&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, (Indianapolis, 1871) p. 83.]
*&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Ibid&amp;apos;&amp;apos;. [http://www.indiana.edu/~libgeol/cox1870/1870cox.html Frontispiece: Illustration of Jug Rock]

==External links==

{{Portal|Indiana}}

*[{{Gnis3|451067}} Geographic Names Information System Feature Detail Report (House Rock)]
*[{{Gnis3|451337}} Geographic Names Information System Feature Detail Report (Pinnacle Rock)]
*[http://www.topoquest.com/map.asp?lat=38.68056&amp;amp;lon=-86.79556 Topographic map from TopoQuest (House Rock and Pinnacle Rock)]
*[http://www.indiana.edu/~librcsd/etext/hoosier/GM-35.html Standing Rocks: Ancient Erosion Remnants (from &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Our Hoosier State Beneath Us&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, Indiana Geological Survey)]

{{Coord|38|41|N|86|48|W|region:US-IN|display=title}}

[[Category:Rock formations in Indiana]]
[[Category:Protected areas of Martin County, Indiana]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
