<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="X (roller coaster)"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="X (roller coaster)" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;:&amp;apos;&amp;apos;See [[X2 (roller coaster)]] for the steel roller coaster formerly known as X operating at Six Flags Magic Mountain in Valencia, California, USA.&amp;apos;&amp;apos;
{{Update|inaccurate=y|date=March 2013}}
{{Infobox roller coaster
|name=X
|image=X-nowayout.jpg
|caption=X is enclosed in a large pyramid shaped building
|location=Thorpe Park
|section=Lost City
|type=Steel
|status=Operating
|opened=March 23, 1996
|last retheme=2013
|manufacturer=Vekoma
|designer=Vekoma
|model=Enigma
|track=Modified Enigma
|lift= Drive tire lift hill
|height_ft=42
|drop_ft=32
|length_ft=1312
|speed_mph=29
|inversions=0
|duration=2:00
|angle=
|capacity=1,000
|cost=
|acceleration=
|gforce=2.4
|renamed=2013
|rcdb_number=846
|coordinates={{coord|51.4036|-0.5132|display=title,inline}}
}}
&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;X&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (previously known as &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;X:/ No Way Out&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; from 1996-2012) is a [[roller coaster]] located in the [[Thorpe Park#Lost City|Lost City]] area of [[Thorpe Park]], [[England]], [[UK]]. It was the park&amp;apos;s first non-powered roller-coaster.
The ride was marketed as the &amp;quot;world&amp;apos;s first backwards roller coaster in the dark.&amp;quot; It was built themed around the idea of &amp;apos;being trapped in a computer virus&amp;apos;, although nowadays there isn&amp;apos;t much in the ride to accommodate this theme. Due to the loud dance music, low lighting and UV lights the ride can be related to a [[rave]].  The ride is situated inside a blue and terracotta pyramid. The ride once had a longer queue line, but this was modified to accommodate for the &amp;apos;Hellgate&amp;apos; Fright Night maze and later &amp;quot;The Passing&amp;quot; maze. From 2011, the pyramid the ride is housed in has been partially been blocked from view by [[Storm Surge (ride)|&amp;apos;Storm Surge&amp;apos;]].
The original roller coaster had many sections of theming, but over the past few years, these have mainly been removed, or are simply not functioning. The ride originally had an [[on-ride camera]], but this was removed at the end of the 2005 season. The ride had several modifications for the 2007 season, including improved queue line lighting, new video and sound effects, and a new control cabin. However, the queueline video ceased playing after a year and the television screens are now switched off. In 2010, X intermittently operated with the safety lights turned on, meaning the ride was sometimes run with the interior of the building being visible.

== Ride experience ==
After queuing in the exterior queue-line riders enter the pyramid and proceed down a long and narrow corridor with neon lights and lasers in the ceiling. Loud dance music plays throughout the corridor. After turning a few corners there is a large room with a long queue-line in it; on busy days this is used as an interior queue-line. After queuing in this room, riders enter the station. An empty train enters the station and riders board the train. The train then exits the station and into a tight right bend that leads up onto the lift hill. After reaching the top of the hill, the train plummets down at speeds of 29mph into various helixes and tight turns. Throughout the ride there are three mid-ride brake runs where the train stops for a few seconds before continuing. On one of the brake runs the train rolls backwards before continuing forwards. While all this is happening there are bright multi-coloured disco lights and laser effects that accompany the dance music heard in the queue-line. The train stops in a different station to where boarding happens and the riders exit and the empty train continues into the boarding station.

==Differences to X/: No Way Out==

When the ride was rethemed as X in 2013 some substantial changes were made to the ride. The computer-gone-haywire theme of the original ride was lost and the ride now travels forwards along the track instead of backwards. It is also no longer a completely dark ride as it has disco-lights and lasers inside the pyramid.

==External links==
* [http://www.totalthorpepark.co.uk/guide/nowayout.shtml X:\No Way Out at Total Thorpe Park]
* [http://www.themeparks-uk.com/thorpe-park-guide/rides/x-no-way-out.html X:\No Way Out at ThemeParks-UK]

{{TP Coasters}}

[[Category:Roller coasters in the United Kingdom]]
[[Category:Roller coasters operated by Merlin Entertainments]]
[[Category:Roller coasters introduced in 1996]]
[[Category:Thorpe Park]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
