<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Zymotic disease"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Zymotic disease" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Zymotic diseases&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (for the [[Greek language]] term &amp;apos;&amp;apos;zumoun&amp;apos;&amp;apos; for &amp;quot;ferment&amp;quot;), was a term in [[medicine]] of the 19th century, applied to a class of acute infectious maladies,&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;{{cite book|title=Hospitalism and Zymotic Disease|author=Kennedy, Evor|year=1869|edition=2nd|location=London|publisher=Longmans, Green, and Co.|url=http://books.google.com/books?id=N2Gp-S-xgKAC}}&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt; presumed to be due to some virus or organism which acts in the system like a ferment. It was in British official use from 1839.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;{{cite book|author=Marjorie Cruickshank|title=Children and Industry: Child Health and Welfare in the North-west Textile Towns During the Nineteenth Century|url=http://books.google.com/books?id=iny7AAAAIAAJ&amp;amp;pg=PA67|accessdate=23 June 2013|date=1 January 1981|publisher=Manchester University Press|isbn=978-0-7190-0809-2|page=67}}&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt; Note: This term was obsolete even in 1911, the date of the original version of the text below:

&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;As originally employed by [[William Farr|Dr W. Farr]], of the [[General Register Office|British Registrar-General&amp;apos;s department]], the term included the diseases which were &amp;quot;epidemic, endemic and contagious,&amp;quot; and were regarded as owing their origin to the presence of a morbific principle in the system, acting in a manner analogous to, although not identical with, the process of fermentation. A large number of diseases were accordingly included under this designation. The term, however, came to be restricted in medical nomenclature to the chief fevers and contagious diseases (e.g. [[typhus]] and [[typhoid fever]]s, [[smallpox]], [[scarlet fever]], [[measles]], [[erysipelas]], [[cholera]], [[whooping-cough]], [[diphtheria]], &amp;amp;c.). The science of [[bacteriology]] has displaced the old [[fermentation theory]], and the term has practically dropped out of use.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;{{Cite EB1911|wstitle=Zymotic Diseases}}&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;

&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Zyme&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; or &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;microzyme&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; was the name of a germ presumed to be the cause of zymotic diseases.

This term was used extensively in the English Bills of Mortality as a cause of death from 1842, and ceased to be used in the early 1900s. Robert Newstead used this term in a 1908 publication in the Annals of Tropical Medicine and Parasitology, to describe the contribution of house flies (&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Musca domestica&amp;apos;&amp;apos;) towards the spread of infectious diseases.

[[Antoine Béchamp]] proposed that microzymas, not cells, were a fundamental building block of life, surviving the death of the organism, and coalescing to form blood clots and bacteria. His ideas did not gain acceptance.&amp;lt;ref name=hess&amp;gt;{{cite book|last=Hess|first=David J.|title=Can bacteria cause cancer?: alternative medicine confronts big science|url=http://books.google.co.uk/books?id=KojMTlCdYCUC&amp;amp;pg=PA76|year=1997|publisher=NYU Press|isbn=0-8147-3561-4|pages=76–77}}&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

Bechamp (late 19th century) discovered tiny organisms he called &amp;quot;microzymas&amp;quot; which are present in all things - animal, vegetable, and mineral, whether living or dead {{when|date=April 2013}}. Depending upon the condition of the host, these microzymas could assume various forms. Bad bacteria and viruses were simply the forms assumed by the microzymas when there was a condition of disease{{vague|date=April 2013}}. In a diseased body, the microzymas became pathological bacteria and viruses. In a healthy body, microzymas formed healthy cells. When a plant or animal died, the microzymas lived on.{{clarify|date=April 2013}}

==References==
{{reflist}}
{{Refimprove|date=January 2010}}

{{DEFAULTSORT:Zymotic Disease}}
[[Category:Medical terminology]]
[[Category:Obsolete medical theories]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
