<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Ecoinformatics"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Ecoinformatics" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Ecoinformatics&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, or ecological informatics, is the science of information ([[Informatics (academic field)|Informatics]]) in [[Ecology]] and [[Environmental science]]. It integrates environmental and information sciences to define entities and natural processes with language common to both humans and computers. However, this is a rapidly developing area in ecology and there are alternative perspectives on what constitutes ecoinformatics.

A few definitions have been circulating, mostly centered on the creation of tools to access and analyze natural system data. However, the scope and aims of ecoinformatics are certainly broader than the development of metadata standards to be used in documenting datasets. Ecoinformatics aims to facilitate environmental research and management by developing ways to access, integrate [[database]]s of environmental information, and develop new algorithms enabling different environmental datasets to be combined to test ecological hypotheses.

Ecoinformatics characterize the [[semantics]] of natural system knowledge. For this reason, much of today&amp;apos;s ecoinformatics research relates to the branch of [[computer science]] known as [[Knowledge representation]], and active ecoinformatics projects are developing links to activities such as the [[Semantic Web]].

Current initiatives to effectively manage, share, and reuse ecological data are indicative of the increasing importance of fields like Ecoinformatics to develop the foundations for effectively managing ecological information. Examples of these initiatives are  [[National Science Foundation]] [[Datanet]] projects, [[DataONE]] and Data Conservancy.

==External links==
*[http://www.ecoinformatics.org ecoinformatics.org] -- Online Resource for Managing Ecological Data and Information

*[http://ecoinformatics.uvm.edu Ecoinformatics Collaboratory] -- Research links and public wiki for discussion.

*[http://ecoinformatics.oregonstate.edu Ecoinformatics Education]-- Ecosystem Informatics at Oregon State University

*[http://www.bui-berlin.de industrial Environmental Informatics]-- Industrial Environmental Informatics at HTW-Berlin, University of Applied Sciences

*[http://www.waite.adelaide.edu.au/ISEI/ International Society for Ecological Informatics]

*[http://www.science.uottawa.ca/~jkerr Canadian Facility for Ecoinformatics Research] -- Ecoinformatics at the University of Ottawa, Canada

*[http://www.ecoinfoindia.org ecoinfoindia.org -- Ecoinformatics Centre at ATREE, India] -- Eco Informatics Centre at the Ashoka Trust for Research in Ecology and the Environment (ATREE)

*[http://www.nceas.ucsb.edu/ecoinfo Ecoinformatics program at the National Center for Ecological Analysis &amp;amp; Synthesis]

*[http://www.elsevier.com/wps/find/journaldescription.cws_home/705192/description Ecological Informatics: An International Journal on Ecoinformatics and Computational Ecology]

*[http://www.ecologicaldata.org/ Ecological Data]

*[http://www.nsf.gov/pubs/2007/nsf07601/nsf07601.htm NSF DataNet call for proposals]

*[http://www.dataone.org DataONE]

*[http://www.dataconservancy.org Data Conservancy]

*[http://eco-informatics.engr.oregonstate.edu/]-- EcoInformatics Summer Institute, an NSF-funded REU site (Research Experience for Undergraduates)

[[Category:Ecology]]
[[Category:Information science]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
