<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Academician"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Academician" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Refimprove|date=November 2012}}

The title &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Academician&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; denotes a &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Full Member&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; of an art, literary, or scientific  [[academy]]. In many countries, it is an [[honorary title (academic)|honorary title]]. However, in some other systems, like [[Academy of Sciences of USSR]] it gave very real privileges and administrative responsibilities for funding allocation and research priorities.

== Corresponding Member ==

A related title also exists in some countries — a &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Corresponding Member&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; ({{lang-fr|membre correspondant}}; {{lang-ru|член-корреспондент}} &amp;quot;chlen-korrespondent&amp;quot;) is a person who is eminent in respect of scientific discoveries and attainments but is not normally resident in the country where the academy is located.&amp;lt;ref name=&amp;quot;AAS&amp;quot;&amp;gt;{{cite web | url=http://science.org.au/fellows/corresp.html | title=Corresponding members | accessdate=November 25, 2012 | author=Australian Academy of Sciences}}&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt; Because they are unable to read their communications in person, they have to use &amp;quot;[[communication|correspondence]]&amp;quot;. For example, Corresponding Members of the [[Australian Academy of Science]] who reside outside of Australia include: Sir [[David Attenborough]] (United Kingdom), [[Rolf M. Zinkernagel]] (Switzerland), [[Elizabeth Blackburn]] (USA) and [[Gunnar Öquist]] (Switzerland).&amp;lt;ref name=&amp;quot;AAS&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;

== History ==

Historically, the meaning for the title of &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Academician&amp;apos;&amp;apos; follows the traditions of the two most successful early scientific societies: either the [[Royal Society]], where it was an honorary recognition by an independent body of peer reviewers and was meant to distinguish a person, while giving relatively little formal power, or the model of [[French Academy of Sciences]], which was much closer integrated with the government, provided with more state funding as an organization, and where the title of &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Academician&amp;apos;&amp;apos; implied in a lot more rights when it came to decision making. While both approaches are, to a degree, political, normally in the scientific academies shaped after British model, the nature of politics involved in becoming an academician is more rooted in scientific argument, while organization modeled after French typically involve a lot more vested funding interests and purely political reasons that have nothing to do with science.

== Eastern Europe and China ==

&amp;quot;Academician&amp;quot; may also be a functional title and denote a full member of the [[National academy|National Academy]] of Sciences in those countries where the academy has a strong influence on national scientific life, particularly countries that were part of, or influenced by, the [[Soviet Union]]. In such countries, &amp;quot;Academician&amp;quot; is used as an [[honorific]] title (like &amp;quot;Doctor&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Professor&amp;quot;, etc.) when addressing or speaking about someone. Countries where the term &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Academician&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is used in this way include [[China]], [[Armenia]], [[Azerbaijan]], [[Bulgaria]], [[Croatia]], [[Estonia]], [[Georgia (country)|Georgia]], [[Hungary]], [[Latvia]], [[Lithuania]], [[Republic of Macedonia|Macedonia]], [[Moldova]], [[Mongolia]], [[Romania]], [[Russia]], [[Serbia]], [[Slovenia]], [[Tajikistan]], [[Turkey]], [[Ukraine]] and [[Bosnia and Herzegovina]].

However, since the reforms of late USSR dismantled the de-facto monopoly of the state on forming academies and allowed the creation of voluntary academies. While some of the newly created academies did improve the relatively rigid structure, the prestige and meaning of the title has been substantially undermined, as the title &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Academician&amp;apos;&amp;apos; could be awarded by associations of pseudoscientists or organizations that see their sole purpose of the existence of selling the title for money. Therefore, it became customary and almost compulsory to list which academy gave the title to assert its meaningfulness.

== United Kingdom ==

The British honour &amp;quot;[[Fellow of the Royal Society]]&amp;quot; (FRS) can be considered a rough equivalent.

== Canada ==

In Canada, Fellowship of the [[Royal Society of Canada]] is a comparable honour.

== Finland ==

In [[Finland]], &amp;quot;Academician&amp;quot; ({{lang-fi|akateemikko}}) is an honorary title and the [[President of Finland|President of the Republic]] nominates the Academicians. There can be 12 Finnish Academicians representing science and scholarly pursuits and eight Academicians representing fine arts and literature at the same time. The [[Academy of Finland]] is the state funding agency of Finnish science and letters, but it has no organizational connection to Finnish Academicians. The scientists and scholars funded by the Academy of Finland are called Academy Professors ({{lang-fi|akatemiaprofessori}}) and Academy Research Fellows ({{lang-fi|akatemiatutkija}}). In addition to Academy of Finland, Finland has four independent national academies.

== Notes and references ==
{{Reflist}}

== See also ==

* [[Académie française]]

[[Category:Academic honours]]
[[Category:Professional titles and certifications]]

[[fi:Akateemikko]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
