<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Jin-qua"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Jin-qua" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Unreferenced|date=December 2009}}
&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Jin-qua&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, is a character in [[James Clavell]]&amp;apos;s [[novel]] &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Tai-Pan (novel)|Tai-Pan]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos;. His full Chinese name is Chen-tse Jin Arn.

Jin-qua was a merchant who possessed a monopoly on all the foreign trade in China during the early 19th century.

With the arrival of the British merchants and the establishment of Hong Kong, he began cultivating a relationship with [[Dirk Struan]], the tai-pan of the Noble House, the chief trading company in Hong Kong. He arranged for two of his own descendants to become Struan&amp;apos;s misstresses.

The first, [[Kai-sung]], was Jin-qua&amp;apos;s daughter. She was the mother by Dirk Struan of [[Gordon Chen]].

The second was [[T&amp;apos;Chung Jin May-may]], Jin-qua&amp;apos;s granddaughter. She was secretly assigned the task of teaching Struan civilized ways.

In 1841, Struan&amp;apos;s was on the brink of ruin, about to be destroyed by rival [[Tyler Brock]]. In desperation, Dirk Struan turned to Jin-qua, who lent him one million sterling in specie. In return, Struan agreed that a member of the Chen family would forever be [[compradore]] of Noble House, the first being [[Gordon Chen]].

Additionally, four bronze coins were split in half, with Dirk Struan given one half of each coin. Struan agreed that whenever anyone presented the tai-pan with another half-coin, the tai-pan would be obliged to grant that person one favor, whether legal or illegal. Furthermore, this obligation was handed down to all successive tai-pans (who could only become tai-pan after first blindly swearing to uphold these agreements).

Of the four coins, one was kept by Jin-qua, one given to the warlord [[Wu Fang Choi]], one given to Gordon Chen, and one given out in secret.

{{DEFAULTSORT:Jin-Qua}}
[[Category:Asian Saga characters]]
[[Category:Fictional businesspeople]]
[[Category:Fictional Hong Kong people]]


{{lit-char-stub}}&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
