<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Whale Cove (Oregon)"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Whale Cove (Oregon)" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{| width=&amp;quot;300&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;right&amp;quot;
|[[Image:Wpdms usgs photo whale cove oregon.jpg|thumb|center|250px|Whale Cove, south of Depoe Bay, Oregon, colorized aerial photograph]]
|-
|[[Image:Joducus hondius new albion 1589.png|thumb|center|250px|The Jonucus Hondius map of 1589 of Drake&amp;apos;s New Albion cove]]
|}

&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Whale Cove&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is a small [[cove]], approximately one-third of a mile (0.5&amp;amp;nbsp;km) in diameter, located on the [[Pacific Ocean|Pacific Coast]] of [[Oregon]] in the [[United States]], approximately 1.4&amp;amp;nbsp;mi (2.3&amp;amp;nbsp;km) south of the city of [[Depoe Bay, Oregon|Depoe Bay]].&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;1.8&amp;amp;nbsp;mi (2.9&amp;amp;nbsp;km) from Depoe Bay to Whale Cove Inn at the south end of Whale Cove by road&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;  The cove is located at approximately 44 deg 44 min N latitude.

A portion of the cove is protected as part of [[Rocky Creek State Park]].

==Drake Theory==

In 1978, [[United Kingdom|British]] amateur [[historian]] Bob Ward proposed that Whale Cove was the location where [[Francis Drake]] spent the summer of 1579 during his [[circumnavigation]] of the globe by sea. The exact location of Drake&amp;apos;s landing spot, at which he claimed a portion of the west coast of [[North America]] as &amp;quot;[[New Albion]]&amp;quot;, has been claimed to be identified by proponents of more than twenty sites. The officially-recognized Drake landing site is at the Drakes Bay Historic and Archaeological District National Landmark in northern [[California]] on the coast of [[Marin County, California|Marin County]].

Ward proposed Whale Cove as the actual spot of Drake&amp;apos;s landing based on its similarity to a 16th century map made by [[Jodocus Hondius]]. Ward theorized that Drake may have conspired with [[Elizabeth I of England|Queen Elizabeth I]] to mislead the [[Spanish Empire|Spanish]] about the true location of the cove to keep the Spanish from discovering [[Puget Sound]], which Ward believes that Drake thought was the [[Northwest Passage]].

One longstanding puzzling feature of the Hondius map is the small island on the peninsula protecting the cove. According to Ward, a narrow strip of the peninsula protecting Whale Cove &amp;quot;has a strip through which water flows at [[tide|high tide]]&amp;quot; turning 80% of the peninsula into an island.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;Ward does not explain why the Hondius map shows a peninsula &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;and&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; an island while the theory has a peninsula &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;cut off&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; to form an island.{{cite article | publisher=Royal Geographical Society | magazine=Geographical Magazine | volume=VIII | month=July | year=1981 | page = 647}}&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

==Navigation==

Whale Cove remains an unnavigable bay in a dangerous part of the Oregon coast:  mariners are advised to stay at least 600 yards offshore for the distance one mile north of Whale Cove to one mile south of Whale Cove.  Whale Cove is not considered a usable bay by any size of vessel.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;Cape Foulweather is 1 NM south of Whale Cove.  &amp;quot;Dangers extend for nearly 2 miles N of the N point of Cape Foulweather and about 600 yards offshore.&amp;quot;  Whale Cove is not even mentioned as a place to be considered by mariners of any size of vessel.{{cite book | title=United States Coast Pilot 7:  Pacific Coast:  California, Oregon, Washington, and Hawaii | edition=Twenty-fifth Edition | publisher=U.S. Department of Commerce, National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, National Ocean Service | year=1989 | page=219}}&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;While Depoe Bay, one NM north of Whale Cove, &amp;quot;has a well-deserved reputation for having one of the most intimidating entrances of any west coast harbor,&amp;quot; the area of Whale Cove is a more-dangerous &amp;quot;stay clear&amp;quot; area for boaters and is marked &amp;quot;Foul.&amp;quot;  {{cite book | title=Charlie&amp;apos;s Charts of the U.S. Pacific Coast:  Seattle, Washington to San Diego, California including the Channel Islands | last1=Wood | first1=Charles | last2=Wood | first2=Margo | publisher=Charlie&amp;apos;s Charts | year=1995 | edition=second | page=53}}&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

==Footnotes==

&amp;lt;references /&amp;gt;

==Further reading==
*Samuel Bawlf, &amp;apos;&amp;apos;The Secret Voyage of Sir Francis Drake&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, Penguin Books, ISBN 0-14-200459-6

{{coord|44|47|19|N|124|4|17|W|scale:10000_region:US|display=title}}

[[Category:Coves of the United States]]
[[Category:Bodies of water of Oregon]]
[[Category:Pre-statehood history of Oregon]]
[[Category:Oregon Coast]]
[[Category:Landforms of Lincoln County, Oregon]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
