<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="InterNorth"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="InterNorth" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Unreferenced|date=February 2007}}
&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;InterNorth Inc.&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; was a very large energy company headquartered in [[Omaha, Nebraska]], in the [[United States]], specializing in [[natural gas]] pipelines but also a force in the [[plastics]] industry, coal and petroleum exploration and production. They operated the largest natural gas pipeline in North America. It was formed in 1979 as a [[holding company]] for [[Northern Natural Gas Company (founded in 1931)]], [[Northern Liquid Fuels Company]], [[Northern Petrochemicals Company]], [[Northern Propane Gas Company]], and [[Northern Border Pipeline Company]].  InterNorth was briefly renamed &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;HNG/InterNorth&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; in 1985, following its takeover of [[Houston Natural Gas]] Company, before taking the name [[Enron]] Corporation just six months later.

Later that year, the company launched an unsolicited takeover bid for &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Crouse-Hinds Company&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, which wound up being acquired by [[Cooper Industries]] the following year.  The company continued to pursue expansion opportunities and, in 1985, reached a deal, seen by some as overpriced, to acquire the smaller competitor [[Houston Natural Gas]] (HNG) Company.  InterNorth was an arbitrage target and acquired HNG as a [[Shareholder rights plan|poison pill]]. Regardless it was still a target of Irwin Jacobs of Minneapolis. Ex-HNG CEO Ken Lay &amp;quot;borrowed&amp;quot; over $400,000,000 from the [[employee stock ownership program]] to [[buy back]] Jacobs stock, so he could keep his job and cover other financial losses of Enron as early as 1987.  Lay then froze the ESOP for seven years except for retirement or death benefits.

Although intended to secure InterNorth&amp;apos;s independence, the HNG takeover proved a &amp;quot;wag-the-dog&amp;quot; transaction: despite an initial plan for dual headquarters in Omaha and Houston, with InterNorth CEO [[Samuel Segnar]] in control, the company soon was based entirely in [[Houston]] and run by HNG&amp;apos;s [[CEO]], [[Kenneth Lay]], who renamed the company [[Enron Corporation]].  Initially, Mr. Lay and his secretary, Nancy McNeil picked the name Enteron, due to the positive connotations of the words &amp;quot;enter&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;on&amp;apos;. though it was soon discovered to be a Greek term for digestive system or intestine.  The markets reacted with hilarity and a month later he changed the name again to ENRON costing many millions in advertising, signage, stationery and contracts.  Nancy McNeil is now married to [[Richard Kinder]] of [[Kinder Morgan]] who was the #2 executive of Enron before 1997.

The most valuable asset of Internorth had been Northern Natural Gas company which was at one time the largest natural gas distributor in North America.  After the bankruptcy of Enron, Northern Natural Gas briefly became part of Dynegy Corp of Houston whose Chairman Daniel Dienstbier had been president of NNG before Ken Lay seized control of Internorth.  [[Dynegy]] then sold NNG to [[Warren Buffett]]&amp;apos;s [[Berkshire Hathaway]] who moved it back to Omaha.

{{DEFAULTSORT:Internorth}}
[[Category:Enron]]
[[Category:Natural gas companies of the United States]]
[[Category:Companies based in Omaha, Nebraska]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
