<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Digital imaging technician"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Digital imaging technician" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;A &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;digital imaging technician&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (DIT) works in collaboration with a [[cinematographer]] on work flow, systemization, signal integrity and image manipulation to achieve the highest image quality and creative goals of cinematography in the digital realm.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;[http://www.digitalproductionme.com/article-718-4k__bane_or_blessing/2/ DigitalProductionME.com - 4K - Bane or blessing? - The role of the Digital Imaging Technician (DIT)]&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

A DIT&amp;apos;s role is especially prevalent with the widespread use of digital imaging technology, and to assist cinematographers normally accustomed to [[film stock]] in achieving their desired look. They may also be in charge of transferring and managing the image data, replacing the traditional [[film loader]] position.

The Digital Imaging (or Image) Technician is a relatively new position on a motion picture set.  The position was created as a response to the transition from the long established film medium into digital cinema, which utilizes various formats like HD, 2K, and 4K. Since video reacts much differently than film in many situations, the DIT&amp;apos;s job is to work with the cinematographer and help achieve the best results.  This includes but is not limited to: monitoring exposure, setting up &amp;quot;look up tables&amp;quot; (LUTs), set camera settings, and media management.

==References==
{{reflist}}

[[Category:Cinematography]]
[[Category:Digital art]]


{{filming-stub}}&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
