<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Reprisal"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Reprisal" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{about||the novel by F. Paul Wilson|Reprisal (novel)}}
:&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Not to be confused with a [[reprise]], or with a [[wikt:reappraisal|reappraisal]].&amp;apos;&amp;apos;
A &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;reprisal&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is a limited and deliberate violation of [[international law]] to punish another sovereign state that has already broken them.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;Karl Josef Partsch: Self-Preservation. EPIL IV (2000), pages 380-383&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt; Reprisals in the [[laws of war]] are extremely limited, as they commonly breached the rights of civilians, an action outlawed by the [[Geneva Conventions]]. It is not to be confused with [[retorsion]]s, as these constitute unfriendly acts generally permitted by international law.

==Etymology==
The word came from French, where it originally meant &amp;quot;act of taking back&amp;quot;, for example, raiding back the equivalent of cattle lost to an enemy raid.

==International law==
Reprisals refer to acts which are illegal if taken alone, but become legal when adopted by one state in retaliation for the commission of an earlier illegal act by another state.{{Citation needed|date=March 2012}} Counter-reprisals are generally not allowed.

An example of reprisal is the [[Naulila]]a dispute between [[Portugal]] and [[Germany]] in October 1914. After three Germans were mistakenly killed in Naulilaa on the border of the Portuguese colony of [[Angola]] (in a manner that did not violate international law),&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;http://www.legalaffairs.org/issues/January-February-2003/scene_giry_janfeb2003.msp&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt; Germany carried out a military raid on Naulilaa, destroying property in retaliation. A claim for compensation was brought by Portugal. The tribunal emphasized that before reprisals could be legally undertaken, a number of conditions had to be satisfied:
*There had to be a previous act by the other party that violated international law.
*Reprisals had to be preceded by an unsatisfied demand for reparation or compliance with the violated international law.
*There must be proportionality between the offence and reprisal.
The German claim that it had acted lawfully was rejected on all three grounds.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;{{cite book |title=International Law (6th edn) |last=Shaw |first=Malcolm |authorlink=Malcolm Shaw |year=2008 |publisher=Cambridge University Press |location=Cambridge |isbn=978-0-521-72814-0 |page=1129}}&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

After 1945, as a result of the general prohibition on use of force imposed by Article 2(4) of the [[UN Charter]], armed reprisals in time of peace are no longer legal, but the possibility remains of non-armed reprisals (also known as [[countermeasure]]s)&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;{{cite book |title=Principles of Public International Law (7th edn) |last=Brownlie |first=Ian |authorlink=Ian Brownlie |year=2008 |publisher=[[Oxford University Press]] |location=New York |isbn=978-0-19-921770-0 |page=466}}&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt; as well as belligerent reprisals during hostilities when the law of international armed conflict (LOIAC) is violated.&amp;lt;ref name=loiac&amp;gt;{{cite book |title=The Conduct of Hostilities under the Law of International Armed Conflict |last=Dinstein |first=Yôrām |authorlink=Yoram Dinstein|year=2004 |publisher=Cambridge University Press |location=Cambridge |isbn=0-521-54227-8 |page=220 |url=http://books.google.com/books?id=a88YJ7MuaMoC&amp;amp;printsec=frontcover&amp;amp;dq=the+conduct+of+hostilities+under+the+law+of+international+armed+conflict#v=onepage&amp;amp;q&amp;amp;f=false |accessdate=21 October 2010}}&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

In the case of belligerent reprisals, apart from the three factors in the Naulilaa case, a warning must also be issued beforehand; once the other party has stopped violation of LOIAC, belligerent reprisals must also be terminated; and the decision to engage in belligerent reprisals must be taken by a competent authority.&amp;lt;ref name=loiac/&amp;gt; In the [[United States military]], the lowest ranked commander who may authorize a reprisal is a [[general]] in command of a [[theater (warfare)|theater]].

All four Geneva Conventions prohibit reprisals against, respectively, battlefield casualties, [[shipwrecked|shipwreck survivors]], [[Prisoner of war|prisoners of war]] and [[civilian]]s, as well as certain buildings and property. An additional 1977 protocol extends this to cover historic monuments, works of art, and places of worship.

==See also==
*[[Collective punishment]]
*[[Letter of marque]] (license to hunt enemy ships and retake lost ships from the enemy).
*[[War]]

==References==
{{reflist}}

==External links==
{{wiktionary|reprisal}}
*[http://www.crimesofwar.org/a-z-guide/reprisal-killings/ crimes of war: 1944 reprisal by french partisans against german prisoners]

[[Category:Laws of war]]
[[Category:Collective punishment]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
