<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Office of Scientific Research and Development"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Office of Scientific Research and Development" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;The &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Office of Scientific Research and Development&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (OSRD) was an agency of the [[United States]] federal government created to coordinate scientific research for military purposes during [[World War II]]. Arrangements were made for its creation during May 1941, and it was created formally by [http://www.presidency.ucsb.edu/ws/index.php?pid=16137# Executive Order 8807] on June 28, 1941. It superseded the work of the [[National Defense Research Committee]] (NDRC), was given almost unlimited access to funding and resources, and was directed by [[Vannevar Bush]], who reported only to President [[Franklin Delano Roosevelt]].

The research was widely varied, and included projects devoted to new and more accurate [[bomb]]s, reliable detonators, work on the [[proximity fuze]], [[guided missile]]s, [[radar]] and early-warning systems, lighter and more accurate hand weapons, more effective medical treatments, more versatile vehicles, and, most secret of all, the &amp;quot;[[S-1 Uranium Committee|S-1 Section]]&amp;quot;, which later became the [[Manhattan Project]] and developed the first [[atomic weapon]]s.

==Human experimentation==
From October 1943 to October 1946, OSRD used [[conscientious objectors]] from [[Civilian Public Service]] as subjects for research of malaria, altitude pressure, life raft rations, high altitude, frostbite, psycho-acoustics, poison gas, ingestion of and exposure to sea water, temperature extremes, climate, physiological hygiene, thiamine, [[bed rest]] and aero medicine.

To study the effects of diet and nutrition, [[Ancel Keys|Dr. Ancel Keys]] of the [[University of Minnesota]] Laboratory of Physiological Hygiene placed 32 conscientious objectors on a controlled diet. For three months they were given a normal 3200 [[calorie]] diet. This was followed by six months of an 1800 calorie diet, fewer calories than provided by the famine diet experienced by the civilian population in wartime Europe. The research documented the men&amp;apos;s ability to maintain physical output and the psychological effects such as introversion, lethargy, irritability and severe depression. The study then studied the men&amp;apos;s recovery as they returned to a normal diet and regained the weight lost during the experimentation. The men indicated later they would not have volunteered for this project had they known how rigorous it would be.

The OSRD was discontinued during December 1947.

==External links==
*[http://www.loc.gov/rr/scitech/trs/trsosrd.html Office of Scientific Research and Development Collection] at [[Library of Congress]]. Original research conducted by the U.S. and Allies during World War II- includes technical reports, memos, drawings, etc.
*[http://history.sandiego.edu/gen/WW2Timeline/OSRD.html OSRD timeline]
*[http://www.archives.gov/research/guide-fed-records/groups/227.html Records of the OSRD at the National Archive]
*Stewart, Irvin. &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[http://www.archive.org/details/organizingscient00stew Organizing Scientific Research for War: The Administrative History of the Office of Scientific Research and Development].&amp;apos;&amp;apos; Boston: Little, Brown and Company, 1948.

{{DEFAULTSORT:Office Of Scientific Research And Development}}
[[Category:Agencies of the United States government during World War II]]
[[Category:Manhattan Project]]
[[Category:Nuclear history of the United States]]
[[Category:Research and development organizations]]
[[Category:Government agencies established in 1941]]
[[Category:Research and development in the United States]]


{{World-War-II-stub}}&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
