<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Jack-in-the-box"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Jack-in-the-box" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{otheruses}}
{{multiple image
| align     = right
| direction = vertical
| width     = 220

| image1    = Jack-in-the-box.jpg
| alt1      =
| caption1  = A jack-in-the-box

| image2    = Jack-in-the-box 1863 Harpers.png
| alt2      =
| caption2  = Two boys playing with a jack-in-the-box in an 1863 illustration
}}
A &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;jack-in-the-box&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is a [[child]]ren&amp;apos;s [[toy]] that outwardly consists of a box with a crank.&amp;lt;ref name=&amp;quot;Sobey2008&amp;quot;/&amp;gt; When the crank is turned, it plays a [[melody]], often &amp;quot;[[Pop Goes the Weasel]]&amp;quot;. At the end of the tune there is a &amp;quot;surprise&amp;quot;:&amp;lt;ref name=&amp;quot;Hayes2012&amp;quot;/&amp;gt; the lid pops open and a figure, usually a [[clown]] or [[jester]], pops out of the box. Some jack-in-the-boxes open at random times when cranked, making the startle even more effective.

==Origin==
A theory as to the origin of the jack-in-the-box is that it comes from the 13th century [[England|English]] [[prelate]] [[John Schorne|Sir John Schorne]],&amp;lt;ref name=&amp;quot;Vince2008&amp;quot;/&amp;gt; who is often pictured holding a [[boot]] with a [[devil]] in it. According to [[folklore]], he once cast the devil into a boot to protect the village of [[North Marston]] in [[Buckinghamshire]]. This theory may explain why in French, a jack-in-the-box is called a &amp;quot;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;diable en boîte&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;quot; (literally &amp;quot;boxed devil&amp;quot;).

1500s
One of the earliest documented jack-in-the-boxes was made by a German clock maker in the early 1500s. It was a gift for the son of a local Prince on the boy&amp;apos;s fifth birthday. A plain wooden box with metal edges and a crank handle, it played a simple tune and the &amp;apos;jack&amp;apos; was a comical devil with a &amp;apos;leering smile&amp;apos;--according to a pamphlet published by the Nuremburg Toy Museum. When other nobles requested a &amp;quot;Devil-in-a box&amp;quot; for their own children, a trend took off that continues to this day.

1700s
Improved toy mechanisms in the 18th century allowed the toy to be more easily produced. Not just for royalty any longer, the toy became a common plaything. The image of the jack/devil in a box became a popular cartoonists image for poking fun at politicians. This caused jack-in-the-boxes to be made for adults with the &amp;apos;jack&amp;apos; being a caricature of some politician of the day.

Origins
The most widely accepted theory about the origin of the jack-in-the-box relates the toy to an English churchman from the 13th century, Sir John Schorne. Folklore credits Sir John with casting a devil into a boot to protect the Buckinghamshire village of North Marston. There are engravings from that era of Sir John holding a boot with a devil peeking out the top, which may have inspired the medieval toy makers.

Jesters and More
Sometime during the Renaissance, Jesters began to replace devils as the popular pop-up figure inside the box. In the 1930s and 1940s, jack-in-the-box toys that had boxes made from stamped tin became quite popular. They were lighter weight and easier to mass-produce. Many boxes had nursery rhyme themes, thus a box might play the tune &amp;quot;Mary Had a Little Lamb&amp;quot; and the &amp;apos;jack&amp;apos; would be a lamb. Clown-like figures still remain very popular jack-in-the-box inhabitants, even though modern &amp;apos;jacks&amp;apos; can be anything form dragons or bears to pirates or ninjas.

Surprising Popularity
The Encyclopedia of American Folk Art credits the element of surprise for the enduring popularity of the jack-in-the-box. For some reason, people continue to be amused and delighted by the toy, even once they know what will happen when they turn the crank. Perhaps the suspense of the randomly triggered pop-up provides enough entertainment for the child in everyone.

==References==
{{Reflist|refs=
&amp;lt;ref name=&amp;quot;Sobey2008&amp;quot;&amp;gt;{{Citation
 | first1    = Ed
 | last1     = Sobey
 | first2    = Woody
 | last2     = Sobey
 | title     = The Way Toys Work: The Science Behind the Magic 8 Ball, Etch a Sketch, Boomerang, and More
 | publisher = Chicago Review Press
 | page      = 71
 | year      = 2008
 | isbn      = 1613743092
 | url       = http://books.google.com/books?id=F2ApK7QnbPUC&amp;amp;pg=PA71
 | postscript= .
}}&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

&amp;lt;ref name=&amp;quot;Hayes2012&amp;quot;&amp;gt;{{Citation
 | first1    = Justin Cord
 | last1     = Hayes
 | title     = The Unexpected Evolution of Language: Discover the Surprising Etymology of Everyday Words
 | publisher = Adams Media
 | page      = 106
 | year      = 2012
 | isbn      = 1440542791
 | url       = http://books.google.com/books?id=1V__EEFEwbcC&amp;amp;pg=PT106
 | postscript= .
}}&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

&amp;lt;ref name=&amp;quot;Vince2008&amp;quot;&amp;gt;{{Citation
 | first1    = John
 | last1     = Vince
 | title     = Discovering Saints in Britain
 | edition   = 3rd
 | publisher = Osprey Publishing
 | page      = 29
 | year      = 2008
 | isbn      = 0747804753
 | url       = http://books.google.com/books?id=pij89MWD_lYC&amp;amp;pg=PA29
 | postscript= .
}}&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;
}}

==External links==
{{commons category inline|Jack-in-the-box}}

{{DEFAULTSORT:Jack-In-The-Box}}
[[Category:Traditional toys]]

{{Toy-stub}}&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
