<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="John H. Stracey"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="John H. Stracey" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{BLP sources|date=July 2012}}
&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;John H. Stracey&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (born September 22, 1950 in [[Bethnal Green]], England) is a former professional [[Boxing|boxer]] who was world [[Welterweight]] champion.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;{{cite book|last=Phillips|first=Neil|title=Doctor to the world champions : my autobiography|year=2007|publisher=Trafford|location=Victoria, BC|isbn=9781425112615|pages=579-|url=http://books.google.com/books?id=Hky42XmoBZcC&amp;amp;pg=PA579&amp;amp;lpg=PA579&amp;amp;dq=John+H.+Stracey&amp;amp;source=bl&amp;amp;ots=MfUFcv1M20&amp;amp;sig=1UL7F_E9Pap1XN0SKPVds3X3vmU&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ei=caUBUP_WJYLY2AW-_53ACw&amp;amp;ved=0CDkQ6AEwAQ#v=onepage&amp;amp;q=John%20H.%20Stracey&amp;amp;f=false}}&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;  He also had, at one point, a boxing school in London.

==1969==
Stracey began his professional career on September 17, 1969, knocking out Santos Martins in two rounds. Stracey won his first twelve fights, eleven by knockout, but against obscure opposition. Fight number thirteen was against Teddy Cooper, on January 19, 1971. Cooper was not a big name in boxing either, but this fight ended in controversy when Stracey won by a fifth round disqualification. On October 5 of 1971, Stracey drew (tied) in ten rounds against Frankie Lewis.

==1972==
Stracey had five more wins in a row before being matched with Marshall Butler, on May 25, 1972. Stracey suffered his first defeat when outpointed by Butler over ten rounds. He then put a string of four more wins before facing Bobby Arthur for the British Welterweight title on Halloween night, 1972. He lost the fight for the regional title with another controversial ending: This time, Stracey found himself disqualified, in round seven. Stracey then won five more in a row, and he met Arthur in a rematch on June 5, 1973, this time winning the title with a fourth round knockout of Arthur.

==1974==
After five more wins and another loss, Stracey had his first fight abroad, fighting Roger Menetrey in [[Paris, France]] at the [[Stade de Roland Garros]], on May 27, 1974. The fight was for the European Welterweight title, and Stracey proceeded to win that belt with an eighth round knockout.

During the 1970s, it was a common practice in boxing to give world title shots to boxers that held continental titles. For example, the OPBF (Oriental Pacific Boxing Federation) champion would be given priority over other challengers for world title fights. Stracey was not the exception, and, after winning five more fights in a row (including a win over [[Ernie Lopez]]), he received his first world title shot: challenging [[World Boxing Council|WBC]] World Welterweight champion [[José Nápoles]] in Nápoles&amp;apos; home-town of [[Mexico City|Mexico City, Mexico]], Stracey was sent down in round one, but he recuperated to close Nápoles&amp;apos; eye and have referee [[Octavio Meyran]] stop the fight in the sixth round, Stracey winning the world championship by a technical knockout. The new champion declared &amp;quot;he could have knocked me down in every round but I&amp;apos;d have won it anyway&amp;quot;. It was Nápoles&amp;apos; last fight.

==1976==
On March 20 of 1976, he retained the title against perennial world title challenger [[Hedgemon Lewis]] by a knockout in round ten, but on June 22, at [[Wembley Arena|Wembley]], he lost the world title, being knocked out in twelve rounds by [[California]] based Mexican [[Carlos Palomino]].

In his next fight, he lost to future  world championship challenger &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Dave Boy Green]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, with a badly damaged eye in round ten.

==1978==
Stracey retired as a winner, when he knocked out George Warusfel in nine rounds at [[Islington]], May 23 of 1978.

==Current==
Stracey currently does [[autograph]] and private speaking tours with friends and fellow former world champions [[Alan Minter]], [[Lloyd Honeyghan]], [[Jim Watt (boxer)|Jim Watt]] and [[John Conteh]], among others.

==Record==
He had a career record of 45 wins, 5 losses and 1 draw, with 37 [[knockout]]s.

==Public house==
There is a Public House in the Village of [[Briston]], Norfolk called the John H Stracey in tribute to the boxer.

John also owned a hotel in [[Bournemouth]].

{{s-start}}
{{s-sports}}
{{Succession box|
 before=[[José Nápoles]]|
 title=[[WBC Welterweight Champion]]|
 after=[[Carlos Palomino]]|
 years=6 Dec 1975–22 Jun 1976
}}
{{s-end}}

== See also ==
* [[List of British welterweight boxing champions]]
* [[List of WBC world champions]]

==References==
{{Reflist}}

== External links ==
* [http://www.boxrec.com/boxer_display.php?boxer_id=012567 John H. Stracey&amp;apos;s career boxing record]

{{Persondata &amp;lt;!-- Metadata: see [[Wikipedia:Persondata]]. --&amp;gt;
| NAME              = Stracey, John H.
| ALTERNATIVE NAMES =
| SHORT DESCRIPTION = British boxer
| DATE OF BIRTH     = September 22, 1950
| PLACE OF BIRTH    =
| DATE OF DEATH     =
| PLACE OF DEATH    =
}}
{{DEFAULTSORT:Stracey, John H.}}
[[Category:1950 births]]
[[Category:Living people]]
[[Category:Welterweight boxers]]
[[Category:World boxing champions]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
