<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Hecatomb"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Hecatomb" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{For|the collectible card game|Hecatomb (card game)}}
In [[Ancient Greece]], a &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;hecatomb&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; ({{IPAc-en|ˈ|h|ɛ|k|ə|t|uː|m}} or {{IPAc-en|ˈ|h|ɛ|k|ə|t|oʊ|m}}; {{lang-grc|ἑκατόμβη}} &amp;apos;&amp;apos;hekatómbē&amp;apos;&amp;apos;) was a sacrifice to the gods of 100 cattle (&amp;apos;&amp;apos;hekaton&amp;apos;&amp;apos; = one hundred). Hecatombs were offered to Greek gods [[Apollo]], [[Athena]], and [[Hera]], during special religious ceremonies.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;{{fr icon}} [http://dagr.univ-tlse2.fr/sdx/dagr/feuilleter.xsp?tome=3&amp;amp;partie=1&amp;amp;numPage=57&amp;amp;nomEntree=HEKATOMBAIA Le Dictionnaire des Antiquités Grecques et Romaines de Daremberg et Saglio (consultation de l&amp;apos;ensemble du corpus)]&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

In the &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Iliad]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos; hecatombs are described formulaically.  The following is one instance, from [[Samuel Butler (novelist)|Samuel Butler]]&amp;apos;s translation:

:[T]hey ranged the holy hecatomb all orderly round the altar of the god. They washed their hands and took up the barley-meal to sprinkle over the victims [cattle], while [the priest] lifted up his hands and prayed aloud on their behalf.
:...
:When they had done praying and sprinkling the barley-meal, they drew back the heads of the victims (Cattle) and killed and [[flaying|flayed]] them. They cut out the thigh-bones, wrapped them round in two layers of fat, set some pieces of raw meat on the top of them, and then [the priest] laid them on the wood fire and poured wine over them, while the young men stood near him with five-pronged spits in their hands. When the thigh-bones were burned and they had tasted the inward meats, they cut the rest up small, put the pieces upon the spits, roasted them till they were done, and drew them off: then, when they had finished their work and the feast was ready, they ate it, and every man had his full share, so that all were satisfied. As soon as they had had enough to eat and drink, pages filled the mixing-bowl with wine and water and handed it round, after giving every man his drink-offering.

:Thus all day long the young men worshipped the god with song, hymning him and chaunting the joyous paean, and the god took pleasure in their voices[.]

==See also==
{{Wiktionary}}
*[[Fire sacrifice]]

==References==
{{reflist}}

[[Category:Greek animal sacrifice]]
[[Category:Greek words and phrases]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
