<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="James Harrison Rigg"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="James Harrison Rigg" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;James Harrison Rigg&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (16 January 1821 – 7 April 1909), English nonconformist [[Anglicanism#Anglican divines|divine]], was born at [[Newcastle-on-Tyne]].

His father was a [[Methodism|Wesleyan]] minister and sent his son to the Old Kingswood School, Bristol, where he subsequently became an assistant teacher. In 1845 he entered the Wesleyan ministry, and during the agitation of 1849-52 wrote successfully in exposition and defence of the polity of [[Methodism]]. In 1857 he published &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Modern Anglican Theology&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, an acute criticism of the writings of [[Samuel Taylor Coleridge|Coleridge]], [[Julius Charles Hare|Hare]], [[John Frederick Denison Maurice|Maurice]], [[Charles Kingsley|Kingsley]] and [[Benjamin Jowett|Jowett]]. The book was timely and well received, and though Kingsley at first resented the criticism he afterwards became a cordial friend of the writer.

Rigg had now become a leading figure in his own church, and in 1868 was appointed Principal of the Westminster Wesleyan Training College for day-school teachers, a post which he held with growing distinction for 35 years. In 1870 he was elected on the first [[London School Board|School Board for London]], one of the most remarkable assemblies of modern times, and took an important part in providing the syllabus of religious instruction and framing the religious settlement for teachers.

In 1873 he wrote &amp;apos;&amp;apos;National Education in its Social Conditions and Aspects.&amp;apos;&amp;apos; A resolute opponent of secular education, he maintained that the state ought not to compete with the churches, but welcome their aid in the work of national education. He was also strongly against the adoption of a rigid universal code. In 1886 he sat on the Royal Commission of Education, and was brought into close contact with [[Matthew Arnold]], and with [[Arthur Penrhyn Stanley|Dean Stanley]], [[Frederick Temple|Bishop Temple]] and other [[Anglican Church|Anglican]] prelates, who held him in high esteem. In 1877 he became chairman of the second London district of Methodism, and for fourteen years helped to make the history of his church in the home counties.

In 1878 he was elected [[:Category:Presidents of the Methodist Conference|president of conference]]--and again in 1892. From 1881 he was ministerial treasurer of the Wesleyan Missionary Society, taking an active part in its work. He resigned his principalship in 1903 and died at [[Brixton]] on 7 April 1909.

Dr. Rigg was universally honoured as the [[:wikt:nestor|Nestor]] of Wesleyan Methodism, in the development of which he had taken a foremost part for over 60 years. His &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Connexional Economy&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is a standard work, and his &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Living Wesley&amp;apos;&amp;apos; a most discriminating study of the character and work of its subject. His &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Oxford High Anglicanism&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (1895) showed how keenly he followed modern developments in the [[Church of England]]. His lifelong principle was that Methodism is &amp;quot;a church friendly to all, but owing allegiance to none.&amp;quot;

==References==
*&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Life&amp;apos;&amp;apos; by [[John Telford]] (London, 1909).
*{{1911}}

&amp;lt;!--what other categories?--&amp;gt;

{{Authority control|VIAF=30381364|LCCN=no/89/017844}}
{{Persondata &amp;lt;!-- Metadata: see [[Wikipedia:Persondata]]. --&amp;gt;
| NAME              = Rigg, James Harrison
| ALTERNATIVE NAMES =
| SHORT DESCRIPTION =
| DATE OF BIRTH     = 16 January 1821
| PLACE OF BIRTH    =
| DATE OF DEATH     = 7 April 1909
| PLACE OF DEATH    =
}}
{{DEFAULTSORT:Rigg, James Harrison}}
[[Category:1821 births]]
[[Category:1909 deaths]]
[[Category:Members of the London School Board]]
[[Category:Presidents of the Methodist Conference]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
