<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Control unit"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Control unit" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{About|the component of a computer&amp;apos;s CPU}}
{{Multiple issues|refimprove = June 2008|cleanup = June 2008|expert=Computing|date=November 2008}}

The &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;control unit&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; coordinates the components of a computer system. It fetches the code of all of the instructions in the program.
It directs the operation of the other units by providing timing and control signals.
All computer resources are managed by the CU. It directs the flow of data between the Central Processing Unit (CPU) and the other devices.

The control unit was historically &amp;lt;!-- reluctant to write &amp;quot;first&amp;quot; for &amp;quot;historically&amp;quot; without further research which, sorry, I&amp;apos;m not bothering about right now --&amp;gt; defined as one distinct part of the 1946 reference model of [[Von Neumann architecture]]. In modern computer designs, the control unit is typically an internal part of the [[Central processing unit|CPU]]&amp;lt;!-- or other device that directs its operation--&amp;gt; with its overall role and operation unchanged.

The control unit is the circuitry that controls the flow of data through the processor, and coordinates the activities of the other units within it. In a way, it is the &amp;quot;brain within the brain&amp;quot;, as it controls what happens inside the processor, which in turn controls the rest of the computer.
The examples of devices that require a control unit are CPUs and graphics processing units (GPUs). The control unit receives external instructions or commands which it converts into a sequence of control signals that the control unit applies to the data path to implement a sequence of [[register-transfer level]] operations.

== Hardwired control unit ==&amp;lt;!-- Front end processor redirects here --&amp;gt;

Hardwired control units are implemented through use of [[sequential logic]] units, featuring a finite number of gates that can generate specific results based on the instructions that were used to invoke those responses. Hardwired  control units are generally faster than microprogrammed designs.

Their design uses a fixed architecture &amp;amp;mdash; it requires changes in the wiring if the [[instruction set]] is modified or changed.
This architecture is preferred in [[Reduced instruction set computing|reduced instruction
set computer]]s (RISC) as they use a simpler instruction set.

A controller that uses this approach can operate at high speed. However, it has little flexibility, and the complexity of the instruction set it can implement is limited.

The hardwired approach has become less popular as computers have evolved as at one time, control units for CPUs were ad-hoc logic, and they were difficult to design.

== Microprogram control unit ==
{{main|Microcode}}

The idea of microprogramming was introduced by [[Maurice Wilkes]] in 1951 as an intermediate level to execute computer program instructions. Microprograms were organized as a sequence of &amp;apos;&amp;apos;microinstructions&amp;apos;&amp;apos; and stored in special control memory. The algorithm for the microprogram control unit is usually specified by [[flowchart]] description.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;{{Cite book  | last1 = Barkalov | first1 = Alexander | title = Logic synthesis for FSM based control units / Alexander Barkalov and Larysa Titarenko | year = 2009 | publisher = Springer | location = Berlin | isbn = 978-3-642-04308-6 | pages =  }}&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt; The main advantage of the microprogram control unit is the simplicity of its structure. Outputs of the controller are organized in microinstructions and  they can be easily replaced.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;{{Cite book  | last1 = Wiśniewski | first1 = Remigiusz | title = Synthesis of compositional microprogram control units for programmable devices   | year = 2009 | publisher = University of Zielona Góra | location = Zielona Góra | isbn = 978-83-7481-293-1 | pages = 153 }}&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

== Functions of the control unit ==
The control unit implements the [[instruction set]] of the CPU. It performs the tasks of fetching, decoding, managing execution and then storing results. It may manage the translation of instructions (not data) to micro-instructions and manage scheduling the micro-instructions between the various execution units. On some processors the control unit may be further broken down into other units, such as a scheduling unit to handle scheduling and a retirement unit to deal with results coming from the pipeline; It is the main function of CPU.

== See also ==
*[[CPU design]]
*[[Computer architecture]]
*[[Richards controller]]
*[[Controller (computing)]]

==References==
{{reflist}}

{{CPU technologies}}

{{DEFAULTSORT:Control Unit}}
[[Category:Central processing unit]]
[[Category:Digital electronics]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
