<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Edict of Gülhane"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Edict of Gülhane" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;The Hatt-i Sharif (Hatt-ı Şerif) of the [[Gülhane Park|Gülhane]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; &amp;apos;&amp;apos;(Imperial Edict of the Rose House)&amp;apos;&amp;apos; or &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Tanzimat|Tanzimât]] Fermânı&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; &amp;apos;&amp;apos;(Imperial Edict of Reorganization)&amp;apos;&amp;apos; was an 1839 proclamation by [[Ottoman Empire|Ottoman]] [[Sultan]] [[Abdülmecid I]] that launched the [[Tanzimat|Tanzimât]] period of reforms and reorganization.

The proclamation was issued at the behest of reformist [[Grand Vizier]] [[Koca Mustafa Reşid Pasha|Mustafa Reshid Pasha]]. It promised reforms such as the abolition of [[tax farming]], reform of [[conscription]], and guarantee of rights to all Ottoman citizens regardless of religion or ethnic group.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;{{cite book |title=A History of the Modern Middle East |first1=William L |last1=Cleveland |first2=Martin |last2=Bunton |edition=4th |publisher=Westview Press |year=2009 |page=83}}&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt; The goal of the decree was to help modernize the empire militarily and socially so that it could compete with the [[Great Power]]s of [[Europe]]. It also was hoped the reforms would win over the disaffected parts of the empire, especially in the Ottoman controlled parts of Europe, which were largely [[Christian]].
[[File:Mustafa reshid pasha.jpg|thumb|200px|[[Koca Mustafa Reşid Pasha|Great Mustapha Rashid Pasha]] &amp;lt;br/&amp;gt; Principal architect of the &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Tanzimat|Tanzimât تنظيمات]] Hatt-i Sharif of [[Gülhane Park|Gülhane]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; &amp;lt;br/&amp;gt; &amp;apos;&amp;apos;( The Ottoman Imperial Edict of Reorganization, proclaimed on November 3rd, 1839 )&amp;apos;&amp;apos;.]]

==Clauses==

Some of the most important clauses are as follows:

* In the future, the case of every accused party will be tried publicly, in conformity with our divine law. Until a regular sentence has been pronounced, no one can put another to death, secretly or publicly, by poison or any other form of punishment.
* No one will be permitted to assail the honour of any one, whosoever he may be.
* Every person will enjoy the possession of his property of every nature, and dispose of it with the most perfect liberty, without any one being able to impede him. Thus, for example, the innocent heirs of a criminal will not be deprived of their legal rights, and the property of the criminal will not be confiscated.
* These imperial concessions extend to all our subjects, whatever religion or sect they may belong to; and they will enjoy them without any exception.
* Perfect security is, therefore, granted by us to the inhabitants of the empire, with regard to their life, their honor, and their fortune, as the sacred text of our law demands.
* With reference to the other points, as they must be regulated the concurrence of enlightened opinions, our Council of Justice (augmented by as many new members as may deemed necessary), to whom will be adjoined, on certain days which we shall appoint our Ministers and the notables of the empire, will meet for the purpose of establishing the fundamental laws on those points relating to the security of life and property, and the imposition of the taxes. Every one in these assemblies will state his ideas freely, and &amp;quot;give his advice freely.&amp;quot;
* The laws relating to the regulations of the military service will be discussed by the Military Council, holding its meetings at the Place of the Seraskier. As soon as a law is decided upon, it will be presented to us, and in order that it may be eternally valid and applicable will confirm it by our sanction, written above it with our imperial hand.
* As these present institutions are solely intended for the regeneration of religion, government, the nation, and the Empire, we to do nothing which may be opposed to them.

==See also==
*[[Tanzimat|Tanzimât Era]] (3 November 1839 - 22 November 1876)
*[[Hatt-ı Hümayun]] (18 February 1856)

==References==
===Sources===
* Incorporates text from &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[History of Ottoman Turks]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (1878)
* [[Edward Shepherd Creasy]], &amp;apos;&amp;apos;History of Ottoman Turks; From the beginning of their empire to the present time,&amp;apos;&amp;apos; 2 vols., London, Richard Bentley (1854-6); (1878); Beirut, Khayats (1961).

===Notes===
{{reflist}}

[[Category:Politics of the Ottoman Empire|Hatt-i Sharif]]
[[Category:Ottoman law]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
