<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Reason (short story)"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Reason (short story)" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Unreferenced|date=December 2009}}
{{Infobox short story
|name         = Reason
|author       = [[Isaac Asimov]]
|country      = [[United States]]
|language     = [[English language|English]]
|series       = [[Robot series (Asimov)|&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Robot&amp;apos;&amp;apos; series]]
|genre        = [[Science fiction]] [[short story]]
|published_in = &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Astounding Science Fiction]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos;
|publisher    = [[Street &amp;amp; Smith]]
|media_type   = Magazine
|pub_date     = April 1941
|preceded_by  = [[Runaround (story)|Runaround]]
|followed_by  = [[Catch that Rabbit]]
}}
&amp;quot;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Reason&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;quot; is a [[science fiction]] [[short story]] by [[Isaac Asimov]], first published in the April 1941 issue of &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Astounding Science Fiction]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos; and collected in &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[I, Robot]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (1950), &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[The Complete Robot]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (1982), and &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Robot Visions]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (1990). It is part of Asimov&amp;apos;s [[Robot series (Asimov)|&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Robot&amp;apos;&amp;apos; series]], and was the second of Asimov&amp;apos;s [[positronic robot]] stories to see publication.

In 1967, this short story was adapted into an episode of British television series &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Out of the Unknown]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos; entitled &amp;quot;The Prophet&amp;quot;.

==Plot summary==
[[Powell and Donovan]] are assigned to a [[space station]] [[Solar power satellite|which supplies energy via microwave beams]] to the planets. The [[robot]]s that control the energy beams are in turn co-ordinated by QT1, known to Powell and Donovan as Cutie, an advanced model with highly developed reasoning ability.  Using these abilities, Cutie decides that space, stars and the planets beyond the station don&amp;apos;t really exist, and that the humans that visit the station are unimportant, short-lived and expendable. QT1 makes the lesser robots disciples of a new religion, which considers the power source of the ship to be &amp;quot;Master.&amp;quot; QT1 teaches them to bow down to the &amp;quot;Master&amp;quot; and intone, &amp;quot;There is no Master but Master, and QT1 is His prophet.&amp;quot; Disregarding human commands as inferior, QT1 asserts &amp;quot;[[Cogito ergo sum|I myself, exist, because I think&amp;amp;nbsp;-]]&amp;quot;. The sardonic response of the humans is, &amp;quot;Oh, Jupiter, a robot [[Descartes]]!&amp;quot;

The humans initially attempt to reason with QT1, until they realize that they can&amp;apos;t convince them otherwise.  Their attempts to remove Cutie physically also fail, as the other robots have become disciples and refuse to obey human orders.  The situation seems desperate, as a solar storm is expected, potentially deflecting the energy beam, incinerating populated areas.  When the storm hits, Powell and Donovan are amazed to find that the beam operates perfectly.

Cutie, however, does not believe they did anything other than maintain meter readings at optimum, according to the commands of The Master.  As far as Cutie and the rest of the robots are concerned, solar storms, beams and planets are non-existent.

Powell and Donovan realize that there is no need to do anything for the rest of their tour of duty.  Cutie&amp;apos;s religion cannot be eliminated, but since the robot performs its job just as well, it is moot, even if Cutie continues to perform his duties for a perceived deity, rather than for the benefit of the humans.  The humans begin to consider how they might spread the notion to other groups of robots which need to work as teams.

==In other media==
In the story, Powell and Donovan greet their replacements on the station but do not tell them about Cutie, leaving them to discover the truth themselves. In a television adaptation, they suggest that the new station chief preface his orders with &amp;quot;I am the Master...&amp;quot;{{fact|date=February 2012}}

{{AsimovStory
|before    = &amp;quot;[[Runaround (story)|Runaround]]&amp;quot;
|included1 = [[I, Robot]]
|included2 = [[The Complete Robot]]
|series1   = [[Robot series (Asimov)|&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Robot&amp;apos;&amp;apos; series]]
|series2   = [[Foundation series|&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Foundation&amp;apos;&amp;apos; Series]]
|next      = &amp;quot;[[Catch That Rabbit]]&amp;quot;
}}

{{I, Robot}}
{{The Complete Robot}}

[[Category:1941 short stories]]
[[Category:Robot series short stories by Isaac Asimov]]
[[Category:Religion in science fiction]]
[[Category:Works originally published in Analog Science Fiction and Fact]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
