<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Voyage of the Scarlet Queen"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Voyage of the Scarlet Queen" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{lead too long|date=May 2012}}
{{unreferenced|date=May 2012}}
&amp;lt;!--  Commented out: [[Image:Elliottlewis.jpg|right|thumb|150px|Elliott Lewis]] --&amp;gt;
&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Voyage of the Scarlet Queen&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; was a radio adventure on the high seas, airing on Mutual from 3 July 1947 to 14 February 1948. James Burton produced the scripts by Gil Doud and Robert Tallman. [[Elliott Lewis (radio)|Elliott Lewis]] starred as Philip Carney, master of the 78-foot [[ketch]] &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Scarlet Queen&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, with Ed Max as first mate Red Gallagher.

The show seems to foreshadow &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Star Trek]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos; in a number of ways. Each episode opens with an entry from the ship&amp;apos;s log: &amp;quot;Log entry, the [[ketch]] &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Scarlet Queen&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, Philip Carney, master. Position -- three degrees, seven minutes north, 104 degrees, two minutes east. Wind, fresh to moderate; sky, fair...&amp;quot; with a similar closing: &amp;quot;Ship secured for the night. Signed, Philip Carney, master.&amp;quot; Arriving at an exotic [[port of call]], the captain and first mate would go ashore and immediately run into trouble with local authorities, agents of rival merchants, or desperate women in need of rescue. After some investigation and at least one good fight they would solve the problem, get back on the ship and sail away, Carney and Gallagher sharing a laugh and a drink at the wheel before the captain&amp;apos;s closing log entry.

Technically the show was among the better radio productions of the time, employing realistic sound effects and sailing terminology, well paced stories and colorfully detailed settings. Most places visited by the &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Queen&amp;apos;&amp;apos; are real. Even the map coordinates given by the captain are mostly accurate, following a zigzag course around the South Pacific.

After the show was cancelled, an attempt was made to revive it under a different name.  Unfortunately, only the audition show was produced which was not picked up.  The new show&amp;apos;s title was to be &amp;quot;The Log Of The Black Parrot&amp;quot;.  The cast included Ed Max, Ted Osborne, Lillian Buyeff, Harold Hughes, [[Jack Kruschen]], and Ben Wright.  Music was directed by Walter Schumann and composed by Nathan Scott.  The audition was produced by the star of Scarlet Queen, Elliot Lewis and directed by Gil Doud.  The announcer was Bob Stevenson.  It was recorded on May 6, 1950.

A [[TV pilot]] was made in 1975 loosely based on the same concept, titled &amp;quot;The Log of the Black Pearl,&amp;quot; which likewise included Jack Kruschen in the cast, co-starring with [[Ralph Bellamy]] and [[Kiel Martin]], with [[Jack Webb]] as executive producer.

==Listen to==
*[http://www.otr.net/?p=vosq OTR Network Library: &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Voyage of the Scarlet Queen&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (33 episodes)]
*[http://www.archive.org/details/VoyageOfTheScarletQueen Internet Archive: &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Voyage of the Scarlet Queen&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (32 episodes, mp3 format)]

==External links==

[[Category:American radio drama]]
[[Category:1940s American radio programs]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
