<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Tâmega River"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Tâmega River" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{unreferenced|date=December 2007}}

[[Image:Madalena.jpg|thumb|The Tâmega in Chaves]]

The &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Tâmega&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; ({{IPA-pt|ˈtɐmɨɣɐ|lang}}) or &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Támega&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; ({{IPA-es|ˈtameɣa|lang}}) is an international river belonging to Spain and Portugal. The river begins its course near [[Verín]], [[Galicia (Spain)|Galicia]] flowing south to [[Portugal]], in the historical provinces of [[Trás-os-Montes Province|Trás-os-Montes]] and [[Douro Litoral]].

[[Image:Tamegaatdusk.jpg|thumb|right|The Tâmega as it passes through Chaves.]]
The Tâmega River is a tributary of the [[Douro River]]. From [[Verín]] it flows south to Portuguese city of Chaves, then it flows through a fertile valley called the Veiga. Below Chaves the river narrows to pass through mountains and valleys. Owing to low water level and frequent small dams it is not navigable, passing through the cities of [[Amarante, Portugal|Amarante]] and [[Marco de Canaveses]], flowing in the [[Douro River]], near Entre-os-Rios: in fact Entre-os-Rios means between the rivers.

The Tâmega is more important historically than economically. It has always served as an invasion route for foreign armies intent on reaching the richer southern lands of Portugal. The valley around [[Chaves, Portugal|Chaves]] has especially seen its share of battles and invading armies.

Unfortunately, like many rivers today, the Tâmega suffers from pollution and the ravages of sand and gravel extraction companies. The quality of the water has deteriorated greatly. Another problem is the periodic occurrence of flooding. At the time of writing these problems have not been addressed.

Since the completion of the Torrão Damn in 1988, situated less than 1&amp;amp;nbsp;km from the outlet into the Douro river and the town of [[Entre-os-Rios]] in the municipality of Marco de Canaveses, the Tâmega has been slowly recovering from the effects of pollution. Sand extraction activities have been prohibited and many upstream cities installed modern sewage treatment plants.  A new dam is planned between the city of [[Amarante, Portugal|Amarante]] and the town of [[Mondim de Basto]]. Besides producing electricity, the project will have feature a flood control system that will divert the waterflow towards the smaller [[Olo River]].

== Transport ==

The [[Tâmega line]], which closed in 2009, was a [[narrow gauge]] railway line which closely followed the river.

== See also ==
* [[List of rivers of Spain]]

== External links ==
{{Commons category|Tâmega river}}

{{coord|41.082|N|8.293|W|display=title|source:ptwiki}}

{{DEFAULTSORT:Tamega}}
[[Category:Rivers of Portugal]]
[[Category:Rivers of Galicia]]
[[Category:International rivers of Europe]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
