<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Gastrectomy"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Gastrectomy" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Interventions infobox |
  Name        = Gastrectomy |
  Image       = Illu stomach.jpg |
  Caption     = Diagram of the stomach, showing the different regions. |
  ICD10       = |
  ICD9        = {{ICD9proc|43.5}}-{{ICD9proc|43.9}} |
  MeshID      = D005743 |
  MedlinePlus = 002945 |
  OtherCodes  = |
}}
A &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;gastrectomy&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is a partial or full surgical removal of the [[stomach]].

==Indications==
Gastrectomies are performed to treat cancer and perforations of the stomach wall.

In severe duodenal ulcers it may be necessary to remove the lower portion of the stomach called the [[pylorus]] and the upper portion of the [[small intestine]] called the [[duodenum]].  If there is a sufficient portion of the upper duodenum remaining a [[Billroth I procedure]] is performed, where the remaining portion of the stomach is reattached to the duodenum before the [[bile duct]] and the duct of the [[pancreas]].  If the stomach cannot be reattached to the duodenum a [[Billroth II]] is performed, where the remaining portion of the duodenum is sealed off, a hole is cut into the next section of the small intestine called the [[jejunum]] and the stomach is reattached at this hole.  As the pylorus is used to grind food and slowly release the food into the small intestine, removal of the pylorus can cause food to move into the small intestine faster than normal, leading to [[gastric dumping syndrome]].

==Polya&amp;apos;s operation==
A type of posterior gastroenterostomy which is a modification of the [[Billroth II]] operation. Resection of 2/3 of the stomach with blind closure of the duodenal stump and retrocolic [[anastomosis]] of the full circumference of the open stomach to jejunum.

==Post-operative effects==
The most obvious effect of the removal of the stomach is the loss of a storage place for food while it is being digested. Since only a small amount of food can be allowed into the small intestine at a time, the patient will have to eat small amounts of food regularly in order to prevent [[gastric dumping syndrome]].

Another major effect is the loss of the intrinsic-factor-secreting parietal cells in the stomach lining. Intrinsic factor is essential for the uptake of [[Vitamin B12|vitamin B&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;12&amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt;]] and without it the patient will suffer from a [[vitamin B12 deficiency|vitamin B&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;12&amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt; deficiency]]. This can lead to a type of anemia known as [[pernicious anemia]] which severely reduces red-blood cell synthesis (known as [[erythropoiesis]]). This can be treated by giving the patient direct injections of vitamin B&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;12&amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt;.

==History==
The first successful gastrectomy was performed by [[Theodor Billroth]] in 1881 for cancer of the stomach.

Historically, gastrectomies were used to treat [[peptic ulcer]]s.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;E. Pólya:Zur Stumpfversorgung nach Magenresektion. Zentralblatt für Chirurgie, Leipzig, 1911, 38: 892-894.&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;  These are now usually treated with [[antibiotic]]s, as it was recognized that they are usually due to [[Helicobacter pylori]].

In the past a gastrectomy for peptic ulcer disease was often accompanied by a [[vagotomy]], to reduce acid production. Nowadays, this problem is managed with [[proton pump inhibitor]]s.

==See also==
*[[Finsterer-Hofmeister operation]]
*[[Roux-en-Y]]
*[[Sleeve gastrectomy]]

==References==
&amp;lt;references/&amp;gt;

{{commons}}
{{Digestive system surgical procedures}}
{{Ectomy, stomy, and otomy}}

[[Category:Digestive system surgery]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
