<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Ki Society"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Ki Society" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;The {{Nihongo|&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Ki Society&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;|気の研究会|Ki no Kenkyūkai}} is an [[aikido]] organization founded by [[Koichi Tohei]] in 1971, while he was the chief instructor at the [[Aikikai Hombu Dojo]].  The official Japanese name of the organization is Shin Shin Toitsu Aikido Kai (心身統一合気道会), but it is more usually known in English-speaking countries as &amp;quot;Ki Society&amp;quot;.  Its foundation reflected Tohei&amp;apos;s differences with the [[Aikikai]], and his own emphasis on developing the concept of [[qi|Ki]]. Tohei&amp;apos;s art is correctly called [[Shin Shin Tōitsu-dō]] (心身統一道), meaning &amp;quot;the way of realizing the [original] unity of mind and body&amp;quot;, but the martial discipline of the art is frequently isolated and referred to as Ki-Aikido, particularly in the [[Western world]].

==History==
At the Ki Society, Tohei envisioned a place where [[qi|Ki]] could be taught to students of all ages, including the handicapped and infirm, and also to those incapable of Aikido practice. Aikido is just one of the disciplines in Tohei&amp;apos;s holistic art of Shin Shin Toitsudo; there are in fact five disciplines learned by students at a Ki Society Dojo:

* Shin Shin Toitsu [[Aikido]]
* Kiatsu (personal health and healing)
* Ki Breathing
* Ki Meditation
* Ki Development Exercises (methods for realizing oneness of mind and body are Oneness Rhythm Exercise, Sokushin no Gyo, and Senshin no Gyo)

Being one of the first [[Japanese people|Japanese]] to bring Aikido to [[Western world|the West]] from [[Japan]] in 1953, Tohei discovered numerous obstacles in teaching. Western students did not accept teachings at face value, and bombarded Tohei with questions, and even occasional &amp;quot;attacks&amp;quot; to test Tohei&amp;apos;s real ability. Due to these teaching situations, Tohei was forced to create a very clear system of teaching that combines Western methods to teach Eastern concepts such as ki, one-point, relaxing completely in a live fashion, etc. Through his lifetime in wars abroad and at home, and through his experiences with Aikido, in Sokushin no Gyo at the Ichikukai dojo, and the Japanese [[Yoga]] teachings of [[Tempu Nakamura]], Tohei realized four universal principles that he felt should be used in all Ki Society practice, and in everyone&amp;apos;s daily life.

* Keep [[Dantian|One Point]]
* Relax Completely
* Keep Weight Underside
* Extend Ki

Shin Shin Toitsu Aikido Kai hosts an All-Japan Taigi Competition every year at Ki no Kenkyukai (HQ), and every four years the World Taigi Competition is held there.  Various techniques are grouped into 31 sets, each of which are called a &amp;apos;Taigi&amp;apos;, and participant teams perform from two to five taigi, selected from that year&amp;apos;s taigi choices. The competition is one of measuring the nage&amp;apos;s form and movement with uke, rather than a competition between two opponents. It is most closely compared to paired figure skating competition or ice dancing competition, with judges awarding points for balance, largeness, and rhythm.

The Ki-society has its primary facilities, known as &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Ki Society H.Q&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (Ki no Sato), in [[Tochigi Prefecture|Tochigi]] [[Prefectures of Japan|Prefecture]].

==Further reading==
*Koichi Tohei: &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Ki in Daily Life.&amp;apos;&amp;apos; Japan Publications, Tokyo, 1978, ISBN 0-87040-436-9
*Koichi Tohei: &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Book of Ki: Co-ordinating Mind and Body in Daily Life.&amp;apos;&amp;apos; Japan Publications, Tokyo, 1976, ISBN 0-87040-379-6
*[[Koretoshi Maruyama]]: &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Aikido with Ki.&amp;apos;&amp;apos; Japan Publications, Tokyo, 1984, ISBN 0-87040-566-7
*Reed, William:  &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Ki:  A Practical Guide for Westerners.&amp;apos;&amp;apos;  Japan Publications, Tokyo, 1986, ISBN 0-87040-640-X
*Reed, William:  &amp;apos;&amp;apos;A Road That Anyone Can Walk: Ki.&amp;apos;&amp;apos;  Japan Publications, Tokyo, 1992, ISBN 0-87040-799-6

==External links==
*{{en icon}} [http://www.ki-society.com/english/ Official Ki Society Homepage]
*{{en icon}} [http://www.ki-society.com/english/renew/aikidokai_002.html Official List of International Ki Society Dojo]


[[Category:Aikido organizations]]

{{Aikido styles}}&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
