<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Halotolerance"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Halotolerance" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Halotolerance&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is the [[osmoregulation|adaptation]] of living [[organism]]s to conditions of high [[salinity]].&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;Walter Larcher, 2001&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt; Halotolerant species tend to live in areas such as [[hypersaline lake]]s, [[dune|coastal dunes]], saline [[desert]]s, salt [[marsh]]es, and inland salt [[sea]]s and [[spring (hydrosphere)|spring]]s. [[Halophile]]s are a group of [[bacterium|bacteria]] that live in highly saline environments, and indeed in many cases require the salinity to survive. [[Halophyte]]s are salt-tolerant higher plants.
==Applications==
Fields of scientific research relevant to halotolerance include [[biochemistry]], [[molecular biology]], [[cell biology]], [[physiology]], [[ecology]], and [[genetics]].

An understanding of halotolerance can be applicable to areas such as [[arid-zone agriculture]], [[xeriscaping]], [[aquaculture]] (of fish or algae), bioproduction of desirable compounds (such as [[phycobiliprotein]]s or [[carotenoid]]s) using seawater to support growth, or [[Environmental remediation|remediation]] of salt-affected soils. In addition, many environmental stressors involve or induce osmotic changes, so knowledge gained about halotolerance can also be relevant to understanding tolerance to extremes in moisture or temperature.

Goals of studying halotolerance include increasing the agricultural productivity of lands affected by [[soil salination]] or where only saline water is available. Conventional agricultural species could be made more halotolerant by gene transfer from naturally halotolerant species (by conventional [[Artificial selection|breeding]] or [[genetic engineering]]) or by applying treatments developed from an understanding of the mechanisms of halotolerance. In addition, naturally halotolerant plants or microorganisms could be developed into useful [[agriculture|agricultural]] crops or [[fermentation (biochemistry)|fermentation]] organisms.

==Cellular functions==
Tolerance of high salt conditions can be obtained through several routes. High levels of salt entering the plant can trigger ionic imbalances which cause complications in respiration and photosynthesis, leading to reduced rates of growth, injury and death in severe cases. To be considered tolerant of saline conditions, the [[protoplast]] must show methods of balancing the toxic and [[osmotic]] effects of the increased salt concentrations. Halophytic vascular plants can survive on soils with salt concentrations around 6%, or up to 20% in extreme cases. Tolerance of such conditions is reached through the use of [[stress proteins]] and compatible cytoplasm osmotic solutes.

To exist in such conditions, halophytes tend to be subject to the uptake of high levels of salt into their cells, and this is often required to maintain an osmotic potential lower than that of the soil to ensure water uptake. High salt concentrations within the cell can be damaging to sensitive organelles such as the chloroplast, so sequestration of salt is seen. Under this action, salt is stored within the [[vacuole]] to protect such delicate areas. If high salt concentrations are seen within the vacuole, a high concentration gradient will be established between the vacuole and the cytoplasm, leading to high levels of energy investment to maintain this state. Therefore, the accumulation of compatible cytoplasmic osmotic solutes can be seen to prevent this situation from occurring. [[Amino Acids]] such as proline accumulate in halophytic [[Brassica]] species, quaternary ammonium bases such as Glycine Betaine and sugars have been shown to act in this role within halophytic members of [[Chenopodiaceae]] and members of [[Asteraceae]] show the build up of cyclites and soluble sugars. The build up of these compounds allow for the balancing of the osmotic effect while preventing the establishment of toxic concentrations of salt or requiring the maintenance of high concentration gradients

==Bacterial halotolerance==
The extent of halotolerance varies widely amongst different species of bacteria.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;Dieter Häussinger and Helmut Sies, 2007&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt; A number of [[cyanobacteria]] are halotolerant; an example location of occurrence for such cyanobacteria is in the [[Makgadikgadi Pans]], a large [[hypersaline lake]] in [[Botswana]].&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;C. Michael Hogan, 2008&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

==See also==
* [[Soil salinity]]
* [[Salinity control]]

==References==
* Dieter Häussinger and Helmut Sies (2007) &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Osmosensing and Osmosignaling&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, Academic Press, 579 pages  ISBN 0-12-373921-7
* C. Michael Hogan (2008) [http://www.megalithic.co.uk/article.php?sid=22373&amp;amp;mode=&amp;amp;order=0&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Makgadikgadi&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, The Megalithic Portal, ed. A. Burnham]
* Walter Larcher (2001) &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Physiological Plant Ecology&amp;apos;&amp;apos;  ISBN 3-540-43516-6

===Line notes===
{{reflist}}

{{Animalosmo}}

[[Category:Biology]]
[[Category:Salts]]

[[de:Halophil]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
