<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Xi Beach"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Xi Beach" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;[[Image:Xi Beach Kefalonia.jpg|thumb|Xi Beach with its red sand, backed by white cliffs]]
[[Image:Xi Beach Shade Kefalonia.jpg|thumb|Areas of Xi beach are well developed]]
[[Image:Xi beach cliffs kefalonia.jpg|thumb|The cliffs are composed of a soft, white clay which has been eroded by the rain]]

&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Xi Beach&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is situated in the south of the [[Paliki]] peninsula of [[Kefalonia]], [[Greece]] and part of the district [[Mantzavinata]] near the town [[Lixouri]].

== Location ==
Its location can be seen in Google Maps.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;[http://maps.google.co.uk/maps?f=q&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;geocode=&amp;amp;q=paliki&amp;amp;sll=38.160615,20.414314&amp;amp;sspn=0.002788,0.003492&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;ll=38.160864,20.41307&amp;amp;spn=0.005576,0.006984&amp;amp;t=h&amp;amp;z=17  Satellite image showing location]&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

The beach is a 4&amp;amp;nbsp;km strip of sand which is up to 50 m wide in places. Several roads branch on the approach to the area and bring one out at different locations along its length, usually close to a bar, taverna or apartment complex.

==Character==
Xi is renowned for its soft, red sand. It is a blue-flag beach &amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;[http://www.blueflag.org/blueflag/2008/Greece/Kefallonia/Xi Blue Flag Beach entry]&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

The sand slopes reasonably gently so that one can go out a distance from the shoreline.

The areas of the beach that are close to hotels are developed and organised with beach loungers and sun shades. Areas that are away from amenities present a more natural aspect.

==Geology==
The surrounding sediment and cliffs at Xi Beach are made up of a white clay, which is eroded into sharp profiles by the rain. The beach is made up of a soft, red sand.

==Travel and Amenities==
Well-made roads lead down to the beach areas.

At the end of the roads, car parking is located on-road or in car parks linked with Tavernas. This can be crowded at the height of the tourist season.

There are several large Tavernas providing drinks and meals along the 4&amp;amp;nbsp;km length of the beach area.

Beach loungers and umbrellas are for hire in some areas of the beach, usually at points where hotels, Tavernas or bars are situated close to the beach.

The area has some hotel complexes and apartments. The beaches are associated with a high population density of tourists in high season. In September the number of toursists decreases significantly, with continuation of good weather.

==References==
{{reflist}}

==External links==
360 Movie of the beach from Greeka.com [http://www.greeka.com/ionian/kefalonia/kefalonia-pictures-360/kefalonia-pictures-360-20-a.htm]

{{coord|38.16086|N|20.41307|E|type:landmark_source:enwiki|display=title}}

[[Category:Bays of Greece]]
[[Category:Visitor attractions in the Ionian Islands]]
[[Category:Cephalonia]]
[[Category:Beaches of Greece]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
