<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Spanish Prisoner"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Spanish Prisoner" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{for|the film based on this term|The Spanish Prisoner}}

The &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Spanish Prisoner&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is a [[confidence trick]] originating in the late 19th century.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;{{cite news | url= http://query.nytimes.com/gst/abstract.html?res=980CE5D71638E433A25753C2A9659C94699ED7CF |title= AN OLD SWINDLE REVIVED.; The &amp;quot;Spanish Prisoner&amp;quot; and Buried Treasure Bait Again Being Offered to Unwary Americans |work= [[The New York Times]] |date= 20 March 1898 |page= 12 | accessdate= 2010-07-01 }}&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;&amp;lt;ref name=NETZHYPES/&amp;gt; In its original form, the [[con-man]] tells his victim (the &amp;apos;&amp;apos;mark&amp;apos;&amp;apos;) that he is (or is in correspondence with) a wealthy person of high estate who has been imprisoned in Spain under a false identity. Some versions had the imprisoned person being an unknown or remote relative of the mark.&amp;lt;ref name=NETZHYPES&amp;gt;{{cite news|title=100 Jahre alte Web-Phänomene Diese Netz-Hypes sind älter als das Internet|url=http://einestages.spiegel.de/external/ShowTopicAlbumBackground/a26941/l25/l0/F.html#featuredEntry|accessdate=23 January 2013|newspaper=[[Spiegel Online]], einestages feature|language=German}}&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;  Supposedly the prisoner cannot reveal his identity without serious repercussions, and is relying on a friend (the confidence trickster) to raise money to secure his release.&amp;lt;ref name=NETZHYPES/&amp;gt; The confidence trickster offers to let the mark put up some of the funds, with a promise that he will be financially rewarded when the prisoner returns, and perhaps also by gaining the hand of a beautiful woman represented to be the prisoner&amp;apos;s daughter. After the mark has turned over the funds, he is informed that further difficulties have arisen and more money is needed. With such explanations, the trickster continues to press for more money until the victim is cleaned out or declines to put up more funds.

==Characteristics==
Key features of the Spanish Prisoner trick are the emphasis on secrecy and the trust the confidence trickster apparently places in the mark not to reveal the prisoner&amp;apos;s identity or situation.  The confidence trickster will typically claim to have chosen the mark carefully, based on his reputation for honesty and straight dealing, and may appear to structure the deal so that the confidence trickster&amp;apos;s ultimate share of the reward will be distributed voluntarily by the mark.

==Modern variants==
Modern variants of the Spanish Prisoner include the [[advance-fee fraud]], in particular the Nigerian money transfer (or 419) scam.&amp;lt;ref name=NETZHYPES/&amp;gt; In the advance-fee fraud, a valuable item must be ransomed from a warehouse, crooked customs agent, or lost-baggage facility before the authorities or thieves recognize its value. In the Nigerian variation, a self-proclaimed relative of a deposed African dictator offers to transfer millions of ill-gotten dollars into the bank account of the victim in return for small initial payments to cover bribes and other expenses. More recent examples feature people sharing the same surname as the intended victim, with the scammer guessing the surname from observing patterns in e-mail addresses, or obtaining full names from harvested e-mail headers. Another variation spreads via hijacked Facebook accounts, where a message is sent to all the Facebook-friends of the victim, claiming that the victim is in a foreign country, has been robbed, and needs one of the Facebook-friends to &amp;quot;send money&amp;quot; via Western Union to pay hotel and travel bills.  Of course, the scammer can go to any Western Union retail outlet, in any country, in order to claim the transferred money.

==See also==
*[[Advance fee fraud]] (also known as the Nigerian Letter)
*[[The Spanish Prisoner]] (1997 film)

==References==
{{Reflist}}

==External links==
*[http://www.hidden-knowledge.com/funstuff/spanishprisoner/spanishprisoner1.html The Spanish Prisoner] Original story by Arthur Train
*[http://www.met.police.uk/fraudalert/419.htm Metropolitan Police Service - Fraud Alert]
*[http://www.startribune.com/blogs/84354257.html Feb. 13, 1910: Fraud Letters Flood State] &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Minneapolis Tribune&amp;apos;&amp;apos; newspaper article
*[http://www.samizdat.com/solovieff.html Examples of Spanish Prisoner letters]

{{Scams and confidence tricks}}

[[Category:Confidence tricks]]
[[Category:Nonexistent people used in hoaxes]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
