<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Unexpected (Star Trek: Enterprise)"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Unexpected (Star Trek: Enterprise)" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Unreferenced|date=February 2012}}
{{DISPLAYTITLE:Unexpected (&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Star Trek: Enterprise&amp;apos;&amp;apos;)}}
{{Infobox television episode
| Title = Unexpected
| Image =
| Caption =
| Series = [[Star Trek: Enterprise]]
| Season = 1
| Episode = 5
| Production = 105
| Airdate = {{Startdate|2001|10|17}}
| Writer = [[Rick Berman]]&amp;lt;BR /&amp;gt;[[Brannon Braga]]
| Director = [[Mike Vejar]]
| Music = [[Jay Chattaway]]
| Producer= [[Dawn Valazquez]]
| Guests =
*[[Julianne Christie]] – Ah&amp;apos;Len
*[[Randy Oglesby]] – Trena&amp;apos;L
*[[Christopher Darga]] – Captain Vorok
*[[Regi Davis]] – Klingon First Officer
*[[T.L. Kolman]] – Alien Man
*[[John Cragen]] – Crewman
*[[Drew Howerton]] – Steward
*[[Mike Baldridge]]
| Prev = [[Strange New World (Star Trek: Enterprise)|Strange New World]]
| Next = [[Terra Nova (Star Trek: Enterprise)|Terra Nova]]
| Episode list = [[List of Star Trek: Enterprise episodes|List of &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Star Trek: Enterprise&amp;apos;&amp;apos; episodes]]
}}
__NOTOC__
&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Unexpected&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is the fifth episode (production #105) of the [[Television program|television series]] &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Star Trek: Enterprise]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos;.

A ship feeding off the &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Enterprise (NX-01)|Enterprise]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos;{{&amp;apos;}}s warp field is exposed after the crew ignites the plasma exhaust. [[Charles Tucker III|Commander Tucker]] takes a trip to the ship to help them repair their warp drive. After his return to the &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Enterprise&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, he finds some unexpected developments both on and inside his body.

==Plot==
In Engineering, Chief Engineer Trip Tucker is trying to solve ship-wide problems with power supply and life support. [[T&amp;apos;Pol]] discovers a distortion in the plasma wake of the &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Enterprise&amp;apos;&amp;apos;. Archer ignites the plasma waste, revealing a cloaked ship. Captain [[Jonathan Archer|Archer]] hails the vessel and the Xyrillian Captain Trena&amp;apos;l explains that they have been tapping the &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Enterprise&amp;apos;&amp;apos;{{&amp;apos;}}s plasma wake to recharge their engines. Archer offers engineering assistance. Trip is to stay on the Xyrillian ship for three days until the repairs are completed. Because of the different atmosphere in the Xyrillian ship, Trip is given injections by Dr. [[Phlox (Star Trek)|Phlox]] so his body can adapt.

Once aboard, Trip meets Ah&amp;apos;len, the Xyrillian engineer. Trip and Ah&amp;apos;len become friendly while repairing the ship. While waiting for the teraphasic coils to recharge, Ah&amp;apos;len takes Trip to a holodeck to show him Thera, the Xyrillian homeworld. During the holographic tour, Ah&amp;apos;len engages in a psychic game with Trip that allows them to share thoughts.  When the repairs are completed, Trip returns to the &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Enterprise.&amp;apos;&amp;apos; Trip notices a strange growth on the inside of his wrist, and visits Phlox, who tells him that he is pregnant.  Phlox explains that the Xyrillians only utilise genetic material in reproduction, the males acting as hosts. He also reveals that the embryo cannot be removed without risking both of their lives. Trip mentions the telepathic game and Phlox says that it might be the transfer medium for the genetic material.

Archer asks T&amp;apos;Pol to locate the Xyrillian ship, which Reed detects, only to discover it hiding in a Klingon warship&amp;apos;s plasma wake. Archer hails the Klingon ship, which fires two warning shots. Archer hails again and asks Captain Vorak if they have been experiencing any technical problems. The Klingons detect the Xyrillian ship with Archer&amp;apos;s help, but then order that the Xyrillians must be executed. T&amp;apos;Pol interrupts to tell Vorak that Archer is the man who found Klaang and saved [[Qo&amp;apos;noS]] from civil war and that the Chancellor himself called Archer brother in the High Council Chamber. Archer convinces Vorak to take Trip to the Xyrillian ship, but only after informing him of Trip&amp;apos;s pregnancy. There, Ah&amp;apos;len tells a relieved Trip that the embryo can be safely removed.

Back on their ships, Vorak ends the encounter by stating that the debt to Archer is repaid and that Archer will regret meeting the Klingons if they ever cross paths again. In the Captain&amp;apos;s Mess, Archer asks T&amp;apos;Pol if the Klingon Chancellor called him &amp;quot;brother.&amp;quot; T&amp;apos;Pol replies by saying that Klingons are known to exaggerate, so she saw nothing wrong with doing the same. T&amp;apos;Pol tells Trip that his &amp;quot;pregnancy is the first recorded instance of a human male pregnancy&amp;quot;.

==External links==
{{wikiquote|Star Trek: Enterprise#Unexpected|Unexpected}}
*{{IMDb title|id=572263|title=Unexpected}}
*{{tv.com episode|star-trek-enterprise/unexpected-68570|Unexpected}}
*{{memoryalpha|Unexpected}}
*{{StarTrek.com link|ENT|121950|Unexpected}}

{{Star Trek holodeck stories}}
{{Star Trek Klingon stories}}
{{Star Trek ENT S1}}
{{Star Trek ENT}}
{{Star Trek}}

[[Category:Star Trek: Enterprise episodes]]
[[Category:2001 television episodes]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
