<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Spoliation of evidence"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Spoliation of evidence" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;The  &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;spoliation of evidence&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is the intentional or negligent withholding, hiding, altering, or destroying of [[evidence (law)|evidence]] relevant to a legal proceeding.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;[[Black&amp;apos;s Law Dictionary]] (8th ed. 2004).  For an overview of spoliation, see generally Michael Zuckerman, [http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=1536805 Yes, I Destroyed the Evidence -- Sue Me?], Journal of Computer and Information Law &amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt; Spoliation has two possible consequences: in jurisdictions where the (intentional) act is criminal by [[statute]], it may result in fines and [[incarceration]] for the parties who engaged in the spoliation; in jurisdictions where relevant [[case law]] precedent has been established, proceedings possibly altered by spoliation may be interpreted under a &amp;apos;&amp;apos;spoliation inference&amp;apos;&amp;apos;.

The spoliation inference is a negative evidentiary inference that a [[finder of fact]] can draw from a party&amp;apos;s destruction of a document or thing that is relevant to an ongoing or reasonably foreseeable [[Civil law (common law)|civil]] or [[Criminal law|criminal]] proceeding: the finder of fact can review all evidence uncovered in as strong a light as possible against the spoliator and in favor of the opposing party.

The theory of the spoliation inference is that when a party destroys evidence, it may be reasonable to infer that the party had &amp;quot;consciousness of guilt&amp;quot; or other motivation to avoid the evidence.  Therefore, the factfinder may conclude that the evidence would have been unfavorable to the spoliator.  Some [[jurisdiction]]s have recognized a spoliation [[tort]] action, which allows the victim of destruction of evidence to file a separate tort action against a &amp;apos;&amp;apos;spoliator&amp;apos;&amp;apos;.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;http://library.findlaw.com/1996/Nov/1/231209.html&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

Spoliation is often an issue in the context where a person claims he has been injured by a defective product which he then discarded or lost.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;http://www.whitelawtwining.com/pdfs/Spoliation_and_Preserving_Evid.pdf&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt; In that circumstance, the defendant manufacturer or distributor may move to dismiss the case on the basis of spoliation (instead of just having to rely on the plaintiff&amp;apos;s usual burden of proof, the argument being that any testimony of plaintiff&amp;apos;s witnesses would not overcome the spoliation inference born of the lost evidentiary value of the missing product itself).&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;Dead link - http://www.law.com/jsp/legaltechnology/pubArticleLT.jsp?id=1182935157632&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

==References==
{{reflist}}

==See also==
* [[Obstruction of justice]]
* [[Illegal disposal of bodies in the water]]

[[Category:American legal terms]]
[[Category:Searches and seizures]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
