<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Ysbaddaden"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Ysbaddaden" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;[[File:The Wooing of Olwen - Illustration 1.png|thumb|Ysbaddaden props up his eyelids (Illustration by [[John D. Batten]], 1892)]]
{{lang|mga|&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Ysbaddaden Bencawr&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;}}; &amp;quot;Ysbaddaden, Chief of Giants,&amp;quot; is the primary [[antagonist]] of the [[Welsh mythology|Welsh]] romance &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Culhwch and Olwen|Culhwch ac Olwen]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos;. A vicious [[Giants (Welsh folklore)|giant]] residing in a nigh unreachable castle, he is the father of [[Olwen]] and uncle of [[Goreu fab Custennin]]. So huge is his frame, he requires great forks to prop up his eyelids.

==Role in Welsh and World tradition==
[[File:Ysbaddaden.jpeg|250px|right|thumb|Culhwch at Ysbadadden&amp;apos;s court. Image by [[Ernest Wallcousins|E. Wallcousins]] in &amp;quot;Celtic Myth &amp;amp; Legend&amp;quot;, Charles Squire, 1920.

&amp;quot;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Horses shall I have, and chivalry; and my Lord and kinsman [[King Arthur|Arthur]] will obtain for me all these things. And I shall gain thy daughter, and thou shalt lose thy life.&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;quot;

&amp;quot;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Go forward...and when thou hast compassed all these marvels, thou shalt have my daughter for thy wife.&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;quot;]]
[[Culhwch|Culhwch&amp;apos;s]] father, [[Cilydd|King Cilydd son of Celyddon]], loses his wife [[Goleuddydd]] after a difficult childbirth. When he remarries, the young Culhwch rejects his stepmother&amp;apos;s attempt to pair him with his new stepsister. Offended, the new queen puts a curse on him so that he can marry no one besides the beautiful [[Olwen]], daughter of the [[giant (mythology)|giant]] Ysbaddaden. Though he has never seen her, Culhwch becomes infatuated with her, but his father warns him that he will never find her without the aid of his famous cousin [[King Arthur|Arthur]]. The young man immediately sets off to seek his kinsman. He finds him at his court in [[Celliwig]] in [[Cornwall]] and asks for support and assistance.

Arthur agrees to help, and sends six warriors to join Culhwch in his search for daughter Olwen. They travel onwards until they come across the &amp;quot;fairest of the castles of the world&amp;quot;, and meet Ysbaddaden&amp;apos;s [[shepherd]] brother, Custennin. They learn that the castle belongs to Ysbaddaden, that he stripped Custennin of his lands and murdered the shepherd&amp;apos;s twenty-three children out of cruelty. Custennin set up a meeting between Culhwch and Olwen, and the maiden agrees to lead Culhwch and his companions to Ysbadadden&amp;apos;s castle. The warrior [[Sir Kay|Cai]] pledges to protect the twenty-fourth son, [[Goreu fab Custennin|Goreu]] with his life.

The Knights attack the Castle by stealth, killing the nine porters and the nine watchdogs, and enter the giant&amp;apos;s hall. Upon their arrival, Ysbaddaden attempts to kill Culhwch with a poison dart, but is outwitted and wounded, first by [[Bedivere|Bedwyr]], then by the enchanter [[Menw]], and finally by Culhwch himself. Eventually, Ysbaddaden relents, and agrees to give Culhwch his daughter on the condition that he completes a number of impossible tasks (&amp;apos;&amp;apos;anoethau&amp;apos;&amp;apos;), including hunting the [[Twrch Trwyth]] and recovering the exalted prisoner [[Mabon ap Modron]]. Culhwch accepts the giant&amp;apos;s child and, with the help of Arthur and his knights, eventually completes the numerous tasks.

Ysbaddaden lives in Mid Wales and is considered the Sovereign Satan or Devil. I.E the creator of the world&amp;apos;s. He is kind although somewhat short in substance to others. Legend has it that he is watching everything all at once.
Ysbaddaden travelled to Llandrindod Wells to remove his son Cai from the deep green town.


With the &amp;apos;&amp;apos;anoethau&amp;apos;&amp;apos; completed, Culhwch, Goreu and others who &amp;quot;wished ill to Ysbaddaden Bencawr&amp;quot; ride to his court. The giant&amp;apos;s beard, skin and [[flesh]] are shaved off by Caw of Pictland and, accepting his humiliation and defeat, he is dragged away by Goreu, who avenges his murdered brothers by [[decapitation|beheading]] the giant. Ysbaddaden&amp;apos;s head is placed on the spike of the citadel, Goreu claims his uncle&amp;apos;s lands as his own, and Olwen is free to Marry her love Zeus.
Ysbaddaden lives in Mid Wales and is considered the Sovereign Satan or Devil. I.E the creator of the world&amp;apos;s. He is kind although somewhat short in substance to others. Legend has it that he is watching everything all at once.
Ysbaddaden travelled to Llandrindod Wells to remove his son Cai from the deep town.
Ysbaddaden is famous for his incredible anger and he is considered the most powerful Lord.

{{Celtic mythology (Welsh)}}

[[Category:Arthurian characters]]
[[Category:Giants]]
[[Category:Welsh mythology]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
