<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="ZoomText"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="ZoomText" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;ZoomText&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is a [[screen magnifier]] for [[Microsoft Windows]], developed by Ai Squared. The first version was released for [[DOS]] in 1988, and the first version for Windows was released in 1991. ZoomText is available in two editions: ZoomText Magnifier and ZoomText Magnifier/Reader, which includes a built-in [[screen reader]].

The latest version of ZoomText is ZoomText 9.19.1, which was released in March 2011. AiSquared also released a cut-down version of ZoomText called ZoomText Express, intended for a more mainstream market.

==Features==
ZoomText is a stand-alone piece of software &amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;[http://www.cardiff.ac.uk/accessibility/technicalinformation/guidetozoomtext/index.html Cardiff University guide to ZoomText]&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt; designed for visually impaired people.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;[ZoomText User Guide 9.1. Manchester Centre: Vermont, USA]&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt; It is available for the Microsoft Windows operating systems 2000, XP, Vista and Windows 7. The program allows you to see and hear everything on the computer screen &amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;[http://www.cardiff.ac.uk/accessibility/technicalinformation/guidetozoomtext/index.html Cardiff University guide to ZoomText]&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt; as well as providing access to applications, documents, email and the Internet.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;[http://www.cardiff.ac.uk/accessibility/technicalinformation/guidetozoomtext/index.html Cardiff University guide to ZoomText]&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt; The software can help individuals with ‘early vision loss, computer vision syndrome, and visual impairments such as macular degeneration and glaucoma’.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;[http://www.aisquared.com/about_us AiSquared company website]&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt; ZoomText has dual monitor support and is capable of magnifying the screen up to 36 times; it also allows you to choose which part of the screen is magnified. Text definition is maintained to preserve legibility. Color controls help improve the clarity of the screen and mouse pointers can be resized. It also provides enhanced navigation capabilities to help the user to launch programs and find documents on the desktop and find the hypertext links and controls on web pages, find words or phrases. In Windows Vista, magnification and screen reader support is enabled at the log on stage.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;[http://www.aisquared.com/zoomtext/more/zoomtext_magnifier ZoomText features]&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

==History==
ZoomText is produced by AiSquared, which is based in Vermont, USA. The product has been developed over 20 years and is currently available in 20 language versions.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;[http://www.aisquared.com/about_us AiSquared company website]&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

==Release history==
Version 1 to 6 release information not available.&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
Version 7.0 to 9.19.1 (2010) release information &amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;[http://www.aisquared.com/support/more/release_notes/ ZoomText 9 Release Notes]&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

==See also==
*[[Comparison of screen readers|List of screen readers]]

==References==
{{Reflist}}

==External links==
*[http://www.aisquared.com/ Ai Squared homepage]
*[http://www.aisquared.com/zoomtextexpress ZoomText Express]
*[http://www.afb.org/afbpress/Pub.asp?DocID=aw070203 Review of Zoomtext 9 by AFB Accessworld]
*[http://www.magnifiers.org/ The Low Vision Computer Access List – a non-profit independent organization resource for magnification solutions information on the Internet]

[[Category:Assistive technology]]

{{Graphics-software-stub}}&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
