<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Kihon"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Kihon" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Unreferenced|date=February 2009}}
{{misleading|date=August 2012}}
{{Nihongo|&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Kihon&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;|基本, きほん}} is a [[Japanese language|Japanese]] term meaning &amp;quot;basics&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;fundamentals.&amp;quot; The term is used to refer to the basic techniques that are taught and practiced as the foundation of most [[Japanese martial arts]].

The practice and mastery of kihon is essential to all advanced training, and includes the practice of correct body form and breathing, while practicing basics such as stances, punches, kicks, blocks, and thrusts, but it also includes basic representative &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[kata]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos;.

Kihon is not only practicing of techniques, it is also the [[karateka]] fostering the correct spirit and attitude at all times.

Kihon techniques tend to be practiced often, in many cases during each practice session.  They are considered fundamental to mastery and improvement of all movements of greater complexity. Kihon in martial arts can be seen as analogous to basic skills in, for example, [[basketball]]. Professional [[NBA]] players continue to practice dribbling, passing, free throws, jump shots, etc. in an effort to maintain and perfect the more complex skills used during a basketball game.

==In Karate==
[[File:Kihon for the 5th Kyu test.ogv|thumb|250px|right|a karateka demonstrating Kihon-techniques for a [[Kyu]] test (shotokan style)]]
Styles of [[karate]] differ greatly in the emphasis placed on kihon. Kihon may be practiced as &amp;quot;floor exercises&amp;quot;, where the same technique or combination is repeated multiple times as the students move back and forth across the floor. Japanese kihon training is notorious for extended periods of kihon training. This style of practice is believed to ingrain the techniques into the [[muscle memory]] of the [[karateka]].

Some styles employ &amp;quot;kihon [[kata]]&amp;quot; in teaching beginners. Additionally, kihon may take the form of prearranged partner drills whereby two students face each other and alternate execution of a technique. This approach combines repetition with training in distancing. Targets for punching and kicking, such as bags, shields, or dummies, are generally used at more advanced stages of kihon training to strengthen muscles, bones, and skin. Examples of traditional striking targets include [[makiwara]], among many others.

Some styles have a small set of basic techniques that are practiced consistently every single class. Others might have scores of techniques that are each only practiced every couple of months.

==In Kendo==
In [[kendo]] there are various kihon systems. Two of such systems are the &amp;quot;Dai Ichi Kihon&amp;quot; (first major kihon) and the &amp;quot;Dai Ni Kihon&amp;quot; (second major kihon) developed by Japanese police forces.

In 2005 the [[All Japan Kendo Federation]] presented the new methodology &amp;quot;Bokuto Ni Yoru Kendo Kihon-waza Keiko-ho&amp;quot;. The aim of the methodology was to develop a form of training that could be included into standard kendo practice for the following purposes:
# Help beginners learn the concept that the &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[shinai]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is the representation of the [[katana]].
# Develop solid basics and techniques that are directly translatable into &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[bogu|bōgu]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos; practice.
# Develop the student&amp;apos;s abilities and understanding for later practice of the kendo &amp;apos;&amp;apos;kata&amp;apos;&amp;apos;.
# Develop &amp;apos;&amp;apos;reihō&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (manners).

==In Aikido==

In [[aikido]] there are also assorted kihon systems depending on the style.  [[Iwama style]] kihon tends to be from a static powerful grab, whereas [[Shodokan Aikido|Shodokan]] kihon starts with two people separated by a defined distance.  In all cases the role of both participants is strictly defined.  [[Yoshinkan]] aikido also places a strong emphasis on kihon techniques.

{{Karate schools}}

[[Category:Japanese martial arts terms]]
[[Category:Karate kata]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
