<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Ryū (school)"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Ryū (school)" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{nihongo|&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Ryū&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;|-流|-ryū|mainly used as a sufix meaning style, type, form, manner, system, school; here as &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;ryūha&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; 流派 a school, a school of thought}} is a Japanese [[kanji]] referring to a [[school (discipline)|school]] in any discipline.

In English, the word is frequently used to refer to schools of [[Japan]]ese [[martial art]], although it can also be found used in other disciplines (for example Nihon-[[koryū]] and [[Sogetsu|Sōgetsu-ryū]] in [[ikebana]], Kantei-ryū in [[shodo|calligraphy]], etc.).

==Ryū in the martial arts==

Japanese martial arts are often classified and codified into ryūha. Usually a given style will have its own curriculum, ranks and licensure system.  These may be based on the parent style or a combination of sources that form the background of the system.

The name of a style may have particular meaning or may simply be a location. [[Toyama-ryū]] is named for the [[Toyama, Toyama|Toyama]] Military Academy in Japan. In contrast, [[Gōjū-ryū]] is the &amp;apos;hard-soft&amp;apos; style, which indicates both characteristic techniques and thematic elements that form a &amp;apos;signature&amp;apos; of the style. Sometimes this is merged or confused with the name of the [[dojo|dōjō]] (as is the case with [[Shotokan|Shōtōkan-ryū karate]]).

High-level practitioners of an established style may splinter off and form their own derivative styles based on their own experience or interpretation.  Sometimes this is encouraged by the parent style, sometimes it represents an ideological schism between senior members of the style.  Sometimes, it is done simply for &amp;apos;marketing&amp;apos; reasons or to adjust a system to modern times.

There is no universal licensing or ranking system across all ryūha. A high-ranking person or [[Black belt (martial arts)|black belt]] in one style does not necessarily correspond to a high level understanding in another style or group of styles. There are many ryūha in Japan that have existed for many hundreds of years, as well as many more that were created in modern times. The concept of organizing a codified system is obviously not a Japanese or outwardly Asian one, though many international or foreign styles may adopt the nomenclature and systemization of [[koryū]] [[bujutsu]] ryūha in order to add an air of mystique or legitimacy to their system, or simply as a way to show respect to their roots and background.

==References==
* &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Kenkyusha&amp;apos;s New Japanese-English Dictionary&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, Kenkyusha Limmited, Tokyo 1991, ISBN 4-7674-2015-6
* &amp;apos;&amp;apos;The Compact Nelson Japanese-English Character Dictionary&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, Charles E. Tuttle Publishing Co., Inc. ISBN 0-8048-2037-6

==External links==
* [http://www.bugei-usa.com/index.php?option=com_content&amp;amp;view=article&amp;amp;id=17:what-is-koryu&amp;amp;catid=9:essay&amp;amp;Itemid=15 Article about Koryu - North American Bugei Society ]
*[http://www.koryubooks.com/library/wmuromoto3.html What is a &amp;apos;Ryu&amp;apos;?], an article by Wayne Muromoto.

{{DEFAULTSORT:Ryu (School)}}
[[Category:Japanese words and phrases]]
[[Category:Japanese martial arts terms]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
