<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Battle of the Medway"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Battle of the Medway" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{for|the battle of the [[Second Anglo-Dutch War]]|Raid on the Medway}}
{{No footnotes|date=June 2009}}
{{Infobox military conflict
|image=
|caption=
|conflict=Battle of the Medway
|partof=the [[Roman conquest of Britain]]
|date={{start-date|0043|43}}
|place=Kent
|result=Roman victory
|combatant1=[[Roman Empire]]
|combatant2=[[Celtic tribes in the British Isles|British tribes]]
|commander1=[[Aulus Plautius]]
|commander2=[[Togodumnus]],&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt; [[Caratacus]]
|strength1= 24,000
|strength2= 17,000
|casualties1= 850
|casualties2= 5,000
|campaignbox= {{Campaignbox Roman conquest of Britain}}
}}

The &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Battle of the Medway&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; took place in 43 AD on the [[River Medway]] in the lands of the [[Iron Age]] tribe of the [[Cantiaci]], now the [[England|English]] county of [[Kent]]. It was an early battle in the  [[Roman conquest of Britain|Claudian invasion of Britain]], led by [[Aulus Plautius]].

== Build-up ==

On the news of the Roman landing, the British tribes united under the command of [[Togodumnus]] and his brother [[Caratacus]] of the [[Catuvellauni]] tribe to fight them. After losing two initial skirmishes in eastern Kent, the natives gathered on the banks of a river further west to face the invaders.

At the same time, the Romans received the surrender of the [[Dobunni]] tribe in western Britain. The Dobunni were subjects of the Catuvellauni and this diplomatic gain was likely a blow to native morale and manpower.

== Chronology ==

There was no bridge over the river, so a detachment of specially-trained Roman auxiliaries (described by the only historical source for the battle [[Cassius Dio]] as &amp;quot;[[Celt]]ic&amp;quot;) swam across the river and attacked the natives&amp;apos; [[chariot]] horses. In the chaos that followed, the bulk of the invasion force spearheaded by [[Legio II Augusta]] under [[Vespasian]] crossed the river, under the overall command of [[Titus Flavius Sabinus II]]. The natives were taken by surprise at how fully armed legionaries were able to cross the river, and Peter Salway stated even Dio seems taken aback. The Romans were unable to press home victory immediately, and the first day of fighting ended without a result. During the second day, a daring attack led by [[Gnaeus Hosidius Geta]] almost led to the Roman officer being captured. His troops retaliated however and put the Britons to flight. Geta was awarded a triumph for securing victory, a rare honor for someone who had not been [[consul]]. Given the primary roles taken by Geta and Sabinus on different days, it has been suggested by the historian [[Malcolm Todd]] that the Romans were operating as two, or possibly three, [[battle group]]s.

Such a long battle was unusual in [[ancient warfare]], and it was likely the Romans defeated a significant native force. The Britons fell back to the [[River Thames|Thames]] where they were afforded a greater strategic advantage.

== Location ==

Dio does not name the battle&amp;apos;s location or the river, but its site is claimed to be on the Medway. The Romans would have used existing trackways as they moved west from [[Richborough]], and the most well-travelled prehistoric trackway would have been the route of the later [[Pilgrims&amp;apos; Way]], which forded the Medway at [[Aylesford]]. Other theories, however, note that the river is narrow enough at Aylesford not to pose significant difficulties in crossing, and place the battle closer to [[Rochester, Kent|Rochester]], where a large Iron Age settlement stood at the time. Further evidence of a more northern location is at [[Bredgar]], where a find of a [[hoard]] of Roman coins from the period has been interpreted as a Roman officer&amp;apos;s savings buried for safekeeping before a battle. This hoard could, however, post-date the battle by as much as 20 years. Possibly the Romans followed the future route of [[Watling Street]] to the battle, although its role as a pre-Roman communications route is not certain.

== See also ==
* http://www.britishbattles.com/roman-britain/battle-medway.htm

== References ==

{{refbegin}}
* Frere, S, &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Britannia&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, Routledge, 1987
* Salway, P, &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Roman Britain&amp;apos;&amp;apos; OUP, 1986
* Todd, M, &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Roman Britain&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, Fontana, 1985
{{refend}}

{{coord|51.440|0.742|display=title|region:GB_scale:20000}}

[[Category:43]]
[[Category:1st-century conflicts]]
[[Category:Battles involving the Roman Empire|Medway 43]]
[[Category:Battles involving the Britons|Medway 43]]
[[Category:Military history of Roman Britain]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
