<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Revolving credit"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Revolving credit" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Refimprove|date=December 2009}}
&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Revolving credit&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is a type of [[Credit (finance)|credit]] that does not have a fixed number of payments, in contrast to [[installment credit]]. [[Credit cards]] are an example of revolving credit used by consumers. Corporate revolving credit facilities are typically used to provide liquidity for a company&amp;apos;s day-to-day operations. They were first introduced by the [[Strawbridge&amp;apos;s|Strawbridge and Clothier Department Store]].&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;[http://www.creditratings101.com/types-of-credit/revolving-credit/ Revolving Credit], Retrieved October 5, 2011.&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

==Typical characteristics==
* Case study is required
* The borrower may use or withdraw funds up to a pre-approved credit limit.
* The amount of available credit decreases and increases as funds are borrowed and then repaid.
* The credit may be used repeatedly.
* The borrower makes payments based only on the amount they&amp;apos;ve actually used or withdrawn, plus interest.
* The borrower may repay over time (subject to any minimum payment requirement), or in full at any time.
* In some cases, the borrower is required to pay a fee to the lender for any money that is undrawn on the revolver; this is especially true of corporate bank loan revolving credit facilities.

A revolving loan facility provides a borrower with a maximum aggregate amount of capital, available over a specified period of time. However, unlike a term loan, the revolving loan facility allows the borrower to drawdown, repay and re-draw loans advanced to it of the available capital during the term of the facility. Each loan is borrowed for a set period of time, usually one, three or six months, after which time it is technically repayable. Repayment of a revolving loan is achieved either by scheduled reductions in the total amount of the facility over time, or by all outstanding loans being repaid on the date of termination. A revolving loan made to refinance another revolving loan which matures on the same date as the drawing of the second revolving loan is known as a &amp;quot;rollover loan&amp;quot;, if made in the same currency and drawn by the same borrower as the first revolving loan. The conditions to be satisfied for drawing a rollover loan are typically less onerous than for other loans.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;http://www.lma.eu.com/uploads/files/Introductory_Guides/Guide_to_Par_Syndicated_Loans.pdf&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

A revolving loan facility is a particularly flexible financing tool as it may be drawn by a borrower by way of straightforward loans, but it is also possible to incorporate different types of financial accommodation within it - for example, it is possible to incorporate a letter of credit facility, swingline facility or overdraft facility within the terms of a revolving credit facility. This is often achieved by creating a sublimit within the overall revolving facility, allowing a certain amount of the lenders&amp;apos; commitment to be drawn in the form of these different facilities.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;http://www.lma.eu.com/uploads/files/Introductory_Guides/Guide_to_Par_Syndicated_Loans.pdf&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

==Examples==
* [[Line of credit]]

==See also==
*[[Installment credit]]
*[[Debt-snowball method]]

==References==
{{Reflist}}

{{DEFAULTSORT:Revolving Credit}}
[[Category:Credit]]
[[Category:Personal finance]]

{{Econ-stub}}&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
