<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Duma"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Duma" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{about|the councils in tsarist Russia|the current Russian legislative body|State Duma|other uses|Duma (disambiguation)}}
{{multiple issues |one source=February 2012 |no footnotes=February 2012}}

The &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Duma&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; were council assemblies which were created by the [[Czar of Russia]]. Simply, it is a form of Russian governmental institution that was formed during the reign of the last Tsar, [[Nicholas II]]. It is also the term for a council to early Russian rulers (&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Boyar Duma&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;), as well as for [[city council]]s in [[Imperial Russia]] (&amp;apos;Municipal dumas&amp;apos;), and city and regional legislative bodies in the [[Russian Federation]].

==In early Russian history==
The term comes from the Russian word думать (&amp;apos;&amp;apos;dumat’&amp;apos;&amp;apos;) meaning &amp;quot;to think&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;to consider&amp;quot;. The &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Boyar Duma&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; was an advisory council to the [[grand prince]]s and [[czar]] of Russia. The Duma was discontinued by [[Peter I of Russia|Peter the Great]], who transferred its functions to the [[Governing Senate]] in 1721.

==Municipal dumas==
[[Image:Mosdumaold.jpg|thumb|250px|[[Moscow City Duma]].]]
Since the year 1 the municipalities in European Russia have had institutions like those of the [[zemstvo]]s. All owners of houses, tax-paying merchants and workmen are enrolled on lists in a descending order according to their assessed wealth. The total valuation is then divided into three equal parts, representing three groups of electors very unequal in number, each of which elects an equal number of delegates to the municipal duma. The executive is in the hands of an elective [[mayor]] and an &amp;apos;&amp;apos;uprava&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, which consists of several members elected by the duma. Under [[Alexander III of Russia|Alexander III]], however, by laws promulgated in 1892 and 1894, the municipal dumas were subordinated to the governors in the same way as the zemstvos. In 1894 municipal institutions, with still more restricted powers, were granted to several towns in Siberia, and in 1895 to some in Caucasia.

==State Duma in Imperial Russia==
{{main|State Duma of the Russian Empire}}
Under the pressure of the [[Russian Revolution of 1905]], on 6 August 1905, [[Sergei Witte]] issued a manifesto about the convocation of the Duma, initially thought to be an advisory organ. In the subsequent [[October Manifesto]], Nicholas II pledged to introduce basic [[civil liberties]], provide for broad participation in the State Duma, and endow the Duma with legislative and oversight powers.

However, Nicholas II was determined to retain his autocratic power. Just before the creation of the Duma in May 1906, the Tsar issued the [[Russian Constitution of 1906|Fundamental Laws]]. It stated in part that Tsar&amp;apos;s [[Minister (government)|minister]]s could not be appointed by, and were not responsible to, the Duma, thus denying [[responsible government]] at the executive level. Furthermore, the Czar had the power to dismiss the Duma and announce new elections whenever he wished.

The imperial State Duma was elected four times: in 1906, twice in 1907, and in 1912.

== State Duma in the Russian Federation ==
{{main|State Duma}}
The State Duma (Russian: Государственная дума, &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Gosudarstvennaya Duma&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, common abbreviation: Госдума, &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Gosduma&amp;apos;&amp;apos;) in Russia is the [[lower house]] of the [[Federal Assembly of Russia]] ([[parliament]]), the  [[upper house]] being the [[Federation Council of Russia]]. Under Russia&amp;apos;s 1993 constitution, there are 450 deputies of the State Duma (Article 95), each elected to a term of four years (Article 96); this was changed to a five-year term in late 2008. In previous elections of 1993, 1995, 1999 and 2003 one half of the deputies were elected by a system of [[proportional representation]] and one half were elected by [[Plurality voting system|plurality in single member districts]]. However, the 2007 Duma elections were carried out in a new format: all 450 deputies were elected by a system of proportional representation. Russian citizens at least 21 years old are eligible to run for the Duma (Article 97).

== See also ==
* [[Elections in Russia]]
* [[Tauride Palace]]
* [[Moscow City Duma]]
* [[Saint Petersburg City Duma]]
* [[Zemsky Sobor]]
* [[Veche]]

==References==
* {{1911}}

{{coord|55|45|29|N|37|36|55|E|region:RU-MOW_type:landmark_source:kolossus-dewiki|display=title}}

[[Category:Historical legislatures|Russia]]
[[Category:Government of Russia]]
[[Category:Russian words and phrases]]
[[Category:Government of the Russian Empire]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
