<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Induced coma"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Induced coma" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;A &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;barbiturate-induced coma&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, or &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;barb coma&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, is a temporary [[coma]] (a deep state of [[unconsciousness]]) brought on by a controlled dose of a [[barbiturate]] drug, usually [[pentobarbital]] or [[thiopental]]. Barbiturate comas are used to protect the [[brain]] during major [[neurosurgery]], and as a last line of treatment in certain cases of [[status epilepticus]] that have not responded to other treatments.

Barbiturates reduce the metabolic rate of brain tissue, as well as the [[cerebral blood flow]]. With these reductions, the [[blood vessel]]s in the brain narrow, decreasing the amount of space occupied by the brain, and hence the [[intracranial pressure]]. The hope is that, with the swelling relieved, the pressure decreases and some or all [[brain damage]] may be averted. Several studies have supported this theory by showing reduced mortality when treating refractory intracranial hypertension with a barbiturate coma.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;{{cite journal|date=Jun-July 2000 |title=Use of barbiturates in the control of intracranial hypertension|journal=Journal of Neurotrauma|publisher=The Brain Trauma Foundation| volume=17| issue=6–7| pages=527–30| pmid=10937896|doi=10.1089/neu.2000.17.527}}&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;{{cite journal|title=The efficacy of barbiturate coma in the management of uncontrolled intracranial hypertension following neurosurgical trauma|journal=Journal of Neurotrauma| date=1994-06-01|first=MW|last=Lee|coauthors=Deppe SA, Sipperly ME, Barrette RR, Thompson DR.|volume=11|issue=3|pages=325–31|pmid=7996586|doi=10.1089/neu.1994.11.325}}&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;{{cite journal|title=The effect of high dose barbiturate decompression after severe head injury: A controlled clinical trial|journal=Acta Neurochirurgica |year=1984|first=HK|last=Nordby|coauthors=Nesbakken R| volume=72| issue=3–4| pages=157–66| pmid=6382945| doi=10.1007/BF01406868}}&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

Controversy exists, however, over the benefits of using barbiturates to control [[intracranial hypertension]]. Some studies have shown that barbiturate-induced coma can reduce intracranial hypertension but does not necessarily prevent brain damage. Furthermore, the reduction in intracranial hypertension may not be sustained. Some [[Randomized controlled trial|randomized trial]]s have failed to demonstrate any survival or morbidity benefit of induced coma in diverse conditions such as neurosurgical operations, [[head trauma]],&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;{{cite journal|title=The University of Toronto head injury treatment study: a prospective, randomized comparison of pentobarbital and mannitol|journal=The Canadian Journal of Neurological Sciences|date=1984-11-01|first=ML|last=Schwartz|coauthors=Tator CH, Rowed DW, Reid SR, Meguro K, Andrews DF|volume=11|issue=4|pages=434–40|pmid=6440704}}&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt; [[cerebral aneurysm|intracranial aneurysm]] rupture, [[intracranial hemorrhage]], ischemic [[stroke]], and [[status epilepticus]]. If the patient survives,  cognitive impairment may also follow recovery from the coma.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt; {{cite journal|title=Clinical outcome and cognitive impairment in patients with severe head injuries treated with barbiturate coma|journal=Acta Neurochir|year=1992|first=W|last=Schalén|coauthors=Sonesson B, Messeter K, Nordström G, Nordström CH|volume=117|issue=3–4|pages=153–9|pmid=1414516|doi=10.1007/BF01400613}}&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

About 55% of the glucose and oxygen utilisation by the brain is meant for its electrical activity and the rest for all other activities such as metabolism{{Citation needed|date=February 2013}}. This is recognized by a device such as an [[electroencephalogram]] (EEG), which measures electrical activity in the brain.  When barbiturates are given to brain injured patients for induced coma, they act by reducing the electrical activity of the brain, which in theory reduces the metabolic and oxygen demand{{Citation needed|date=February 2013}}.  Once there is improvement in the patient&amp;apos;s general condition, the barbiturates are withdrawn gradually and the patient regains consciousness.

Induced coma was used in the treatment of symptomatic [[rabies]] through the [[Milwaukee protocol]]{{Citation needed|date=February 2013}}.

==Famous people with induced coma==
*[[Ariel Sharon]]
*[[Gabrielle Giffords]]
*[[Tupac Shakur]]
*[[Phil Harris]]
*[[Fritzl case|Kerstin Fritzl]]
*[[Jesse Ryder]]
*[[Harryx Stafford (motorcycle racer)|Harry Stafford]]

==See also==
*[[Traumatic brain injury]]

==References==
{{Reflist}}

[[Category:Neurology procedures]]
[[Category:Intensive care medicine]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
