<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Calf of Man"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Calf of Man" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Infobox islands
&amp;lt;!-- See Template:Infobox islands for additional fields and descriptions --&amp;gt;
| name            = Calf of Man
| native name     = Yn Cholloo
| native name lang= glv
| other name      = Calf of Mann
| image name      = Sound IOM.JPG
| image caption   = The Calf Sound, taken from direction of [[Cregneash]]
| country         = [[Isle of Man]]
| highest mount   = Unnamed
| elevation_ft    = 415
| area ha         = 250
| population      = 2
| density km2     =
}}
&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Calf of Man&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; ({{lang-gv|Yn Cholloo}}), sometimes known as the &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Calf of Mann&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, is a {{convert|618|acre|ha|adj=on}} island (almost 1 square mile), off the southwest coast of the [[Isle of Man]].&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;[http://www.gov.im/mnh/heritage/countryside/sound/visitingcalf.xml Manx Heritage website - Visiting the Calf of Man page]&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;[http://www.bbc.co.uk/isleofman/content/articles/2005/10/07/calf_of_man_feature.shtml BBC Isle of Man website]&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;[http://www.gov.im/mnh/heritage/countryside/sound/landandsea.xml Manx Heritage website - Land and Sea page]&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt; It is separated from the Isle of Man by a narrow stretch of water called the [[Calf Sound]]. Like the nearby rocky islets of [[Chicken Rock]] and [[Kitterland]], it is part of the parish of [[Rushen]]. It has two seasonal inhabitants. The word &amp;apos;calf&amp;apos; derives from the [[Old Norse]] word &amp;apos;&amp;apos;kalfr&amp;apos;&amp;apos; which means a small island lying near a larger one. It is possible to reach the Calf of Man by boat from both Port Erin and Port St Mary. Cow Harbour and South Harbour are the main landing places. The highest part of the island is to the west where an unnamed peak reaches 415 feet (128 metres) above [[sea level]].

Until 1939 the island was under private ownership by the Keig family, but in that year the island was purchased by Mr F J Dickens of Silverdale, Lancashire who then donated it to the [[National Trust for Places of Historic Interest or Natural Beauty|National Trust]] to become a bird sanctuary. In 1951 the [[Manx National Heritage|Manx National Trust]] was established, which became Manx National Heritage. In 2006 Manx National Heritage employed the charity [[Manx Wildlife Trust]] as the Calf Warden Service Provider, but it retains ownership. The island has been a [[bird observatory]] since 1959 and welcomes visits from volunteers and ornithologists. The observatory is able to accommodate up to eight visitors in basic self-catering accommodation which can be booked through Manx National Heritage.

[[File:Calf of Man, Lower Lighthouse - geograph.org.uk - 725406.jpg|thumb|left|Calf of Man, Lower Lighthouse One of two built by Robert Stevenson in 1818 to steer ships clear of Chicken Rock. Now disused]]
The Calf of Man and its offshore rocks have no fewer than four [[lighthouses]]: two lighthouses were built in 1818 by [[Robert Stevenson (civil engineer)|Robert Stevenson]] to warn mariners of the hazards of the [[Chicken Rock]]s off the south end of the Calf. These were replaced in 1875 by a lighthouse built on the Chicken Rocks themselves. In 1968, a third lighthouse was built on the Calf after a severe fire destroyed the Chicken Rocks light. The Chicken Rocks lighthouse was later rebuilt.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;Coakley, F. (2001) [http://www.isle-of-man.com/manxnotebook/maritime/lighthse/lh_calf.htm Calf of Man Lights] and [http://www.isle-of-man.com/manxnotebook/maritime/lighthse/lh_crock.htm Chicken Rock Light], both in: &amp;apos;&amp;apos;A Manx Notebook: An electronic compendium of matters past and present connected with the Isle of Man&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, [accessed 14 may 2007]&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt; There are two minor, unfenced roads on the island and two very short streams.

Between the Isle of Man and the Calf is the islet of [[Kitterland]], while the islets of {{lang|gv|Yn Burroo}} and The Stack lie close to the Calf&amp;apos;s shore. The southern shore of the island encloses a small bay called The Puddle. Almost a mile southwest of the Calf is Chicken Rock, the most southerly part of the Isle of Man&amp;apos;s territory.

Calf of Man is home to a breeding population of [[Manx Shearwater]]s, a seabird which derives its name from its presence in Manx waters.

==References==
{{reflist}}
* Ralph Phillips. Modern British Locals Catalogue. Part I [CD-ROM] (title from CD-ROM label). [S.l.]: British Locals Philatelic Agency, 2009.

==External links==
* [http://www.isleofman.com/Community/ePedia/Geography/Islands/CalfOfMan.aspx Information about the Calf of Man]
* [http://www.gov.im/mnh/heritage/countryside/sound/observatory.xml Calf of Man Bird Observatory]

{{coord|54|03|10|N|4|49|13|W|display=title|region:IM_type:isle}}

[[Category:Islands of the Isle of Man]]
[[Category:Calves (islands)]]

{{Link GA|fr}}&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
