<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="William Henry Fitton"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="William Henry Fitton" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Use dmy dates|date=April 2012}}
[[Image:William Henry Fitton.jpg|thumb|William Henry Fitton in 1860]]

&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;William Henry Fitton&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (January 1780 – 13 May 1861) was an Irish physician and amateur geologist
==Biography==
Fitton was born in [[Dublin]] and educated at [[Trinity College, Dublin|Trinity College]] in that city. He gained the senior scholarship in 1798, and graduated in the following year. At this time he began to take an interest in geology and to form a collection of [[fossils]]. Having adopted the medical profession, he proceeded in 1808 to [[Edinburgh]], where he attended the lectures of Robert Jameson, and thenceforth his interest in natural history and especially in geology steadily increased. He moved to London in 1809, where he studied medicine and chemistry. In 1811 he presented to the [[Geological Society of London]] a description of the geological structure of the vicinity of Dublin, with an account of some rare minerals found in Ireland. He took a medical practice at [[Northampton]] in 1812, and for some years the duties of his profession engrossed his time. He was admitted M.D. at [[Cambridge]] in 1816.

In 1820, having married a lady of means, Fitton settled in London, and devoted himself to geology. His &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Observations on some of the Strata between the Chalk and the Oxford Oolite, in the South-east of England&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (Trans. Geol. Soc. ser. 2, vol. iv.) embodied a series of researches extending from 1824 to 1836, and form the memoir  known as &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Fitton&amp;apos;s Strata below the Chalk&amp;apos;&amp;apos;. In this work he established the true succession and relations of the Upper and Lower Greensand, and of the Wealden and Purbeck formations, and elaborated their detailed structure. He had been elected fellow of the [[Royal Society]] in 1815, and he was [[president of the Geological Society of London]] in 1827–1829. His house then became a meeting place for scientific workers, and during his presidency he held a [[conversazione]] open on Sunday evenings to all fellows of the Geological Society. From 1817 to 1841 he contributed to the Edinburgh Review many essays on the progress of geological science, and reviews of the groundbreaking books of [[William Smith (geologist)]], [[Charles Lyell]], and [[Roderick Murchison]]; he also wrote &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Notes on the Progress of Geology in England&amp;apos;&amp;apos; for the Philosophical Magazine (1832–1833). His only independent publication was &amp;apos;&amp;apos;A Geological Sketch of the Vicinity of [[Hastings]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (1833). He was awarded the [[Wollaston Medal]] by the Geological Society in 1852. This medal is now in the collection of the Geological Museum, Trinity College, Dublin. Around 1825, according to [[Charles Babbage]]&amp;apos;s autobiography, he invented the [[thaumatrope]], which was later commercially publicised by Dr. [[John Ayrton Paris]] (to whom the invention is more usually attributed). He died in London.

==References==
{{Wikisource1911Enc|Fitton, William Henry}}
*{{1911|article=William Henry Fitton|url=http://www.1911encyclopedia.org/William_Henry_Fitton}}
*Gass, KC. 2000. Fragments of History. Specialized Quality Publications, Wisconsin Rapids, 41p.
*Wyse Jackson, Patrick N. 1998. William Henry Fitton (1780-1861) and the Wollaston Medal of 1852. Geoscientist vol. 6, p. 10.

&amp;lt;!--on account of location of birth and education--&amp;gt;

{{GLS Presidents}}

{{Authority control|VIAF=47517277}}
{{Persondata &amp;lt;!-- Metadata: see [[Wikipedia:Persondata]]. --&amp;gt;
| NAME              = Fitton, William Henry
| ALTERNATIVE NAMES =
| SHORT DESCRIPTION =
| DATE OF BIRTH     = 1780
| PLACE OF BIRTH    =
| DATE OF DEATH     = 13 May 1861
| PLACE OF DEATH    =
}}
{{DEFAULTSORT:Fitton, William Henry}}
[[Category:1780 births]]
[[Category:1861 deaths]]
[[Category:Alumni of Trinity College, Dublin]]
[[Category:British geologists]]
[[Category:Irish geologists]]
[[Category:Fellows of the Royal Society]]
[[Category:People from County Dublin]]
[[Category:Presidents of the Geological Society of London]]
[[Category:Wollaston Medal winners]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
