<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Nickajack Expedition"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Nickajack Expedition" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;The &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Nickajack Expedition&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; was the last great battle of the [[Chickamauga Wars (1776–1794)|Chickamauga wars]]. It was fought from late summer to fall of 1794 between American [[frontiersmen]] and the [[Chickamauga Cherokee]]. The military expedition was a decisive success for the American settlers of the [[Southwest Territory]] and surrounding regions, eventually becoming known as the &amp;quot;Last Battle of the Cherokee&amp;quot;.

==Background==
Following a 1777 [[peace treaty]] between [[Native Americans in the United States|Native Americans]] and the American settlers of [[Washington District, North Carolina|the Overhill settlements]] west of the [[Appalachian Mountains]] during the [[American War of Independence]], followers of the [[Cherokee]] chief [[Dragging Canoe]] (who opposed the peace), separated from the tribe and relocated to what is today southeastern Tennessee, near the borders with [[Georgia (U.S. state)|Georgia]] and the area later known as [[Alabama]].  They were joined by groups of [[Shawnee]] and [[Creek people|Creek]] at this new settlement, which had been established along Chickamauga Creek &amp;amp;ndash;which became their namesake. The Chickamauga Cherokee engaged in ongoing [[Raid (military)|raid]]s against American settlers, often with [[British people|British]] and [[Spanish people|Spanish]] military aid. Shortly after the conclusion to the war, they again moved, this time west of [[Lookout Mountain]], using Nickajack Cave as a [[stronghold]].  Violence between the two sides continued unabated for decades.

Not withstanding the December 1791 [[Treaty of Holston]] between [[Territories of the United States|Territorial]] Governor [[William Blount]]  and most Cherokee tribes, settlers in the &amp;quot;[[Cumberland River|Cumberland Region]]&amp;quot; (especially around the [[Nashville, Tennessee|Nashville]] area) still feared for their lives, having come under increasing attacks from the Chickamauga and their allies to the south. By 1792, Blount was engaged in continuing peace negotiations with the Chickamauga. However, when the sons of Colonel Anthony Bledsoe and Major General George Winchester were killed in 1794, Blount finally sanctioned military action.

== The expedition ==
[[File:Fiver Lower Towns.jpg|thumb|rt|250 px|The area of the Chickamauga Cherokee settlements]]
Governor Blount appointed Major James Ore to head an expedition against the Chickamauga, or &amp;quot;Lower Cherokee&amp;quot; as they had come to be known. Col. John Montgomery commanded the territorial militia, and Col. William Whitley of Kentucky (whose state had been the subject of many attacks launched from this area by the Cherokee) commanded his 6th Regiment of militia.  They singled out two Chickamauga villages, [[Nickajack Town]] and [[Running Water Town]], as the objects of attack, as these villages were the source of many of the raiding parties. However, finding their locations and a method of attack was problematic for the American force.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;[http://www.rootsweb.ancestry.com/~tnmcmin2/jguylastbattle.htm Last Battle of the Cherokee]&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

The armies finally came against Nickajack Town in mid-August, but found only a hundred or so warriors present.  Many of the villagers had heard of the army&amp;apos;s approach and had fled to Running Water Town before Ore&amp;apos;s men could reach the village. Warriors from Running Water Town were on their way to Nickajack to investigate the activity and encountered the fleeing villagers along the way.  The Nickajack group merged with the Running Water group, and together they proceeded back to engage the Americans.

By this time the militias had begun a pursuit of the fleeing villagers. The two sides met at &amp;quot;the Narrows&amp;quot; along the [[Tennessee River]] and engaged in battle.  It proved to be a disaster for the Chickamauga.  They were quickly routed, and managed to wound only three Americans, killing none. The armies quickly destroyed both villages, leaving seventy dead. It was reported that Col. Whitley personally shot a warrior out of a moving canoe at some distance after some of his men had failed to make the deadly shot.

== Aftermath ==
Coupled with other military victories which followed quickly upon their defeat at Nickajack Town and Running Water Town, the Chickamauga were resigned to sign several treaties favorable to the Americans, including the [[Treaty of Tellico]].

==References==
{{reflist}}

==Notes==
*Albright, E. (1909).&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Early History of Middle Tennessee&amp;apos;&amp;apos; Nashville: Branden. Chapter 38 available from [http://www.rootsweb.com/~tnsumner/early38.htm the [[RootsWeb.com]] website] for [[Sumner County, Tennessee]]

[[Category:Conflicts in 1794]]
[[Category:1794 in the United States]]
[[Category:Cherokee Nation (19th century)]]
[[Category:Pre-statehood history of Tennessee]]
[[Category:Colonial American and Indian wars]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
