<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="William Molineux"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="William Molineux" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;There are several people bearing the name of William Mol&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;y&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;neux: for the list, see [[Molyneux (surname)]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos;

&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;William Molineux&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (c. 1717 &amp;amp;ndash; October 22, 1774) was a hardware merchant in colonial [[Boston]] best known for his role in the [[Boston Tea Party]] of 1773 and earlier political protests.

Molineux was unusual among the Boston [[Radical Whigs|Whigs]] in having been born in [[England]] and emigrating to Massachusetts. He was also not part of the province&amp;apos;s [[Congregational church|Congregationalist]] orthodoxy, attending an [[Anglican]] church and reportedly dabbling with [[deist]] views. Insurance records show that Molineux broke British trade laws in his business by sending ships to the [[Dutch Republic]], so he might have been motivated to join the radical cause by increased [[customs]] duties and enforcement in the 1760s. Colleagues like [[John Adams]] described him as a volatile man.

Molineux rose to prominence leading committees and crowds in demonstrations against the [[Townshend Acts]], seizures by customs officers, and the stationing of British troops in Boston. He also organized a public works effort to employ the town&amp;apos;s poor at spinning and weaving linen. With Doctor [[Thomas Young (American Revolutionary)|Thomas Young]] he was one of the most radical among the genteel Whig organizers who sought to steer public demonstrations in Boston after 1765. For example, on January 18, 1770, he advocated a march on acting governor [[Thomas Hutchinson (governor)|Thomas Hutchinson]]&amp;apos;s mansion despite warnings that such an act against the king&amp;apos;s representative was tantamount to treason, and reportedly threatened to kill himself if his colleagues did not agree.

Molineux was the only top Whig organizer not in [[Old South Meeting House]] on the night of the Tea Party, meaning he was probably at the dock observing the destruction of the tea. In 1774 he set an example by refusing [[jury duty]] under royal judges and may have helped to gather field [[artillery]] for the province. However, in late October, he suddenly became ill, and on October 22 he died, reportedly saying, &amp;quot;O save my Country, Heaven.&amp;quot;

Conflicting rumors circulated. The working-class Whigs who followed Molineux suggested he had been poisoned by British army officers. Friends of the royal government said he had committed suicide after being caught embezzling for the linen project from a New York merchant whose affairs he represented. His estate was in debt to that man, but Molineux may have died of entirely natural causes.

Because Molineux died before the [[American Revolutionary War]] began, and because some of his colleagues were uncomfortable with his radical methods, he was largely omitted in histories of America&amp;apos;s independence. In fact, his name was preserved most prominently in a short story by [[Nathaniel Hawthorne]] titled &amp;quot;My Kinsman, Major Molineux,&amp;quot; set in the 1740s, in which the title character is a victim, not a leader, of a Boston crowd. Molineux&amp;apos;s home on [[Beacon Hill, Boston, Massachusetts]] was torn down to make room for the [[Massachusetts State House]].

He is a featured character in the 2012 video game, [[Assassin&amp;apos;s Creed III]]

==References==
*Bell, J. L. [http://boston1775.blogspot.com/2007/06/william-molineux-forgotten.html &amp;quot;William Molineux, Forgotten Revolutionary&amp;quot;]
*Tyler, John W. &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Smugglers &amp;amp; Patriots: Boston Merchants and the Advent of the American Revolution&amp;apos;&amp;apos;. Boston: Northeastern University Press, 1986. ISBN 0-930350-76-6.

{{Authority control|VIAF=7237147}}
{{Persondata &amp;lt;!-- Metadata: see [[Wikipedia:Persondata]]. --&amp;gt;
| NAME              = Molineux, William
| ALTERNATIVE NAMES =
| SHORT DESCRIPTION =
| DATE OF BIRTH     = 1717
| PLACE OF BIRTH    =
| DATE OF DEATH     = 1774
| PLACE OF DEATH    =











}}
{{DEFAULTSORT:Molineux, William}}
[[Category:1717 births]]
[[Category:1774 deaths]]
[[Category:Colonial American merchants]]
[[Category:Colonial American smugglers]]
[[Category:Patriots in the American Revolution]]
[[Category:People from colonial Boston, Massachusetts]]
[[Category:People of Massachusetts in the American Revolution]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
