<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="University of Glasgow Medico-Chirurgical Society"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="University of Glasgow Medico-Chirurgical Society" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{ Infobox Students Union |
name = University of Glasgow Medico-Chirurgical Society|
image = |
address =  |
established = 1802 |
institution = [[University of Glasgow]] |
president = Sophie Hodgson |
affiliated =  |
location = [[Glasgow]], [[Scotland]], [[UK]] |
members = 700 |
homepage = [http://www.medchir.co.uk Med-Chir Homepage] |
}}
The &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;University of Glasgow Medico-Chirurgical Society&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is a student society at the [[University of Glasgow]] which organises social and educational events for medical and nursing students at the University. The current President (2012-2013) is Sophie Hodgson.
==History==
Founded in 1802, Med-Chir is one of the University&amp;apos;s oldest societies and, along with the [[Glasgow University Dialectic Society]] and [[Glasgow University Sports Association|Glasgow University Athletic Club]], was instrumental in founding the [[Glasgow University Union]], with which it retains close ties.
==Activities==
The University of Glasgow Medico-Chirurgical Society, AKA MedChir, is one of Glasgow University’s longest running societies and has been making Thursday nights fun since 1802.  MedChir are responsible for organising the biggest and best social nights, educational events and the sports teams for Glasgow University Medical Students.  MedChir also raise money for a different charity each year.  Last year they raised over £1600 for [http://ronaldmcdonaldhouse.co.uk Yorkhill Family Housing Ltd], a charity dedicated to providing accommodation to the families of sick children.  This year MedChir are supporting [http://www.unitecharity.com Unite Against Cancer], a new charity that aims to fund research into novel cancer treatments.

MedChir organise major social events, such as the Annual Medical School Ball and the Revue (all-medic talent competition, won by [[Emeli Sandé]] during her time at Glasgow).  They also offer talks from the most prestigious speakers in their fields, events for students to practice their clinical skills and hold joint evenings with the Royal College of General Practitioners and Royal College of Physicians and Surgeons.  MedChir members participate in the Scottish and Northern Irish Medics Sports tournament (SNIMS) every year, hosting and winning the event in October 2012.

Additionally, &amp;apos;Surgo&amp;apos; has been MedChir’s in-house publication since 1935 and it provides a light-hearted look at medic life as well as anything else that catches the editorial team’s eyes.

Many illustrious former members maintain a link with the society and the MedChir Life Members Tie has been spotted on more than a few occasions, notably when [[Sam Galbraith]] presented the Scottish Cup. During the 2011-12 session the MedChir Life Members Badge was introduced.

==Archives==
The archives for the University of Glasgow Medico-Chirurgical Society are maintained by the [[Archives of the University of Glasgow| Archives of the University of Glasgow (GUAS)]].

== External links ==
*[http://www.medchir.co.uk Med-Chir Homepage]

[[Category:1802 establishments in Scotland]]
[[Category:Clubs and societies of the University of Glasgow|Medico-Chirugical Society]]

{{UK-university-stub}}
{{University of Glasgow}}&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
