<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Zheng Zhong"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Zheng Zhong" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Unreferenced|date=February 2008}}

&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Zheng Zhong&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (鄭眾), courtesy name &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Jichan&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (季產) (died 107), was the first [[Han Dynasty]] [[eunuch]] with true power in government, thanks to the trust that [[Emperor He of Han|Emperor He]] had in him for his contributions in overthrowing the clan of [[Empress Dou (Zhang)|Empress Dowager Dou]], particularly her autocratic brother [[Dou Xian]].  He was also a close associate of Emperor He&amp;apos;s wife [[Empress Deng Sui]] and continued to be powerful after Emperor He&amp;apos;s death, during her regency over his son [[Emperor Shang of Han|Emperor Shang]] and [[Emperor An of Han|Emperor An]].  He was also the first Eastern Han Dynasty eunuch to be created a marquess.  (The only Western Han Dynasty eunuch who was created a marquess was [[Empress Xu Pingjun]]&amp;apos;s father Xu Guanghan (許廣漢), whose creation was thanks to his relationship with his daughter and his son-in-law [[Emperor Xuan of Han|Emperor Xuan]], not his post as a eunuch.)

Zheng was from Nanyang Commandery (roughly modern [[Nanyang, Henan|Nanyang]], [[Henan]]) -- the same commandery that the Eastern Han imperial clan was from.  He was described to be cautious, agile, and a deep thinker.  He first served in the household of [[Emperor Zhang of Han|Emperor Zhang]] while he was still [[crown prince]] under his father [[Emperor Ming of Han|Emperor Ming]].  After Emperor Zhang ascended the throne, he was eventually promoted to the post of imperial attendant (中常侍).

During the time of Empress Dowager Dou&amp;apos;s regency over Emperor He, Zheng served as the director of imperial gardens (鉤盾令).  He was one of the eunuchs who did not endear himself to Empress Dowager Dou&amp;apos;s clan.  In 92, Emperor He, apparently dissatisfied with his suppression by the Dou clan, plotted a coup d&amp;apos;état with his brother [[Liu Qing (prince)|Liu Qing]] the Prince of Qinghe, and Zheng.  They were successful in carrying out the overthrow of the Dous, and as a reward, Emperor He promoted Zheng to the post of the empress&amp;apos; palace&amp;apos;s head of household (大長秋).  Zheng accepted the post but declined most of the monetary rewards that Emperor He gave him, a fact that made Emperor He even more impressed with him.  Emperor He often consulted with him on major affairs of state, and this started a precedent of eunuchs becoming involved in imperial governance.

In 102, breaking past precedent, Emperor He created Zheng the Marquess of Chaoxiang.

Zheng supported Emperor He&amp;apos;s wife Empress Deng through the turmoils of Emperor He&amp;apos;s death in 106 and the death of his son and successor Emperor Shang later that year.  For his support, she added 300 households to his [[marches|march]] in 107.  He died later that year.

{{Persondata &amp;lt;!-- Metadata: see [[Wikipedia:Persondata]]. --&amp;gt;
| NAME              = Zheng, Zhong
| ALTERNATIVE NAMES =
| SHORT DESCRIPTION = Han Dynasty Eunuch
| DATE OF BIRTH     =
| PLACE OF BIRTH    =
| DATE OF DEATH     = 107
| PLACE OF DEATH    =
}}
{{DEFAULTSORT:Zheng, Zhong}}
[[Category:Han Dynasty eunuchs]]
[[Category:107 deaths]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
