<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="R-1 (missile)"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="R-1 (missile)" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{more footnotes|date=October 2007}}
The &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;R-1&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; rocket ([[NATO reporting name]] SS-1 Scunner, Soviet code name SA11) based&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;http://www.energia.ru/ru/history/systems/rockets/r1.html&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt; on the [[Germany|German]] [[V-2 rocket]] manufactured by the [[Soviet Union]].  Even though it was a copy, it was manufactured using Soviet industrial plants and gave the Soviets valuable experience which later enabled  the USSR to construct its own much more capable rockets.
[[File:Soviet SS- 1a Scunner.gif|thumb||SS- 1a Scunner]]
In 1945 the Soviets captured several key V-2 rocket production facilities, and also gained the services of some German scientists and engineers connected to the project.  In particular the Soviets gained control of the main [[Mittelwerk|V-2 manufacturing facility]] at [[Nordhausen]], and had 30 V-2 missiles assembled there by September 1946.

In October 1946 the Soviets transferred the German missile engineers working for them to a special research facility near [[Moscow]], where they  were forced to remain until the mid-1950s. The Soviets established a missile design bureau of their own ([[OKB-1]]), under the direction of [[Sergey Korolev]].  This team was directed to create a Soviet capability to build missiles, starting with a Soviet copy of the German V-2 and moving to more advanced, Soviet-designed missiles in the near future.

In April 1947 Stalin authorised the production of the R-1 missile, the designation for the Soviet copy of V-2. The [[GRAU]] index 8A11 was also used. The first tests of the missile began in September 1948. The system was accepted by the Soviet army in November 1950. The R-1 missile could carry a 785&amp;amp;nbsp;kg warhead of conventional explosive to a maximum range of 270&amp;amp;nbsp;km, with an accuracy of about 5&amp;amp;nbsp;km.

In 1947, the R-1A was tested, a variant with a separable warhead. High-altitude scientific experiments were flown with two of the R-1As, and later a series of specialized scientific rockets were built on the basis of the R-1: The R-1B, R-1V, R-1D and R-1E.  These carried dogs, and experiments to analyze the upper atmosphere, measure cosmic rays and take far-UV spectra of the Sun.

The R-1&amp;apos;s [[electrical wiring|insulated electrical wiring]] attracted [[vermin]]. In one January 1953 incident, thousands of flood-displaced mice disabled many rockets by eating the insulation, requiring &amp;quot;hundreds of [[cat]]s and repairmen&amp;quot;.&amp;lt;ref name=siddiqi2000&amp;gt;{{cite book | last = Siddiqi | first = Asif A. | url = http://history.nasa.gov/printFriendly/series95.html | title = Challenge To Apollo: The Soviet Union and the Space Race, 1945-1974 | publisher = [[NASA]]}}&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;{{rp|116}}

==Operators==
;{{USSR}}
*[[Soviet Army]]

== See also ==

* [[List of missiles]]

==References==
&amp;lt;references/&amp;gt;
http://www.russianspaceweb.com/r1.html&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
http://www.astronautix.com/lvs/r1.htm

== External links ==
* [http://www.globalsecurity.org/wmd/world/russia/r-1.htm Global Security: R-1 / SS-1 SCUNNER]
* [http://mil.mipt.ru/military/press/f_2gqoov/a_2gqoug.html &amp;quot;Decision for breakthrough [technology&amp;amp;#93;&amp;quot;] (Russian)

{{Russian and Soviet surface-to-surface missiles}}

{{Russian and Soviet military designation sequences}}

[[Category:Short-range ballistic missiles of the Soviet Union|R-001]]
[[Category:Cold War missiles of the Soviet Union]]
[[Category:Germany–Soviet Union relations]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
