<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Kushtaka"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Kushtaka" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Unreferenced|date=August 2008}}

&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Kushtaka&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; are [[myth]]ical creatures found in the stories of the [[Tlingit people|Tlingit]] and [[Tsimshian]] Indians of Southeastern [[Alaska]]. Loosely translated, kushtaka means, &amp;quot;land otter man&amp;quot;.

They are similar to the [[Nat&amp;apos;ina]] of the [[Dena&amp;apos;ina people|Dan&amp;apos;aina]] Indians of South Central Alaska, and the [[Urayuli]] of the [[Eskimos]] in Northern Alaska.

Physically, kushtaka are [[Shapeshifting|shape-shifter]]s capable of assuming either human form or the form of an [[otter]]. In some accounts, a kushtaka is able to assume the form of any species of otter; in others, only one. Accounts of their behaviour seem to conflict with one another. In some stories, kushtaka are cruel creatures who take delight in tricking poor Tlingit sailors to their deaths. In others, they are friendly and helpful, frequently saving the lost from death by freezing. In many stories, the kushtaka save the lost individual by distracting them with curiously otter-like [[illusion]]s of their family and friends as they [[transform]] their subject into a fellow kushtaka, thus allowing him to survive in the cold. Naturally, this is counted a mixed blessing. However, kushtaka legends are not always pleasant. In some legends it is said the kushtaka will imitate the cries of a baby or the screams of a woman to lure victims to the [[river]]. Once there, the kushtaka either kills the person and tears them to shreds or will turn them into another kushtaka.

Legends have it kushtaka can be warded off through copper, urine, and in some stories fire.

Since the kushtaka mainly preys on small children, it has been thought by some that it was used by Tlingit mothers to keep their children from wandering close to the [[ocean]] by themselves.

It is also said that the kushtaka emit a high pitched, three part whistle in the pattern of low-high-low.

== Kushtaka in modern literature ==
Kushtaka&amp;apos;s appear in [[Pamela Rae Huteson]]&amp;apos;s &amp;quot;Legends in Wood, Stories of the Totems&amp;quot; in the legend &amp;apos;War with the Land Otter Men&amp;apos;, as well as [[Pamela Rae Huteson]]&amp;apos;s &amp;quot;Transformation Masks&amp;quot; with the &amp;apos;Kushtaka Den&amp;apos;; and [[Garth Stein]]&amp;apos;s &amp;quot;Raven Stole the Moon&amp;quot;. [[Harry D. Colp]] describes a miner&amp;apos;s encounter with the kushtaka, published as &amp;quot;The Strangest Story Ever Told.&amp;quot;[http://www.bigfootencounters.com/stories/harrycolp.htm]

[[Category:Legendary creatures of the indigenous peoples of North America]]
[[Category:Legendary mammals]]
[[Category:Hominid cryptids]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
