<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="H. J. Mulliner &amp; Co."
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="H. J. Mulliner &amp; Co." />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;[[File:1954 Bentley R-Type Continental HJ Mulliner Sports Saloon - chassis BC2LC - fvr.jpg|thumb|right|Bentley Continental 2-dr sports saloon by H J Mulliner &amp;amp; Co of Chiswick 1954]]
[[File:1954 Bentley R-Type Continental HJ Mulliner Sports Saloon - chassis BC2LC - int.jpg|thumb|right|interior of the Bentley in the image above]]

&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;H. J. Mulliner &amp;amp; Co.&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; was a well-known British [[coachbuilder]] operating at Chiswick in West London.

The Mulliner family can trace their coachbuilding history back to 1760, building coaches for the Royal Mail in [[Northampton]].

Mulliner now is the personal commissioning department for [[Bentley Motors Limited|Bentley]].

==Origin==
There were at one time four separate businesses trading with the name Mulliner, all seem to have belonged to people descended from the original family:

*&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Arthur Mulliner&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; based in [[Northampton]];
*&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Mulliner&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; based in [[Liverpool]] which also opened a showroom in Brook Street, [[Mayfair]], London jointly with Arthur Mulliner trading as &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Mulliner (London) Ltd.&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;;
*&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;H.J. Mulliner&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; who bought the Mayfair showroom;
*&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Mulliners (Birmingham)|Mulliners&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; of Birmingham]].

==History==

===Arthur Mulliner===
Arthur H Mulliner was the son of F Mulliner who set up the original Mulliner company making mail coaches in Northampton. Arthur H&amp;apos;s son Arthur Felton Mulliner (born 1859) took the company into the construction of motor car bodies and by 1900 they had built over 150 mainly on [[Daimler Company|Daimler]] cars. In 1907, as well as the Northampton works, a new sales office and factory was opened in Long Acre, London. Business boomed during the 1920s with orders for bodies on [[Armstrong Siddeley]] and [[Vauxhall Motors|Vauxhall]] cars being exhibited at the 1920 London Motor Show.

In the 1930s although orders for the more traditional makers such as Rolls-Royce and Bentley continued, large production runs from the middle market makers were proving harder to get and in 1939 the business was sold to the car distributor [[Henlys Group|Henlys]] which closed the coachbuilding business but kept the sales and marketing operation which lasted until 1976.

===H J Mulliner &amp;amp; Co===

Henry Jervis Mulliner founded H.J. Mulliner &amp;amp; Co. a coachbuilding business in 1900 in Brook Street, Mayfair, London. These were probably the premises previously occupied by Mulliners (London) Ltd. The location was convenient for his clients. One of the early clients was [[C.S. Rolls]] who had a body built on a Rolls-Royce Silver Ghost for his own use.

In 1906 the works moved out of Mayfair to Chiswick and shortly afterwards H.J. Mulliner sold his interest in the company to John Croall and retired. A family connection was maintained as Croall employed H. J. Mulliner&amp;apos;s brother in law Frank Piesse to run the company.

Although bodies were fitted to other chassis, by the 1930s virtually the entire output was being fitted to Rolls-Royce and Bentleys.

[[Rolls-Royce Limited|Rolls-Royce]] acquired Mulliner in 1959 and merged it with [[Park Ward]] which they had owned since 1939 forming [[Mulliner Park Ward]] in 1961.

==See also==
*[[Mulliner Park Ward]]
*[[Park Ward]]
*[[Mulliners (Birmingham)]]

==References==
*A-Z of British Coachbuilders. Nick Walker. Bay View Books 1997. ISBN 1-870979-93-1

==External links==
{{commons category|H J Mulliner coachwork}}
*[http://www.flickr.com/photos/14531705@N00/5117602217/lightbox/ Design for a coupé de ville on a Bentley 4¼ litre chassis]

{{DEFAULTSORT:H. J. Mulliner and Co.}}
[[Category:Coachbuilders of the United Kingdom|Mulliner]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
