<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Hooded Spirits"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Hooded Spirits" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;[[File:Genii cucullati and Goddess, relief, Corinium Museum .jpg|thumb|Three &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Genii Cucullati&amp;apos;&amp;apos; and a goddess on a relief from [[Roman Britain]]]]

The &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Hooded Spirits&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; or &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Genii Cucullati&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; are figures found in religious sculpture across the [[Gallo-Roman|Romano-Celtic]] region from [[Roman Britain|Britain]] to [[Pannonia]], depicted as &amp;quot;cloaked scurrying figures carved in an almost abstract manner&amp;quot; (Henig, 62).  They are found with a particular concentration in the [[Rhineland]] (Hutton).  In Britain they tend to be found in a [[triple deity]] form, which seems to be specific to the British representations (De la Bedoyère).

The hooded cape was especially associated with [[Gauls]] or [[Celts]] during the Roman period. The hooded health god was known as [[Telesphorus (mythology)|Telesphorus]] specifically and may have originated as a Greco-Gallic syncretism with the [[Galatia]]ns in Anatolia in the 3rd century BC.

The religious significance of these figures is still somewhat unclear, since no inscriptions have been found with them in this British context (De la Bedoyère). There are, however, indications that they may be fertility spirits of some kind.  [[Ronald Hutton]] argues that in some cases they are carrying shapes that can be seen as eggs, symbolizing life and rebirth, while Graham Webster has argued that the curved hoods are similar in many ways to contemporary Roman curved phallus stones. However, several of these figures also seem to carry swords or daggers, and Henig discusses them in the context of warrior cults.

[[Guy de la Bédoyère]] also warns against reading too much in to size differences or natures in the figures, which have been used to promote theories of different roles for the three figures, arguing that at the skill level of most of the carvings, small differences in size are more likely to be hit-and-miss consequences, and pointing out that [[experimental archaeology]] has shown hooded figures one of the easiest sets of figures to carve.

[[File:Musée Picardie Archéo 03.jpg|thumb|upright|225px|[[Gallo-Roman culture|Gallo-Roman]] bronze statuette of a Genius cucullatus (or a [[Priapus]]?) discovered in [[Picardy]], northern France, made in two parts, with the top section concealing a giant phallus.]]

== References ==
* {{cite book | first=Guy | last=de la Bedoyère | title=Gods with Thunderbolts: Religion in Roman Britain | pages=166–168 | publisher=Tempus | location=Stroud, UK | year=2002 | isbn=0-7524-2518-8}}
* {{cite book | first=Martin | last=Henig | title=Religion in Roman Britain | pages=62 | publisher=Batsford | location=London, UK | year=1984 | isbn=0-7134-1220-8}}
* {{cite book | first=Ronald | last=Hutton | title=The Pagan Religions of the Ancient British Isles | pages=214–216 | publisher=Blackwell | location=Oxford, UK | year=1991 | isbn=0-631-18946-7}}
* {{cite book | first=Graham | last=Webster | title=The British Celts and their Gods under Rome | pages=66–70 | publisher=Batsford | location=London, UK | year=1986 | isbn=0-7134-0648-8}}

{{Celtic mythology (ancient)}}
[[Category:Briton gods]]
[[Category:Gaulish gods]]
[[Category:Fertility gods]]
[[Category:Health gods]]

{{celt-myth-stub}}&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
