<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="José Francisco Peña Gómez"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="José Francisco Peña Gómez" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Unreferenced|date=February 2009}}
&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;José Francisco Peña Gómez&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (March 6, 1937 – May 10, 1998) was a politician from the [[Dominican Republic]]. He was the leader of the [[Dominican Revolutionary Party]] (PRD), a three-time candidate for president of the Dominican Republic and former Mayor of [[Santo Domingo]]. He is considered, along with [[Joaquín Balaguer]] and [[Juan Bosch]], as one of the most prominent Dominican political figures of the 20th century.

== Early life ==

Reportedly born to Haitian immigrants Oguís Vincent and María Marcelino, on March 6, 1937 in [[Mao, Dominican Republic|Mao]], [[Valverde Province|Valverde]], [[Dominican Republic]], Peña Gómez was adopted as an infant by a Dominican peasant family when his parents were forced to flee back to Haiti as the Dominican dictator [[Rafael Leonidas Trujillo|Rafael Trujillo]] enacted the [[Parsley Massacre]] against Haitians that same year.

Peña Gómez received a BA-equivalent degree from the [[Autonomous University of Santo Domingo]] (UASD) in 1966 before going on to higher studies at the [[University of Paris|Sorbonne]] in [[Paris]].

== The April Civil War and Exile ==

Since 1961, Peña Gómez became a supporter of [[Juan Bosch]], then leader of the Dominican Revolutionary Party (PRD). Bosch won the presidential elections of 1962, the first democratic president in 32 years, but his government was ousted in a military coup on September 25, 1963. In 1965, Peña rose to political prominence as he went on Radio Santo Domingo and called for a popular insurrection against the military coup and a return of Bosch. U. S. President Lyndon Johnson ordered a military invasion to prevent what he feared was a possible communist movement within the country.

== Leadership of the P.R.D. ==

In December 1973, Bosch formed the [[Dominican Liberation Party]] (P.L.D.). Under Peña&amp;apos;s leadership, the P.R.D. won the presidential election in 1978 ([[Antonio Guzmán Fernández|Antonio Guzmán]]) and 1982 ([[Salvador Jorge Blanco]]), and he himself was Mayor of Santo Domingo from 1982 to 1986. His period is mostly remembered for the creation of the &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Plaza Güibia&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (Güibia Plaza), on the seaside boulevard and plantation of ornamental trees in mayor [[Santo Domingo|Santo Domingo city]] avenues.

In 1990, Peña ran for the presidency, coming in third behind Balaguer of the [[Social Christian Reformist Party]] (PRSC) and Bosch of the PLD.

By 1994, the PRD was solidified and motivated. The presidential campaign was violent and dirty, and Peña lost to Balaguer in an extremely tight election marred by strong irregularities and fraud. Peña called a general strike which was widely supported by his followers and after international protest and intense negotiations, Balaguer announced that he would leave office prematurely in 1996 after serving seven terms in power.

In the 1996 poll, Peña won the first round of voting but fell short of the majority needed. In the second round of voting, [[Leonel Fernández]], a lawyer representing the PLD, won a narrow victory due to an alliance between the PLD and the PRSC.

==Final years==

Peña Gómez died on May 10, 1998 in [[Cambita Garabitos]], [[San Cristóbal Province|San Cristóbal]], 6 days before the mayoral elections of Santo Domingo, in which he was running.

Peña Gómez was one of the most popular leaders in recent political history in Dominican Republic, especially among the poor masses.

Being a key political figure until his death, the main Dominican Republic international airport was renamed from &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;quot;Aeropuerto Internacional Las Américas&amp;quot;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; to &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;quot;Aeropuerto Internacional Las Américas &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;José Francisco Peña Gómez&amp;quot;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;. Honoring his memory was not the motivation, but mainly a political [[revenge|retaliatory]] action excised by the PRD congressional members against the executive branch&amp;apos;s naming the newly founded &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Puente Presidente Bosch&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (President Bosch Bridge) after the winning party’s late founder, [[Juan Bosch]].

==See also==
*[[List of political parties in the Dominican Republic]]
*[[Politics of the Dominican Republic]]

==External links==
*[http://www.dominicantoday.com/dr/local/2009/4/19/31731/The-legacy-of-Dr-Jose-Francisco-Pena-Gomez Dominican Today: The legacy of Dr. José Francisco Peña Gómez ]

{{Persondata &amp;lt;!-- Metadata: see [[Wikipedia:Persondata]]. --&amp;gt;
| NAME              = Pena Gomez, Jose Francisco
| ALTERNATIVE NAMES =
| SHORT DESCRIPTION =Dominican politician
| DATE OF BIRTH     =March 6, 1937
| PLACE OF BIRTH    =
| DATE OF DEATH     =May 10, 1998
| PLACE OF DEATH    =Cambita Carabitos, San Cristobal
}}
{{DEFAULTSORT:Pena Gomez, Jose Francisco}}
[[Category:1937 births]]
[[Category:1998 deaths]]
[[Category:University of Paris alumni]]
[[Category:Harvard University alumni]]
[[Category:Michigan State University alumni]]
[[Category:Dominican Revolutionary Party politicians]]
[[Category:Dominican Republic people of Haitian descent]]
[[Category:Mayors of places in the Dominican Republic]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
