<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="New World (supermarket)"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="New World (supermarket)" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Unreferenced|date=June 2010}}
{{Infobox Company
| name             = New World
| logo             = [[File:New World Hor 2D CMYK.svg|250px]]
| type             = Subsidiary
| foundation       = 1963
| founder          =
| location_city    = Wellington
| location_country = New Zealand
| locations        = 138 (October 2012)
| parent           = [[Foodstuffs]]
| homepage         = [http://www.newworld.co.nz/ www.newworld.co.nz]
| intl             = yes
}}

&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;New World&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is a [[New Zealand]] full-service [[supermarket]] chain. Each store is independently owned, operated and is part of one of the 3 [http://www.foodstuffs.co.nz/ Foodstuffs’ co-operatives] (Foodstuff South Island, Foodstuffs Wellington and Foodstuffs Auckland).  Other members of the Foodstuffs Co-operatives which are also independently owned and operated include [http://www.paknsave.co.nz/ Pak’nSave] and [http://www.foursquare.co.nz/ Four Square] stores.

Founded in 1963, New World was the first American-style full-service supermarket brand of Foodstuffs, and the second in New Zealand (after [[Foodtown]]). As of October 2012, there is a total of 138 New World supermarkets across the North and South Islands of New Zealand.

New World stores tend to be smaller ({{convert|2500|-|3000|m2}}) and more upscale than their competitors. Prices tend to be higher in most stores, due to the cost of upscale presentation, large employee numbers (200-300 in some large stores), and often a lack of competition, especially in smaller towns.  New World has been a member of the [[Fly Buys (New Zealand)|Fly Buys]] program since that program started in September 1996.

New World traditionally advertises with a circular, delivered weekly to [[Letter box|mailbox]]es, and containing discounts and specials.  New World&amp;apos;s in the North Island have done away with pop out coupons.  Instead using &amp;quot;Auto-Coupons&amp;quot;, which are much like regular coupons but come off automatically at the register without a customer having to physically present a cut-out coupon.
South Island stores required the customer to use a coupon discount card which is found in the circulated coupon book. The card has a barcode which when scanned reduces coupon products to the discount price. If you do not receive it in the mail, you can usually use the store one, with prompting. This was replaced by the North Island System at the end of 2009.

In early 2003 New World helped introduce [[Superbank]], a completely electronic banking network aimed at saving customers money. While New World Supermarkets had much advertising for the service in their stores, Superbank didn&amp;apos;t have any physical services inside the store. In August 2006 it was announced that after heavy losses Superbank would be shut down and have its portfolio sold to [[GE Money]].

==Gallery==
&amp;lt;gallery&amp;gt;
File:New World supermarket, Dunedin.jpg|Centre City New World in [[Dunedin, New Zealand|Dunedin]]
File:New World.JPG|[[Warkworth, New Zealand|Warkworth]] New World
File:New World Wanganui.jpg|[[Whanganui]] New World
&amp;lt;/gallery&amp;gt;

==External links==
{{Commons cat|New World (supermarket)}}
*[http://www.newworld.co.nz New World official site]

[[Category:Supermarkets of New Zealand]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
