<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Ruby Cabernet"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Ruby Cabernet" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Infobox grape variety
| name          = Ruby Cabernet
| image         = Ruby Cabernet - Winemakers Seal - Gallo family - E &amp;amp; J Gallo Winery.jpg
| caption       =
| species       = &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Vitis vinifera]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos;
| also_called   = -
| origin        =   [[California]], [[USA]]
| hazards       = Powdery mildew, leaf roll virus, fan leaf virus
| regions       = California, South Africa, Australia
| notable_wines =
}}

&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Ruby Cabernet&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is a red [[Olmo grape]] [[variety (wine)|variety]] that is  a cross between [[Cabernet Sauvignon]] and [[Carignan]], it can produce wines with good colour and a pleasant cherry flavour, but is mostly blended into bulk wines.&amp;lt;ref name=&amp;quot;Jancis&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Robinson, Jancis &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Vines, Grapes &amp;amp; Wines&amp;apos;&amp;apos; Mitchell Beazley 1986 ISBN 1-85732-999-6&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

The purpose for the creation of the crossing of the [[grape]] varieties utilized to produce Ruby Cabernet was to obtain the superior quality of a Cabernet wine, and the resistance to heat of the Carignan combined in an inexpensive [[table wine]]. Even though the wine made from these grapes does not possess the distinctive flavor and the overall structure of other types of Cabernet wines,  it does carry their fruitful essence.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;[http://www.snooth.com/varietal/ruby-cabernet/ Ruby Cabernet profile] Snooth. Retrieved on 2010-03-05&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

The grape for this type of red wine was  developed for California&amp;apos;s hot climate, specially for regions such as the [[San Joaquin valley|San Joaquin]] and the [[Napa County, California|Napa]] Valleys.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;[http://cabernetreserve.com/napa-valley.html Napa Valley Cabernet] Retrieved on 2010-03-05&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;  Ruby Cabernet has improved the quality of the bulk wines produced in these areas thanks to its natural, special acidity.

==History==
[[File:OLMO HAROLD 1978.jpg|left|thumb|Dr. Harold Olmo, creator of Ruby Cabernet.]]
Ruby Cabernet is a cross between Cabernet Sauvignon and Carignan created in 1936 by Dr [[Harold Olmo]] at [[UC Davis]] in [[California]]. The intention was to combine Carignan&amp;apos;s heat tolerance with Cabernet Sauvignon&amp;apos;s quality, like the [[Cinsaut]] x [[Pinot noir]] cross that led to [[Pinotage]] a few years previously.

==Wine regions==
===Argentina===
A little is grown in [[Argentine wine|Argentina]] for blending into bulk wines.

===Australia===
Small amounts are grown in the Hunter Valley and Murray-Darling region, disappearing into nondescript blends.
However a few producers take the variety seriously. Andrew McPherson in Victoria uses the variety in several export wines f.x Full Fifteen exported to England and Denmark.

===Chile===
Some Ruby Cabernet is supposedly grown in [[Chile (wine)|Chile]], but few wines will admit to it on the label.

===South Africa===
For a while Ruby Cabernet was thought to hold a lot of promise for the hotter regions of [[South Africa (wine)|South Africa]], but in practice problems with fruit set have limited its success. It is successfully grown in the Robertson district, and forms the main ingredient of the Van Loveren &amp;quot;River Red&amp;quot; blend.

===USA===
Ruby Cabernet is mostly planted in [[California (wine)|California]], particularly in the San Joaquin Valley where it adds colour and backbone to bulk wines. Vineyards where farming techniques are employed to maximize quality however can produce wines with exceptional aroma, flavor, and mouth feel.

==Vine and Viticulture==
[[File:Carignan close up.jpg|right|thumb|Carignan]]
The vine is very drought resistant, and stands up well to high winds. Poor fruit set has been a problem in South Africa, and it is vulnerable to powdery mildew.
In California&amp;apos;s San Joaquin Valley, vineyards should limit irrigation, thin crop, and expose fruit to the sun to maximize wine quality.

===Vineyard ground===
The [[vineyard]]s on which grapes for Ruby Cabernet are grown, are seat on vigorous grounds filled with deep clay [[loam]]. The [[Canopy (grape)|canopies]] on these vineyards are usually quite open and not completely erected. The spacing below the vineyard row is normally of about seven to eight feet for optimal vertical shoot positioning. In case of vineyards which are [[quadrilateral]] and divided in a horizontal way, the space must be of about six to seven feet.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;University of California. [http://ucce.ucdavis.edu/datastore/datastoreview/showpage.cfm?usernumber=32&amp;amp;surveynumber=351 &amp;quot;Ruby Cabernet Viticulture&amp;quot;] 2010-03-05.&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

==Synonyms==
[[File:Clare Valley Cabernet Sauvignon.jpg|left|thumb|Cabernet Sauvignon]]
none

==References==
{{Reflist}}

[[Category:Red wine grape varieties]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
