<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Hannibal Gisco"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Hannibal Gisco" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{distinguish2|[[Hannibal|Hannibal Barca]], Carthaginian leader of the Second Punic War}}
{{unreferenced|date=December 2009}}

&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Hannibal Gisco&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (c. 300-290 &amp;amp;ndash; 258 BC) was a [[Carthage|Carthaginian]] military commander in charge of both land armies and naval fleets during the [[First Punic War]] against [[Roman Republic|Rome]]. His efforts proved ultimately unsuccessful and his eventual defeat in battle led to his downfall and execution.

==Life and career==
The details of Hannibal Gisco&amp;apos;s early life and career are unknown.

===Agrigentum===
Hannibal Gisco&amp;apos;s first appearance in the sources is in 261 BC, as the general in command of the [[garrison]] besieged by the Romans in [[battle of Agrigentum|Agrigentum]]. Despite the tenacity shown by Gisco and his men for months and the arrival of reinforcements led by [[Hanno]], the city eventually fell into Roman hands. Gisco managed to escape to Carthage in the late stages of the battle.

===The Straits of Messina===
Apparently, the defeat at Agrigentum did not bar Gisco from continuing leadership. In the following year, 260 BC, Gisco returned as the admiral in charge of the Carthaginian fleet in the [[Straits of Messina]]. The Romans were about to launch their first-ever navy, and Carthage had determined that this innovation should be thwarted. Gisco defeated and captured the Roman [[consul]] [[Gnaeus Cornelius Scipio Asina]] in the [[Battle of the Lipari Islands|Lipari encounter]], which earned Scipio the nickname Asina (&amp;quot;Donkey&amp;quot;). However, this victory was robbed of practical meaning with the bulk of the Roman fleet continuing to maneuver in the surrounding waters.

===Mylae===
Later in 260 BC, Gisco was to engage this fleet and to be the first Punic general to encounter the Roman &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[corvus (weapon)|corvus]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos; boarding device with its deadly effect. Confident in Carthage&amp;apos;s superiority at sea, Gisco deployed his ships for the [[Battle of Mylae]] in the traditional long line arrangement. Although inexperienced in sea battle, the Romans, led by [[consul]] [[Gaius Duilius]], heavily defeated the Carthaginian fleet, mainly due to the innovative use of land tactics in naval warfare.

Hannibal was recalled, but his fall from favor lasted not very long. In 258, he was sent to [[Sardinia]], which he had to defend against the Romans. However, he was no match for the Roman commander Gaius Sulpicius Paterculus, who defeated him.

Having lost the confidence of his peers, Hannibal Gisco was subsequently executed for incompetence shortly afterwards, together with other defeated Punic generals. According to some references he was crucified by his own men.

== External links ==
* [http://www.livius.org/ha-hd/hannibal/hannibal_3.html Livius.org: Hannibal]

{{Famous Carthaginians}}

{{Persondata &amp;lt;!-- Metadata: see [[Wikipedia:Persondata]]. --&amp;gt;
| NAME              = Gisco, Hannibal
| ALTERNATIVE NAMES =
| SHORT DESCRIPTION =
| DATE OF BIRTH     =
| PLACE OF BIRTH    =
| DATE OF DEATH     =
| PLACE OF DEATH    =
}}
{{DEFAULTSORT:Gisco, Hannibal}}
[[Category:Carthaginians]]
[[Category:First Punic War commanders]]
[[Category:3rd-century BC births]]
[[Category:260 BC deaths]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
