<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Iphicrates"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Iphicrates" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Iphicrates&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; [[Greek language|Greek]]: &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Ιφικράτης&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (born c.418 BCE - died c. 353 BCE) was an [[Athens|Athenian]] general, the son of a shoemaker, who flourished in the earlier half of the 4th century BC.

He owes his fame as much to the improvements he made in the equipment of the [[peltast]]s or light-armed mercenaries (named for their small &amp;apos;&amp;apos;pelte&amp;apos;&amp;apos; shield) as to his military successes. Historians have debated about just what kind of &amp;quot;peltasts&amp;quot; were affected by his reforms; one of the most popular positions is that he improved the performance of the Greek [[skirmisher]]s so that they would be able to engage in prolonged hand-to-hand fighting as part of the main battle line, while another strong opinion posits that he worked his changes upon the mercenary [[hoplite]]s that were an important factor in late 5th- and early 4th-century B.C. Greek land warfare.

A third possibility is that his reforms were limited to hoplites serving as marines on board ships of the Athenian navy.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;Ueda-Sarson, Luke, [http://www.ne.jp/asahi/luke/ueda-sarson/Iphikrates1.html The Evolution of Hellenistic Infantry, Part 1: The Reforms of Iphikrates]&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

His &amp;quot;Iphicratean reforms&amp;quot; consisted of increasing the length of their spears and swords, substituting linen cuirasses in place of heavier bronze armor, and introducing new footwear (later called &amp;apos;&amp;apos;iphicratids&amp;apos;&amp;apos;) that were easier to don and remove than previous models. In addition, he replaced the heavy [[aspis|&amp;apos;&amp;apos;hoplon&amp;apos;&amp;apos;/&amp;apos;&amp;apos;aspis&amp;apos;&amp;apos;]] with a lighter &amp;apos;&amp;apos;pelte&amp;apos;&amp;apos; that could be strapped to the forearm, freeing the left hand to help hold the lengthened spears. By these changes he greatly increased the rapidity of their movements. He also paid special attention to discipline, drill and maneuvers; the longer weapons, combined with the lighter armor and shield, forced his troops to take a more aggressive approach in tactical situations. With his peltasts Iphicrates dealt the [[Sparta]]ns a heavy blow in 392 BC-390 BC by almost annihilating a &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[mora (military unit)|mora]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (a battalion of about 600 men) of their famous hoplites.

Following up success, he took city after city for the Athenians; but in consequence of a quarrel with the [[Argives]] he was transferred from [[Corinth]] to the [[Hellespont]], where he was equally successful. After the peace of [[Antalcidas]] (387 BC) he assisted Seuthes, king of Thracian [[Odrysae]], to recover his kingdom, and fought against [[Cotys I (Odrysian)|Cotys]], with whom, however, he subsequently concluded an alliance. About 378 BC, he was sent with a force of mercenaries to assist the [[Persian Empire|Persians]] to reconquer [[Egypt]]; but a dispute with [[Pharnabazus (5th century BC)|Pharnabazus]] led to the failure of the expedition. On his return to Athens he commanded an expedition in 373 BC for the relief of [[Corcyra]], which was besieged by the [[Lacedaemonians]].

After the peace of 371 BC, Iphicrates returned to [[Thrace]] and somewhat tarnished his fame by siding with his father-in-law [[Cotys I (Odrysian)|Cotys]] in a war against Athens for the possession of the entire [[Thracian Chersonese]]. Iphicrates, however, refused to besiege the Athenian strongholds and fled to [[Antissa]].&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;[[Demosthenes]], &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Against Aristocrates&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt; The Athenians soon pardoned him and gave him a joint command in the [[Social War (357-355 BC)|Social War]] against some of their allies from the second [[Delian League|Athenian Empire]]. He and two of his colleagues were impeached by [[Chares]], the fourth commander, because they had refused to give battle during a violent storm.

Iphicrates was acquitted but sentenced to pay a heavy fine. Afterwards, he remained at Athens (according to some he retired to Thrace) until his death in about 353 BC.

==References==
{{reflist}}

==Sources==
*{{1911}}

==External links==
* [http://www.tertullian.org/fathers/nepos.htm#Iphicrates  Life of Iphicrates], by [[Cornelius Nepos]]
* [http://www.attalus.org/old/sayings1.html#187  Sayings of Iphicrates], from the [[Moralia]] of [[Plutarch]]
* [http://www.attalus.org/translate/polyaenus3.html#9.1  Sixty-three Stratagems of Iphicrates], from Book 3 of [[Polyaenus]]

{{Persondata &amp;lt;!-- Metadata: see [[Wikipedia:Persondata]]. --&amp;gt;
| NAME              = Iphicrates
| ALTERNATIVE NAMES =
| SHORT DESCRIPTION = Athenian general
| DATE OF BIRTH     =
| PLACE OF BIRTH    =
| DATE OF DEATH     =
| PLACE OF DEATH    =
}}
[[Category:353 BC deaths]]
[[Category:Ancient Athenian generals]]
[[Category:4th-century BC Greek people]]
[[Category:Military history of Ancient Greece]]
[[Category:Ancient Greek Thrace]]
[[Category:Late Classical Greece]]
[[Category:Year of birth unknown]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
