<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Legal technicality"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Legal technicality" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{refimprove|date=August 2012}}
The term &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;legal technicality&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is a casual or [[colloquial]] phrase referring to a technical aspect of law.  The phrase is not a [[term of art]] in the [[law]]; it has no exact meaning, nor does it have a legal definition. It implies that strict adherence to the [[letter of the law]] has prevented the spirit of the law from being enforced. However, as a vague term, the definition of a technicality varies from person to person, and often is simply used to denote any portion of the law which interferes with the  outcome desired by the user of the term.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;An example: In the case of U.S. v. Shipp, 214 US 386 (1909), the U.S. Supreme Court quoted a local newspaper as follows:
*“In the News, published the evening of March 19, there was an editorial reviewing the local proceedings, which concluded: &amp;apos;All of this delay is aggravating to the community. The people of Chattanooga believe that Johnson is guilty, and that he ought to suffer the penalty of the law as speedily as possible. If by legal technicality the case is prolonged and the culprit finally escapes, there will be no use to plead with a mob here if another such crime is committed. Such delays are largely responsible for mob violence all over the country.&amp;apos;”(U.S. v. SHIPP, 1909) The newspaper plainly was using the phrase &amp;quot;legal technicality&amp;quot; to refer to technical aspects of the law which the newspaper&amp;apos;s editorial staff saw as an obstacle to its preferred outcome.&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

Some legal technicalities govern legal procedure, enable or restrict access to courts, and/or enable or limit the discretion of a court in handing down judgment.  These are aspects of [[procedural law]].  Other legal technicalities deal with aspects of [[substantive law]], that is, aspects of the law which articulate specific criteria that a court uses to assess a party&amp;apos;s compliance with or violation of, for example, one or more [[criminal law]]s or [[Civil law (common law)|civil laws]].&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;In the U.S., for example, the Supreme Court has used the informal phrase &amp;quot;legal technicality&amp;quot; in its decisions 13 times in the last century.{{Citation needed|date=November 2008}}  In every case the use of the words refers to merely &amp;quot;technicalities of the law&amp;quot;.  The three most recent uses are illustrative:
*(1) “The function of counsel as a guide through complex legal technicalities long has been recognized by this Court.” (U.S. v. Ash, 1973)
*(2) ”Furthermore, during the federal habeas corpus hearing Davis showed his awareness of legal technicalities.”(used in a footnote, Davis v. North Carolina, 1966)
*(3) ”If recovery were denied in this case, the railroads, by the simple expedient of doing each other&amp;apos;s work, could tie their employees up in legal technicalities...&amp;quot; (Shenker v. Baltimore and Ohio R.Co., 1963)&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

==United States==
In the [[United States]], [[United States Constitution|Constitutional]] guarantees such as those included in the [[Fourth Amendment to the United States Constitution|Fourth]] and [[Fifth Amendment to the United States Constitution|Fifth]] amendments to protect an accused from unreasonable search and seizure or from self-incrimination have been referred to as &amp;quot;technicalities&amp;quot; by critics of court decisions based on them, even though they are foundations of the American legal system rather than obscure fine points. A commonly cited example would be attempted prosecution of a crime that was discovered by illegally obtained evidence. Such cases may be dismissed based on lack of evidence as the illegally obtained evidence would not be allowed to be the basis of the prosecution&amp;apos;s case (called the &amp;quot;[[fruit of the poisonous tree]]&amp;quot; doctrine).  Other procedural &amp;quot;technicalities&amp;quot; arise from [[common law]] as well, for example, the standard procedural defenses of [[Laches (equity)|laches]] and [[estoppel]] applicable within civil law.

Some examples of technical aspects of legal procedure are:
* [[Time constraints]], including [[Statute of limitations|Statutes of limitations]]
* [[Statute of frauds]]
* Various immunities, such as [[Sovereign immunity]], [[Diplomatic immunity]]
* [[Rules of appellate procedure]]

==See also==
* [[Legal abuse]]
* [[Letter and spirit of the law]]
* [[Loophole]]

==References==
{{reflist}}

{{DEFAULTSORT:Legal Technicality}}
[[Category:Informal legal terms]]
[[Category:Legal procedure]]
[[Category:Abuse of the legal system]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
