<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Remote control vehicle"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Remote control vehicle" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{unreferenced|date=October 2006}}
[[Image:Explosieven Opruimingsdienst.jpg|Remote controlled vehicle to clear explosives|thumb]]
[[Image:Remote-control Mini-vehicle Radiological Survey - TST Observatory, HK - 2007-03-25 09h51m DSC07457.JPG|thumb|Remote-control Mini-vehicle Radiological Survey]]

A &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;remote control vehicle&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is defined as any [[vehicle]] that is [[remote control|controlled]] by a means that does not restrict its [[motion (physics)|motion]] with an origin external to the device. This is often a [[radio control]] device, [[cable]] between control and vehicle, or an [[infrared]] controller.  A &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;remote control vehicle&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; or RCV differs from a [[robot]] in that the RCV is always controlled by a human and takes no positive action autonomously.

==Applications==
===Scientific===
Remote control vehicles have various scientific uses including hazardous environments, working in the deep ocean, and space exploration. RCV is used by police to detect bombs,or some chemicals,etc. It detects chemicals or whatever with its high-power sensors. The majority of the probes to the other planets in our solar system have been remote control vehicles, although some of the more recent ones were partially autonomous.  The sophistication of these devices has fueled greater debate on the need for manned spaceflight and exploration.  The [[Voyager I]] spacecraft is the first craft of any kind to leave the solar system.  The martian explorers [[Spirit]] and [[Opportunity]] have provided continuous data about the surface of Mars since January 3, 2004.

[http://www.whoi.edu/marops/vehicles/jason/index.html  Jason] is the [[Woods Hole Oceanographic Institution]]&amp;apos;s deep water explorer and can withstand depths of up to 6,500 feet.  The [[Scorpio ROV]] is a British submersible that rescued the crew of the [[Russia]]n [[AS-28]] on August 7, 2005.

===Military and law enforcement===
Military usage of remotely controlled military vehicles dates back to the first half of 20th century. John Hays Hammond, Jr., invented and patented methods for wireless control of ships starting in 1910.  Soviet [[Red Army]] used remotely controlled [[teletank]]s during 1930s in the [[Winter War]] and early stage of [[World War II]]. There were also remotely controlled cutters and experimental remotely controlled planes in the Red Army.

Remote control vehicles are used in law enforcement and military engagements for some of the same reasons.  The exposure to hazards are mitigated to the person who operates the vehicle from a location of relative safety.  Remote controlled vehicles are used by many police department bomb-squads to defuse or detonate explosives. See [[Dragon Runner]], [[Military robot]].

Unmanned Aerial Vehicles ([[Unmanned aerial vehicle|UAV]]s) have undergone a dramatic evolution in capability in the past decade.  Early UAV&amp;apos;s were capable of reconnaissance missions alone and then only with a limited range.  Current UAV&amp;apos;s can hover around possible targets until they are positively identified before releasing their payload of weaponry.  Backpack sized UAV&amp;apos;s will provide ground troops with over the horizon [[surveillance]] capabilities.

===Recreation and hobby===
See [[Radio-controlled model]].
Small scale remote control vehicles have long been popular among hobbyists.  These remote controlled vehicles span a wide range in terms of price and sophistication. There are many types of radio controlled vehicles.  These include on-road cars, off-road trucks, boats, airplanes, and even helicopters.  The &amp;quot;robots&amp;quot; now popular in television shows such as [[Robot Wars (TV series)|Robot Wars]], are a recent extension of this hobby (these vehicles do not meet the classical definition of a [[robot]]; they are remotely controlled by a human). [[Radio-controlled submarines|Radio-controlled submarine]] also exist.

Recently, [[Sony Ericsson]] released a remote control car that could be controlled by any [[Bluetooth]] [[cell phone]].  Radio is the most popular because it does not require the vehicle to be limited by the length of the cable or in a direct line of sight with the controller (as with the infrared set-up).

== See also ==
* [[Remote-controlled animal]]
* [[Remotely operated underwater vehicle]]
* [[Unmanned aerial vehicle]]
* [[Unmanned ground vehicle]]

{{Mobile robots}}
{{Robotics}}

[[Category:Unmanned vehicles]]

[[ja:遠隔操作#遠隔操作型無人機]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
