<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Foreign relations of Saint Vincent and the Grenadines"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Foreign relations of Saint Vincent and the Grenadines" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Unreferenced|date=December 2009}}
{{Politics of Saint Vincent and the Grenadines}}
[[Saint Vincent and the Grenadines]] maintains close ties to the [[United States|U.S.]], [[Canada]], and the [[United Kingdom]], and cooperates with regional political and economic organizations such as the [[Organisation of Eastern Caribbean States]] (OECS) and [[CARICOM]]. St. Vincent and the Grenadines is a member of the [[United Nations]], the [[Commonwealth of Nations]], the [[Organization of American States]], and the [[Association of Caribbean States]] (ACS).

As a member of CARICOM, St. Vincent and the Grenadines strongly backed efforts by the United States to implement UN Security Council Resolution 940, designed to facilitate the departure of [[Haiti]]&amp;apos;s de facto authorities from power. The country agreed to contribute personnel to the multinational force, which restored the democratically elected government of Haiti in October 1994.

In May 1997, Prime Minister Mitchell joined 14 other Caribbean leaders and U.S. President [[Bill Clinton]] during the first-ever U.S.-regional summit in [[Bridgetown]], Barbados. The summit strengthened the basis for regional cooperation on justice and counternarcotics issues, finance and development, and trade.

St. Vincent and the Grenadines maintains close relations with [[Cuba]], which provides a number of scholarship and other exchange programs for Vincentians, particularly in the field of [[healthcare]]. It also has diplomatic relations with the [[Republic of China]] (Taiwan) instead of the [[People&amp;apos;s Republic of China]].

Saint Vincent protests [[Venezuela]]&amp;apos;s claim to give full effect to [[Aves (Bird) Island]], which creates a Venezuelan [[EEZ]]/[[continental shelf]] extending over a large portion of the [[Caribbean Sea]].

Saint Vincent is a [[transshipment]] point for South American illicit drugs destined for the US and Europe.

==See also==
*[[List of diplomatic missions in Saint Vincent and the Grenadines]]
*[[List of diplomatic missions of Saint Vincent and the Grenadines]]
{{Foreign relations in the Caribbean}}

{{DEFAULTSORT:Foreign Relations Of Saint Vincent And The Grenadines}}
[[Category:Foreign relations of Saint Vincent and the Grenadines| ]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
