<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Wikipedia:Articles for deletion/Same-sex sexual practices"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Wikipedia:Articles for deletion/Same-sex sexual practices" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;* This article actually seems pretty pointless.  All it can ever really be is a list of sexual things, which is already covered on [[list of sexology topics]], plus I see no real reason to have a seperate page for same-sex and opposite-sex practices since after all with the exception of penile-vaginal intercourse everyone does basically the same thing. [[User:Exploding Boy|Exploding Boy]] 12:20, Mar 31, 2004 (UTC)
*Delete/redirect/merge/whatever. Like I said for different-sex sexual practices, there are only one or two activities that differentiate (sp?) them, and the topics seem pretty well covered elsewhere. [[User:Niteowlneils|Niteowlneils]] 16:41, 31 Mar 2004 (UTC)
*Keep! I don&amp;apos;t know y it&amp;apos;s listed here, it&amp;apos;s more than just &amp;apos;&amp;apos;a list of sexual practices&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, if u like, u can add something about the moral debate on that, laws related to that and more. if u mean hand job, oral sex, anal sex etc cover all the sexual practises, i don&amp;apos;t see there is any room for other articles like [[cybersex]], [[telephone sex]] etc: they are all, of course, doing the same thing -- to get sexual pleasure. --[[User:Yacht|Yacht]] 17:37, Mar 31, 2004 (UTC)
**Everything you mention is covered elsehwere.  Cybersex and telephone sex are specific sexual practices that need their own articles.   [[User:Exploding Boy|Exploding Boy]] 01:51, Apr 1, 2004 (UTC)
*Delete.  Is anything on there an actual fact?  It seems to be various predjudices (in the nicest possible sense of the word) listed.
*Delete. I tried to help it by changing its name, but it&amp;apos;s really not a useful article as written.  [[User:Moncrief|Moncrief]] 22:34, Mar 31, 2004 (UTC)
**Okay, okay, okay! I will keep silent! All sexual practices are no more than just &amp;apos;&amp;apos;oral sex&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, &amp;apos;&amp;apos;anal sex&amp;apos;&amp;apos; etc. y do we write the rest of all the other articles in the [[list of sexology topics]]? isn&amp;apos;t cyerber sex just hand job? they use computer to do rub their dxxx? --[[User:Yacht|Yacht]] 09:18, Apr 1, 2004 (UTC)
**No need to keep silent!  In my opinion cyber sex requires its own article separate from &amp;quot;masturbation&amp;quot; because there are a variety of issues that can be covered in such an article above and beyond mere masturbation.
** Keep. [[User:Secretlondon|Secretlondon]] 02:08, 2 Apr 2004 (UTC)
* Keep. [[User:Davodd|Davodd]] 22:13, Apr 4, 2004 (UTC)
*Keep. There&amp;apos;s ample material for useful coverage of the diffrences in frequency, practices and legality or social acceptance or otherwise of the same practices in same and different sex situations. [[User:Jamesday|Jamesday]] 16:18, 6 Apr 2004 (UTC)

Hey, did we reach a consensus on this in the end? Someone turned the page into a redirect anyway. [[User:Marnanel|Marnanel]] 20:49, Apr 5, 2004 (UTC)
*No, we didn&amp;apos;t. Someone seems to have made the mistake of moving it to a gay sexual practices article, which is a subset of same-sex sexual practices and will probably be an offensive title for those who don&amp;apos;t self-identify as homosexual. [[User:Jamesday|Jamesday]] 16:18, 6 Apr 2004 (UTC)
* Delete. POV in places and overall redundant. [[User:80.255|80.255]] 14:30, 9 Apr 2004 (UTC)
** Hang on, you used the existence of this article as partial justification for your vote to keep [[Different-sex sexual practices]] which is really no different.  Why delete one and keep the other? And if this one&amp;apos;s deleted, should the other one be also? [[User:Exploding Boy|Exploding Boy]] 17:31, Apr 9, 2004 (UTC)
*** It seems likely (given the votes thusfar) that this article will be kept. Hence, so should [[Different-sex sexual practices]]. This is a question of consistency. However, on merit, I don&amp;apos;t believe that this deserves to be kept, thus my position is &amp;apos;all-or-nothing&amp;apos;. Being realistic, however, I should rather that DSSP be kept if this is kept (which seems inevitable, unless there&amp;apos;s a sea-change), so there&amp;apos;s nothing illogical about my justification for keeping the former. [[User:80.255|80.255]] 18:52, 9 Apr 2004 (UTC)&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
