<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Yerrapragada"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Yerrapragada" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{refimprove|date=December 2010}}
&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Errana&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; or Errapregada ({{lang-te|ఎర్రాప్రగడ}}) was a great [[Telugu people|Telugu]] poet in the court of Prolaya Vemareddy (1325–1353), the founder of [[Reddy dynasty]] (1325–1424) of Kondaveedu, who ruled [[Guntur]], [[Prakasam district|Prakasam]], [[Nellore]], and [[Kurnool]] districts of the state of [[Andhra Pradesh]]. Errana was also known as &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Yellapregada&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; or &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Errapregada&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;. He was honored with the title &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Prabandha Parameshwara&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (the supreme lord of Prabandha) and &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Shambudasusu&amp;apos;&amp;apos;.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;[http://www.textbooksonline.tn.nic.in/Books/10/Telugu/Poetry/2%20VaishnavaYaagam.pdf Vaishanava yugamu]&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;!--  Commented out because image was deleted: [[Image:Errana1.jpg|thumb|100px|Center|Great Poet Errana]] --&amp;gt;

==Birth and Ancestors==
Errana was born in [[Gudluru]] village in Pakanadu and lived in Chadalawada.  He belonged to Shrivatsa gotram and Apastambha sutram of the Brahmin caste. His father was Surana and mother was Potamma.  His grandfather was Errapotana whose name was given to him and his grandmother was Perama.  His great-grandparents were Bolana and Polama and his great-great-grandfather was Bhimana.  His family religion was Aradhya Shaivism.  His teacher was Srisankaraswamy, an orthodox Shaiva. Although Errana was a devotee of Lord Shiva and his family was Shaiva family, he worshipped Lord Vishnu also.

==Contributions==
The [[Sanskrit]] Mahabharatamu was translated into [[Telugu language|Telugu]] over a period of several centuries (11th to 14th centuries AD). Errana was one of the [[kavitrayam]] (the trinity of poets) who translated Mahabharatamu. The other two poets were [[Nannaya]] and [[Tikkana]]ks) of Mahabharatamu ([[Mahabharat]]). Tikkana translated the remaining books starting from the 4th, leaving the half finished third book, Aranya Parvamu (the Book of Forest), for Errana. [[Tikkana]] did not touch this part because it was considered to be inauspicious to translate this book, which was left half-finished by [[Nannaya]]. Errana started the remaining half of the Aranya Parvamu with the style of Nannaya and ended it with the style of Tikkana as a bridge between the parts translated by Nannaya and Tikkana. Just like Nannaya and Tikkana, he used half [[Sanskrit]] and half [[Telugu language|Telugu]] in his Telugu translation of Sanskrit Mahabharatamu. He translated Harivamsamu and Ramayanamu from Sanskrit and dedicated to king Prolaya Vemareddy. Nrisimhapuranamu was his own independent work. Errana got his inspiration for Nrisimhapuranam from his grandfather Errapotana. According to legend, one day when Errana was meditating, his grandfather appeared and advised him to write Narisimhapuranamu. This work was based on Brahmandapuranamu and Vishnupuranamu.

According to Vishnupuranamu, [[Hiranyakasyapa]] was a powerful king of [[Bharatavarsha]] (the mythological country that encompassed the entire [[Indian subcontinent]]) and was a contemporary of [[Indra]], the king of Ilavritavarsha, also known as [[Swarga]], which was located in the North. The subjects of Bharatavarsha were called Manavas (the descendants of Manu - humans). The subjects of Indra were Devatas. Hiranyakasyapa fought a war with [[Indra]] and occupied Ilavritavarsha. Under the rule of Hiranyakasyapa, most of the Devatas either converted to or disguised as Manavas for the fear of Hiranyakasyapa. Another contemporary of Hiranyakasyapa was Lord Vishnu, who ruled the land beyond Ilavritavarsha in the ksheerasagar (sea of milk).

Hiranyakasyapa had a son, [[Prahlada]]. Prahlada is a devote of Lord Vishnu and for that reason father and son didn&amp;apos;t get along very well.  Hiranyakasyapa tortured Prahlada for defying him. [[Prahlada]] ran away and took refuge in the northern kingdom of Lord Vishnu in the Ksheersagar. However, Hiranyakasyapa gave amnesty to Prahlada, later. Prahlada returned to the Bharatavarsha and served his father with love and affection. Soon after, Hiranyakasyapa was killed by a lion during a hunting expedition in the wild.  Prahlada took over as the king of Bharatavarsha. Vishnupurana, the Sanskrit original, didn&amp;apos;t describe how and why Lord Vishnu killed Hiranyakasyapa. However, Errana introduced Narasimha (lion-man), an incarnation of Lord [[Vishnu]], as the killer of Hiranyakasyapa.

==Notes==
{{reflist}}

==See also==
* [[Telugu literature]]
* [[Kavitrayam]]

{{Persondata &amp;lt;!-- Metadata: see [[Wikipedia:Persondata]]. --&amp;gt;
| NAME              = Yerrapragada
| ALTERNATIVE NAMES =
| SHORT DESCRIPTION = Telegu poet
| DATE OF BIRTH     =
| PLACE OF BIRTH    =
| DATE OF DEATH     =
| PLACE OF DEATH    =
}}
[[Category:14th-century writers]]
[[Category:Telugu people]]
[[Category:Telugu poets]]
[[Category:Translators from Sanskrit]]
[[Category:Telugu writers]]
[[Category:People from Prakasam district]]
[[Category:Year of birth unknown]]
[[Category:Year of death unknown]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
