<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Aëdon"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Aëdon" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Aëdon&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; ({{lang-grc|Ἀηδών}}) is, in [[Greek mythology]], the daughter of [[Pandareus]] of [[Ephesus]].  According to Homer she was the wife of [[Zethus]], and the mother of [[Itylus]].&amp;lt;!-- I just got done reading this part of The Odyssey, and I can&amp;apos;t find what this reference refers to... It may not be right. --&amp;gt;&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;[[Homer]], &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Odyssey]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos; xix. 517, &amp;amp;c.&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

Envious of [[Niobe]], the wife of her husband&amp;apos;s brother [[Amphion]], who had six sons and six daughters, she formed the plan of killing the eldest of Niobe&amp;apos;s sons, but by mistake slew her own son Itylus.  Zeus relieved her grief by changing her into a [[nightingale]], whose melancholy tunes are represented by the poet as Aëdon&amp;apos;s lamentations about her child.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Bibliotheca (Pseudo-Apollodorus)|Bibliotheca]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos; iii. 5. § 5&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

According to a later tradition preserved in [[Antoninus Liberalis]],&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;[[Antoninus Liberalis]], c. 11&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt; Aëdon is instead the wife of Polytechnos, an artist of [[Colophon (city)|Colophon]].  The couple boasted that they loved each other more than [[Hera]] and [[Zeus]].  Hera sent [[Eris (mythology)|Eris]] to cause trouble between the two of them.  Polytechnus was then making a chair, and Aëdon a piece of [[embroidery]], and they agreed that whoever should finish the work first should receive from the other a female slave as the prize.  Polytechnos was furious when Aëdon (with Hera&amp;apos;s help) won.  He went to Aëdon&amp;apos;s father, and pretending that his wife wished to see her sister Chelidonis, he took her with him.  On his way home he [[rape]]d her, dressed her in slave&amp;apos;s attire, commanded her to silence, and gave her to his wife as the promised prize.  After some time Chelidonis, believing herself unobserved, lamented her own fate, but she was overheard by Aëdon, and the two sisters conspired against Polytechnus for revenge.  They murdered Polytechnos&amp;apos; son [[Itys]] and served him up as a meal to his father.

Aëdon then fled with Chelidonis to her father, who, when Polytechnos came in pursuit of his wife, had him bound, smeared with honey, and exposed to the insects.  Aëdon now took pity upon the sufferings of her husband, and when her relations were on the point of killing her for this weakness, Zeus changed Polytechnos into a [[pelican]], the brother of Aëdon into a whoop, her father into a sea-eagle, Chelidonis into a [[swallow]], and Aëdon herself into a [[nightingale]].  This myth seems to have originated in mere [[etymology|etymologies]], and is of the same class as that about [[Philomela (princess of Athens)|Philomela]] and [[Procne]].&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;{{Citation
  | last = Schmitz
  | first = Leonhard
  | author-link =
  | contribution = Aedon
  | editor-last = Smith
  | editor-first = William
  | title = [[Dictionary of Greek and Roman Biography and Mythology]]
  | volume = 1
  | pages = 23–24
  | publisher =
  | place = Boston
  | year = 1867
  | contribution-url = http://www.ancientlibrary.com/smith-bio/0032.html }}&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

== References ==
{{reflist}}

{{SmithDGRBM}}

{{DEFAULTSORT:Aedon}}
[[Category:Metamorphoses in Greek mythology]]
[[Category:Women in Greek mythology]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
