<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Castle Infinity"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Castle Infinity" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;[[Image:C8screenshot.jpg|300px|thumb|right|A screenshot of the Central Fountain]]

&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Castle Infinity&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is a [[freeware]] [[MMOG]] for [[Microsoft Windows]] developed by Castle Infinity, LLC, an [[United States|American]] [[non-profit organization]].

The official language of the characters in Castle Infinity is a modification of [[Esperanto]].

The [[new wave music|new wave]] [[a cappella]] group [[The Bobs]] provided several original songs for the soundtrack. Additionally, members of the band also lent their voices for several of the characters in Castle Infinity.

==History==
&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Castle Infinity&amp;apos;&amp;apos; was first released in 1996, making it the first fully released MMOG designed for children. It was originally designed by [[Russell Ginns]], [[Gregg Foster]], and [[Scott Wallin]]. It was developed by [[Starwave]], but the company was bought three times and eventually acquired by [[Disney]]. The game itself changed owners several times, from [[Digital Evolution]] to [[US Interactive]]. Access to the game became intermittent starting in 1998 and had shut down entirely by 2000. Soon after, the game servers were [[Dumpster diving|rescued from a dumpster]] by [http://quitt.net/ Kevin Quitt], a [[C (programming language)|C]] programmer, who happened to be one of the game&amp;apos;s lead players, and improvements on the game started up. From this group, Castle Infinity, Inc. a non-profit organization was born. Player population has dwindled in the years since, leaving only a few die-hard fans. Nonetheless, in 2005 there was fresh media coverage of the game by way of [[Slashdot]] and [[BoingBoing]].

===Corruption and Closure===
On October 6, 2008, it was announced that the database had been corrupted following a programming error. Kevin D. Quitt, the administrator of Castle Infinity at that time, made the following announcement: &amp;quot;I have... with great reluctance and many tears, closed the Castle - almost certainly forever.&amp;quot; However following this a [[Facebook]] wall was made, and old players continued to discover the community. Talk soon emerged of redevelopment of the castle, but until recently no action was ever taken.

===Revival===
On January 9, 2011 a test server was launched with the help of a  former player who wished to remain anonymous.With the approval of Russell Ginns and some of the original development team, as well as Kevin D. Quitt; Spencer Jerome(The Architect Seademond) with the help of Donald Butyen (The Architect Fonos) and Rachel Coleman (The Architect Morelia) revived the Castle and are maintaining the revived server as long as there is interest. Spencer has since founded Castle Infinity, LLC, a company to manage the Castle. A website has launched, and a beta is now available for download, with new features and content being consistently added to the game.

==Gameplay==
Castle Infinity places a heavy emphasis on player interaction. Players can take on challenges which require multiple players to participate together, activating new levels and advancing into deeper tasks within the game. For example, in order to jump to higher levels, at least 3 or 4 members are required to stand on the same spot for the lift to activate. Once all members are present, the jump activates and players will advance to a higher level.

==References==
&amp;lt;References/&amp;gt;

==External links==
* [http://castle-infinity.com/ Castle Infinity Revival Project Website]
* [http://web.archive.org/web/20020914015751/http://www.castleinfinity.org/ Castle Infinity website] from Starwave era
* [http://web.archive.org/web/20070930082037/http://www.castleinfinity.org/ Castle Infinity website] from user-owned era
* {{google video|-5641872610738005071|Excerpt from Attack of the Show featuring Castle Infinity}}
* [http://games.slashdot.org/games/05/06/21/0133233.shtml?tid=206&amp;amp;tid=209&amp;amp;tid=10 Slashdot thread] about the return of Castle Infinity

[[Category:1996 video games]]
[[Category:Multiplayer online games]]
[[Category:Windows games]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
