<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Dedun"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Dedun" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Dedun&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (or &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Dedwen&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;) was a [[Nubia]]n god worshipped during ancient times in that part of Africa and attested as early as 2400 BC. There is much uncertainty about his original nature, especially since he was depicted as a [[lion]], a role which usually was assigned to the son of another deity. Nothing is known of the earlier Nubian mythology from which this deity arose, however. The earliest known information in Egyptian writings about Dedun indicates that he already had become a god of [[incense]] by the time of the writings. Since at this historical point, incense was an extremely expensive luxury commodity and Nubia was the source of much of it, he was quite an important deity. The wealth that the trade in incense delivered to Nubia led to his being identified by them as the god of [[prosperity]], and of [[wealth]] in particular.

He is said to have been associated with a fire that threatened to destroy the other deities, however, leading many [[Nubiology|Nubiologists]] to speculate that there may have been a great fire at a shared complex of temples to different deities, that started in a temple of Dedun, although there are no candidate events known for this.

Although mentioned in the [[pyramid texts]] of [[Ancient Egypt]] as being a Nubian deity,&amp;lt;ref name=Lichtheim&amp;gt;{{cite book |last= Lichtheim |first=Miriam|title=Ancient Egyptian Literature, vol 1|publisher=University of California Press|year=1975|location=London, England|isbn=0-520-02899-6}}&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt; there is no evidence that Dedun was worshipped by the Egyptians, nor that he was worshipped in any location north of [[Swenet]] (contemporary Aswan), which was considered the most southerly city of Ancient Egypt. Nevertheless, in the [[Middle Kingdom of Egypt]], during the Egyptian rule over [[Kingdom of Kush|Kush]], Dedun was said by the Egyptians to be the protector of deceased Nubian rulers and their god of incense, thereby associated with funerary rites.

== References ==

&amp;lt;references/&amp;gt;

[[Category:Fortune gods]]
[[Category:Nubian deities]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
