<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Plot hole"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Plot hole" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{unreferenced|date=October 2012}}

A &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;plot hole&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, or &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;plothole&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, a play on the word &amp;quot;[[pothole]],&amp;quot; is a gap or inconsistency in a storyline that goes against the flow of [[logic]] established by the story&amp;apos;s [[Plot (narrative)|plot]], or constitutes a blatant omission of relevant information regarding the plot sometimes even contradicting itself. These include such things as unlikely behaviour or actions of characters, illogical or impossible events, events happening for no apparent reason, or statements/events that contradict earlier events in the storyline.

While many stories have unanswered questions, unlikely events or chance occurrences, a plot hole is one that is essential to the story&amp;apos;s outcome. Plot holes are usually seen as weaknesses or flaws in a story, and writers usually try to avoid them to make their stories seem as realistic as possible. However, certain [[genre]]s (and some media) that require or allow [[suspension of disbelief]]—especially [[action (fiction)|action]], [[comedic genres|comedy]], [[fantasy]], and [[horror fiction|horror]]—are more tolerant of plot holes.

Writers can deal with plot holes in different ways, from completely rewriting the story, to having characters acknowledge illogical or unintelligent actions, to having characters make vague statements that could be used to deflect accusations of plot holes (e.g. &amp;quot;I&amp;apos;ve tried everything I can think of...&amp;quot; to keep critics from asking why a particular action was not taken). The nature of the plot hole and the developmental stage at which it is noticed usually determine the best course of action to take. For example, a motion picture that has already wrapped production would much more likely receive an added line of dialogue rather than an entire script rewrite.

==See also==
*[[Chekhov&amp;apos;s gun]]
*[[Continuity (fiction)]]
*&amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Deus ex machina]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos;
*[[Retroactive continuity]]
*[[Suspension of disbelief]]

==External links==
* [http://muse.jhu.edu/journals/narrative/v017/17.1.ryan.html Cheap Plot Tricks, Plot Holes, and Narrative Design]

{{DEFAULTSORT:Plot Hole}}
[[Category:Continuity errors]]
[[Category:Fiction]]
[[Category:Plot (narrative)]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
