<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Zhang Heng (Water Margin)"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Zhang Heng (Water Margin)" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{other uses|Zhang Heng (disambiguation)}}
{{Water Margin character infobox
|Name = Zhang Heng
|Nickname = &amp;quot;Boatman&amp;quot;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;船火兒
|Aliases =
|Rank = 28th, &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Balance&amp;apos;&amp;apos; Star (天平星) of the 36 Heavenly Spirits
|Image = Senkaji Chao wringing out hin loincloth.jpg
|imagesize =
|Caption =
|Allegiance = Liangshan
|Designation = Navy leader
|Origin = Pirate
|Hometown =
|First appearance = Chapter 37
|Weapon =
|Simp = 张横
|Trad = 張橫
|Pinyin = Zhāng Héng
|WG = Chang Heng
|Other =
}}
{{chinese-name|[[Zhang (surname)|Zhang]]}}

&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Zhang Heng&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is a fictional character in the &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Water Margin]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, one of the [[Four Great Classical Novels]] of [[Chinese literature]]. He ranks 28th of the 36 Heavenly Spirits of the 108 Liangshan heroes and is nicknamed &amp;quot;Boatman&amp;quot;.

==Background==
The &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Water Margin&amp;apos;&amp;apos; describes Zhang Heng as a man seven &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Chi (unit)|chi]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos; tall, with triangular eyes, yellow whiskers, red hair and crimson eyes. He is an excellent swimmer and he can leap out of the water from wave to wave like [[flying fish]]. Even harsh weather conditions do not deter him from performing superhuman feats in water. He is nicknamed &amp;quot;Boatman&amp;quot; for his marine abilities.

Zhang Heng lives at the foot of Mount Gu with his younger brother [[Zhang Shun]]. The brothers engage in some illegal trading on the nearby [[Xunyang River]] to earn a living. Zhang Heng is an impulsive gambler and loses large sums of money from frequent gambling. He decides to become a pirate in disguise as a ferryman to rob his customers.

Once, [[Song Jiang]] is pursued by the Mu brothers after offending them and he boards Zhang Heng&amp;apos;s boat to escape from them in desperation. In the middle of the river, Zhang Heng attempts to kill Song Jiang by forcing him off the boat. Just then, [[Li Jun (Water Margin)|Li Jun]] appears and he stops Zhang Heng. Li Jun then introduces Song Jiang to Zhang Heng and the others, who recognise him as the famous philanthropist. Zhang Heng apologises to Song Jiang and becomes friends with him.

==Becoming an outlaw==
After the [[Mount Liang|Liangshan]] outlaws storm the execution ground in Jiangzhou (present-day [[Jiangxi]]) and rescued Song Jiang from death, Zhang Heng, Li Jun and several others fetch them at the riverbank after they defeat the pursuing soldiers. Zhang Heng and company ferry the heroes back to Liangshan Marsh and Zhang decides to join the Liangshan cause after that. He becomes a leader of Liangshan&amp;apos;s navy and make great contributions to Liangshan in the naval campaigns against the enemies of Liangshan.

When [[Huyan Zhuo]] leads the imperial army to attack the outlaws, he orders the artillery commander [[Ling Zhen]] to bombard Liangshan with heavy cannon fire. Zhang Heng leads the navy to sabotage the cannons and lure Ling Zhen into a trap. Ling Zhen pursues the outlaws to the middle of the river where his boat is capsized and he is captured. Song Jiang persuades Ling Zhen to join Liangshan. When the imperial army attack Liangshan a second time under [[Guan Sheng]]&amp;apos;s command, Zhang Heng attempts to launch a surprise offensive on the enemy but he falls into a trap and is captured. He is only released after Guan Sheng surrenders and joins Liangshan.

==Campaigns and death==
After the Liangshan outlaws are granted amnesty by the [[Emperor Huizong of Song|emperor]], Zhang Heng follows them on their campaigns against the [[Liao Dynasty|Liao]] invaders and other rebel forces. During the [[Fang La]] campaign, Zhang Shun is killed in the battle of [[Hangzhou]]. After Zhang Shun&amp;apos;s death, his spirit possesses Zhang Heng and he slays the enemy general [[Fang Tianding]] for revenge. Zhang Shun&amp;apos;s spirit leaves his brother&amp;apos;s body after that and Zhang Heng recovers from his trance. He is deeply saddened by the loss of his brother and collapses on the spot, dying from illness not long later.

==References==
* {{zh icon}} Li, Mengxia. &amp;apos;&amp;apos;108 Heroes from the Water Margin&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, page 57. EPB Publishers Pte Ltd, 1992. ISBN 9971-0-0252-3.
* [[Pearl S. Buck|Buck, Pearl]]. &amp;apos;&amp;apos;All Men are Brothers&amp;apos;&amp;apos;. Moyer Bell Ltd, 2006. ISBN 9781559213035.
* Zhang, Lin Ching. &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Biographies of Characters in Water Margin&amp;apos;&amp;apos;. Writers Publishing House, 2009. ISBN 978-7506344784.
* Keffer, David. &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[http://www.poisonpie.com/words/others/somewhat/outlaws/index.html Outlaws of the Marsh]&amp;apos;&amp;apos;.
* Miyamotois, Yoko. &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[http://www.demystifyingconfucianism.info/water-margin Water Margin: Chinese Robin Hood and His Bandits]&amp;apos;&amp;apos;.
* {{jp icon}} Ichisada, Miyazaki. &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Suikoden: Kyoko no naka no Shijitsu&amp;apos;&amp;apos;. Chuo Koronsha, 1993. ISBN 978-4122020559.
* Shibusawa, Kou. &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Bandit Kings of Ancient China&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, page 82. KOEI, 1989.

{{ChineseText}}
{{Water Margin characters}}

{{DEFAULTSORT:Zhang, Heng (Water Margin)}}
[[Category:36 Heavenly Spirits]]
[[Category:Fictional pirates]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
