<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Searing"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Searing" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;[[Image:Sushi searing.jpg|thumb|200px|Eel [[sushi]] is seared using a [[blow torch]].]]

&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Searing&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (or &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;pan searing&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;) is a technique used in [[grilling]], [[baking]], [[braising]], [[roasting]], [[sautéing]], etc., in which the surface of the [[food]] (usually [[meat]], [[poultry]] or [[Fish (food)|fish]]) is [[cooking|cook]]ed at high temperature so a [[caramelization|caramelized]] crust forms. Similar techniques, [[Browning (partial cooking)|browning]] and [[blackening (cooking)|blackening]], are typically used to sear all sides of a particular piece of meat, fish, poultry, etc. before finishing it in the oven. To obtain the desired brown or black crust, the meat surface must exceed 150 °C (300 °F), so searing requires the meat surface be free of water, which boils at around 100 °C (212 °F).

Although often said to &amp;quot;lock in the moisture&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;seal in the juices&amp;quot;, searing has been demonstrated&amp;lt;ref name=&amp;quot;McGee&amp;quot;&amp;gt;{{cite book | author=McGee, Harold | title=On Food and Cooking (Revised Edition) | publisher=Scribner | year=2004 | isbn=0-684-80001-2}} Page 161, &amp;quot;The Searing Question&amp;quot;.&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt; to result in a greater net loss of moisture versus cooking to the same internal temperature without first searing. Nonetheless, it remains an essential technique in cooking meat for several reasons:

*The browning creates desirable flavors through [[caramelization]] and the [[Maillard reaction]].
*The appearance of the food is usually improved with a well-browned crust.
*The contrast in taste and texture between the crust and the interior makes the food more interesting to the [[palate]].

Typically in [[grilling]], the food will be seared over very high heat and then moved to a lower-temperature area of the grill to finish cooking. In [[braising]], the seared surface acts to flavor, color and otherwise enrich the liquid in which the food is being cooked.

==Sealing in the juices==

The belief that searing meat &amp;quot;seals in the juices&amp;quot; is widespread and still often repeated. This theory was first put forth by [[Justus von Liebig]],&amp;lt;ref name=McGee/&amp;gt; a German chemist and food scientist, around 1850. The notion was embraced by contemporary cooks and authors, including [[Auguste Escoffier]]. It is more typically cited in regards to larger cuts, especially steaks and chops, of non-poultry meats such as beef, pork, lamb and tuna.

Simple experimentation can test the theory: cook two similar cuts of meat, searing one first and not the other. Then cook each normally in a preferred method (roasting, baking, grilling etc.) until each exactly the same predetermined internal temperature. Weigh the end results to see which loses more moisture. (The [[Food Network]] program &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Good Eats]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos; carried out such a test in [http://www.foodnetwork.com/food/show_ea/episode/0,1976,FOOD_9956_36653,00.html episode EA1H22], &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Myth Smashers&amp;apos;&amp;apos;.) As early as the 1930s,&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;McGee, Harold (1990), &amp;apos;&amp;apos;The Curious Cook: More Kitchen Science and Lore,&amp;apos;&amp;apos; page 13, &amp;quot;The Searing Truth&amp;quot;&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt; such experiments were carried out; the seared roasts lost the same amount of moisture or more. (Generally more liquid is lost, since searing exposes the meat to higher temperatures that destroy more cells, in turn releasing more liquid.)

Moisture in liquid and vapor form continues to escape from a seared piece of meat. For this reason, searing is sometimes done at the end of the cooking process to gain the flavor benefits of the [[Maillard reaction]], as well as the benefits of cooking for a greater duration with more wetness.

==Notes==
{{reflist}}

{{Cooking Techniques}}

[[Category:Cooking techniques]]

[[pl:Passerowanie]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
