<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Kenfig"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Kenfig" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;[[File:Kenfig Burrows - geograph.org.uk - 161888.jpg|thumb|right|Kenfig Burrows]]
&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Kenfig&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; ({{lang-cy|Cynffig}}) is a [[village]] and former [[borough]] in [[Bridgend]], [[Wales]].
The borough contributed with other [[Glamorgan]] towns to sending a member of parliament to [[Parliament of Great Britain|Westminster]] until the [[Reform Act]] of 1832. The municipal [[ceremonial mace]] is in the [[National Museum of Wales]] but a [[pewter]] copy is on view in a public house.

The area was originally settled in the [[Bronze Age]], while the later [[Kenfig Castle]] and [[mediaeval]] town are now covered by the Kenfig Burrows [[sand dune]]s. This was the subject of a TimeTeam episode screened on 18th March 2012. The current village is a continuation of the mediaeval one, built further inland.  Other attractions include the ruins of [[Kenfig Castle]] and a natural [[pond|pool]] popular with [[birdwatcher]]s. This is one of the few places in Britain where the [[bittern]] can be seen during the winter.

[[File:Kenfig Pool, Bridgend.jpg|thumb|right|300px|Kenfig Pool]]
The area of sand dunes and the pool are managed by Bridgend County Borough Council as [[Kenfig Pool]] [[National Nature Reserve]], and the area is designated as a [[Site of Special Scientific Interest]]. There is a visitor and interpretation centre next to a car park. The dunes are home to a wide variety of rare and endangered species of plants and animals, including an exceptionally high concentration of [[fen orchid]] (or Liparis Loeselii). It makes up part of the largest active [[sand dune]] system in [[Europe]].

Kenfig is an area that is renowned in local [[legend]] and [[folklore]], not to mention a novel, &amp;apos;&amp;apos;The Maid of Sker&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, by [[R. D. Blackmore]], Inspired by a combination of local legend and [[Sker House]] itself. The Bronze Age settlement was originally situated around [[Kenfig Castle]], but the encroaching sand became too much for the inhabitants in around the 13th century CE, at which time they relocated the village further inland, thereby forming the current village of Kenfig and Marlas. The church was moved from the original village stone by stone and currently stands in the village of [[Pyle]], where the relocation is evident in the unusual fact that the smaller stones are at the bottom of the church, while the larger ones are at the top.  All that remains now of Kenfig Castle is covered by the sand dunes, except for the top of its 50-foot keep, which was uncovered in the early 20th century.

==Industrial history==
In 1968 [[BorgWarner]] opened a plant at Kenfig for the manufacture of automatic transmissions.&amp;lt;ref name=Autocar197601&amp;gt;{{cite journal| authorlink = Ray Hutton (Ed)|title = News: Two million Borg-Warner boxes| series = 144| journal = [[Autocar (magazine)|Autocar]] | volume =  (nbr 4133)| pages = page 43|date = date 24 January 1976 }}&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;   In January 1976 the plant celebrated the completion of its two millionth gearbox, which was &amp;apos;presented&amp;apos; to [[Volvo|A B Volvo]].&amp;lt;ref name=Autocar197601/&amp;gt;   At that time a press release stated that Borg-Warner&amp;apos;s UK plants at [[Letchworth]] and at Kenfig were producing transmissions for use in more than fifty different car models, and that more than half the gearboxes produced were exported outside the UK.&amp;lt;ref name=Autocar197601/&amp;gt; In 2001, the factory faced the threat of closure but was saved by a new contract from Korean car company [[Kia Motors|Kia]].  In December 2008, Borg-Warner announced that the plant would finally close by mid-2010 with the loss of all 110 jobs at the site; a statement from the company blamed the [[Late-2000s recession|economic downturn]] for the decision.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;[http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/wales/south_west/7773706.stm BBC NEWS | Wales | South West Wales | 110 jobs to go as car plant shuts]&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

==Nearest places==
*[[Margam]]
*[[Pyle]]
*[[North Cornelly]]
*[[South Cornelly]]
*[[Porthcawl]]

==Sources and further reading==
{{reflist}}

==External links==
*[http://www.kenfig.org.uk/ Kenfig.org.uk - Local History site]
*[http://www.kenfigsociety.org/ Kenfig Society]
*[http://www.abandonedcommunities.co.uk/page7.html The history of the medieval town, its charter and governances, and its destruction by sand]
*[http://www.cynffigchronicles.co.uk/ Bro Cynffig Chronicles, the story of Cynffig told by its children.]
*[http://www.castlewales.com/kenfig.html Castle Wales pages]
*[http://www.bbc.co.uk/wales/southeast/sites/reserves/pages/kenfig.shtml BBC nature reserve page, including video footage.]
*[http://www.glamorganwalks.com/kenfig.htm Glamorgan Walks suggested tour]
*[http://www.geograph.org.uk/search.php?i=3081760 www.geograph.co.uk : photos of Kenfig and surrounding area]

{{coord|51.5153|N|3.7272|W|region:GB_type:city|display=title}}

{{Bridgend}}

[[Category:Villages in Bridgend County Borough]]
[[Category:M4 corridor]]
[[Category:Former populated places in Wales]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
