<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Penalty area"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Penalty area" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;[[File:Flickr RangersZenit1.jpg|thumb|right|The penalty area with penalty box marking and the penalty arc in parallel to the goal. The smaller box is often called the &amp;apos;&amp;apos;6-yard box&amp;apos;&amp;apos;]]
The &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;penalty area&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (colloquially also known as the 18-yard box, penalty box or simply the box), is an area of an [[association football]] [[Association football pitch|pitch]]. It is rectangular and extends {{convert|16.5|m|ft}} to each side of the goal and {{convert|16.5|m|ft}} in front of it. Within the penalty area is the penalty spot (or penalty mark), which is {{convert|11|m|ft}} from the goal line, directly in-line with the centre of the goal. A penalty arc adjoins the penalty area, and encloses the area within {{convert|9.15|m|ft}} from the penalty spot; it does not form part of the penalty area and is only of relevance during the taking of a [[Penalty kick (football)|penalty kick]].&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;http://www.fifa.com/mm/document/affederation/generic/81/42/36/lawsofthegame_2012_e.pdf Laws of the Game at Fifa.com&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

Previously, penalty areas extended the width of the field, but were reduced to their current dimensions in 1901.

==Functions==
[[Image:Soccer field - empty.svg|left|thumb|Schematic of an [[association football]] [[Association football pitch|pitch]], the penalty areas are the larger of the two rectangular regions surrounding the goals at both ends of the pitch]]
[[Image:WM06 Portugal-France Penalty.jpg|right|thumb|A player taking a penalty kick from inside the penalty area.]]
Fouls punishable by a [[direct free kick]] (i.e. handling the ball and most physical fouls), committed by the defensive team within the penalty area, may be penalised by a penalty kick. A penalty kick is taken from the penalty spot.The penalty spot is located 12 yards (10.97m) away from the goal line

The penalty area has other functions, including:
* [[Goalkeeper (football)|Goalkeeper]]s: The area delimiting the area in which a goalkeeper may legally handle the ball;
* [[Goal kick]]s: The ball is not in play until it has left the area, and opposing players must remain outside the area until this time;
* Defensive direct free kicks and [[indirect free kick]]s: Again, the ball is not in play until it has left the area, and opposing players must remain outside the area until this time;
* Taking of penalty kicks: players other than the kicker and the goalkeeper must remain outside the area (and also the penalty arc) until the kick has been taken.

{{clear}}

==References==
{{reflist}}

==See also==
* [[Penalty shoot-out (association football)]]
* [[Association football pitch]]

[[Category:Laws of association football]]
[[Category:Association football terminology]]

[[fr:Lexique du football#S]]
[[ru:Футбольное поле#Штрафная площадь]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
