<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Supreme Court of Judicature Act 1873"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Supreme Court of Judicature Act 1873" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{unreferenced|date=August 2008}}
{{Infobox UK legislation
|short_title=Supreme Court of Judicature Act 1873
|parliament=Parliament of the United Kingdom
|long_title=An Act for the constitution of a Supreme Court,and for other purposes relating to the better Administration of Justice in England; and to authorise the transfer to the Appellate Division of such Supreme Court of the Jurisdiction of the Judicial Committee of Her Majesty&amp;apos;s Privy Council
|statute_book_chapter=36 &amp;amp; 37 Vict c. 66
|introduced_by=
|territorial_extent=England and Wales
|royal_assent=
|commencement=
|repeal_date=
|amendments=
|related_legislation=
|repealing_legislation=
|status=
|original_text=
|activeTextDocId=
|legislation_history=
|}}
The &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Supreme Court of Judicature Act 1873&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (sometimes known as the &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Judicature Act 1873&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;) was an [[Act of Parliament]] by the [[Parliament of the United Kingdom]] in 1873. It reorganized the [[English court system]] to establish the [[High Court of England and Wales|High Court]] and the [[Court of Appeal of England and Wales|Court of Appeal]] and also originally provided for the abolition of the [[judicial functions of the House of Lords]] with respect to [[England]] but, under the act, it would have retained those functions in relation to [[Scotland]] and [[Ireland]] for the time being. However, the [[William Ewart Gladstone|Gladstone]] [[Liberal Party (UK)|Liberal]] government fell in 1874 before its entry into force, and the succeeding [[Benjamin Disraeli, 1st Earl of Beaconsfield|Disraeli]] [[Conservative Party (UK)|Tory]] government suspended the entry into force of the Act by means of further Acts passed in 1874 and 1875.

==Liberal view==
One of the reasons that the Liberal government under Gladstone wanted to abolish the judicial aspect of the [[House of Lords]] was that it was concerned for the poor quality of [[judge]]s at this court. Judges at the House of Lords secured their position by mere virtue of the fact that their fathers were [[hereditary peer]]s and so individuals would automatically inherit seats in the upper house rather than securing their position through merit. Therefore, some of the best [[lawyer]]s in the land were prohibited from sitting as judges in the upper house simply because of their parentage.

==Conservative view==
However, under the Conservative government, the 1874 and 1875 Acts retained the judicial aspect of the House of Lords and ensured the quality of judicial appointments to the House of Lords was ensured by legislating, under the [[Appellate Jurisdiction Act 1876]], for the mechanism of judicial [[life peer]]s. The reigning monarch could appoint any individual to be a peer and thus a judge in the House of Lords. These judicial life peers would hold seats only for the duration of their life; their seat would not pass through their inheritance to their son. Thus, [[Queen Victoria]] and subsequent monarchs were able to appoint leading lawyers to adjudicate in the House of Lords by making them life peers.

==Appellate Jurisdiction Act 1876==
[[Hugh Cairns, 1st Earl Cairns|Lord Cairns]], Disraeli&amp;apos;s [[Lord Chancellor]], sought to remove the [[House of Lords]] jurisdiction for Scottish and Irish appeals as well, which would have completely removed its judicial jurisdiction. However, the Lord Chancellor could not muster the necessary support in the Parliament for the bill as originally proposed in 1874 or when it was reintroduced in 1875. Finally, when it became clear that the English legal profession was firmly opposed to the reform proposals, the [[Appellate Jurisdiction Act 1876]] removed the provisions for the abolition of the judicial functions of the House of Lords, although it retained the provisions that established the [[High Court of Justice|High Court]] and the [[Court of Appeal of England and Wales|Court of Appeal]].

==See also==
*[[Judicature Act]]
*[[Judicature Acts]] (1873 and 1875)


{{UK legislation}}
[[Category:United Kingdom Acts of Parliament 1873]]
[[Category:1873 in law]]
[[Category:Court systems in England and Wales]]
[[Category:High Court of Justice]]
[[Category:Court of Appeal of England and Wales]]
[[Category:Civil procedure]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
