<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Canadian Foundation for Climate and Atmospheric Sciences"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Canadian Foundation for Climate and Atmospheric Sciences" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;The &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Canada|Canadian]] Foundation for [[Climate]] and [[Earth&amp;apos;s atmosphere|Atmospheric]] [[Science]]s&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (CFCAS) is Canada&amp;apos;s main funding body for university-based [[research]] on climate, atmospheric and related oceanic work.  As an autonomous, charitable [[Foundation (nonprofit organization)|foundation]] established in 2000, CFCAS funds research that improves the scientific understanding of [[Process (science)|processes]] and [[prediction]]s, provides relevant science to [[policy]] makers and improves understanding of the ways in which these challenges affect [[human]] [[health]] and the [[natural environment]] in addition to strengthening Canada&amp;apos;s scientific capacity.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;[http://www.cfcas.org CFCAS Home web page.]&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt; Its chair is [[Gordon McBean]].

CFCAS fosters partnerships in support of innovation, investment, policy, skills development and service delivery. It funds the generation of new knowledge that is essential to the competitiveness of industries and to the health and safety of Canadians. The foundation has invested over $117 million in university-based research related to climate and atmospheric sciences, in 24 collaborative networks, 2 major initiatives, and 158 projects. Several of the networks are linked to international research programs; all involved multiple partners. Complementary (leveraged) support for networks has doubled the resources available to them. The Foundation has also hosted or co-hosted a number of workshops and symposia on topics such as extreme weather and Arctic climate, and provides support to international project offices.

==Research==

Research funded by CFCAS informs decision- and policy-makers in government and industry, including those working in:
*Municipalities&amp;amp;nbsp;– for building regulations; emergency planning; snow clearing
*Energy Industry&amp;amp;nbsp;– for load forecasting; pipeline routing; pricing
*Health sector&amp;amp;nbsp;– for anticipating flu/allergy seasons; tracking spread of toxins, pollutants or new diseases
*Transportation industry&amp;amp;nbsp;– for plane de-icing; aviation routing; ship loads
*Resource industries&amp;amp;nbsp;– for winter roads, selection of disease resistant species for reforestation planning, water stewardship
*Financial services industry&amp;amp;nbsp;– for insurance rates; trade in weather derivatives
*Tourist industry&amp;amp;nbsp;– for seasonal planning at resorts; hazard management; cruise routes
*Sovereignty&amp;amp;nbsp;– for security infrastructure; siting of bases and support structures
*Agriculture&amp;amp;nbsp;– for crop choices; pest control, tilling techniques
*Weather services&amp;amp;nbsp;– for storm alerts, regional forecasts, anticipating severe events

==See also==
*[[Experimental Lakes Area]] - scheduled to be closed in 2013

==External links==
* [http://www.cfcas.org/ Canadian Foundation for Climate and Atmospheric Sciences]
** [http://www.cfcas.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/12/2011-CFCAS-Annual-Report-E-FINAL.pdf 2010-2011 Final Report]
** [http://www.cfcas.org/LettertoPM19apr06e.pdf CFCAS Letter to PM, November 25, 2005]
* [http://wc2n.unbc.ca/ Western Canadian Cryospheric Network - University of Northern British Columbia]
* [http://www.cbc.ca/news/technology/story/2010/11/23/climate-research-funding-cfcas.html Canadian climate research fund drying up (Canadian Broadcasting Corporation) November 23, 2010]
* [http://www.ctv.ca/CTVNews/TopStories/20100314/climate_research_100314/ Scientists warn of decline of Canadian climate research (CTV News) March 14, 2010]
* [http://www.canada.com/technology/Arctic+research+centre+scrambles+survive/1298434/story.html Arctic research centre scrambles to survive (canada.com) February 17, 2009]

==References==
{{Reflist}}
sid.com.sid

==Further reading==
*{{cite book|last=Christie|first=Peter|title=The Sky&amp;apos;s the Limit: Ten Years of Achievements|year=2010|publisher=Canadian Foundation for Climate and Atmospheric Sciences|location=Ottawa, ON|isbn=0-9689270-2-5|pages=52}}

[[Category:Climate institutions and programs]]
[[Category:Foundations based in Canada]]
[[Category:Scientific organizations based in Canada]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
