<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Xuan paper"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Xuan paper" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Citations needed|date=October 2011}}

&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Xuan paper&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (&amp;apos;&amp;apos;xuanzhi&amp;apos;&amp;apos; {{zh|t=[[wikt:宣紙|宣紙]]|s=[[wikt:宣纸|宣纸]]|p=xuānzhǐ}}), or &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Shuen paper&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; or &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;rice paper&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, is a kind of [[paper]] originating in ancient [[China]] used for writing and painting. Xuan paper is renowned for being soft and fine textured, suitable for conveying the artistic expression of both [[Chinese calligraphy]] and painting.

== Origin ==
Xuan paper was first mentioned in ancient Chinese books &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Notes of Past Famous Paintings&amp;apos;&amp;apos; and &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[New Book of Tang]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos;. It was originally produced in the [[Tang Dynasty]] in [[Jing County, Anhui]], as well as in neighboring cities such as Xuancheng and Taiping.  The county was under the jurisdiction of Xuanzhou Prefecture in the Tang Dynasty, hence the name Xuan paper. By the [[Song Dynasty]], the paper producing industries in Huizhou, Chizhou and Xuanzhou were gradually transferred to Jing County.

== Classification ==
Due to different producing methods, Xuan paper can be classified into &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Shengxuan&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Shuxuan&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, and &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Banshuxuan&amp;apos;&amp;apos;. Shengxuan (literally &amp;quot;Raw Xuan&amp;quot;), which is not specially processed, excels in its ability to absorb water, causing the ink on it to blur. Shuxuan (literally &amp;quot;Ripe Xuan&amp;quot;), however, is smeared on by [[Potassium alum]] during its production, which results in its texture being harder and its ability to absorb water weaker. This feature makes Shuxuan more suitable for [[Gongbi]] rather than [[Xieyi]], and more easily torn at the same time. Banshuxuan (literally &amp;quot;Half-ripe Xuan&amp;quot;) has intermediate absorbability, between Shengxuan and Shuxuan.

== Features ==
Xuan paper features great tensile strength, smooth surface, pure and clean texture and clean stroke, great resistance to crease, corrosion, moth and mold. The majority of ancient Chinese books and paintings by famous painters that survived till today are well preserved on Xuan paper. Xuan paper won the Golden Award at the Panama International Exposition in 1915.Xuan paper was used to make scrolls

== Material and Production ==
The material Xuan paper uses is closely related to the geography of Jing County. The bark of Pteroceltis tatarinowii, a common species of [[elm]] in the area, was used as the main material to produce Xuan paper. [[Rice]], along with several other materials, was subsequently added to the recipe in the Song and Yuan Dynasties. [[Bamboo]] and [[mulberry]] also began to be used to produce xuan paper around that time.

The production procedure of Xuan paper can be loosely described as an 18-step-process, and a detailed account would involve over a hundred. Some paper makers have invented steps which have been kept secret from others. The process includes steaming and bleaching the bark of Pteroceltis tatarinowii, as well as the addition of a variety of juices.

== See also ==
*[[Rice paper]]

== References ==
* [http://www.chinaculture.org/gb/en_aboutchina/2003-09/24/content_21859.htm Anhui Xuan paper on chinaculture.org], retrieved on 2009-02-08.
* {{zh-cn icon}} [http://www.ahlib.com/ahlib/tszy/gongyimeishu/wenfangsibao/xuanzhi.htm?subfcode=007090110 Xuan paper at Anhui Online Library], retrieved on 2009-02-08.

{{Paper}}

{{material-stub}} {{art-stub}}

[[Category:Chinese painting]]
[[Category:Paper]]
[[Category:Chinese calligraphy]]
[[Category:Intangible Cultural Heritage of Humanity]]
[[Category:Traditional Chinese objects]]
[[Category:Chinese inventions]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
