<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Male genital waxing"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Male genital waxing" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;[[File:Mbrazilian.jpg|thumb|300px]]

&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Male [[waxing]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is the practice of male [[bikini waxing]]. Because of increased public awareness, it is thought to have become more acceptable during the 1990s, although the number of users  historically and currently are unknown. Male waxing is popular in the body building and male modeling community. There are several types of wax used for hair removal.

Waxing is accomplished by spreading a wax combination thinly over the skin. A cloth or paper strip is then pressed on the top and ripped off with a quick movement against the direction of hair growth. This removes the wax along with the hair and dead skin cells, leaving the skin smooth. Home waxing kits have become increasingly popular over the years.  A hard wax which does not require the cloth paper strip is sometimes used on the more sensitive areas such as the scrotum or penis.  A light oil such as baby oil can be applied to those sensitive areas before wax is applied to reduce wax adhesion to the skin.  It is desirable to not cover the genitals with a modesty towel when using oil since the towel can absorb the protective oil, lessening its effectiveness.

== Benefits ==

There are benefits to waxing compared to other forms of hair removal. Waxing is a long-lasting method. Hair in waxed areas will not grow back for three to eight weeks; when the hair does grow back, it is soft and thin. When hair is shaved or removed by depilatory cream, the hair is removed at the surface rather than the root. In a few days, the hair can be seen at the surface. With these methods, hair tends to grow back in a rough stubble. Areas that are repeatedly waxed over long periods of time often exhibit a thinning of regrowth, and regrowth that is thinner, softer, and lighter in color. The use of a hair inhibitor will also aid the slow re-growth of hair; used over a long period of time this can be used as an almost permanent method.{{Citation needed|date=August 2010}}

== Potential dangers ==
Some physicians do not recommend waxing for persons suffering from [[diabetes]] or who have [[varicose vein]]s or poor [[Circulation (physiology)|circulation]] as they are more susceptible to [[infection]].

Patients on [[Retin-A]], [[Renova]], [[Differin]] or [[isotretinoin]] have been advised by doctors not to have waxing performed; these [[medication]]s can weaken the skin, and lead to tearing of the skin.

==References==
;Notes
{{reflist}}
{{refimprove|date=November 2009}}

;Bibliography
* Barker, Olivia [http://www.usatoday.com/life/lifestyle/2005-08-23-waxing_x.htm?loc=interstitialskip/ The male resistance to waxing is melting away] in &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[USA Today]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, August 23, 2005.

==External links==
* [http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Category:Shaved_genitalia_%28male%29 Shaved male genitalia on Wikimedia Commons]

{{DEFAULTSORT:Male Genital Waxing}}
[[Category:Depilation]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
