<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Rug making"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Rug making" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{lead too short|date=December 2011}}
{{ref improve|date=December 2011}}
[[File:RugMakingWomanPassesShuttle.jpg|thumb|350px|right|alt=Photo of woman making a rug|Woman passing a [[Shuttle (weaving)|shuttle]] through the [[Warp (weaving)|warp]] on a [[loom]].]]

&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Rug making&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is an ancient craft, and covers a variety of techniques.

==Braided==
[[Braided rug]]s are made by using three or more strips of fabric, usually wool, folding the raw edges to the middle and braiding them together.  For an oval rug the center braid should be one inch longer than the width-length in feet. example 2&amp;apos; x 4&amp;apos; rug center strip would be 2&amp;apos;2&amp;quot; long. The center braid is laced together and new strips are sewn on to make the braid longer as lacing continues.&amp;lt;ref name = RugScout&amp;gt;{{cite web|url=http://www.rugscout.com/info/ask-an-expert-weave.html|title=Ask An Expert: Types of Weave: Hand Knotted, Hand Tufted, Flat Weave|accessdate=2010-03-22|author=RugScout}}&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

==Hooking==
[[Image:Jehla 01.jpg|thumb|right|140px|A latch hook for rugmaking.]]
Traditional [[rug hooking]] is a craft in which rugs are made by pulling loops of [[yarn]] or [[textile|fabric]] through a stiff woven base such as [[burlap]], [[linen]], rug warp or monks cloth. The loops are pulled through the backing material by using a latch hook mounted in a handle (usually wood) for leverage.&amp;lt;ref name = RugScout /&amp;gt;

==Rag Rugs==
Rag rugs were commonly made in households up to the middle of the 20th century by using odd scraps of fabric on a background of old sacking.

===Needlepunch===
[[File:RagRug.jpg|thumb|right|alt=Photo of a rag rug.|Rag rug constructed from t-shirts and bed linens]]
Using either yarn or strips of cloth, you work with the punch tool from the back side of the pattern. The Monk’s cloth backing is tightly stretched on to a frame. Every time you punch the needle down through the backing, it makes a long thread on the right side of the rug. Then, as you lift the needle, it automatically makes it into a loop. These loops pack together to create a rug so solid that chewing dogs and clawing cats are its only enemy. As long as you use the tool correctly, it will automatically make all the loops the same length.

Sometimes referred to as &amp;quot;speed hooking&amp;quot;, this method of rug hooking is liked for its ease and speed.

==Prodded==
Proddy rugs are made, as the name implies, by prodding or poking strips of fabric through burlap or linen from the back side.  Rag rugs made this way have many names; clippies, proddies, stobbies,  pricked, in Northumberland they are called proggy mats, and in Scotland they are called [[clootie]] mats.  They were often made for more utilitarian use such as by the backdoor; their pile hiding dirt well.

==Woven==
Handmade and machine-made. See [[carpet]]. Woven rugs include both flat rugs (for example [[kilim]]s) and pile rugs.&amp;lt;ref name = RugScout /&amp;gt; The more tightly a rug is woven or knotted, the more detailed a design can be. &amp;quot;It is generally believed that the density of knots determines the value of a carpet.[...]

[[Image:Carpet_manufacturing_Ganja_XIXcentury.jpg|thumb|250px|Cushion embroiders at the shop in Yelizavetpol governorate, [[Russian Empire]] (now [[Ganja (city)|Ganja]], [[Azerbaijan]]). Late 19th century.]]

==See also==
* [[Afghan carpet]]
* [[Flooring]]
* [[Gabbeh]]
* [[Heatsetting]]
* [[Knot density]]
* [[Oriental rug]]s
* [[Tapestry]]

==References==
{{reflist}}

==External links==
&amp;lt;!--======================== {{No more links}} ============================
    | PLEASE BE CAUTIOUS IN ADDING MORE LINKS TO THIS ARTICLE. Wikipedia  |
    | is not a collection of links nor should it be used for advertising. |
    |                                                                     |
    |           Excessive or inappropriate links WILL BE DELETED.         |
    | See [[Wikipedia:External links]] &amp;amp; [[Wikipedia:Spam]] for details.  |
    |                                                                     |
    | If there are already plentiful links, please propose additions or   |
    | replacements on this article&amp;apos;s discussion page, or submit your link |
    | to the relevant category at the Open Directory Project (dmoz.org)   |
    | and link back to that category using the {{dmoz}} template.         |
    ======================= {{No more links}} =============================--&amp;gt;
*[http://www.teammead.co.uk/rugmaking Latch Hook Rug Making]
*[http://www.oriental-rugs-history.com/rug-weaving-peoples.html The Rug-Weaving peoples]
*[http://www.beaconsfieldrughooking.com  Beaconsfield Hooking Crafters Guild website]


{{Decorative arts}}
{{Rugs and carpets}}

[[Category:Rugs and carpets]]

[[pt:Tapeçaria]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
