<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Waldo Patent"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Waldo Patent" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;The &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Waldo Patent&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, a [[letters patent]] also known as the &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Muscongus Patent&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; or the &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Lincolnshire Patent&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, was a document granting title to {{convert|36|sqmi|ha}} of land in what is now the [[U.S. state]] of [[Maine]].  It is named variously for businessman [[Samuel Waldo (merchant)|Samuel Waldo]], who eventually gained control of the patent, and for the [[Muscongus River]], one of the grant&amp;apos;s boundaries.

==History==
In March 1630, John Beauchamp of [[London]], [[England]], and Thomas Leverett of [[Boston, England]], obtained a grant of land from a company acting under the authority of the government of England.

This grant was first known as the Muscongus Patent from the [[Muscongus River]] that formed a part of the western boundary. From the seacoast, it extended northerly between [[Penobscot Bay]] and the [[Penobscot River]] on the east, and the Muscongus River on the west, to the line that now constitutes the southern boundary of the towns [[Hampden, Maine|Hampden]], [[Newburgh, Maine|Newburgh]] and [[Dixmont, Maine|Dixmont]].&amp;lt;ref name=Coolidge&amp;gt;{{Cite book  | last = Coolidge  | first = Austin J.| coauthors = John B. Mansfield  | title = A History and Description of New England| year = 1859| location = Boston, Massachusetts| pages = 338–339| url = http://books.google.com/books?id=OcoMAAAAYAAJ&amp;amp;lpg=PA9&amp;amp;dq=coolidge%20mansfield%20history%20description%20new%20england%201859&amp;amp;pg=PA338#v=onepage&amp;amp;q=&amp;amp;f=false}}&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

This grant or patent conveyed nothing but the right of exclusive trade with the [[Native Americans in the United States|Native Americans]]&amp;amp;mdash;perhaps the [[Penobscot people|Penobscot]] or [[Abenaki]] peoples&amp;amp;mdash;for which a [[trading post|trading house]] was built and supplied with such articles of exchange as were necessary to successful traffic. Trade was carried on without interruption to the mutual advantage of the European-American settlers and natives until the opening of the first [[Indian Wars]] in 1675, a period of 45 years.

After 1675, the patent lay dormant until 1719 when Leverett’s great-grandson, [[John Leverett the Younger|John Leverett]], President of [[Harvard College]], revived the ancient claim and formed the Lincolnshire Proprietors, also known as the Ten Proprietors, so named for the ten shares distributed, one to each member. Samuel Waldo of Boston acquired a controlling interest in the patent in 1729 and it henceforward become known as the Waldo Patent.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;Joseph Williamson, “Brigadier-General Samuel Waldo,” Collections of the Maine Historical Society, Vol. IX (Portland: Maine Historical Society, 1887), p. 77.&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;R.H. Howard and Henry E. Crocker, ed., A History of New England: Containing Historical and Descriptive Sketches of the Counties, Cities, and Principal Towns of the Six New England States, Vol. 2, Maine, New Hampshire, and Vermont (Boston: Crocker and Company, Publishers, 1881), p. 122.&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

General [[Samuel Waldo (merchant)|Samuel Waldo]] was proprietor of the Waldo Patent. He is said to have gone to Europe to recruit [[German people|German]] [[immigrant]]s to settle his 576,000 acre (2,331&amp;amp;nbsp;km²) grant, which included parts of what are now [[Waldo County, Maine|Waldo]], [[Penobscot County, Maine|Penobscot]] and [[Lincoln County, Maine|Lincoln]] counties and all of [[Knox County, Maine]], along with the islands within three miles of its border.&amp;lt;ref name=&amp;quot;Coolidge&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;

In 1759, Waldo accompanied the governor of the [[Province of Massachusetts Bay]], [[Thomas Pownall]], and his 400 men to help establish this site. To open the Penobscot River area to settlement, the governor selected Fort Point in [[Stockton Springs, Maine|Stockton Springs]] to build a [[breastwork (fortification)|breastwork]] and [[blockhouse]]. Called [[Fort Pownall]], the fort included a trading post. But Waldo dropped dead on May 23 near present-day [[Bangor, Maine|Bangor]] while exploring the northern reaches of his property. He was buried without monument at [[Cape Jellison#Fort Point State Park|Fort Point]]. Ownership of the Waldo Patent then transferred to his heirs, who included the Fluckers of Boston.  Lucy Flucker married [[Henry Knox]], who served as a general in the [[American Revolutionary War]], and the Knoxes eventually acquired most of the patent.  Much of their land was eventually sold to [[William Bingham]], leading those lands to become known as the [[Bingham Purchase]].

==References==
{{reflist}}
* Joseph Williamson, &amp;apos;&amp;apos;History of the City of Belfast in the State of Maine&amp;apos;&amp;apos;; Loring, Short &amp;amp; Harmon, publishers; Portland, Maine 1877

{{coord missing|Maine}}

[[Category:Former regions and territories of the United States]]
[[Category:Pre-statehood history of Maine]]
[[Category:Colonial settlements in North America]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
