<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Radial arm saw"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Radial arm saw" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{unreferenced|date=January 2009}}
[[Image:Radial arm saw osha.jpg|thumb|300px|right|Radial Arm Saw]]
A &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;radial arm saw&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is a cutting machine consisting of a [[circular saw]] mounted on a sliding horizontal arm. Invented by [[Raymond De Walt]] in 1922, the radial arm saw was the primary tool used for cutting long pieces of stock to length until the introduction of the power [[miter saw]] in the 1970s.

In addition to making length cuts, a radial arm saw may be configured with a [[dado blade]] to create cuts for [[Dado (joinery)|dado]], [[rabbet]] or [[half lap]] joints. In addition some radial arm saws allow the blade to be turned parallel to the back fence, allowing a [[rip cut]] to be performed.

==Origins==
Unlike most types of woodworking machinery, the radial arm saw has a clear genesis: it was invented by [[Raymond De Walt]] of [[Bridgeton, New Jersey]].  De Walt applied for [[patent]]s in 1923, which were issued in 1925.  De Walt and others subsequently patented many variations on the original, but De Walt&amp;apos;s original design (sold under the moniker &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Wonder Worker&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;) remained the most successful: a circular saw blade directly driven by an [[electric motor]] held in a [[yoke]] sliding along a horizontal arm that is some distance above a horizontal table surface.  A saw which combines the sliding and compound features is known as a &amp;apos;&amp;apos;sliding compound miter saw&amp;apos;&amp;apos; or &amp;apos;&amp;apos;SCMS&amp;apos;&amp;apos;.

Before the advent of the radial arm saw, [[table saw]]s and [[hand saw]]s were most commonly used for [[crosscut]]ting [[lumber]].  Table saws can easily rip [[stock (disambiguation)|stock]], but it is awkward to push a long piece of stock [[width]]wise through a table saw [[blade]].  In contrast, when a radial arm saw is used for [[crosscut]]ting, the stock remains stationary on the saw&amp;apos;s table, and the blade is pulled through it.

Beginning about the late 1970s, the compound [[miter saw]] began to replace the radial arm saw, but only for crosscuts and miter cuts since miter saws are unable to perform rip cuts.  The radial arm saw can be less safe when used by an inexperienced or untrained operator, but is not as dangerous when used properly.  In the hands of an experienced operator, the radial arm saw can safely cut compound miters necessary for picture and door frames, rip lumber precisely to width, cut tongues and grooves, and make variable dadoes.  Like the compound miter saw, the radial arm saw can make these cuts with absolute precision, but is capable of making a wider variety of cuts, including more complex ones.

In the home shop the radial arm saw is an alternative to the table saw.  Both machines can rip, crosscut, do simple and compound miters, dado, mold or shape, make tenons, make open mortises, taper cut, and rabbet. The radial arm saw requires less clearance or space in the shop to handle long stock, since it only requires clearance on the sides, whereas a table saw needs clearance to the sides, in front and at the back.  The radial saw is perfectly efficient backed up against a wall, whereas the table saw wants to be placed in the center of the shop to give all around clearance.  With some accessories the former can be used as a shaper, a disk or drum sander, a grinder, a surface planer, a router, a horizontal boring machine and even as a power unit for a lathe; whereas a table saw&amp;apos;s secondary uses are limited to shaper and disk sander.  The major shortcoming of most current radial arm saws for home-use is that, most radial arm saws that have been built after the early 1960s are manufactured with stamped sheet metal parts and are machined to loose tolerances, hence they are not precise for doing accurate work without &amp;apos;tuning&amp;apos;.  A high-quality radial arm saw has carefully machined track arm ways and locking mechanisms, and a motor that runs very smoothly; under &amp;apos;no-load&amp;apos; conditions most of the sound and vibration will originate from the whisper/whistling and the imbalance of the saw blade upon the arbor.

== Safety==
Radial arm saws require a blade with a very low or negative hook angle, to inhibit overly fast feed rate, binding, and the blade&amp;apos;s tendency to try to &amp;apos;&amp;apos;climb&amp;apos;&amp;apos; the material.

Also a 10 deg. positive hook blade with a &amp;quot;triple chip profile&amp;quot; works well on the radial arm saw and can be considered a universal blade. If the saw climbs with this blade, the yoke roller bearings need to be adjusted and tightened.

{{Types of tools}}
{{Woodworking}}


[[Category:Saws]]
[[Category:Woodworking machines]]
[[Category:American inventions]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
