<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Facial"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Facial" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{About|the skin treatment}}
{{Refimprove|date=March 2012}}

[[Image:Facial mask.jpg|thumb|right|200px|Facials may include the use of a facial mask.]]

A &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;facial&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is a procedure involving a variety of skin treatments, including: steam, [[exfoliation (cosmetology)|exfoliation]], extraction, creams, lotions, facial masks, [[chemical peel|peels]], and [[massage]]. They are normally performed in [[beauty salon]]s but are also a common [[spa treatment]].
Facials are generally categorized, for example:
*European facial
*LED [[Deep penetrating light therapy|light therapy facial]]
*Mini-facial

Facials are used for general skin health as well as for specific skin conditions.


== Facial mask ==
There are different kinds of masks (e.g. [[cactus]], [[cucumber]], etc.) for different purposes: deep-cleansing, by penetrating the [[Sweat pore|pores]]; healing [[acne scars]] or hyper-pigmentation; brightening, for a gradual illumination of the skin tone. Some masks are designed to dry or solidify on the face, almost like [[plaster]]; others just remain wet.  The perceived effects of a facial mask treatment include revitalizing, healing, or refreshing; and, may yield temporary or long-term benefits (depending on environmental, dietary, and other skincare factors).

Masks are removed by either rinsing the face with water, wiping if off with a damp cloth, or peeling off of the face by hand. Duration for wearing a mask varies with the type of mask, and manufacturer&amp;apos;s usage instructions. The time can range from a few minutes to overnight. Those with [[sensitive skin type|sensitive skin]] are advised to first test out the mask on a small portion of the skin, in order to check for any irritations. {{Citation needed|date=May 2010}} Some facial masks are not suited to frequent use. A [[glycolic acid|glycolic]] mask can only be used once a month without the risk of burning the skin.{{cn|date=March 2013}}

Masks can be found anywhere from [[pharmacy|drugstores]] to department stores, and can vary in consistency and form. Setting masks include: [[clay]], which is a thicker consistency, and will draw out impurities (and sometimes, natural oils, too) from the [[Sweat pore|pores]];{{Citation needed|date=March 2012}} a cream, which stays damp to hydrate the skin; sheet-style, in which a paper mask is dampened with liquid to tone and moisturize the skin; and lastly, a hybrid/clay and cream form that includes small beads for removing dead surface skin cells. Non-setting facial masks include warm oil and [[paraffin wax]] masks. These different forms are made to suit different skin types (e.g., oily or dry), and different skincare goals or needs (e.g., moisturizing, cleansing, exfoliating).&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;{{cite web|url=http://www.womenio.com/219/top-5-facial-massage-techniques-and-benefits|title=Top 5 Facial Massage Techniques and Benefits|date=11 March 2012|publisher=Womenio|accessdate=22 May 2012}}&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt; [[Clay]] and mud masks suit oily and some &amp;quot;combination&amp;quot; skin types, while cream-based masks tend to suit dry and sensitive skin types.{{Citation needed|date=May 2010}}

[[Egg oil]] has been used as a traditional face mask where it acts as an emollient, moisturizer, anti-oxidant, penetration enhancer, occlusive skin conditioner and anti-bacterial agent.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;[http://books.google.co.uk/books?id=6ZepRgMaa2gC&amp;amp;lpg=PT467&amp;amp;dq=%22egg%20yolk%20oil%22%20skin&amp;amp;pg=PT467#v=onepage&amp;amp;q=%22egg%20yolk%20oil%22%20skin&amp;amp;f=false Halldor Thormar: &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Lipids and Essential Oils as Antimicrobial Agents&amp;apos;&amp;apos;]&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;{{failed verification|date=March 2013}}{{medcn|date=March 2013}}  As an occlusive agent, it protects against dehydration.{{medcn|date=March 2013}} It can be applied for two hours and washed off with a gentle face wash.


==See also==
*[[Spa treatment]]

== References ==
{{Reflist}}

{{Cosmetics}}

[[Category:Human head and neck]]
[[Category:Skin care]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
