<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Honne and tatemae"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Honne and tatemae" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{For|the river in Germany|Hönne}}
&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Honne&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; and &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;tatemae&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; are [[Japanese language|Japanese]] words that describe the contrast between a person&amp;apos;s {{Nihongo|true [[feeling]]s and desires|[[wikt:本音|本音]]|honne}} and {{Nihongo|the behavior and opinions one displays in public|[[wikt:建前|建前]]|tatemae|lit. &amp;quot;façade&amp;quot;}}.

&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Honne&amp;apos;&amp;apos; may be contrary to what is expected by society or what is required according to one&amp;apos;s position and circumstances, and they are often kept hidden, except with one&amp;apos;s closest friends. &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Tatemae&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is what is expected by society and required according to one&amp;apos;s position and circumstances, and these may or may not match one&amp;apos;s &amp;apos;&amp;apos;honne&amp;apos;&amp;apos;.

The &amp;apos;&amp;apos;honne–tatemae&amp;apos;&amp;apos; divide is considered to be of paramount importance in [[Japanese culture]].&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;{{Citation | first = Takeo | last = Doi | authorlink = Takeo Doi | title = The Anatomy of Dependence: Exploring an area of the Japanese psyche: feelings of indulgence | publisher = Kodansha International | year = 1973}}.&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;  The very fact that Japanese have single words for these concepts leads some &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Nihonjinron]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos; specialists{{who|date=July 2012}} to see this conceptualization as evidence of greater complexity and rigidity in [[Japanese etiquette]] and culture.{{cn|date=July 2012}}

==Cause==
Some analysts{{who | date=May 2012}} see &amp;apos;&amp;apos;honne&amp;apos;&amp;apos; and &amp;apos;&amp;apos;tatemae&amp;apos;&amp;apos; as a cultural necessity resulting from a large number of people living in a comparatively small island nation. Close-knit co-operation and the avoidance of [[Group conflict|conflict]] are considered to be of vital importance in everyday life. For this reason, the Japanese tend to go to great lengths to avoid conflict, especially within the context of large groups.

The conflict between &amp;apos;&amp;apos;honne&amp;apos;&amp;apos; and &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Giri (Japanese) |giri]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (social obligations) is one of the main topics of Japanese drama throughout the ages.  For example, the protagonist would have to choose between carrying out his obligations to his family or [[feudal lord]] or pursuing a clandestine love affair.

==Effect==
Contemporary phenomena such as &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[hikikomori]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos; and [[parasite single]]s are seen as examples of late Japanese culture&amp;apos;s growing problem of the new generation growing up unable to deal with the complexities of &amp;apos;&amp;apos;honne–tatemae&amp;apos;&amp;apos; and pressure of an increasingly materialist society.

Debate over whether &amp;apos;&amp;apos;tatemae&amp;apos;&amp;apos; and &amp;apos;&amp;apos;honne&amp;apos;&amp;apos; are a uniquely Japanese phenomenon continues in the West,{{cn|date=June 2012}} especially among those in the anthropological and art fields. Although there might not be direct translations for &amp;apos;&amp;apos;honne&amp;apos;&amp;apos; and &amp;apos;&amp;apos;tatemae&amp;apos;&amp;apos; in many other cultures and languages, similar phenomena outside of Japan likely exist, however the conventions that help to determine appropriate communication and behavior in various social contexts may be implicitly understood without an explicit name for the social mores on which the conventions are based. For example, very young children are generally not expected to mediate their internal thoughts and feelings when communicating in the same way that an older child or adolescent would be reasonably expected to – this ubiquitous phenomenon is evident when a child’s “brutally honest” observation or candid remark is deemed innocuous, or even endearing or cute (e.g. “Teacher, my mommy said your head looks like an old potato, but it’s more like a turnip, huh?”); yet if an adolescent or adult displayed the same degree of frankness or inconsideration for the feelings of others, it would likely be deemed inappropriate or offensive.

==See also==
* [[Japanese values]]
* [[Emotional conflict]]
* [[Ambivalence]]

==References==
&amp;lt;references/&amp;gt;

[[Category:Japanese society]]
[[Category:Japanese values]]
[[Category:Japanese culture]]
[[Category:Japanese words and phrases]]
[[Category:Dichotomies]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
