<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Natural gas field"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Natural gas field" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Use dmy dates|date=March 2012}}
__NOTOC__
[[File:Iran Gas Fields Location-PesareAmol.png|230px|thumbnail|right|location of Gas Fields of Iran]]
[[Petroleum|Oil]] and [[natural gas]] are produced by the same geological process according fossil fuel suggestion: [[Anaerobic digestion|anaerobic]] [[Decomposition|decay]] of [[organic matter]] deep under the Earth&amp;apos;s surface. As a consequence, oil and natural gas are often found together.  In common usage, deposits rich in oil are known as [[oil field]]s, and deposits rich in natural gas are called &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;natural gas fields&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;.

In general, organic sediments buried in depths of 1,000 m to 6,000 m (at temperatures of 60 °[[Celsius|C]] to 150 °C) generate oil, while sediments buried deeper and at higher temperatures generate natural gas. The deeper the source, the &amp;quot;drier&amp;quot; the gas (that is, the smaller the proportion of [[Natural gas condensate|condensate]]s in the gas). Because both oil and natural gas are lighter than water, they tend to rise from their sources until they either [[Petroleum seep|seep]] to the surface or are trapped by a non-permeable layer of rock. They can be extracted from the trap by drilling.

The largest natural gas field is [[South_Pars_/_North_Dome_Gas-Condensate_field|South Pars/Asalouyeh]] gas field, which is shared between [[Iran]] and [[Qatar]]. The second largest natural gas field is the [[Urengoy_gas_field| Urengoy gas field]] in [[Russia]]. The gas field [[Haynesville Shale]]  Louisiana-Texas has been projected bigger than South Pars, since this a new well it has not been officially recorded its overall power.
{{-}}

==Offshore gas fields==
[[Image:Toisa Perseus&amp;amp;Discoverer Enterprise.jpg|thumb|The drillship &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Discoverer Enterprise]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is shown in the background, at work during exploratory phase of a new offshore field. The Offshore Support Vessel &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Toisa Perseus&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is shown in the foreground, illustrating part of the complex logistics of offshore oil and gas exploration and production.]]
Like oil, natural gas is often found underwater in offshore gas fields such as the [[North Sea Oil|North Sea]], [[Corrib Gas Field]] off [[Ireland]], and the [[Sable Offshore Energy Project]] in the [[Scotian Shelf]] near [[Sable Island]]. The technology utilized to extract and transport offshore natural gas is different from land-based fields in that a few, very large rigs are usually used, due to the cost and logistical difficulties in working over water.
Rising gas prices have encouraged drillers to revisit fields that, until now, were not considered economically viable.  For example, McMoran Exploration has passed a drilling depth of over 32,000 feet (9754 m) (the deepest test well in the history of gas production) at the Blackbeard site in the Gulf of Mexico.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;A Famed Dry Hole Gets a Second Shot, Wall Street Journal, 21 July 2008, p.B1&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;  [[Exxon Mobil]]&amp;apos;s drill rig had reached 30,000 feet by 2006 without finding gas; Exxon Mobil abandoned the site.

==See also==
{{portal|Energy}}

;General
* [[Caprock]]
* [[Gazprom]]
* [[List of natural gas fields]]
* [[Oil field]]
* [[Stranded gas reserve]]
* [[Underground hydrogen storage]]

;Offshore aspects
* [[North Sea Oil]]
* [[Oil platform]]
* [[Drillship]]

;Other
* [[Derweze#The_.22Door_to_Hell.22|Darvaza, Turkmenistan - The &amp;quot;Door to Hell&amp;quot;]]

==References==
{{Reflist}}

==Further reading==
* Hyne, Norman J. (2001). &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Nontechnical guide to petroleum geology, exploration, drilling, and production&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (2nd ed.). Tulsa, Oklahoma: PennWell Corporation. ISBN 0-87814-823-X

==External links==
* [http://www.gomr.mms.gov/homepg/gomatlas/atlas.html Atlas of Gulf of Mexico Gas and Oil Sands]

[[Category:Natural gas fields| ]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
