<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Inefficiency"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Inefficiency" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Unreferenced|date=December 2009}}
{{Wiktionary}}

The [[Term (language)|term]] &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;inefficiency&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; has several meanings depending on the context in which its used:

*&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Allocative efficiency|Allocative inefficiency]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; - Allocative inefficiency theory says that the distribution of resources between alternatives does not fit with consumer taste (perceptions of costs and benefits). For example, a company may have the lowest costs in &amp;quot;productive&amp;quot; terms, but the result may be inefficient in allocative terms because the &amp;quot;true&amp;quot; or [[social cost]] exceeds the price that consumers are willing to pay for an extra unit of the product. This is true, for example, if the firm produces pollution (see also [[external cost]]). Consumers would prefer that the firm and its competitors produce less of the product and charge a higher price, to internalize the external cost.

*&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Distributive efficiency|Distributive Inefficiency]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; - refers to the inefficient distribution of income and wealth within a society. Decreasing [[Marginal Utility|marginal utilities]] of wealth suggests that more egalitarian distributions of wealth are more efficient than unegalitarian distributions. Distributive inefficiency is often associated with [[economic inequality]].

*&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Economic inefficiency]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; - refers to a situation where &amp;quot;we could be doing a better job,&amp;quot; i.e., attaining our goals at lower cost. It is the opposite of economic efficiency. In the latter case, there is no way to do a better job, given the available resources and technology.

*&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Keynesian]] inefficiency&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; - might be defined as incomplete use of resources (labor, capital goods, natural resources, etc.) because of inadequate [[aggregate demand]]. We are not attaining [[potential output]], while suffering from [[unemployment types#Cyclical unemployment|cyclical unemployment]]. We could do a better job if we applied [[deficit spending]] or expansive [[monetary policy]].

*&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Pareto efficiency|Pareto inefficiency]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; - Pareto efficiency theory says that one person can not be made better off without making anyone else worse off. In practice, this criterion is difficult to apply in a constantly changing world, so many emphasize [[Kaldor-Hicks efficiency]] and inefficiency: a situation is inefficient if someone can be made better off even after compensating those made worse off—even if the lonely hour of compensation never comes.

*&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Productive efficiency|Productive inefficiency]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; - says that we could produce the given output at a lower cost—or could produce more output for given cost. For example, a company that is inefficient will have higher operating costs and will be at a competitive disadvantage (or have lower profits than other firms in the market).

*&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Resource-market inefficiency&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; - refers to barriers that prevent full adjustment of resource markets, so that resources are either unused or misused. For example, [[unemployment types#Structural_unemployment|structural unemployment]] results from barriers of mobility in labor markets which prevent workers from moving to places and occupations where there are job vacancies. Thus, unemployed workers can co-exist with unfilled job vacancies.

*&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[X-inefficiency]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; - refers to inefficiency in the &amp;quot;black box&amp;quot; of production, connecting inputs to outputs. This type of inefficiency says that we could be organizing people or production processes more effectively. Often problems of &amp;quot;morale&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;[[bureaucratic inertia]]&amp;quot; cause X-inefficiency.

Productive inefficiency, Resource-market inefficiency and X-inefficiency might be analyzed using [[Data Envelopment Analysis]] and similar methods.

==See also==
*[[Efficiency (disambiguation)|Efficiency]]

[[Category:Economic efficiency]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
