<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Zenith Brass Ensemble"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Zenith Brass Ensemble" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;[[Image:Zenith group 2.jpg|300px|right]]

&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;The Zenith Brass Ensemble&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is a group of 35 talented youth brass and percussion players formed in 1995. Drawing on the brass choir literature for college and professional organizations, the repertoire is new to school band members [1]. The Zenith Brass Ensemble performs a wide variety of transcriptions and original music for brass and percussion. Since 1995, Zenith has provided instruction and motivation for over four hundred members.

Zenith Brass rehearses in [[Troy, MI]] (northern [[Detroit]] suburb) on Tuesday evenings from 7 to 9 p.m. from September to May. They perform concerts in November, March and May each year. The concerts feature a wide variety of music designed to be educational for its members and enjoyable for the audience.

Since its inception, Zenith has drawn members from over 73 different school music programs over a wide area. Membership is a supplement to those school music organizations. Zenith gives first priority to its members&amp;apos; commitment to their school music programs. Members are regular participants in the solo and ensemble festivals and study with the best brass teachers in the area.

The Zenith Brass Ensemble is designed for proficient, motivated players. They perform a large amount of music with a minimum of rehearsal.

Zenith was the subject of a feature article in the Local News section of the Detroit Free Press in May, 2008. Zenith was also featured in articles in the Oakland Press, the Royal Oak Tribune and the Macomb Daily in November, 2000.

==History==
[[Image:Zenith022705h.jpg|300px|left]]Zenith director &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Mark Petty&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; has had many musical interests in his life including piano, percussion, singing, [[marching bands]] and [[Drum and bugle corps (modern)|drum and bugle corps]]. He has had an interest in British [[brass bands]] dating back to his college days at the [[University of Michigan]]. Studying that movement through books, scores and recordings, he came to appreciate the potential of the large brass ensemble. A trip to London for the 1975 International Brass Band Championships in [[Royal Albert Hall]] provided a first hand view of the brass band movement.

When Petty concluded his long career with outdoor marching groups, he wanted to dedicate his efforts to concert music in the form of a brass ensemble. He founded the Zenith Brass Ensemble in 1995 to provide an opportunity for outstanding area youth brass players to make music together and develop their skills in the homogeneous atmosphere of similar instruments.

Starting in 1995 with sixteen players recruited from private teachers&amp;apos; studios, the organization has grown to its current size of 35 members. The Zenith Brass Ensemble has become well known and respected among the area&amp;apos;s band directors, private teachers and professional musicians. The Ensemble continues to attract and recruit the very best youth brass players in the area and strives to make continuous improvement in its performance levels.

Although the literature for brass ensemble is small compared to orchestra and wind band, Zenith Brass has found and performed over 365 selections for brass ensemble in its short history.

[[Image:Combined04.jpg|300px|center]]
TENTH ANNIVERSARY

On May 20, 2006, the Zenith Brass Ensemble celebrated its Tenth Anniversary Season with a concert including alumni. Pictured is the combined group of 66 musicians following their performance of Stars and Stripes Forever.

==References==
Smith, Katharine, May 18, 2008, &amp;quot;A Chance to Shine&amp;quot;, Detroit Free Press (Detroit, MI), Community Section, p.&amp;amp;nbsp;1

Messer, Rebecca, Nov.17, 2000, &amp;quot;Top Brass&amp;quot;, Daily Tribune (Royal Oak, MI)

Stempnik, Rebecca, Nov. 19, 2000, &amp;quot;Teen-agers all-brass band prepares for first concert of the season&amp;quot;, Macomb Daily (Mt. Clemens, MI), pg. 12A

Sugameli, Janet, Nov.16, 2000, &amp;quot;Zenith Brass unites young musicians&amp;quot;, Oakland Press (Pontiac, MI)

==External links==
* [http://zenithbrass.org Zenith Brass Ensemble Website]
* [http://www.new.facebook.com/group.php?gid=22541952533 Zenith Brass on Facebook]
* [http://www.german-brass.de/german_brass/home/index.php German Brass]
* [http://www.summitrecords.com/brass/ Summit Brass]
* [http://www.slondonbrass.net/ London Brass]
* [http://www.tentet.org.uk Harveys Brass Tentet]
* [http://www.millarbrass.com/home.html Millar Brass]
* [http://www.chicagobrasschoir.com Chicago Brass Choir]
* [http://www.lgbe.co.uk/ London Gabrieli Brass]
* [http://detroitchamberwinds.org/about.html Detroit Chamber Brass]

==Notes==
1. Zenith Brass concert history [http://zenithbrass.org/concert_pgm.htm]

[[Category:Musical groups established in 1995]]
[[Category:American brass bands]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
