<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Triple fault"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Triple fault" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{for|the geological term|triple junction}}
{{One source|date=May 2012}}

A &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;triple fault&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is a special kind of [[Exception handling|exception]] generated by the [[Central processing unit|CPU]] when an exception occurs while the CPU is trying to invoke the [[double fault]] exception handler, which itself handles exceptions occurring while trying to invoke a regular exception handler.

[[x86]] processors beginning with the [[80286]] will cause a shutdown cycle to occur when a triple fault is encountered. This typically causes the  [[motherboard]] hardware to initiate a CPU reset which in turn causes the whole [[computer]] to reboot.

==Possible causes of triple faults==
Triple faults indicate a problem with the [[operating system]] [[Kernel (computer science)|kernel]] or [[device drivers]].  In modern operating systems, a triple fault is typically caused by a buffer overflow or underflow in a device driver which writes over the [[interrupt descriptor table]]. When the next [[interrupt]] happens, the processor cannot call either the needed interrupt handler or the double fault handler because the descriptors in the &amp;lt;!--not sure if this is the correct destination for “IDT” in this context, please correct if incorrect--&amp;gt;[[Interrupt descriptor table|IDT]] are corrupted. {{Citation needed|date=July 2010}}

==Virtual machines==
&amp;lt;!--could be worked in here if find specific information: http://www.intel.com/cd/ids/developer/asmo-na/eng/197666.htm or pacifica--&amp;gt;
In [[QEMU]], a triple fault produces a dump of the virtual machine in the console, with the instruction pointer set to the instruction that triggered the first exception.

==Other uses==
The [[Intel 80286]] processor was the first to introduce the now-ubiquitous [[protected mode]].  However, the 286 could not revert to the basic 8086-compatible &amp;quot;[[real mode]]&amp;quot; without resetting the processor, which can only be done using hardware external to the CPU.  On the [[IBM Personal Computer AT|IBM AT]] and compatibles, the documented method of doing this was to use a special function on the [[Intel 8042]] keyboard controller, which would assert the RESET pin of the processor.  However, intentionally triple-faulting the CPU was found to cause the transition to occur much faster and more cleanly, permitting multitasking operating systems to switch back and forth at high speed.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;{{cite web|url=http://blogs.msdn.com/larryosterman/archive/2005/02/08/369243.aspx|title=Faster Syscall Trap redux|author=Larry Osterman|date=Feb 8, 2005|work=Larry Osterman&amp;apos;s WebLog|publisher=MSDN Blogs|accessdate=July 23, 2010}}&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

Some operating system kernels, such as [[Linux]], still use triple faults as a last effort in their rebooting process if an [[Advanced Configuration and Power Interface|ACPI]] reboot fails.  This is done by setting the IDTR register to 0 and then issuing an interrupt.  Since the table now has length 0, all attempts to access it fail and the processor generates a triple fault.

==See also==
* [[Double fault]]

==References==
{{Reflist}}

[[Category:Computer errors]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
