<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Zmeu"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Zmeu" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{about||a water flow|Zmeu River|the village in [[Iaşi County]]|Lungani}}
{{Unreferenced|date=July 2008}}
The &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Zmeu&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (plural: &amp;apos;&amp;apos;zmei&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, feminine: &amp;apos;&amp;apos;zmeoaică&amp;apos;&amp;apos;/&amp;apos;&amp;apos;zmeoaice&amp;apos;&amp;apos;) is a fantastic creature of [[Romanian folklore]] and [[Romanian mythology]]. Sometimes compared to other fantastic creatures, such as the &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[balaur]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos; or the &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[vârcolac]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, the zmeu is nevertheless distinct, because it usually has clear anthropomorphic traits: it is humanoid and has legs, arms, the ability to create and use artifacts such as weapons, or the desire to marry young girls. In some stories, Zmeu appears in the sky and [[Fire breathing|spits fire]]. In other stories, it has a magical precious stone on its head that shines like the sun. It likes beautiful young girls, whom it kidnaps, usually for the purpose of marrying them. It is almost always defeated by a daring prince or [[knight-errant]]. Its natural form is that of a [[dragon]] or [[balaur]].

==Name==
Most scholars agree that Zmeu&amp;apos;s name and appearance is derived from the [[Slavic languages|Slavic]] &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Zmey]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos;. However, the linguist Sorin Paliga challenges the notion that the Romanian word &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Zmeu&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is of Slavic origin, and hypothesizes that the pan-Slavic forms were an early Slavic loan from the [[Dacian language]].&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;S. Paliga, Lingvistica si arheologia slavilor timpurii. O alta vedere de la Dunarea de Jos.Ed. Cetatea de Scaun 2009&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt; The relation with Romanian &amp;apos;&amp;apos;zmeură&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (&amp;quot;[[raspberry]]&amp;quot;) has been deemed to be possible, but rather unlikely, by [[Alejandro Ciorănescu|Alexandru Ciorănescu]].{{Citation needed|date=November 2007}}

The word also refers to the [[Kite flying|kite]]s that children fly.

==Role and functions==
The &amp;quot;zmeu&amp;quot; figures prominently in many Romanian folk tales as the manifestation of the destructive forces of greed and selfishness. Often, the zmeu steals something of great value, which only &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Făt-Frumos]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (the Romanian &amp;quot;[[Prince Charming]]&amp;quot;; literally: &amp;quot;handsome youth&amp;quot;) can retrieve through his great, selfless bravery. For example, in the ballad of the knight &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Greuceanu]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, the zmeu steals the sun and the moon from the sky, thereby enshrouding all humanity in darkness. In the story of &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Prâslea the Brave and the Golden Apples]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, the zmeu robs the king of the precious &amp;quot;[[golden apple]]s&amp;quot;; a parallel can be drawn to the [[Germans|German]] fairy tale &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[The Golden Bird]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, the [[Russians|Russian]] &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Tsarevitch Ivan, the Fire Bird and the Gray Wolf]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, and the [[Bulgarians|Bulgarian]] &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[The Nine Peahens and the Golden Apples]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos; &amp;amp;mdash; although in all these other cases, the thief was a bird (nevertheless, in some versions of the Romanian story, the zmeu does transform into a bird to steal the golden apples). Usually, the zmeu resides in the &amp;quot;other  world&amp;quot; (&amp;apos;&amp;apos;celǎlalt tǎrâm&amp;apos;&amp;apos;) and sometimes &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Făt-Frumos&amp;apos;&amp;apos; has to descend into his dark kingdom, implying that the zmeu lives underground.

The zmeu has a plethora of magical, destructive powers at his disposal. He can fly, [[Shapeshifting|shapeshift]], and has tremendous supernatural strength. Ultimately, the abilities of the zmeu are of no avail, as &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Făt-Frumos&amp;apos;&amp;apos; defeats him through martial skill and daring.

Some English translations refer to the &amp;quot;zmeu&amp;quot; as the [[ogre]] or [[Giant (mythology)|giant]] from [[western Europe]]an mythologies. Like the ogre, the zmeu likes to kidnap a maiden to be his wife in his otherworldly realm. After &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Făt-Frumos&amp;apos;&amp;apos; slays the zmeu, he takes the maiden as his bride-to-be. Similarly, like the giant in the popular [[Great Britain|British]] stories of &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Jack and the Beanstalk]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, the zmeu returns home to his fortress from his raids into human lands sensing that a human (&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Făt-Frumos&amp;apos;&amp;apos;) is lying in ambush somewhere nearby. A Zmeu is also sometimes pictured as a flame who goes in the room of a young girl or widow and once inside, becomes a man and seduces her.

==Notes==

{{Reflist}}

[[Category:Dragons]]
[[Category:Shapeshifting]]
[[Category:Romanian legendary creatures]]
[[Category:Romanian words and phrases]]
[[Category:Bulgarian folklore]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
