<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Wikipedia:Articles for deletion/Ktuvok"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Wikipedia:Articles for deletion/Ktuvok" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;This page is an archive of the discussion surrounding the proposed deletion of the page entitled [[Ktuvok]].&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;

&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;This page is kept as an historic record.&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;

&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;The result of the debate was to delete the article.&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;

----

It&amp;apos;s about creatures in an invented world. People can and will go to [[zompist.com]] if they want to know what a ktuvok is. Also, they will not even know they should know what a ktuvok is unless they&amp;apos;ve already been to zompist.com, in which case they probably already know what a ktuvok is. [[User:Cymydog Naakka|Cymydog Naakka]] 20:27, 18 May 2004 (UTC)

* Keep.  There are articles for [[orc]]s and other Tolkeinesque races, as well as Star Wars sentient species.  [[User:DarkFantasy]]
* Delete. Lord of Rings and Star Wars are famous as they were seen by millions of people. Kvutok returns just 1 hit on google [http://www.google.com/search?hl=en&amp;amp;ie=UTF-8&amp;amp;q=kvutok&amp;amp;btnG=Google+Search]. [[User:Andris|Andris]] 01:42, May 19, 2004 (UTC)
** Maybe you should have spelled it right.  Ktuvok returns 74 hits. [[User:DarkFantasy|DarkFantasy]]
*** Sorry for mistake. Does not change my opinion, though. 74 hits are not enough, even if we do not notice that most of those hits are about some Polish person whose e-mail is ktuvok@poczta.onet.pl. [[User:Andris|Andris]] 17:27, May 19, 2004 (UTC)
* Delete. There is significant fiction, and insignificant fiction. Famous books and billion dollar grossing series of films are significant. This doesn&amp;apos;t appear to be. [[User:Average Earthman|Average Earthman]] 12:10, 19 May 2004 (UTC)
** I think it makes more sense to have &amp;quot;insignificant&amp;quot; fictional things here as well.  If it&amp;apos;s significant, chances are the people looking it up have already found information about it elsewhere, while when stumbling across the word &amp;quot;ktuvok&amp;quot; on a website, they may not know where to turn for information about it. [[User:DarkFantasy|DarkFantasy]]
*** According to google, zompist.com is the only website where they can stumble upon that. [[User:Andris|Andris]] 17:29, May 19, 2004 (UTC)
*** In which case, this should go bye-bye. - [[User:Lucky 6.9|Lucky 6.9]] 19:38, 19 May 2004 (UTC)
* Delete: idiosyncratic, insignificant. [[User:Wile E. Heresiarch|Wile E. Heresiarch]] 00:16, 20 May 2004 (UTC)

----

This page is now preserved as an archive of the debate and is no longer &amp;apos;live&amp;apos;. Subsequent comments on the issue or the deletion should be placed on other relevant &amp;apos;live&amp;apos; pages. &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Please do not edit this page.&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;

----&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
