<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Qatar Science &amp; Technology Park"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Qatar Science &amp; Technology Park" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Multiple issues|advert=July 2010|refimprove=February 2010}}
[[Image:QSTPFeb07.jpg|thumb|right]]

&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Qatar Science &amp;amp; Technology Park&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (QTSP) is a home for international technology companies in [[Qatar]], and an [[business incubator|incubator]] of [[startup company|start-up]] technology businesses.  Established in 2004 as a part of [[Qatar Foundation]], the purpose of the science park is to spur development of Qatar’s [[knowledge economy]].

QSTP was inaugurated on 16 March 2009.&amp;lt;ref name=inaugurated&amp;gt;
{{Cite news
| title = Facts and figures
| publisher = Qatar Scient &amp;amp; Technology Park
| url= http://www.qstp.org.qa/home/about-us/facts-figures
| accessdate =2013-02-14}}
&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt;

QSTP functions by providing office and lab space to tenant companies, in a complex of multi-user and single-user buildings, and by providing professional services and support programs to those companies.  In September 2005 the [[Government of Qatar]] passed a law making the science park a &amp;quot;free zone&amp;quot;, allowing foreign companies to set up a 100 percent owned entity free from tax and duties.

A key feature of QSTP is that it is co-located at Qatar Foundation&amp;apos;s [[Education City]] with leading international universities.  These include [[Carnegie Mellon]], [[Cornell University|Cornell]], [[Georgetown University|Georgetown]], [[Northwestern University|Northwestern]], [[Texas A&amp;amp;M University|Texas A&amp;amp;M]] and [[Virginia Commonwealth University|Virginia Commonwealth]].  The science park helps its tenant companies to collaborate with the universities, and acts as an incubator for spin-out ventures from the universities (and other sources).

QSTP has a staff of 1000 which includes all individuals that work at the science park for the various entities in our premise, as well QSTP management.
.&amp;lt;ref name=interview&amp;gt;
{{Cite news
| title = Qatar Science and Technology Park – Where research goes to work
| publisher = Investvine.com
| date = 2013-02-10
| url= http://investvine.com/qatar-science-and-technology-park-where-research-goes-to-work/
| accessdate =2013-02-14}}
&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt; QSTP aims to grow Qatar’s knowledge economy by encouraging companies and institutes from around the world to develop and commercialise their technology in these sectors in Qatar. In addition, to have a big responsibility and commitment to develop the role of Qataris themselves in the R&amp;amp;D technology sector and this includes providing high tech training, supporting new business startups and enhancing technology management skills. The move towards a knowledge based society requires focus and this is how it is structured for the coming years ahead. The second stage of development will start in 2013, with one new facility being completed by 2014, and another by 2016.&amp;lt;ref name=interview /&amp;gt;

Qatar Foundation itself was established in 1995 by the [[Emir of Qatar]], and has been chaired since by his wife Her Highness [[Sheikha Mozah Bint Nasser Al-Missned]].

Tenants of QSTP are required to make technology development their main activity but can also trade commercially.  The first companies to join QSTP were [[EADS]], [[ExxonMobil]], [[GE]],  [[Microsoft]], [[Rolls-Royce plc|Rolls-Royce]], [[Royal Dutch Shell|Shell]], [[Total S.A.|Total]] and [[iHorizons]].

The design architect of QSTP is [[Woods Bagot]].

==References==
{{Reflist}}

==External links==
* [http://www.qstp.org.qa Official Website]

{{Qatar Foundation}}

{{coord|25|19|31.44|N|51|26|14.55|E|display=title}}
{{Use dmy dates|date=June 2011}}

{{DEFAULTSORT:Qatar Science and Technology Park}}
[[Category:Science parks]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
