<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Leg shaving"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Leg shaving" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;[[File:Mujer afeitando sus piernas.jpg|thumb|250px|Woman shaving her legs]]

&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Leg shaving&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is the practice of removing [[leg hair]] by [[shaving]] the hair off using a [[razor]] or [[electric shaver]].  In addition, some people remove leg hair using [[waxing]], [[sugaring (epilation)|sugaring]], [[depilation|depilatories]], depilation [[Tool|device]]s, or [[laser hair removal|lasers]], but shaving remains the least expensive method.

It is a very common practice among women in [[Western countries]], and is also done by some men, especially [[bodybuilder]]s, [[cyclist]]s and [[swimmer]]s.

==Women==
In Western countries, the majority of women engage in leg shaving,&amp;lt;ref name=depilatory&amp;gt;{{cite web|title=Shaving|url=http://www.depilatory.com/core/twentieth.html|publisher=Marzena|accessdate=August 14, 2011}}&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt; doing so largely for [[aesthetic]] reasons. This practice has developed especially since the early 20th century, around the time of the First World War,{{Citation needed|date=July 2010}} as [[hemline]]s on women&amp;apos;s dresses have become shorter and women&amp;apos;s [[swimsuit]]s have become more revealing, displaying all of a woman&amp;apos;s legs.

Some women may only shave the hair below the knee &amp;amp;ndash; depending, for example, on the length of dress styles in fashion &amp;amp;ndash; while others shave the entire leg.&amp;lt;ref name=depilatory/&amp;gt;  The frequency of shaving also varies, with some women shaving their legs every day, and others shaving only at the start of summer, in anticipation of the wearing of a swimsuit.{{Citation needed|date=July 2010}}

Special razors, different in shape from those used by men for face-shaving, are often used by women.  Advertising campaigns also promote hair-removal products, such as depilatories and waxing kits.

==Men==
Among Western men, the shaving of legs is common in sporting situations and in fact has been taking place for longer than women shaving their legs.  For sports such as cycling and swimming, men started shaving their legs around the turn of the 20th Century. Most male swimmers, bicycle racers, and some male non-racers shave their legs regularly. The practice is most useful in long distance swimming, where the effects of drag can cause a significant time difference in races over 400 meters. There&amp;apos;s no objective evidence to support the practice in cycling, and little common agreement as to its rationale, although a multitude of reasons are given. The various reasons include: faster healing and easier cleaning of [[road rash]], less pain during leg massage, aesthetics, vanity – by more clearly displaying leg muscles – fitting in with cycling peers, &amp;quot;feeling faster&amp;quot; without the feel of wind on body hair so less drag, a sense that Lycra cycling shorts &amp;quot;stick&amp;quot; to the skin better with shaved legs, and a sense that the absence of leg hair assists in preventing [[ingrown hairs]] in the upper thighs from tight-fitting Lycra shorts.

[[Seneca the Younger|Seneca]] suggested that in ancient Rome it was considered an ostentatious bit of effeminacy, contrary to [[underarm hair]] removal: &amp;quot;One is, I believe, as faulty as the other: the one class are unreasonably elaborate, the other are unreasonably negligent; the former depilate the leg, the latter not even the armpit&amp;quot; ([[s:Moral letters to Lucilius/Letter 114|letter 114]]). Summers cites [[Ovid]], A. A. i. 506 &amp;quot;Don&amp;apos;t rub your legs smooth with the tight-scraping pumice stone.&amp;quot;

Many athletes also shave their legs or bodies to facilitate therapeutic massage that is frequently a part of their training or post-race recovery programs. They may also shave their legs if they tape protective gear to them to prevent the tape from pulling painfully on the hair when removed. Shaving of the legs is also frequently practised by [[male model]]s and [[bodybuilder]]s, since it accentuates [[muscle]] definition.

==See also==
* [[Depilation]]
* [[Hair removal]]
* [[Hirsutism]]
* [[Underarm hair]]
* [[Waxing]]

==References==
;Notes
{{Reflist}}
{{refimprove|date=July 2011}}

{{Human_hair_footer}}

[[Category:Depilation]]
[[Category:Shaving]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
