<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Regional planning"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Regional planning" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{No footnotes|date=July 2010}}
&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Regional planning&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;  deals with the efficient placement of land use activities, infrastructure, and settlement growth across a larger area of land than an individual city or town.  The related field of [[urban planning]] deals with the specific issues of city planning.  Both concepts are encapsulated in [[spatial planning]] using a eurocentric definition.

==Nomenclature==
Although the term &amp;quot;regional planning&amp;quot; is nearly universal in [[English-speaking countries]] the areas covered and specific administrative set ups vary widely. In [[North America]], regional planning may encompass more than one state, such as the [[Regional Plan Association]], or a larger [[conurbation]] or network of settlements. North American regional planning is likely to cover a much larger area than the [[Regional Assemblies of England|Regional Assemblies]] of the [[UK]]; both, however, are equally &amp;quot;regional&amp;quot; in nature.

==Overview==
Regions require various [[land use]]s; protection of [[farmland preservation|farmland]], cities, industrial space, transportation hubs and infrastructure, military bases, and wilderness.  Regional planning is the science of efficient placement of infrastructure and zoning for the sustainable growth of a region. Advocates for regional planning such as new urbanist [[Peter Calthorpe]], promote the approach because it can address region-wide environmental, social, and economic issues which may necessarily require a regional focus.

A ‘region’ in planning terms can be administrative or at least partially functional, and is likely to include a network of settlements and character areas. In most European countries, regional and national plans are ‘spatial’ directing certain levels of development to specific cities and towns in order to support and manage the region depending on specific needs, for example supporting or resisting, [[polycentrism]].

==Principles==
Specific interventions and solutions will depend entirely on the needs of each region in each country, but generally speaking, regional planning at the macro level will seek to:
*Resist development in [[flood plain]]s or along earthquake faults. These areas may be utilised as parks, or unimproved farmland.
*Designate transportation corridors using [[Spoke-hub distribution paradigm|hubs and spokes]] and considering major new infrastructure
*Some thought into the various ‘role’s settlements in the region may play, for example some may be administrative, with others based upon manufacturing or transport.
*Consider designating essential nuisance land uses locations, including waste disposal.
*Designate [[Green belt]] land or similar to resist settlement amalgamation and protect the environment.
*Set regional level ‘policy’ and zoning which encourages a mix of housing values and communities.
*Consider building codes, [[zoning]] laws and policies that encourage the best use of the land.

==See also==
*[[Land-use planning]]
*[[Metropolitan planning organization]] (MPO)
*[[Principles of Intelligent Urbanism]] (PIU), a theory of urban planning
*[[Regional Planning Councils]] (RPCs), a quasi-governmental body established by the state of Florida
*[[Spatial planning]]
*[[Transportation planning]]
*[[Unified settlement planning]] (USP)
*[[Zoning]]

==Further reading==
* Jonathan Barnett, Planning for a New Century: The Regional Agenda, ISBN 1-55963-806-0
* [http://www.vjel.org/articles/articles/Salkin11FIN.htm Patricia E. Salkin, Supersizing Small Town America: Using Regionalism to Right-Size Big Box Retail, 6 Vermont Journal of Environmental Law 9 (2005)]
* Peter Calthorpe &amp;amp; William Fulton, The Regional City: Planning for the End of Sprawl, ISBN 1-55963-784-6

==External links==
* [http://www.narc.org US National Association of Regional Councils]
* [http://www.institute.redlands.edu/sds/ Spatial Decision Support Knowledge Portal]

{{Environmental social science}}
{{Land-use planning}}
{{Developments}}

[[Category:Urban studies and planning]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
