<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Medallion Records"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Medallion Records" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Unreferenced|date=December 2009}}
[[Image:MedallionRecordLabel.jpg|frame|right|Label of a 1919 Medallion Record by the Louisiana Five]]
&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Medallion Records&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; was a short-lived ([[1919 in music|1919]]-[[1921 in music|1921]]) record label based in the [[United States|United States of America]]. The label was owned by the &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Baldwin Piano]] Corporation of [[Cincinnati, Ohio]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos;.  Most Medallion issues were pressed from masters leased from [[Emerson Records]].

==See also==
* [[List of record labels]]

Note - there were at least four LPs issued in the 1960s on a label with the name Medallion, or, more precisely, Kapp Medallion:
Mr Phil B.: The Greatest Sax in the World, Kapp Medallion ML-7529. Phil B. was Phil Bodner, a session musician who also played clarinet, flute, piccolo, oboe, and English horn.

The second Medallion album was The Sound of Strings, Volume 2-Frank Hunter Orchestra MS-7509.  The album was produced by Michael Kapp; the recording engineer was C. R. Fine; the tape editor was Donald Van Gordon; liner notes were provided by Paul Myers; package designer was Irving Werbin; package production by Milton Sincoff; re-recording engineers - John Quinn (stereophonic)and Grant Ellerbeck (monophonic); and, cover illustration provided by James Cunningham.  The LP play list consisted of:

Side 1
* Dancing In The Dark (Dietz-Schwartz)
*Avalon (Jolson-DeSylva)
*Fools Rush In (Mercer-Bloom)
*[[Moonlight Cocktail]] (Gannon-Roberts)
*Bali Hai (Rogers-Hammerstein)
*The Man That Got Away (Gershwin-Arlen)

Side 2
*L&amp;apos;Arlequin De Toledo (Drejac-Giraud)
*Something To Remember You By (Dietz-Schwartz)
*Love In Bloom (Robin-Rainger)
*But Beautiful (Burke-Van Heusen)
*Jeepers Creepers (Mercer-Warren)
*Belle Of The Ball (Leroy Anderson)

The third Medallion album was The Sound of Strings-Michael Leighton &amp;amp; His Orchestra MS-7502. Subtitled-&amp;quot;A sparkling showcase of string instruments-subtle textures and bold contrasts, dramatized in startling sound.&amp;quot; The LP contained 12 standards from the American Song Book like, Cheek to Cheek, As Time Goes By, Little White Lies and others. The orchestra was made up of 22 violins, 4 violas, 7 cellos, 2 basses, 2 harps, 2 guitars, piano/celeste, and drums. It was produced by Michael Kapp.

The fourth Medallion album, also produced by Michael Kapp, was The Peter London Orchestra-The Sound Of Top Brass MS-7500. It had 12 tracks of standards that included a variety of music from, I Can&amp;apos;t Get Started to [[Parade of the Wooden Soldiers]] to Cuanto Le Gusta.

Kapp Records, Inc., was a firm from New York City and had no association with the original Medallion label.

[[Category:American record labels]]
[[Category:Record labels established in 1919]]
[[Category:Record labels disestablished in 1921]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
