<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Islam in Ivory Coast"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Islam in Ivory Coast" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;[[File:IslamcultCI.jpg|thumb|right|250px|A [[mosque]] in [[Marcory]]]]
{{islam by country}}
[[Muslims]] make up about 35-45% (around 38.7%) of the population of [[Ivory Coast]].
In Ivory Coast, Muslims pray, fast, and give [[alms]] as required by tenets of Islam, and many perform the [[hajj]] being made compulsory. Most Ivoirian Muslims are [[Sunni]], following the [[Maliki]] version of Islamic law. [[Sufism]], involving the organization of mystical brotherhoods (tariqa) for the purification and spread of Islam, is also widespread, laced with indigenous beliefs and practices. The four major Sufi brotherhoods are all represented in Ivory Coast, although the Qadiriya, founded in the eleventh century, and the Tidjaniya, founded in the eighteenth century, are most popular. The Qadiriya is prevalent in the west, and the Tidjaniya, in the east. The other two major Islamic brotherhoods have few adherents in Ivory Coast. The Senoussiya is identified with [[Libya]], where its influence is substantial.

The significant religious authority is the [[marabout]]. He is believed to be a miracle worker, a physician, and a mystic, who exercises both magical and [[moral authority]]. He is also respected as a dispenser of [[amulets]], which protect the wearer—Muslim or non-Muslim—against evil. The influence of marabouts has produced a number of reactions in Ivoirian society, among them a series of reformist movements inspired by Wahabist [[Religious fanaticism|puritanism]], which originated in nineteenth-century [[Saudi Arabia]]. These reform movements often condemn Sufism and marabouts as un-Islamic, but the poor see that marabouts often speak out on behalf of the downtrodden and that reform movements appear to support the interests of wealthier Muslims.

[[Hamallism]] began as an Islamic reform movement in the [[French Sudan]] early in the twentieth century and has provided a channel for expressing political and religious discontent. Its founder, [[Hamallah]], was exiled from the French Sudan to Ivory Coast during the 1930s. He preached Islamic reform tempered by tolerance of many local practices, but he condemned many aspects of Sufism. Orthodox brotherhoods were able to convince the French authorities in Ivory Coast that Hamallah had been responsible for earlier political uprisings in the French Sudan. Authorities then expelled Hamallah from Ivory Coast and banned his teachings.

The massive immigration of Muslims from the Muslim majority countries [[Burkina Faso]] and [[Mali]] helped to increase the number of Muslims substantially.
==See also==
*[[Islam by country]]

==References==
*{{loc}}

{{Africa in topic|Islam in}}

{{DEFAULTSORT:Islam in Ivory Coast}}
[[Category:Islam by country|Ivory Coast]]
[[Category:Islam in Ivory Coast| ]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
