<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Penal law"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Penal law" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{About|penal law as understood in the English law system|a more general article|criminal law}}
{{Refimprove|date=July 2010}}

In [[England|English]] history, &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;penal law&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; refers to a specific series of laws that sought to uphold the [[establishment of religion|establishment]] of the [[Church of England]] against [[Protestantism|Protestant]] [[nonconformism|nonconformists]] and [[Catholic Church|Catholicism]], by imposing various forfeitures, civil penalties, and civil disabilities upon these dissenters. The penal laws in general were repealed in the 19th century during the process of [[Catholic Emancipation]].

==Clarendon Code==

While some of the Penal Laws were much older, they took their most drastic shape during the reign of [[Charles II of England|Charles II]], especially the laws known as the [[#Clarendon Code|Clarendon Code]] and the [[Test Act]].

The four penal laws collectively known as &amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Clarendon Code&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; are named after Charles II&amp;apos;s chief minister [[Edward Hyde, 1st Earl of Clarendon]], though Clarendon was neither their author nor fully in favour of them.&amp;lt;ref&amp;gt;[http://www.historylearningsite.co.uk/clarendon_code.htm History Learning Site - The Clarendon Code]&amp;lt;/ref&amp;gt; These included:

*the [[Corporation Act]] (1661) required all municipal officials to take Anglican communion, and formally reject the [[Solemn League and Covenant]] of 1643. The effect of this act was to exclude [[nonconformists]] from public office. This legislation was rescinded in 1828.
*the [[Act of Uniformity 1662|Act of Uniformity]] (1662) made use of the Book of Common Prayer compulsory in religious service. Over two thousand clergy refused to comply and so were forced to resign their livings (the [[Great Ejection]]). The provisions of the act were modified by the [[Act of Uniformity Amendment Act]], of 1872.
*the [[Conventicle Act 1664|Conventicle Act]] (1664) forbade conventicles (a meeting for unauthorized worship) of more than five people who were not members of the same household. The purpose was to prevent [[English Dissenters|dissenting]] religious groups from meeting.
*the [[Five Mile Act]] (1665) forbade nonconformist ministers from coming within five miles of [[incorporated town]]s or the place of their former livings. They were also forbidden to teach in schools. Most of the Act&amp;apos;s effects were repealed by 1689, but it was not formally abolished until 1812.

Combined with the [[Test Act]], the [[Corporation Act]] excluded all nonconformists from holding civil or military office, and prevented them from being awarded degrees by the Universities of [[University of Cambridge|Cambridge]] and [[University of Oxford|Oxford]].

==Further penal laws in Great Britain==

In the late 17th and 18th centuries, many non-conformist Protestants successfully evaded the political disabilities imposed by the Test Act by taking communion in the Church of England as required, while otherwise attending non-conformist meetings. [[High Church|High churchmen]] and [[Tories]], empowered late in [[Queen Anne of England|Queen Anne]]&amp;apos;s reign, sought to close this loophole with the passing of the [[Occasional Conformity Act 1711|Occasional Conformity Bill]] in 1711, however the Act was repealed after the [[Hanoverian Succession]] with the return to power of the [[Whig (British political party)|Whigs]], who were generally allied with non-conforming Protestants. In the wake of the [[Jacobite Rising of 1715]], the British parliament also passed the [[Disarming Act]] of 1716.

==Penal laws in Ireland==
{{Main|Penal Laws (Ireland)}}

The Penal Laws were introduced into Ireland in the year 1695, disenfranchising nonconformists in favour of the minority established [[Church of Ireland]]. Though the laws also affected adherents of the [[Presbyterian Church in Ireland]] (who were concentrated in [[Ulster]]), their principal victims were members of the [[Catholic Church]], meaning over three quarters of the population. These laws included:
*[[Education Act 1695]]
*[[Banishment Act]] 1697
*[[Registration Act]] 1704
*[[Popery Act]] 1704 and 1709
*[[Disenfranchising Act]] 1728

The laws were eventually repealed largely due to Irish political agitation organised under [[Daniel O&amp;apos;Connell]] in the 1820s, but effects of the laws in terms of [[sectarianism]] between Catholics and Protestants can still be seen, particularly in [[Northern Ireland]], today.

==See also==
* [[Religion in the United Kingdom]]

==References==
{{reflist}}

==External links==
*[http://www.law.umn.edu/irishlaw/subjectlist.html Laws in Ireland for the suppression of Popery]
*[http://www.bbc.co.uk/history/interactive/timelines/ BBC History Penal Laws in Ireland]

[[Category:Law in the United Kingdom]]
[[Category:Criminal law]]
[[Category:English law]]
[[Category:Penology]]
[[Category:History of Roman Catholicism in Great Britain]]
[[Category:History of Ireland]]
[[Category:Religion and politics]]

[[eo:Puna juro]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
