<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Bugsy and Mugsy"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Bugsy and Mugsy" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Infobox Hollywood cartoon
|cartoon_name=Bugsy and Mugsy
|series=[[Looney Tunes]]/[[Bugs Bunny]]
|image=BugsyandMugsy Lobby Card.png
|caption=Lobby card
|director=[[Friz Freleng]]
|story_artist=[[Warren Foster]]
|animator=[[Virgil Ross]]&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;[[Gerry Chiniquy]]&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;[[Arthur Davis (animator)|Arthur Davis]]
|layout_artist=[[Hawley Pratt]]
|background_artist=Boris Gorelick
|voice_actor=[[Mel Blanc]]
|musician=[[Carl Stalling]]&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;[[Milt Franklyn]]
|producer=[[Eddie Selzer]]
|distributor=[[Warner Bros. Pictures]]&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;[[The Vitaphone Corporation]]
|release_date=August 31, 1957 (USA)
|color_process=[[Technicolor]]
|runtime=7 min (one reel)
|movie_language=English
}}
&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;Bugsy and Mugsy&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos;&amp;apos; is a 1957 animated short film in the [[Looney Tunes]] series produced by [[Warner Bros. Cartoons]], Inc.

The film&amp;apos;s plot features [[Bugs Bunny]] with [[Rocky and Mugsy]] in a remake of the 1950 [[Merrie Melodies]] short &amp;apos;&amp;apos;[[Stooge for a Mouse]]&amp;apos;&amp;apos;. Bugs discovers that two robbers are hiding out on the floor above him, and plays them off against each other.

==Plot==
Bugs Bunny has moved into a deserted house to get out of the rain (his rabbit hole has been flooded from the storm). Suddenly [[Rocky and Mugsy]], on the run from the police after a gold robbery, decide to hide in the house until the coast is clear. Misinterpreting the meaning of the word &amp;quot;[[Carat (purity)|carat]]&amp;quot;, Bugs pokes his head out of the hole. Then Bugs, alerted to the fact that he&amp;apos;s dealing with seasoned robbers, decides to nab them.

First, Bugs takes a [[Candlestick telephone]] and slips one end near Rocky&amp;apos;s ear and whispers from the other end in his hole that Mugsy is not so very trustworthy and is coming up with ideas, until Rocky gets out of the chair and confronts Mugsy. Mugsy has no idea what&amp;apos;s up.

Next, Bugs sneaks out and places an axe in Mugsy&amp;apos;s right hand. Then in his hole he whispers through the old phone and informs Rocky that Mugsy isn&amp;apos;t called &amp;quot;the [[Detroit, Michigan|Detroit]] Butcher for nothing&amp;quot;. And Rocky once again confronts Mugsy, seizes the weapon and slices one of the couch&amp;apos;s arms cleanly. Mugsy still doesn&amp;apos;t know what&amp;apos;s up.

Next, Bugs is in the attic unscrewing the screws holding the ceiling light over Rocky&amp;apos;s head. Mugsy sees the screws coming loose. Knowing that Rocky will blame him if the light falls on him, he grabs his own screwdriver and a ladder and tries to screw the light back in. But Bugs beats him to it and the lights falls right on Rocky. Rocky kicks Mugsy several times in the air.

Next, Bugs switches Rocky&amp;apos;s cigarette with a [[dynamite]] stick. He walks over to Mugsy and imitates Rocky&amp;apos;s voice asking for a light. Mugsy gladly does and Rocky is blown up. Rocky snaps, ties Mugsy up and shuts him in a corridor.

Next, Bugs saws a circle around Rocky&amp;apos;s chair, only letting him see the tool near the end. Bugs then slips it into Mugsy&amp;apos;s hands and hides, while Rocky shoots wildly and confronts Mugsy with some hitting. Finally, Bugs pops out from under the floor, unties Mugsy and puts him up his feet with a pair of roller skates and a powerful magnet and drags it down with him. Mugsy skates all around Rocky. Then Bugs and Rocky cause Mugsy to crash from wall to wall. Soon the police arrive and arrest the crooks. Rocky thinks it was Mugsy that gave them away to the police but it was actually Bugs, who put up a neon sign flashing the words &amp;quot;ROCKY&amp;apos;S HIDEAWAY&amp;quot;.

==External links==
* {{bcdb title|3763}}

{{s-start}}
{{succession box
|before=[[What&amp;apos;s Opera, Doc?]]
|title=[[List of Bugs Bunny cartoons|Bugs Bunny Cartoons]]
|years=1957
|after=[[Show Biz Bugs]]}}
{{s-end}}

[[Category:1957 films]]
[[Category:Looney Tunes shorts]]
[[Category:Films directed by Friz Freleng]]


{{LooneyTunes-stub}}&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
