<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:mix="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/mix/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
          jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
  <jcr:content
    cq:template="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/templates/content/content"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
    jcr:title="Lao Buddhist sculpture"
    sling:resourceType="/apps/wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/page/content">
    <content
      jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
      sling:resourceType="wcm-io/wcm/parsys/components/parsys">
      <contentheadline
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentHeadline"
        headline="Lao Buddhist sculpture" />
      <contentrichtext
        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
        sling:resourceType="wcm-io-samples/sample-app/components/content/common/contentRichText"
        text="&lt;p&gt;{{Lead missing|date=September 2010}}

[[Image:Laosgoldenstupa.jpg|thumb|250px|Monk repainting a [[Nāga]] (mythical multi-headed snake) at Pha That Luang]]

==Media for the sculptures==
[[Lao people|Lao]] artisans have, throughout the past, used a variety of media in their sculptural creations. Of the metals, [[bronze]] is probably the most common, but [[gold]] and [[silver]] images also exist. Typically, the precious metals are used only for smaller objects, but some large images have been cast in gold, most notably the [[Phra Say]] of the sixteenth century, which the Siamese carried home as booty in the late eighteenth century. It is in enshrined at Wat Po Chai in [[Nongkhai]], Thailand, just across the [[Mekong]] River from [[Vientiane]]. The Phra Say&amp;apos;s two companion images, the [[Phra Seum]] and [[Phra Souk]], are also in Thailand. One is in [[Bangkok]] and the other is in [[Lopburi]]. Perhaps the most famous sculpture in Laos, the [[Phra Bang]], is also cast in gold, but the craftsmanship is held to be of Sinhalese, rather than Lao, origin. Tradition maintains that relics of the Buddha are contained in the image.

[[Image:Buddhaimage7.JPG|thumb|left|215px|Statue of &amp;quot;the Buddha calling the earth to witness,&amp;quot; the most common representation of the Buddha. The Buddha&amp;apos;s hands are in the &amp;apos;&amp;apos;bhūmisparsa mudrā&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (subduing Māra) position. ([[Haw Phra Kaew]] temple, Vientiane, Laos)]]
Bronze is an alloy of [[copper]], containing about two percent [[tin]]. Other materials are often added, however, and the balance of ingredients determines the characteristics of the bronze. In Laos, like Cambodia and Thailand, the bronze, which is called &amp;apos;&amp;apos;samrit&amp;apos;&amp;apos;, includes precious metals, and often has a relatively high percentage of tin, which gives the newly-cast images a lustrous dark gray color. Other images, such as the Buddha of Vat Chantabouri in Vientiane, have a higher copper and, probably, gold content that give them a muted gold color.

===Most relevant sculptures===
A number of colossal images in bronze exist. Most notable of these are the [[Phra Ong Teu]] (16th century) of Vientiane, the Phra Ong Teu of Sam Neua, the image at [[Vat Chantabouri]] (16th century) in Vientiane and the image at [[Vat Manorom]] (14th century) in Luang Phrabang, which seems to be the oldest of the colossal sculptures. The Manorom Buddha, of which only the head and torso remain, shows that colossal bronzes were cast in parts and assembled in place.

Brick-and-mortar also seems to be a favorite medium for colossal images. Perhaps the most famous of these is the image of [[Phya Vat]] (16th century) in Vientiane, though apparently an unfortunate renovation completely altered the appearance of the sculpture, and it no longer resembles a Lao Buddha.

Wood is popular for small, votive Buddhist images that are often left in caves. Wood is also very common for large, life-size standing images of the Buddha.

The most famous two sculptures carved in semi-precious stone are the Phra Keo (The [[Emerald Buddha]]) and the Phra Phuttha Butsavarat. The Phra Keo, which is probably of Xieng Sen ([[Lanna|Chiang Saen]]) origin, is carved from a solid block of jade. It rested in Vientiane for two hundred years before the Siamese carried it away as booty in the late eighteenth century. It now serves as the [[palladium (mythology)|palladium]] of the Kingdom of Thailand, and resides at the [[Grand Palace]] in Bangkok. The Phra Phuttha Butsavarat, like the Phra Keo, is also enshrined in its own chapel at the Grand Palace in Bangkok. Before the Siamese seized it in the early nineteenth century, this crystal image was the palladium of the Lao kingdom of [[Kingdom of Champasak|Champassack]].

Many mostly wooden Lao Buddhist sculptures have been assembled inside the [[Pak Ou caves]].

==Modern developments==
[[Image:Buddha Park.jpg|thumb|215px|[[Buddha Park]]]]
The religious art tradition of the region has received an original contemporary twist in the monumental fantastic [[Sculpture park|sculpture gardens]] of [[Luang Pu Bunleua Sulilat]]: [[Buddha Park]] near [[Vientiane]], and [[Sala Keoku]] near [[Nong Khai]], [[Thailand]].

==See also==
* [[Korean Buddhist sculpture]]

==References==
*Thao Boun Souk: L’Image du Buddha dans L’Art Lao; Vientiane, 1971
*[[Madeleine Giteau]]: Art et archéologie du Laos; Picard, 2001; ISBN 978-2-7084-0586-8
*Betty Gosling: Old Luang Prabang; Oxford University Press, 1996
*Somkiart Lopetcharat: Lao Buddha - The Image and Its History; Art Media Resources Ltd, 2001; ISBN 978-974-272-207-4
*[[Henri Marchal]]: L’Art decoratif au Laos; Arts Asiatiques Vol. 10, No. 2, 1964
*[[Henri Parmentier]]: L&amp;apos;art du Laos; édition révisée par Madeleine Giteau; [[Ecole française d&amp;apos;Extrême-Orient]], 1988; ISBN 978-2-85539-542-5

==External links==
*[http://www.laos.culturalprofiles.net Laos Cultural Profile (Ministry of Information and Culture/Visiting Arts)]

[[Category:Laotian art|Sculpture]]
[[Category:Buddhist sculpture]]&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </content>
  </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
